<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 15:06:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['007 First Light' Deep Dive Gameplay Is Coming Later This Week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/007-first-light-deep-dive-gameplay-is-coming-later-this-week</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/007-first-light-deep-dive-gameplay-is-coming-later-this-week.1285707/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Thanks, Sony</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="007 First Light" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/ef7d9f6bf856f/007-first-light.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: IO Interactive</em></figcaption></figure><p>IO Interactive's latest flagship title, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/007-first-light">007 First Light</a>, is heading to the Switch 2 in <strong>2026</strong>.</p>
<p>Now, thanks to an upcoming <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/09/01/state-of-play-presents-007-first-light-gameplay-deep-dive-on-september-3/">State of Play</a> from PlayStation (thanks, <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/news/2025/09/state-of-play-confirmed-for-3rd-september-deep-dive-on-007-first-light">Push Square</a>), we're getting our first proper deep dive into the title's gameplay later this week on <strong>Wednesday, 3rd September</strong>.</p>
<p>It goes without saying that the footage showcased in the State of Play won't be representative of the game on Switch 2. IO's recent port of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hitman-world-of-assassination-signature-edition">Hitman: World of Assassination</a> wasn't exactly the gold standard in terms of performance, with the game struggling to hit its 60fps target for the majority of the time. <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/hitman-world-of-assassination-updated-on-switch-2-here-are-the-patch-notes">A recent patch</a> introduced a new option to lock the frame rate at 30fps, making for a generally more pleasant experience.</p><div><figure data-videoid="_evSaRNgyaU" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_evSaRNgyaU?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/_evSaRNgyaU?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_evSaRNgyaU?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed5c6dc3wsygkz&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><figcaption><p><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_evSaRNgyaU" rel="noopener">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></p>
<p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>833k</span></a></p>
</figcaption></figure></div>

<p>Performance concerns aside, though, we're fully expecting First Light on Switch 2 to be on par with other platforms when it comes to features and gameplay. The showcase itself will last for more than 30 minutes, and will feature "a playthrough of Bond’s first mission as an MI6 recruit. The action includes everything from high-speed car chases to on-foot stealth sequences and shootouts".</p>
<p>It all kicks off at <strong>11am PT / 7pm BST / 8pm CEST</strong>, and we'll be sure to keep you up to speed on any significant announcements that the livestream may bring.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:183366 @ 1756737902 -->
<p><em>Are you keen to see more from IO's new James Bond game? Leave a comment down below and share your thoughts.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://blog.playstation.com/2025/09/01/state-of-play-presents-007-first-light-gameplay-deep-dive-on-september-3/" rel="noopener" href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/09/01/state-of-play-presents-007-first-light-gameplay-deep-dive-on-september-3/">blog.playstation.com</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://www.pushsquare.com/news/2025/09/state-of-play-confirmed-for-3rd-september-deep-dive-on-007-first-light" rel="noopener" href="https://www.pushsquare.com/news/2025/09/state-of-play-confirmed-for-3rd-september-deep-dive-on-007-first-light">pushsquare.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/e5a25ffb53fbe26a6ba45972cb173d48 @ 1756736349 --></div></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/007-first-light-deep-dive-gameplay-is-coming-later-this-week]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Review: Operation Night Strikers (Switch) - M2 Does It Again With This Taito-Themed Collection]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch/operation-night-strikers</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/review-operation-night-strikers-switch-m2-does-it-again-with-this-taito-themed-collection.1285629/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section>
<figure><a title="Operation ﻿Night Strikers Review - Screenshot 1 of 4" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/158412/large.jpg"></a></figure><p>Taito may be famous for creating the likes of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/arcade/space_invaders">Space Invaders</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/arcade/bubble_bobble">Bubble Bobble</a>, but for a brief period at the close of the 1980s, it became the hottest name in arcades thanks to the release of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/arcade/operation_wolf">Operation Wolf</a>, a <strong>Rambo</strong>-inspired military shooter with a realistic Uzi strapped to its cabinet.</p>
<p>Ported to pretty much every home system of the era, the game was followed by sequels that expanded on the core gameplay but never <em>quite</em> achieved the same degree of fame. Fast forward to the present, and emulation specialist M2 has bundled up Wolf with <strong>Operation Thunderbolt</strong> and <strong>Space Gun</strong> — and thrown in the utterly superb <strong>Night Striker</strong>, a Super Scaler-style shooter inspired by the likes of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/sega_ages_space_harrier">Space Harrier</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds-eshop/3d_after_burner_ii">After Burner</a> for good measure — to create <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/operation_night_strikers">Operation Night Strikers</a>.</p>
<p>Mindless shooting is the backbone of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/operation_night_strikers">Operation Night Strikers</a>, then, and in lieu of proper light gun support, M2 has opted for a trio of potential control methods. You can use the analogue stick — which works well enough — or opt for using the Joy-Con's gyro controls. The third option involves a USB mouse.</p>
<figure><a title="Operation ﻿Night Strikers Review - Screenshot 2 of 4" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/158409/large.jpg"></a></figure>
<p>The gyro-aiming approach has been used in titles such as <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/house_of_the_dead_remake">House of the Dead: Remake</a>, and it works better than you might imagine, thanks to the presence of an on-screen crosshair. This tends to drift as you play, but thankfully, you can recalibrate with a single button press during the action. Using a USB mouse will feel a <em>little</em> like cheating for light gun purists, but it is perhaps the best interface method of the ones available, assuming you've got a flat surface handy to rest it on.</p>
<p>All three light gun offerings here are excellent, with Operation Wolf giving you plenty to shoot at while its direct sequel spruces things up with more dynamic environments, all made possible by 2D scaling tech. Space Gun takes this to the next level, swapping out hostile military juntas for xenomorphs and cleverly simulating smoothly-scrolling 3D-style corridor sections with angled 2D sprites.</p>
<p>Night Striker is the outlier, as it's not a light gun game but one where you control a futuristic car which can instantly take to the air. It feels like a fusion of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/arcade/out_run">OutRun</a> (thanks to the branching pathways – although to be fair to Taito, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/arcade/darius">Darius</a> features those, too) and Space Harrier, combined with some amazing <strong>Blade Runner</strong>-style locations and a wonderful Zuntata soundtrack.</p>
<figure><a title="Operation ﻿Night Strikers Review - Screenshot 3 of 4" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/158414/large.jpg"></a></figure>
<p>It's arguably the best game in this collection, and this pixel-perfect port even surpasses the one released on the Saturn and PS1 in Japan back in the '90s. It might be pushing it slightly to say the Night Strikers is worth the cost of purchase on its own, but it's certainly close – <a href="https://www.timeextension.com/news/2025/07/m2s-night-striker-gear-gets-new-story-and-gameplay-trailer">and sets us up nicely for M2's forthcoming sequel.</a></p>
<p>Because this is an M2 release, you get the traditionally spot-on emulation as well as various CRT filters and other options, including online leaderboards and in-game achievements. There's also a selection of information arrayed around the screen, which makes things like health and remaining bombs easier to parse; all of this can be toggled on and off at will. It's also possible to select between the US and Japanese versions of each game.</p>
<p>Also impressive is the fact that M2 has gone the extra mile and included the home ports that followed these coin-op releases (on my physical import copy, at least - they're available as <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/operation-night-strikers-cs-pack-70050000060617-switch/">DLC</a> <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/en-gb/Games/Nintendo-Switch-download-software/Operation-Night-Strikers-2890005.html">on the eShop</a>). For Operation Wolf, the Famicom, NES and Master System versions are present, but sadly, the PC Engine port isn't. Operation Thunderbolt's SNES conversion also makes the cut, but it's a pale imitation of the original game, despite offering six different characters to play as.</p>
<figure><a title="Operation ﻿Night Strikers Review - Screenshot 4 of 4" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/158406/large.jpg"></a></figure>
<p>Not all of the ports allow you to use gyro aiming, and there's often quite a notable gulf in quality between them and the arcade originals, but they're still interesting to play. For many of you, the nostalgic pull might be stronger with these versions, as they may well have been your first experiences of these notable arcade releases.</p>
<p>Night Striker's Mega CD port is included, too, and while it looks like a blocky mess when compared to the coin-op, the sense of speed is impressive, and the arranged soundtrack is fantastic.</p>
</section><section id="conclusion"><h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>The notion of picking up a collection featuring three light gun shooters and a relatively obscure Super Scaler-style game might be a little too esoteric for some Switch owners, but hardcore Taito fans will have a blast (no pun intended) with Operation Night Strikers. The emulation is perfect, the control methods are decent, and there's plenty of customisation on offer, making this another highly recommended M2 offering.</p>
<p>Longevity is going to be an issue for some — even with the online leaderboards in place — and some of the included home ports are a little rough around the edges, but players of a certain age will find a lot to like here, given the legendary status of Operation Wolf and the quality of the other titles included.</p></section>

</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch/operation-night-strikers]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rumour: LEGO Pokémon Collection May Include One Of The Biggest Sets Ever]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/rumour-lego-pokemon-collection-may-include-one-of-the-biggest-sets-ever</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rumour-lego-pok%C3%A9mon-collection-may-include-one-of-the-biggest-sets-ever.1285605/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure><a title="LEGO Pokémon Logo" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/0d0d78db27735/lego-pokemon-logo.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: LEGO / The Pokémon Company</em></figcaption></figure><p>We're still waiting for the official word on what next year's <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/03/its-official-lego-pokemon-sets-are-finally-coming-our-way-next-year">Pokémon LEGO collection</a> will look like, but a recent leak suggests that something <em>big</em> might be on the horizon (thanks, <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/one-of-the-first-lego-pokemon-sets-will-reportedly-cost-650-and-be-the-seventh-biggest-lego-build-ever/">VGC</a>).</p>
<p>Over the weekend, a new post appeared on the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Legoleak/">r/Legoleak</a> Reddit forum from user <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/CarterBricks04/">CarterBricks04</a>, claiming to have information about the upcoming collection's first three sets. According to the post, these sets will go on general release on 1st March, with LEGO Insiders getting early dibs from 27th February (which just so happens to be the series' 30th anniversary). What's more, they're all apparently 18+ builds.</p><div><figure data-videoid="RLc1VHm8D80" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RLc1VHm8D80?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/RLc1VHm8D80?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RLc1VHm8D80?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed43f22fzlrhjn&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><figcaption><p><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RLc1VHm8D80" rel="noopener">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></p>
<p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>833k</span></a></p>
</figcaption></figure></div>
<p>The real juicy part of this 'leak', however, is in the sets' supposed prices and piece counts. The post claims that one set will measure in at 587 pieces with a $59.99 price tag, another will cost $199.99 and will contain 2,050 pieces, while the last will feature... wait for it... 6,838 pieces for the eye-watering sum of $649.99.</p>
<p>There's no indication of what these sets will be, but for reference, that last one's piece count would make it the seventh-largest LEGO set released to date, putting it between the Star Wars AT-AT (6,785 pieces) and Millennium Falcon (7,541 pieces) sets. For those wondering, the largest is the World Map build, which measures in at 11,695 pieces.</p>

<p>But wait, there's more! In a <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Legoleak/comments/1n47ptf/promopokemon_february_gwp_insiders_reward_source/">follow-up post</a>, CarterBricks04 shared that an 18+ Pokémon-themed gift with purchase (GWP) would also be arriving on 27th February, with a 12+ "Nintendo-related" Insiders Reward going live on the same day for 2,500 Insiders Points.</p>
<p>It's a very exciting prospect (even if our wallets are already judging us at the mere suggestion of that price), but let's try to stay realistic here. This is still nothing more than a rumour for the time being, and while the Legoleak group has been on the money about the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2023/08/rumour-animal-crossing-lego-it-may-be-coming-next-year-according-to-leaks">Animal Crossing</a> LEGO sets in the past, the official details for the Pokémon collection go no further than the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/03/its-official-lego-pokemon-sets-are-finally-coming-our-way-next-year">initial announcement</a>.</p>
<p>We'll be keeping our eyes peeled for an <em>official</em> first look in the coming months, but until then, we'll cautiously start saving our pennies — heck, whatever form the collection takes, you know it's going to be a pricy one...</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/pokemon/related-articles:187292,179624 @ 1756737588 -->
<p><em>What do you make of this LEGO leak? Would you be tempted to splash out on the biggest set? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/rumour-lego-pokemon-collection-may-include-one-of-the-biggest-sets-ever]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video: First 'Lego Game Boy' Review Gives Us Our Best Look Yet]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/video-first-lego-game-boy-review-gives-us-our-best-look-yet</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/video-first-lego-game-boy-review-gives-us-our-best-look-yet.1285563/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Brick Power!</p>
</section></header><div><section>

<p>Nintendo and Lego are back with yet another enticing collaboration; this time presenting a 421-piece replica of the iconic Game Boy.</p>
<p>Launching on <strong>1st October 2025</strong> at <strong>£54.99 / $59.99</strong>, the new set will come with the Game Boy itself, two cartridges for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gameboy/super_mario_land">Super Mario Land</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gameboy/legend_of_zelda_links_awakening">The Legend of Zelda: Link's Awakening</a>, and lenticular 'screens' that make it look like you're actually playing a game. Pretty cool!</p>
<p>Now, thanks to Lego reviewer <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@TiagoCatarino/videos">Tiago Catarino</a> over on YouTube, we've got our best look yet at the upcoming set. The 9-minute review provides a solid overview of the components, noting how the size of the console and cartridges is remarkably close to the real deal.</p>
<p>We also get a glimpse at how the lenticular sleeves are inserted into the main device, along with a demonstration of how the face buttons and d-pad work – yes, you can press them. We reckon it's only a matter of time until someone mods this thing to play real Game Boy games.</p>
<p>Nintendo and Lego really knocked it out of the park with their <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2020/07/nintendo_officially_unveils_the_lego_nes_console_launches_next_month">NES replica set</a>, so we've got high hopes for this one. It's also, dare we say, quite affordable compared to some of the stuff Lego has put out over the years.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-articles:186058 @ 1756735799 -->
<p><em>What do you make of the Lego Game Boy so far? Has this video convinced you to pick one up? Share your thoughts with a comment.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g3mOz8SneMs" rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g3mOz8SneMs">youtube.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-info/d41d8cd98f00b204e9800998ecf8427e @ 1756735763 --></div></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/video-first-lego-game-boy-review-gives-us-our-best-look-yet]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>