<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 18:26:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Unofficial Paper Mario-Inspired Cookbook Looks Scrumptious]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/this-unofficial-paper-mario-inspired-cookbook-looks-scrumptious</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-unofficial-paper-mario-inspired-cookbook-looks-scrumptious.1325671/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Serving up on Kickstarter</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="5278cd6ac7f6f"><a title="Paper Plates" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/5278cd6ac7f6f/paper-plates.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/legendscookbook.jobjobllc.com/post/3m3ampcvlrs2c">JobJobLLC</a></em></figcaption></figure><p>We've seen a fair few game-inspired cookbooks in our time, though few have looked quite as delicious as Paper Plates, a newly-revealed recipe book that's absolutely rammed with <strong>Paper Mario</strong> sweetness.</p>
<p>This one comes from JobJobLLC, the team behind the Zelda-inspired culinary venture '<a href="https://jobjobllc.com/collections/cookbooks/products/the-legends-cookbook-reprint">The Legend's Cookbook</a>', and '<a href="http://brawlinthefamily.keenspot.com/">Brawl in the Family</a>' artist Matthew Taranto. It promises 35 recipes, all with a Paper Mario twist, and enough of the series' iconic art stylings that you'd assume it's been plucked from the backdrop of an unassuming <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/paper_mario_the_thousand-year_door">Thousand-Year Door</a> locale.</p>
<p>The book recently launched on <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/437762268/paper-plates-a-fan-made-cookbook-inspired-by-paper-mario">Kickstarter</a>, where it hopes to raise $35,000 (around £26,000) by 15th November to make its dishy dreams a reality. It's already almost halfway there (and that's after just one day), with some pretty appealing Backer Rewards from a hardcover copy of the book to a denim overalls-esque apron — we're particularly fond of the idea of the latter.</p>
<p>While the adorable aesthetic was enough to draw us in, the recipes themselves look super appetising. Every dish has a pinch of Paper Mario to it too, so if the likes of Honey Shrooms or Checkerboard Cookies sound up your street, you're in luck.</p>

<p>Naturally, all of this is dependent on Paper Plates hitting its Kickstarter goal in the coming weeks, so be sure to keep an eye out for updates on its fundraising page if the mere idea has already got your mouth a-watering.</p>
<p><em>What do you make of this cookbook? Are you hungry just reading about it? Let your tummy rumble in the comments below.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/437762268/paper-plates-a-fan-made-cookbook-inspired-by-paper-mario" rel="noopener" href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/437762268/paper-plates-a-fan-made-cookbook-inspired-by-paper-mario">kickstarter.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/mario/related-info/d41d8cd98f00b204e9800998ecf8427e @ 1760550142 --></div></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/this-unofficial-paper-mario-inspired-cookbook-looks-scrumptious]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The ROG Xbox Ally X Receives Glowing Reviews, But It's Still Pretty Pricey]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/the-rog-xbox-ally-x-receives-glowing-reviews-but-its-still-pretty-pricey</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-rog-xbox-ally-x-receives-glowing-reviews-but-its-still-pretty-pricey.1325641/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="f637b568ebc0f"><a title="ROG Xbox Ally X" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/f637b568ebc0f/rog-xbox-ally-x.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Microsoft/ASUS</em></figcaption></figure><p>Ahead of its release on <strong>16th October 2025</strong> (yes, tomorrow), the ROG Xbox Ally X has received a whole bunch of reviews, and it sounds like this thing might be the new king of PC handhelds.</p>
<p>Heck, at <strong>£799 / $999</strong>, you'd hope so, wouldn't you?</p>
<p>We're going to highlight the review over at <a href="https://www.purexbox.com/reviews/rog-xbox-ally-x-an-amazing-handheld-pc-with-plenty-of-console-like-potential">Pure Xbox</a> first and foremost, with the team calling the Ally X a "superb PC handheld with outstanding ergonomics, terrific cooling and natural-feeling controls for Xbox fans". Criticisms include the lack of an OLED screen (welcome to the club), a few software frustrations, and the lack of a trackpad for mouse controls.</p>
<p>All in all though, with a score of 9/10, it sounds pretty great.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:189623 @ 1760550593 -->
<p>The folks over at IGN were similarly positive with another <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/asus-rog-xbox-ally-x-review">9/10 review</a>, going so far as to call the Ally X a potential "device for the history books", providing it receives a few software updates.</p>
<p>So it sounds like the Ally X is the PC handheld to beat right now, eclipsing the Steam Deck in raw power, but also commanding a hefty price tag to boot. The standard Xbox Ally is a bit cheaper at <strong>£499 / $599</strong>, but even this is a big ask these days.</p>
<p>It makes the Switch 2 look like somewhat of a bargain by comparison, priced at <strong>£395.99</strong> in the UK and <strong>£449.99</strong> in the US. Yes, it's not as powerful, but you're getting a true console experience with the Switch 2, not to mention the plethora of incredible first-party games that simply won't be available elsewhere.</p>
<p>We do like the Ally X though, and who knows, maybe we'll wind up getting one at some point down the line. Right now, however, the price is just a little bit steep for us, and it's clear that this thing has a very specific target audience in mind.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:185922,192339 @ 1760549406 -->
<p><em>Are you keen to try out the new ROG Xbox Ally X or its cheaper counterpart? Let us know your thoughts with a comment in the usual place.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/the-rog-xbox-ally-x-receives-glowing-reviews-but-its-still-pretty-pricey]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>