<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - www.nintendolife.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for www.nintendolife.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 18:18:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon TCG Pocket's Gen 9-Themed Booster Pack Arrives Next Week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/pokemon-tcg-pockets-gen-9-themed-booster-pack-arrives-next-week</link>
            <guid>1440760</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>The wonders of Paldea</p>
</section></header><div><section>

<p>You know we're closing in on the end of the month when The Pokémon Company lifts the lid on its next <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/mobile/pokemon_trading_card_game_pocket">Trading Card Game Pocket</a> booster set, and today, we've got just that.</p>
<p>The Paldean Wonder themed booster packs will arrive in the app next week on <strong>26th February</strong> from <strong>1am GMT / 2am CET / 5pm PT (25th)</strong>. As you'd expect from that name, this set is all about <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pokemon_scarlet_and_violet">Scarlet and Violet</a>'s Gen IX and the Paldea region.</p>
<p>New Sprigatito, Fuecoco and Quaxly cards will be up for grabs, obviously, but the reveal has also given us a first look at a fresh full art Maushold, as well as two new Meowscarada and Gholdengo ex cards. Here's a closer look at a handful of the newbies:</p>


<p>It'll kick off what's likely to be quite a big week for Pokémon news. We're expecting the annual Pokémon Presents presentation on its usual date of 27th February, and with the 30th anniversary taking place this year, our fingers are crossed that it's going to be a big one.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/pokemon/related-articles:197281 @ 1771523858 -->
<p><em>Will you be checking out this new Booster Pack? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.pokemon.com/uk/pokemon-news/more-pokemon-from-paldea-arrive-in-the-pokemon-tcg-pocket-paldean-wonders-expansion" rel="noopener" href="https://www.pokemon.com/uk/pokemon-news/more-pokemon-from-paldea-arrive-in-the-pokemon-tcg-pocket-paldean-wonders-expansion">pokemon.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/pokemon/related-info/a2b1c491ffd1e32405d8e3cbe84e97f6 @ 1771523735 --></div></article></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/pokemon-tcg-pockets-gen-9-themed-booster-pack-arrives-next-week]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video: Xenoblade Chronicles X: Definitive Edition Shines On Switch 2 In This Side-By-Side Comparison]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/video-xenoblade-chronicles-x-definitive-edition-shines-on-switch-2-in-this-side-by-side-comparison</link>
            <guid>1440697</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Mira, Mira, on the wall</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Well this is a nice surprise! Nintendo popped up out of the blue today to announce <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/xenoblade-chronicles-x-definitive-edition-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Xenoblade Chronicles X: Definitive Edition - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</a>. The real treat? It's available <em>right now</em>.</p>
<p>Yes, you can now head over to the eShop and pick up the latest addition to the 'Switch 2 Edition' roster for £54.99 / $64.99 (or £4.19 / $4.99, if you already own it on Switch 1). There's no new content to speak of this time, but you can expect to see things running at a smooth 60fps, with a crisp 4K resolution in docked mode — assuming your TV offers it.</p>
<p>Naturally, you might be wondering what this upgrade looks like compared to the Switch 1 version. Well, wonder no more, because we've got you covered. In the above video, Mr Alex Olney showcases the two versions running side by side for a neat cutscene comparison, before highlighting just how smoothly things perform in open world exploration and combat.</p>
<p>It's a marked improvement, we must admit, even if the 60fps boost has been rumoured for just about as long as the game has been on Switch. Now, if you'll excuse us, we've got some mech exploring (<em>mechsploring?</em>) to do.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:197715 @ 1771525062 -->
<p><em>What do you make of this Switch 2 upgrade? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/video-xenoblade-chronicles-x-definitive-edition-shines-on-switch-2-in-this-side-by-side-comparison]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rumour: A Monster Hunter Wilds Switch 2 Port Is Coming, A Fresh Datamine Suggests]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/rumour-a-monster-hunter-wilds-switch-2-port-is-coming-a-fresh-datamine-suggests</link>
            <guid>1440658</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>We are hunters</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="fb5c637913584"><a title="Monster Hunter Wilds Nintendo Switch 2" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/fb5c637913584/monster-hunter-wilds-nintendo-switch-2.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Damien McFerran / Nintendo Life / Capcom</em></figcaption></figure><p>Rumours that <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/monster_hunter_wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> is Switch 2-bound have been circling like an aggroed Rathalos for a while now, and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/rumour-monster-hunter-wilds-latest-update-has-fans-talking-about-a-switch-2-version">datamining late last year</a> suggested a Nintendo version of the 2025 game isn't far off, with <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1q201pw/datamining_group_leaks_detailed_presets_for/">more recent efforts</a> uncovering evidence of docked and handheld mode performance presets.</p>
<p>Well, according to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/monsterhunterleaks/comments/1r8c00w/tempered_gogmazios_and_zoh_shia_sw2_version/">Lener30 on Reddit</a> (thanks, <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/fans-uncover-strongest-evidence-yet-that-monster-hunter-wilds-is-coming-to-nintendo-switch-2/">VGC</a>), there's a little more than a line of code pointing to a port this time. This time, a "Tutorial image for Local Communication" has apparently been found and (as posted by Universo Nintendo's <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/necro.universonintendo.com/post/3mf64ozbqes2j">Necro Felipe</a>) that sure isn't Sony or Microsoft hardware:</p>

<p>Pinches of salt and all that — and Capcom is obviously keeping quiet — but assuming it's legit, that's a smoking gun and a half. "Interestingly enough they scrubbed all the text mentions of the NSW2 Version," says Lener30.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/monster_hunter_rise">Monster Hunter Rise</a> was a big hit on Switch, of course, but if you haven't been keeping track of Monster Hunter happenings outside the realm of Nintendo systems, Wilds launched back in February 2025 and became the fastest-selling game in Capcom's history.</p>
<p>It went down well with critics, too, although not <em>quite</em> as well as 2018's <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps4/monster_hunter_world">World</a>; the latter is sitting on a <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/monster-hunter-wilds/">"Generally Favourable"</a> 88 on Metacritic versus the <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/monster-hunter-world/">"Universal Acclaim"</a> of World's 90.</p>
<p>If you want to find out more about why these Wilds rumours are exciting, check out <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/reviews/ps5/monster-hunter-wilds">the review from our friends over at Push Square</a>, and let us know below if you're preparing to go, ahem, <em>wild</em> for Wilds on Switch 2.</p>
<p>Oof. Apologies.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:178487,195760,193151 @ 1771524011 --></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.reddit.com/r/monsterhunterleaks/comments/1r8c00w/tempered_gogmazios_and_zoh_shia_sw2_version/" rel="noopener" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/monsterhunterleaks/comments/1r8c00w/tempered_gogmazios_and_zoh_shia_sw2_version/">reddit.com</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/fans-uncover-strongest-evidence-yet-that-monster-hunter-wilds-is-coming-to-nintendo-switch-2/" rel="noopener" href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/fans-uncover-strongest-evidence-yet-that-monster-hunter-wilds-is-coming-to-nintendo-switch-2/">videogameschronicle.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/69b1d31e4a00cdde809c26b29239ba08 @ 1771524067 --></div></article><div><p>Gavin first wrote for Nintendo Life in 2018 before joining the site full-time the following year, rising through the ranks to become Editor. He can currently be found squashed beneath a Switch backlog the size of Normandy.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/dartmonkey"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('dartmonkey');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/rumour-a-monster-hunter-wilds-switch-2-port-is-coming-a-fresh-datamine-suggests]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA Sports FC Revealed To Use AI For Some Commentator Voiceover]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/ea-sports-fc-revealed-to-use-ai-for-some-commentator-voiceover</link>
            <guid>1440619</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="ac56ce1c8a42f"><a title="EA Sports FC 26" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/ac56ce1c8a42f/ea-sports-fc-26.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: EA</em></figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b007t9y1">Match of the Day</a> commentator Guy Mowbray has been a staple voice in various football (soccer) games over the years. Having worked on the iconic BBC show for over 20 years, he's become one of the defining voices of the sport for a thousands.</p>
<p>But commentating real football game on live TV is <em>very</em> different to supplying voice lines for a video game franchise like <strong>EA Sports FC</strong>, and in a report from <a href="https://www.bbc.com/sport/football/articles/c4g40828ngjo">BBC Sport</a>, it's been revealed that EA uses an AI replica of Mowbray's voice to do some of the work. With Mowbray's permission, of course.</p><div><figure data-videoid="r2Zh6lJRTak" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/r2Zh6lJRTak?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytr2Zh6lJRTak" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/r2Zh6lJRTak?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/r2Zh6lJRTak?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed62bd51nrjgih&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>842k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p>In the piece, Mowbray — whose first video game commentary can be heard on the UEFA Champions League Season 2001/2002 on PS2 — admits that doing voiceover for EA nowadays is a "never-ending job" as it "constantly needs updating" with new names joining the beautiful game constantly alongside additional game modes and new terms.</p>
<p>"Either recording or doing prep, it is part of my weekly routine - pretty much every week from November all the way through to the start of July", Mowbray says, meaning it takes up a huge chunk of the football season in the UK.</p>
<p>It's not just that Mowbray has to say hundreds of footballer names, however, more that he has to say each of them multiple different times in different styles, pitches, or tones, depending on where they might be on the pitch and what they're doing. With over 20,000 players in the FC, that's a huge ask. Which is where AI comes in, at least to help with some of the player names.</p>
<p>"AI has long been part of our development pipeline - from animation to gameplay systems - and continues to support our teams in making better, more responsive football experiences," EA tells the BBC, reiterating that the human touch is necessary for the experience: "...when it comes to commentary and content, it's always a collaboration with our talent - not a replacement."</p>

<p>Mowbray collaborates with EA on this, and advised that the commentary "has got to be at different levels depending where he is on the pitch, as I would do when commentating normally."</p>
<p>"It can't be scripted for me because it has got to be in my style and how I would say it in real life, so I have to think of those lines myself. It's the same for Sue [Smith] on co-comms — she will need 10 different ways of adding insight or colour too."</p>
<p>So it's a very in-depth process, but it's not clear whether EA uses AI for commentators other than Mowbray. We've reached out to EA for clarification on this.</p>
<p>Of course, there are a number of concerns about AI use around actors and voice actors in particular, with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2024/09/bayonetta-star-jennifer-hale-on-the-sag-aftra-strikes-ai-is-coming-for-us-all">Mass Effect star Jennifer Hale speaking out about the issue back in 2024</a>, and a number of strikes held by voice acting unions over the years.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>How do you feel about the use of AI voicework in EA Sports FC? Let us know in the comments</em>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:195525,188128 @ 1771522737 --></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/ea-sports-fc-revealed-to-use-ai-for-some-commentator-voiceover]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>