<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 10:55:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["I Can't Afford To Give It Away For Free" - Silksong's Low Price Is Causing Devs To Re-Evaluate Their Own Games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/i-cant-afford-to-give-it-away-for-free-silksongs-low-price-is-causing-devs-to-re-evaluate-their-own-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/i-cant-afford-to-give-it-away-for-free-silksongs-low-price-is-causing-devs-to-re-evaluate-their-own-games.1289634/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section>
<figure><a title="Silksong / Lone Fungus" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/d620621c38f20/silksong-lone-fungus.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>After an exceptionally long wait, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hollow-knight-silksong-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a> is out now on the Switch and Switch 2, and perhaps one of the most pleasantly surprising aspects of its launch is its price.</p>
<p>You're looking at <strong>$19.99 / £16.75 / €19.99 / ¥2300</strong> for the new release which, given the sheer length of its development and presumptions around its runtime, seems very reasonable indeed. Some folks, however, think that Team Cherry has legitimately priced the game too low, and therefore may be distorting players' expectations regarding what a $20 game should look like (thanks, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/is-hollow-knight-silksongs-cheap-price-a-problem-for-other-indie-games-devs-and-publishers-weigh-up-its-impact">Eurogamer</a>).</p><div><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067nrjzmo&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><figcaption><p><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C1rrCdi_XjA" rel="noopener">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></p>
<p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>833k</span></a></p>
</figcaption></figure></div>
<p>First up is BastiArtGames, the solo-developer of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/lone_fungus">Lone Fungus</a>, who took to <a href="https://x.com/BastiArtGames/status/1962412246039953783">X</a> and asked what its sequel, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2463220/Lone_Fungus_Melody_of_Spores/">Lone Fungus: Melody of Spores</a>, should be priced at now that Silksong has launched. The game was originally targeting a price of $20, which the developer had considered fair, but is now questioning whether it should be lowered to undercut Silksong.</p>

<p>Similarly, RJ Lake, who is directing the upcoming rhythm game <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2240620/UNBEATABLE/">Unbeatable</a>, posted a thread stating that while he is pleased that Silksong is so cheap, it could have severe ramifications on how players perceive the value of games, stating that "'The Gamer' is a creature very bad at knowing why things cost what they do".</p>

<p>Developer Toukana, who worked on <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/dorfromantik">Dorfromantik</a> and is now about to release <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2719750/Star_Birds/">Star Birds</a>, told Eurogamer that the latter's price has also been affected following the game's short delay from 4th September to 10th September:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Yes, Silksong's price has influenced our decision. We're trying not to compete too directly with Silksong, both in terms of release date and pricing. Of course, these are two very different games with potentially different player bases, but there's definitely some overlap. That makes things tricky, especially since Star Birds is a joint project between two studios, together employing more people than Team Cherry."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It's an interesting situation, to be sure, but we also think a significant jump in price from the original <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/hollow_knight">Hollow Knight</a> to Hollow Knight: Silksong would have almost certainly ruffled a few feathers. Given the anticipation around the game along with how few people were involved in its development, we reckon Team Cherry probably made the correct decision regarding price.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:187338,187438 @ 1757067303 -->
<p><em>But what do you think, dear readers? Is Silksong priced appropriately, or do you think Team Cherry could have gotten away with pricing it higher? Let us know with a comment.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.eurogamer.net/is-hollow-knight-silksongs-cheap-price-a-problem-for-other-indie-games-devs-and-publishers-weigh-up-its-impact" rel="noopener" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/is-hollow-knight-silksongs-cheap-price-a-problem-for-other-indie-games-devs-and-publishers-weigh-up-its-impact">eurogamer.net</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/f7f12d6e45c5f3a7d03253a13ddcb8bf @ 1757066597 --></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/i-cant-afford-to-give-it-away-for-free-silksongs-low-price-is-causing-devs-to-re-evaluate-their-own-games]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft Employee Explains Why Star Wars Outlaws Is A Game-Key Card]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/ubisoft-employee-explains-why-star-wars-outlaws-is-a-game-key-card</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-employee-explains-why-star-wars-outlaws-is-a-game-key-card.1289529/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>And it's seemingly got nothing to do with cost</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="Star Wars Outlaws" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/878241ef8df8a/star-wars-outlaws.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Ubisoft</em></figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/star-wars-outlaws">Star Wars Outlaws</a>, released on <strong>4th September 2025</strong>, is the latest in a long line of Switch 2 titles utilising the Game-Key Card physical release.</p>
<p>It's safe to say that most folks are under the assumption that cost is likely the driving factor behind the use of the Game-Key Card medium, with Nintendo supposedly only offering 64GB cartridges to third-party developers.</p>
<p>Over on <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/cubusaddendum.bsky.social/post/3lxzsvi6s7c2e">Bluesky</a>, however, Rob Bantin, who is the audio architect for Ubisoft's proprietary Snowdrop engine, explained the decision to use Game-Key Cards, and it's seemingly got nothing to do with cost. Instead, it's all to do with the disc streaming required for Outlaws' open world, with Bantin stating that the Switch 2 cartridges simply don't offer the performance needed for Ubisoft to hit its quality target.</p><div><figure data-videoid="6EOKFq0qA_o" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6EOKFq0qA_o?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/6EOKFq0qA_o?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6EOKFq0qA_o?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed60cf74tjlxyq&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><figcaption><p><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6EOKFq0qA_o" rel="noopener">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></p>
<p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>833k</span></a></p>
</figcaption></figure></div>
<blockquote>
<p>"Snowdrop relies heavily on disk streaming for its open world environments, and we found the Switch 2 cards simply didn’t give the performance we needed at the quality target we were going for. I don’t recall the cost of the cards ever entering the discussion - probably because it was moot.</p>
<p>"I think if we’d designed a game for Switch 2 from the ground up it might have been different. As it was, we’d build a game around the SSDs of the initial target platforms, and then the Switch 2 came along a while later. In this case I think our leadership made the right call."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>John Linneman of Digital Foundry empathised with the reasoning, stating:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Honestly, and this sucks, I do kinda get it. To match other consoles, they needed storage that was fast like a modern SSD, right? The cost on that stuff has not come down like the flash memory used for SW1 games. I think they probably did what they could and, even still, those carts cost $23 a piece."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Naturally, the explanation here likely won't (and can't) be applied to every Switch 2 game released on Game-Key Card. Some of it is probably going to be tied to cost, but it's nice to see a bit more nuance added to the conversation from both Bantin and Linneman.</p>
<p>Regardless of what side of the fence you sit on, it seems Game-Key Cards are here to stay, whether it's down to cost or technical limitations.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:187003,187348 @ 1757069157 -->
<p><em>What do you make of the explanation provided here? Does it change your view of Game-Key Cards at all? Let us know with a comment, and thanks to user Suketoudara for the tip.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://bsky.app/profile/cubusaddendum.bsky.social/post/3lxzsvi6s7c2e" rel="noopener" href="https://bsky.app/profile/cubusaddendum.bsky.social/post/3lxzsvi6s7c2e">bsky.app</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/d48352d9a6603ad331114d3fb409cc1d @ 1757069360 --></div></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/ubisoft-employee-explains-why-star-wars-outlaws-is-a-game-key-card]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>