<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 17:54:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hori's New Switch 2 Pad Lets You Lock The Home And Capture Buttons]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/horis-new-switch-2-pad-lets-you-lock-the-home-and-capture-buttons</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/horis-new-switch-2-pad-lets-you-lock-the-home-and-capture-buttons.1317799/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>But why?</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="fe3dadf3e45d7"><a title="Horipad Turbo 1" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/fe3dadf3e45d7/horipad-turbo-1.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>Accessory manufacturer Hori has introduced another budget-friendly alternative to the official Switch 2 Pro Controller, with a new pad coming in at roughly $54 when converted from Japanese yen (thanks, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/791438/hori-wireless-horipad-turbo-nintendo-switch-2-controller">The Verge</a>).</p>
<p>This means it's priced significantly lower than the $89.99 Nintendo itself is asking for with its official offering, but a few sacrifices have been made to bring costs down. So crucially, the Horipad Turbo controller cannot wake the Switch 2 remotely, there's no headphone jack, and it doesn't sport any NFC functionality for your amiibos.</p>
<p>What it <em>does</em> do, however, is let you lock the buttons in the middle – like the home, capture, +, and - buttons – via a small toggle located on the back. Why? Well, who knows, but there you go.</p>
<p>In all seriousness though, there are plenty of arcade controllers these days that include tournament lock toggles to disable any inessential inputs while in the heat of battle. It's possible Hori might want to capture some of that niche, but these new pads don't particularly strike us as the go-to option for fight fans.</p>
<p>Aside from that, the joysticks utilise TMR technology to minimise any potential stick drift, while there are two additional inputs on the back of the pad to rival those found on the Pro Controller. Finally, Hori has seen fit to allow remapping across pretty much the entire suite of buttons, so that should come in handy if you like to tinker around with that kind of stuff.</p>

<p>There's no word on when (or even if) these new pads will make their way to the West, but we'll be keep a close eye on them regardless. Even if they don't sport all the features you're looking for in a Switch 2 controller, it's always nice to have options.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:183944 @ 1759772699 -->
<p><em>What do you make of the new Horipad Turbo? Do you think you'd want to pick one up? Share your thoughts with a comment.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.theverge.com/news/791438/hori-wireless-horipad-turbo-nintendo-switch-2-controller" rel="noopener" href="https://www.theverge.com/news/791438/hori-wireless-horipad-turbo-nintendo-switch-2-controller">theverge.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/69b1d31e4a00cdde809c26b29239ba08 @ 1759773026 --></div></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/horis-new-switch-2-pad-lets-you-lock-the-home-and-capture-buttons]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meet The Sages (And Zelda's Maid) In Hyrule Warriors: Age Of Imprisonment]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/meet-the-sages-and-zeldas-maid-in-hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/meet-the-sages-and-zeldas-maid-in-hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment.1317631/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>A new old age</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="2631c2ae41c87"><a title="Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/2631c2ae41c87/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.gamecity.ne.jp/zelda-fuuin/jp/">Koei Tecmo has shared</a> some new info about some of Zelda's companions in the upcoming Musou prequel, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment">Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment</a>.</p>
<p>Earlier today, the game's developer shared five new profiles, and a bunch of new screenshots, of the cast on the official website (via <a href="https://nintendoeverything.com/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-characters-zeldas-maid/">Nintendo Everything</a>). So we now know the names of the four Sages (well, their Japanese-translated names) and of... Zelda's maid?</p>
<p>First up, we have Argusta, the Goron Sage and leader of the Goron Tribe. Known as a close friend to Rauru, he is a kind, generous, and intelligent ruler. Kia is next, the Zora Sage and princess who is a master of martial arts. She's known for her bravery, which inspires her people.</p><div><figure data-videoid="SFfvavDRTdA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SFfvavDRTdA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/SFfvavDRTdA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SFfvavDRTdA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed405340uomsvw&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>836k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>

<p>Krafika is the Rito leader and the Rito Sage, and perhaps not the easiest to understand. However, he is loyal and cares about his friends. The last of the Sages then is Ardi, a member of the Gerudo tribe and a follower of Ganondorf, the current leader.</p>
<p>Of everyone here, though, we <em>most</em> want to meet Lanaria (or Ranaria), who is Zelda's maid. Trusted by Rauru, she's is a gentle woman who is both quick at her work and is fascinated with the mystical. She's always carrying around a notebook with her.</p>


<p>While that's not a ton of new info, simply knowing <em>anything</em> about the Sages is a big deal at this stage. Especially given that we're one month away from the game's release date.</p>
<p>We got a chance to go hands-on with Age of Imprisonment <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/previews/feature-zelda-layton-mega-man-10-games-we-played-at-tgs-2025-coming-to-switch-1-and-2">very briefly at Tokyo Game Show</a>, and we're pretty excited to see what this "canonical" prequel brings to the Tears of the Kingdom story.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Let us know what you think of the new characters down below.</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:187487,188043 @ 1759772767 --></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.gamecity.ne.jp/zelda-fuuin/jp/" rel="noopener" href="https://www.gamecity.ne.jp/zelda-fuuin/jp/">gamecity.ne.jp</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://nintendoeverything.com/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-characters-zeldas-maid/" rel="noopener" href="https://nintendoeverything.com/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-characters-zeldas-maid/">nintendoeverything.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/619bd1d5f829693b1a19b1a1c1e99b75 @ 1759772454 --></div></article><div><p>Alana has been with Nintendo Life since 2022, and while RPGs are her first love, Nintendo is a close second. She enjoys nothing more than overthinking battle strategies, characters, and stories. She also wishes she was a Sega air pirate.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/AlanaHagues"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/alanahagues.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('AlanaHagues');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/meet-the-sages-and-zeldas-maid-in-hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>