<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 08:42:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Launches Switch 2 Backwards Compatibility Search Page]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/nintendo-launches-switch-2-backwards-compatibility-search-page</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-launches-switch-2-backwards-compatibility-search-page.1348408/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Find out if the Switch game you want to play is compatible</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="05bd7684ae54f"><a title="Super Smash Bros. Ultimate" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/05bd7684ae54f/super-smash-bros-ultimate.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Since the launch of the Switch 2 in June, Nintendo has released game upgrades, updates, and system firmware patches to make more games compatible with its new hybrid system.</p>
<p>It's not always been the easiest to keep track of every update, and to help make this process a little easier, a new website has now gone live.</p>
<p>It allows you to check the compatibility of Switch software on the Nintendo Switch 2. It's as simple as <a href="https://switch-software-compatibility.nintendo.com/en-US">typing a Switch game into the search bar</a>, and it will reveal if it's "supported" or not. Nintendo also notes how search results include both physical and digital versions of software.</p><div><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytC1rrCdi_XjA" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067jkwzvq&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>838k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<figure data-uuid="ff24e60ddee85"><a title="Game" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/ff24e60ddee85/game.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>This search functionality extends to apps, and each search may or may not include additional information such as recent patches. Other searches will result in "incompatible" or "unsupported" as you can see in the screenshots below - with Nintendo even acknowledging specific issues.</p>
<p>So, instead of having to refer to the official PDFs or other search methods on Nintendo's website, you can now simply enter the game title in the search bar and find out if the software you want to play is compatible on the Switch 2.</p>

<p>When Nintendo initially revealed Switch game compatibility for the Switch 2, it mentioned at the time how not every game would be supported at launch, but explained how the work to make more games compatible was ongoing.</p>
<p>This new search page means you can now regularly check the status of games that may not yet be compatible with the Switch 2 and see if there are any updates.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:164338,192705,176994 @ 1762761191 -->
<p>Are there any particular Switch games or apps you would like to see made compatible with the Switch 2? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://switch-software-compatibility.nintendo.com/en-US" rel="noopener" href="https://switch-software-compatibility.nintendo.com/en-US">switch-software-compatibility.nintendo.com</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://x.com/OatmealDome/status/1987690692462747969" rel="noopener" href="https://x.com/OatmealDome/status/1987690692462747969">x.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/0cafcdd7980df7d2201dfb7a9cfa2992 @ 1762760736 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/nintendo-launches-switch-2-backwards-compatibility-search-page]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Images Of Yoshi From 'The Super Mario Galaxy Movie' Have Leaked Online]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/images-of-yoshi-from-the-super-mario-galaxy-movie-have-leaked-online</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/images-of-yoshi-from-the-super-mario-galaxy-movie-have-leaked-online.1348321/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Mlem!</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="ff15af76a3a5b"><a title="Mario Galaxy 2" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/ff15af76a3a5b/mario-galaxy-2.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure><p><strong>The Super Mario Galaxy Movie</strong> officially launches on <strong>3rd April 2026</strong>, and Nintendo will be keen to ensure its marketing is on top form for the upcoming sequel. This will no doubt include keeping certain characters under wraps until the opportune moment.</p>
<p>Well... sadly, it seems someone's let the cat out of the bag a little bit too soon... or should that be the Yoshi out of the bag?</p>
<p>Yes, over on the <a href="https://shop.topsmarkets.com/store/tops-markets/products/83425108-pillsbury-ready-to-bake-yoshi-egg-sugar-cookie-dough-9-1-oz">Tops Markets</a> website, the US baking company Pillsbury has uploaded a new product that blatantly shows two images of Yoshi from The Super Mario Galaxy Movie. One shows the character taking centre stage on the front of the package with Mario himself striking his best 'Galaxy pose' in the background.</p>
<p>The other is on the back, showing Mario atop Yoshi's back as they soar through space. We also get a glimpse at some of the potential planets from the movie along with what we're assuming is a loose take on Rosalina's Observatory. And is that... Bowser Jr..? Yes, yes it is.</p>
<p>You can check out the images in the embed below, or head on over to the Tops Market website for a look at the original uploads in more detail.</p>

<p>Of course, these new images also corroborate an <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/its-official-the-mario-movie-sequel-is-based-on-mario-galaxy">earlier leak from 'Old Spice'</a>, which showcased a similar image of Yoshi alongside a separate product featuring Luigi. This was back in September just prior to the official teaser trailer from Nintendo itself.</p>
<p>It's also been claimed that a <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/a-trailer-for-the-super-mario-galaxy-movie-will-debut-this-month-its-claimed">trailer for the new movie will be broadcast this month</a> ahead of <strong>Wicked: For Good</strong>, with speculation pointing to a potential Direct presentation either on or before 21st November 2025.</p>
<p>If this is indeed the case, then we reckon it's a pretty safe bet to say that Yoshi will show up in some capacity.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/super-mario/related-articles:193336,188258 @ 1762761102 -->
<p><em>So, what are your thoughts on these new images of Yoshi from The Super Mario Galaxy Movie? Let us know with a comment down below.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://shop.topsmarkets.com/store/tops-markets/products/83425108-pillsbury-ready-to-bake-yoshi-egg-sugar-cookie-dough-9-1-oz" rel="noopener" href="https://shop.topsmarkets.com/store/tops-markets/products/83425108-pillsbury-ready-to-bake-yoshi-egg-sugar-cookie-dough-9-1-oz">shop.topsmarkets.com</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://x.com/Wario64/status/1987622414067302597" rel="noopener" href="https://x.com/Wario64/status/1987622414067302597">x.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/super-mario/related-info/d41d8cd98f00b204e9800998ecf8427e @ 1762763566 --></div></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/images-of-yoshi-from-the-super-mario-galaxy-movie-have-leaked-online]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Feature: Now Samus Is Doing It - What Is It About The 'Akira Slide' That's So Great?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/now-samus-is-doing-it-what-is-it-about-the-akira-slide-thats-so-great</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/feature-now-samus-is-doing-it-what-is-it-about-the-akira-slide-thats-so-great.1348165/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="935049b296b1e"><a title="Samus and Kandeda - the Akira Slide" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/935049b296b1e/samus-and-kandeda-the-akira-slide.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>The cultural consciousness loves the ‘Akira Slide’; a single moment in the 1988 anime movie <strong>Akira</strong> where Shōtarō Kaneda, following a bike race, skids across the tarmac to slow himself down, facing the screen, his bike side-on, trails of smoke billowing up from the road. Of course, he <em>could</em> use his brakes, but it wouldn’t be as flashy now, would it? Distributors Toho knew what they were doing when they slapped Kaneda and the bike on the movie poster.</p>
<p>Even if you’ve never seen the movie, you’ve almost definitely seen the physics-defying Akira Slide. 37 years later, TV showrunners, animators, and directors can’t get enough of that effortless skid. It’s featured in everything from <strong>Batman: The Animated Series</strong> to <strong>Adventure Time</strong> to Jordan Peele’s 2022 sci-fi horror <strong>Nope</strong> to even adorable shows like <strong>Doraemon</strong> and the <strong>Pokémon</strong> anime.</p>
<p>And of course, Shadow the Hedgehog even got his own chance to do it in the <strong>Sonic the Hedgehog 3</strong> movie last year.</p>

<p>It’s natural, then, that video games equally fell in love with this seconds-spanning moment. The latest example sees space bounty hunter and all-around badass Samus Aran in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/metroid-prime-4-beyond-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</a>, riding Vi-O-La and braking in the exact same motion as Kaneda nearly four decades ago (actually more than that if you count the 1982 manga, <a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/photos/2626551-akira-slide">where it’s a lot more low-key</a>).</p>
<p>Somehow, I’d convinced myself that Samus had <em>already</em> done the Akira Slide; Vi-O-La was revealed way back in September, and she’s never had a motorbike before. What better way to introduce her fancy new gear than by doing something flashy with it? Yet <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/metroid-prime-4s-sweet-new-trailer-builds-the-hype-for-next-months-launch">this week’s ‘Survive’ trailer</a> (below) is the first time she’s done this.</p>
<p>From what we know about Prime 4, Samus is on a planet called Viewros, and she’s trying to escape. This trailer pits her against many unfamiliar creatures, aliens, and hulking foes, many of which are new to the Metroid series. And she’s ‘surviving’.</p>

<p>Actually, she looks like she’s kicking butt. Her Akira Slide towards the end, right before Sylux makes an appearance, establishes that. Samus is powerful. And while she might be caught out by Sylux’s entrance (at least, the reaction appears to be part of the same scene), she’s still largely in control. The shot frames her as ready to take action.</p>
<p>It’s impossible to deny that Samus is cool; she’s an icon in Nintendo’s storied history <em>and</em> an important female character and role model for girls, women, <em>anyone</em>. But Metroid is a series that I don’t define for its ‘coolness’. Yes, the power-ups and the upgrades offer a power fantasy that builds over the course of the game. But Metroid is the atmosphere, first and foremost. Even the Prime games.</p>

<p>They’re also pretty damn scary at times. <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/metroid_dread">Metroid Dread</a> has some unsettling moments even outside of the stressful E.M.M.I. sequences. <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/snes/super_metroid">Super Metroid</a> will forever be one of my favourite games because of the creepy hallways of Brinstar and Norfair, of watching Crocomire’s skin melt off in the lava and then getting jumpscared by the skeleton as it attempts to take your life one last time. Or Mother Brain not just being a brain, but some cybernetic alien dinosaur that very almost <em>does</em> kill you. And don’t even get me started on the Chozo Ghosts in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/metroid_prime_remastered">Prime</a>. Samus needs those moments of cool.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Akira scared me as a kid; it’s still unsettling today.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Metroid’s Akira Slide is actually the perfect comparison point to the original. Because, like Metroid, Akira’s ‘coolness’ isn’t the thing that sticks with me. The Akira Slide is simply one cool moment that takes place in the first five minutes of the movie, a film full of grotesque imagery, horrifying corruption, and child experiments, and (admittedly) a lot of cool moments.</p>
<p>What I remember is the cyberpunk scenery and atmosphere soaked in rust and neon and petrol, the biker gangs and violence, and the quite-honestly-terrifying body horror sequences towards the end. Akira scared me as a kid; it’s still unsettling today.</p>
<p>But the slide is important, because Kaneda is establishing himself in the movie; he <em>is</em> the one to beat, he <em>is</em> the 'hero', he <em>is</em> the character we’ll see the world through.</p>
<p>It also sets up tonal expectations that are later dashed. Is this a cool action movie? Sometimes! Will there be body horror? At this point, you have no idea. It pairs perfectly with Samus’ own power-versus-the-unknown.</p>
<figure data-uuid="b88c566a72bd4"><a title="No More Heroes 3 Key Art" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/b88c566a72bd4/no-more-heroes-3-key-art.large.jpg"></a><figcaption>This looks familiar! — <em><span></span> Image: Marvelous</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Most of the time, though, the slide isn’t used in that way. Suda51's <strong>No More Heroes</strong> isn’t exactly known for subtlety, so when it slapped an <a href="https://youtu.be/g2nPg42xsXg?si=HJv09pA7jWj0nHZk&amp;t=300">Akira Slide at the end of a trailer for a fake TV show</a> promoting <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/no_more_heroes_iii">No More Heroes III</a>, I wasn’t surprised. The whole point of these games is the ultraviolence, the silliness, the meta and pop culture references, the ‘coolness’ of them. Travis Touchdown also does the Akira Slide at the end of every Bike Mission.</p>
<p>But the world of No More Heroes is pretty messed up; in the third game, mega corporations build entire islands and murderous aliens create fake, murderous competitions based around becoming a superhero. We need that goofiness, that silliness, and those moments of coolness.</p>
<p>Square Enix also couldn’t help (be careful of spoilers here) <a href="https://youtu.be/-h3FewwJibU?si=vUemzZV8DKzb88Bf&amp;t=1314">putting the slide in</a> <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade">Final Fantasy VII Remake</a>, too, another game where light relief is always welcome. I won’t talk about it here, but the bike sequence from the original is a little more fleshed-out here with higher stakes. Cloud also <em>thinks</em> he’s cool, but my favourite defining trait of his? He’s actually a bit of a doofus, and that’s emphasised in Rebirth more. We’ll let him have the slide.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/cyberpunk-2077-ultimate-edition">Cyberpunk 2077</a>, obviously, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fzNCGrlDCAA">had to have the famous slide in it</a>, and it’s one of the ones you can actually do, too; V can bring their motorbike to a stop by angling it <em>just</em> right. Again, who needs brakes? Cyberpunk is one gigantic homage to the genre, so as one of the defining 'things' of anime cyberpunk, this was mandatory.</p>
<p>It’s also the only way any of us will be able to do the Akira Slide without causing a traffic accident in real life.</p>
<figure data-uuid="8d87bda862042"><a title="Cyberpunk 2077 Yaiba Kusanagi CT-3X" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/8d87bda862042/cyberpunk-2077-yaiba-kusanagi-ct-3x.large.jpg"></a><figcaption>A reference to Ghost in the Shell <em>and</em> Akira? C'mon, CD Projekt Red! — <em><span></span> Image: CD Projekt Red</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Whether it's <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jBl5_2bzVp0">character introductions in fighting games</a> (thanks, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/street-fighter-6-years-1-2-fighters-edition">Street Fighter VI</a>) or <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BSLSkPzXdwo">skidding on ink</a> in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/splatoon_3">Splatoon 3</a>, the Akira Slide never fails to impress. Even when it’s not used in the exact same way as the original movie. It’s just a very smooth, stylish action that makes you look pretty darn smokin’</p>
<p>But it does go beyond coolness. Amidst chaos, amidst despair, and amidst the horrors of space, the Akira Slide is there to remind you that this character means business; they're a rebel with a cause, establishing their power or dominance in a single moment, like the modern-day (or futuristic) equivalent of drawing your sword at the start of a battle, or making eye-contact during a duel.</p>
<p>Nothing will stop anyone from making sure you — and your enemies — know who's in charge. Not even the laws of physics.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>What's your favourite Akira Slide in a video game? Does Samus now take the crown as the queen of the bikes? Let us know in the comments</em>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:65182,126453,193515 @ 1762762458 --></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/now-samus-is-doing-it-what-is-it-about-the-akira-slide-thats-so-great]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Street Fighter 6 x Fatal Fury: City Of The Wolves Free Special EX Colours Now Available]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/street-fighter-6-x-fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves-free-special-ex-colours-now-available</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/street-fighter-6-x-fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves-free-special-ex-colours-now-available.1348132/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Give Chun-Li and Ken a new look</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Following the arrival of Chun-Li in the SNK title <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/fatal_fury_city_of_the_wolves">Fatal Fury: City of the Wolves</a> earlier this week, Capcom has released some free "special EX" colours for the same character (and the previous CotW DLC character, Ken) in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/street-fighter-6-years-1-2-fighters-edition">Street Fighter 6</a>.</p>
<p>This will change the colours of Outfit 1 on both characters. You can redeem these colours from the game's 'News' section in the 'Notices' menu and no code input is required. Here's a look:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Chun-Li's kicking into Fatal Fury: City of the Wolves! Celebrate her arrival with free special EX colors for Chun-Li and Ken's Outfit 1!"</p></blockquote><blockquote>
</blockquote>


<p>Although Fatal Fury: City of the Wolves isn't available on the Switch 2, if you want a slice of SNK action, you can always check out the Terry and Mai DLC in Street Fighter 6, or perhaps even some of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/nintendo-expands-switch-onlines-snes-library-with-three-more-titles">SNK's past releases</a>.</p>

<p>Capcom also announced its new <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/ghosts_n_goblins">Ghosts 'n Goblins</a> collab this week. It includes another classic game to unlock and much more. And if you don't already own the latest entry in the Street Fighter series, the base game is currently <strong>50%</strong> off its regular price in select regions - bringing it down to <strong>£17.49 / $19.99</strong>. There's also a demo you can download from the eShop.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:193367,193000,192341,181178 @ 1762760613 --></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/street-fighter-6-x-fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves-free-special-ex-colours-now-available]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>