<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 12:14:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dark Deity 2 Is Bringing Another Healthy Dose Of Fire Emblem Inspo To Switch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/dark-deity-2-is-bringing-another-healthy-dose-of-fire-emblem-inspo-to-switch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dark-deity-2-is-bringing-another-healthy-dose-of-fire-emblem-inspo-to-switch.1270914/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Three Who'sthis?</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Cast your mind back to 2022 and you might remember <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/dark_deity">Dark Deity</a>, the fantasy turn-based RPG that took more than a little inspiration from <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/fire_emblem_three_houses">Fire Emblem: Three Houses</a>. Fast forward to the present day and we have <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/dark_deity_2">Dark Deity 2</a>, the second entry in the series which looks just as tied to the Nintendo touchstone.</p>
<p>This one launched on PC earlier this year, but developer Sword and Axe and publisher Indie.io have announced that it will <em>also</em> be making its way to Switch on <strong>4th September</strong>, and we can't help but feel that it's a good fit.</p>
<p>As you might expect, the Fire Emblem ties are once again strong with this one. Taking place in the fictional, fantasy setting of Verroa, you'll control Gwyn, Riordian and 18 other playable characters on their quest to protect their land from the neighbouring Holy Asverellian Empire.</p>
<p>The action all takes place in a top-down, tactical style, reminiscent of the early Fire Emblem games, with one-on-one turn-based encounters zooming in on the hits in all their pixel art detail. It's a format we've seen many times before, but it doesn't make it any less cool.</p>
<p>This sequel boasts 45 classes for its 20 playable characters, with built-in randomisers and campaign customisers ensuring a decent level of replayability.</p>
<p>Here's a brief rundown of the game's set up and a handful of screenshots:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A quarter of a century has passed, as Irving and the Eternal Order carefully rebuilt Verroa to protect it against a future war. Their efforts will be put to the test far too soon as a new threat looms on the horizon. The neighboring Holy Asverellian Empire needs new lands to grow, and the fractious, fragile Verroa seems ripe for the taking. All that stands in its way is the Order and twenty scrappy heroes-to-be.</p>
<p>Take command of the Eternal Delegation, led by Irving’s descendants. Gwyn and Riordian will have to navigate the treacherous politics of Verroa, and weave a web of alliances to turn the tide of the coming war. Your decisions will determine the shape of these alliances and define your army. Coupled with the help of a giant pool of customizations, no two playthroughs will ever feel the same.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Dark Deity 2 is now available to pre-order on the North American <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/dark-deity-2-switch/">Switch eShop</a> (it doesn't appear to be live on the European variant at the time of writing) for <strong>$24.99</strong>. There's even a 20% pre-launch discount available for those who want to save a few bucks.</p>
<p>We had a perfectly good time with its predecessor back in 2022, stating in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/dark-deity">our review</a> that "Dark Deity delivers a convincing and essentially satisfying facsimile of GBA Fire Emblem, but perhaps fails to stand on its own two feet". Let's hope the sequel moves things in the right direction, eh?</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/switch-eshop/related-articles:129120 @ 1755259340 -->
<p><em>Will you be checking this one out next month? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/dark-deity-2-is-bringing-another-healthy-dose-of-fire-emblem-inspo-to-switch]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sega Drops OST Remix Video For Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/sega-drops-ost-remix-video-for-sonic-racing-crossworlds</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sega-drops-ost-remix-video-for-sonic-racing-crossworlds.1270863/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>That's one radical highway</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>With the release date for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/sonic-racing-crossworlds">Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds</a> drawing ever closer (that's 25th September, speed freaks), Sega is keeping the old hype train rolling along in the right direction with a brand new remix of some of the tunes featured in the upcoming racer, which, we have to say, looks absolutely cracking.</p>
<p>You can check out the video in full above, and honestly, if you've got any nostalgia or love for Sonic in your bones at all, brace for some unexpected emotions.</p>
<p>Here's some further details from the official press release:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>SEGA released the third OST video for <em>Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds,</em> spotlighting a DJ mix that features six remixed tracks from the game. The OST focuses on music inspired by courses including Apotos, Dragon Road, and Market Street based on <em>Sonic Unleashed</em>, Galactic Parade and Sweet Mountain based on <em>Sonic Colors</em>, and Radical Highway based on <em>Sonic Adventure 2</em>.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><em>Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds</em> will release digitally and physically on September 25, 2025 for Switch 1. The Switch 2 version - which will be available as a paid upgrade path from the Switch 1 version - will release this year, too, they've just not put an official date on it. Oh, and physical versions for Switch 2 won't see the light of day until early 2026.</p>
<p>On that note, while there is a little delay for physical Switch 2 fans, as we reported a little while back, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/sonic-racing-crossworlds-on-switch-2-will-feature-the-full-base-game-on-cartridge">the full game will at least be on the cart itself</a>. Hooray!</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Looking forward to some Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds? Liking the soundtrack remix? Let us know how totes your emotions were in the comments!</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:185313,184779 @ 1755257866 -->
</section></article><div><p>PJ is a staff writer across Hookshot Media. He's been playing video games pretty much nonstop since the early 1980s, which is ages ago. Favourite genres include RPGs, puzzle games and lovely big single player adventures of all kinds. The weirder the better.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/PJOReilly"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('PJOReilly');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/sega-drops-ost-remix-video-for-sonic-racing-crossworlds]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tomb Raider IV-VI Remastered Has Been Updated, Here Are The Patch Notes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/tomb-raider-iv-vi-remastered-has-been-updated-here-are-the-patch-notes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tomb-raider-iv-vi-remastered-has-been-updated-here-are-the-patch-notes.1270842/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure><a title="Tomb Raider Chronicles" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/30b5f941dd388/tomb-raider-chronicles.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Eidos</em></figcaption></figure><p>Aspyr has released a new update for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/tomb_raider_iv-vi_remastered">Tomb Raider IV-VI Remastered</a> on Switch, adding in a boatload of improvements and fixes, while also introducing optional golden pistols to <strong>The Last Revelation</strong> And <strong>Tomb Raider Chronicles</strong>. Unfortunately for <strong>The Angel of Darkness</strong> fans (are you out there?), the golden pistols will not be available in this title.</p>
<p>There's plenty to cover here, so let's just dive straight into it, hm?</p>
<h2>Golden Pistols</h2>
<ol>
<li>Scroll toward the Join the Society of Raiders page from the game select screen (past Angel of Darkness screen).</li>
<li>Click on the Register button to generate the QR code.</li>
<li>Scan the QR code to be brought over to the tombraider.com registration page. Register on the page</li>
<li>Once registration is complete, a "Success!" screen will appear.</li>
<li>Enter either <strong>TR 4 or TR 5</strong>.</li>
<li>Once in the game, go to the Sunglass menu -&gt; Outfit to toggle the Golden Pistols on or off.</li>
</ol><div><figure data-videoid="hoJIzOcYU90" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hoJIzOcYU90?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/hoJIzOcYU90?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hoJIzOcYU90?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed54b3efyxolvm&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><figcaption><p><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hoJIzOcYU90" rel="noopener">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></p>
<p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>830k</span></a></p>
</figcaption></figure></div>
<p>Notes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Users must register on tombraider.com before the pistols are unlocked.</li>
<li>Golden Pistols are not available in TR 6.<br></li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>Tomb Raider 4</strong></h2>
<h3>Bug Fixes &amp; Improvements</h3>
<h4>Stability</h4>
<ul>
<li>Fixed a softlock that could occur in New Game Plus if Lara gets on a specific wall before Von Croy reaches it.</li>
<li>Addressed low FPS issues on the NX platform across several levels.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Graphics &amp; Visuals</h4>
<ul>
<li>Lighting &amp; Textures:
<ul>
<li>Resolved issues with flickering black shadows and dark artifacts appearing on geometry in various levels, including The Lost Library and The Mastabas.</li>
<li>Corrected multiple instances of Z-fighting on textures throughout the game, including on stairs, fences, chairs, and elevator floors.</li>
<li>The room darkening effect is no longer missing in HD mode in the Hall of Demetrius.</li>
<li>The red hue in HD FMVs is no longer oversaturated.</li>
<li>Addressed issues where parts of the train car and environment were missing in HD mode.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>VFX &amp; Reflections:
<ul>
<li>Corrected an issue where lens flare VFX was visible in rooms without a skybox in Coastal Ruins.</li>
<li>Fixed issues where additional vegetation was disappearing based on camera angle in The Race for the Iris.</li>
<li>The underwater surface of the frozen pool is now correctly displayed as frozen in HD in the City of the Dead.</li>
<li>The skybox is now correctly visible through the hole in the ceiling in Angkor Wat and no longer visible through hieroglyph tiles in Underneath the Sphinx.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Character Models &amp; Animations:
<ul>
<li>Fixed clipping issues with elements of Von Croy's outfit during movements.</li>
<li>The motorbike lens is no longer rendered over Lara's model when she stands close to it.</li>
<li>Corrected the HD mesh that didn't correspond to the SD mesh after a flipmap was triggered in Inside the Great Pyramid.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Environment:
<ul>
<li>The gate to the room with the Canopic jar no longer falls through the wall when opened in the Temple of Karnak.</li>
<li>Fixed a gap that was present between the trapdoor and room geometry in the Temple of Horus.</li>
<li>Destructible objects in HD mode now correctly match their SD counterparts in the Desert Railroad and Temple of Poseidon.</li>
<li>A loading screen that was missing parts of the environment has been fixed.</li>
<li>The Pharos, Temple of Isis level on the NX platform now correctly features fish.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h4>Gameplay</h4>
<ul>
<li>Controls &amp; Mechanics:
<ul>
<li>The Camera Target function in Modern Controls now works correctly after Lara uses switches and levers in The Tomb of Seth, Burial Chambers, Desert Railroad, and Temple of Karnak.</li>
<li>Corrected an issue where a swinging blade in Inside Menkaure's Pyramid was not dealing damage.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Audio:
<ul>
<li>The crossbow now has correct drawing and holstering sound effects.<br></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>Tomb Raider 5</strong></h2>
<h3>Bug Fixes &amp; Improvements</h3>
<h4>Stability</h4>
<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue that caused the title to crash when loading saves from the Red Alert! level on PS4 and PS5.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Graphics &amp; Visuals</h4>
<ul>
<li>Lighting &amp; VFX:
<ul>
<li>Fixed flickering lights in the Swampy and Monk cutscenes.</li>
<li>The lighting VFX from the Extreme Depth Suit no longer flickers in Deepsea Dive.</li>
<li>Resolved an issue where the signal light from the claw would go through the environment in The Base.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Character Models &amp; Animations:
<ul>
<li>Lara's hair will no longer clip with the Deep Dive outfit when changing outfits in Photo Mode.</li>
<li>A gap in young Lara's head is no longer visible during the cutscene at the beginning of the Old Mill level.</li>
<li>Lara is no longer rendered over the water surface in the cutscene at the end of Deepsea Dive.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Textures &amp; Geometry:
<ul>
<li>Fixed Z-fighting in the Sinking Submarine level.</li>
<li>The skybox is no longer visible through geometry in Trajan's Markets.</li>
<li>Resolved an issue where destructible objects in HD mode were different from those in SD mode in Escape with the Iris.</li>
<li>Larson's dynamic shadow no longer duplicates on the geometry below him in The Streets of Rome.</li>
<li>Computer screen textures for the disabled Metal Detector and X-ray now correctly show that they are inactive.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h4>Gameplay</h4>
<ul>
<li>Inventory &amp; Items:
<ul>
<li>Lara can no longer get two Teleporter Disks by crouching and pressing the action button next to the case in Escape with the Iris.</li>
<li>Corrected the name of the Desert Eagle to "Revolver" in Photo Mode.</li>
<li>The headset models now match between the inventory and gameplay.</li>
<li>The HK gun is now correctly displayed when Lara goes through the X-Ray on Escape with the Iris in HD mode.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>General:
<ul>
<li>The defeated claw operator will no longer respawn after being triggered a second time in The Base.</li>
<li>Lara's health bar no longer flickers when she enters gas chambers in Red Alert!</li>
<li>The Camera Target function in Modern Controls now works correctly when using the Monitor Screen in Escape with the Iris.<br></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>Tomb Raider 6</strong></h2>
<h3>Bug Fixes &amp; Improvements</h3>
<h4>Stability</h4>
<ul>
<li>Addressed multiple issues that caused the game to crash, including:
<ul>
<li>Crashes that could occur after a cutscene in Galleries Under Siege.</li>
<li>Crashes that could happen when exiting the game from The Vault of Trophies.</li>
<li>Fixed crashes that occurred when Lara was killed by Cabal Commandos in Galleries Under Siege while in HD mode.</li>
<li>Resolved a crash that could happen after changing outfits in Photo Mode during a boss fight in Eckhardt's Lab.</li>
<li>Fixed various one-time crashes that could occur during level transitions, such as from PRAGUE4 to PRAGUE4A and between zones in The Sanitarium and Louvre Galleries.</li>
<li>Addressed a soft lock that could occur after entering and exiting an elevator in the Derelict Apartment Block.</li>
<li>Fixed a soft lock that could happen if Karel killed Lara while she was falling in Eckhardt's Lab.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h4>Graphics &amp; Visuals</h4>
<ul>
<li>Photo Mode:
<ul>
<li>The Photo Mode selector is no longer hidden after switching between tabs.</li>
<li>Boran X will no longer disappear from Kurtis' holster after entering Photo Mode with Chirugai drawn.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Reflections &amp; Textures:
<ul>
<li>Addressed an issue where planar reflections were missing on shipping builds.</li>
<li>Water textures are no longer broken in Neptune's Hall.</li>
<li>Floor textures in Aquatic Research Area are no longer broken in HD mode.</li>
<li>Addressed issues with textures disappearing based on camera angle in various levels, including Parisian Back Streets and The Hall Of Seasons.</li>
<li>The water surface will no longer disappear when the camera angle changes, both above and below the water.</li>
<li>Fixed a noticeable change in the water surface in the Aqua Research Area.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Character Models &amp; Animations:
<ul>
<li>Resolved several issues with Lara's braid and hair strands, which were distorted or stretching, especially with the Beta outfit.</li>
<li>Fixed gaps in Lara's Beta outfit.</li>
<li>Addressed clipping issues with Lara's jacket in the Beta TR6 outfit, Karel's coat, and a doctor's lab coat.</li>
<li>Lara will no longer get stuck in a free-fall position after jumping on barrels in The Strahov Fortress.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where Lara could fall through the hatch in The Monstrum Crimescene.</li>
<li>Character models will no longer have visible seams in cutscenes, including Marten Gunderson, Pieter Van Eckhardt, Luddick the journalist, and Joachim Karel.</li>
<li>Sleeper Nephilim's HD model position is now correct, and the bands are no longer missing.</li>
<li>Cleaner's guns no longer clip with their holsters.</li>
<li>The muzzle flash is now correctly aligned with the Cabal Commando's gun.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where SD models of dead Strahov soldiers were displayed in HD mode.</li>
<li>The Boxer model in St. Aicard's Church is no longer distorted.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where Lara could remain in the air after a specific save load on Eckhardt's Lab.</li>
<li>Addressed an issue where Lara could get stuck in geometry while climbing walls in The Strahov Fortress.</li>
<li>Lara will no longer draw a weapon after skipping cinematics.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h4>Audio &amp; Sound</h4>
<ul>
<li>General Audio:
<ul>
<li>Resolved an issue where ambient SFX sometimes wouldn't play.</li>
<li>Fixed a bug where the sound of rain could disappear after saving and reloading.</li>
<li>Addressed several missing sound effects in cutscenes and other in-game events.</li>
<li>Pushing/pulling objects SFX are no longer looped.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Localization &amp; Voice-Overs:
<ul>
<li>Some voice-overs that were missing on the Steam build have been restored.</li>
<li>Fixed issues where various voice-overs and voicelines were too quiet, particularly in the Brazilian Portuguese localization.</li>
<li>English audio is now played in cutscenes with restored lines, even if localizations are without VO.</li>
<li>A specific voiceline from Dr. Muller no longer plays at high speed in the Brazilian Portuguese localization.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Lip Sync:
<ul>
<li>Lip sync is now working for Lara's Beta Outfit.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h4>UI &amp; UX</h4>
<ul>
<li>Controls:
<ul>
<li>The highlight position in the Controls menu will now reset to "Restore Defaults" after reopening the menu.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Healthbar &amp; HUD:
<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where the Healthbar wasn't showing when Lara's breathing was decreasing with the "Auto" setting.</li>
<li>Resolved an issue where several icons were missing when the Healthbar setting was "Auto."</li>
<li>The Healthbar, Auto, and Always On inscriptions are now translated to all supported languages.</li>
<li>Damage dealt to Brother Obscura is now initially displayed on his health bar in NG+.</li>
<li>The 'Use' button no longer overlaps the frame in the Inventory's Health/Items page in Russian localization.</li>
<li>The equip button is now highlighted by default in the Combine menu.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Other UI:
<ul>
<li>Fixed button prompts that weren't centered to their naming in Options.</li>
<li>Action indicator is no longer displayed near a specific lever on the level The Serpent Rouge on Pierre's route.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h4>Gameplay</h4>
<ul>
<li>General:
<ul>
<li>Kurtis no longer performs extra actions after defeating Boaz in phase 1.</li>
<li>The incubation tanks now correctly save their condition after loading a save.</li>
<li>The passports on the shop counter no longer look too dark.</li>
<li>Turrets no longer start firing when Lara jumps in The Strahov Fortress.</li>
<li>Exploded gas cylinders no longer reappear after loading a save in The Sanitarium.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Level Specific:
<ul>
<li>Louvre Guard's AI will no longer be disrupted in Louvre Galleries.</li>
<li>The second part of the sewerage is now properly loaded in The Monstrum Crimescene.</li>
<li>Lara can now climb the pipe a second time without having to return to the ground.</li>
<li>Lara can no longer hang in the air without grabbing anything in Wrath Of The Beast.</li>
<li>The camera no longer goes beyond the level's geometry if Lara is too close to the ceiling in The Vault of Trophies.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Statistics:
<ul>
<li>Statistics are no longer reset after returning to The Archaeological Dig.</li>
<li>Pickup statistics are now correctly divided for Pierre's and Bernard's ways in Café Metro.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:178278,177915 @ 1755258447 -->
<p><em>Are you still dipping your toes into Tomb Raider IV-VI Remastered from time to time? What do you make of this latest update? Let us know with a comment.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/tomb-raider-iv-vi-remastered-has-been-updated-here-are-the-patch-notes]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands 4 On Switch 2 Won't Support Split-Screen Couch Co-Op]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/borderlands-4-on-switch-2-wont-support-split-screen-couch-co-op</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-4-on-switch-2-wont-support-split-screen-couch-co-op.1270791/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>But it will have "full crossplay"</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="Borderlands 4" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/5bcb028bc3af9/borderlands-4.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: 2K Games</em></figcaption></figure><p>Since the announcement of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/borderlands-4">Borderlands 4</a> for the Switch 2, we've had a number of updates from Randy Pitchford and the team at Gearbox Software about what exactly fans can expect.</p>
<p>Following the news last month the game would run at "mostly" 30fps (instead of 60fps) on Nintendo's new hybrid hardware, we've now got another Switch 2-related update. This was spotted in the <a href="https://support.borderlands.com/hc/en-us/articles/43481582561939-Borderlands-4-Nintendo-Switch-2-FAQ#h_01K1XYNQ5NRRFJZ170AXZSQYQ7">game's official FAQ</a>, which was updated earlier this month.</p>
<p>This version will apparently offer "the same exciting" experience as other platforms "minus the split-screen option". Although this is missing, the same paragraph notes how the Nintendo release will have crossplay support with the other platforms. Here it is in full:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Switch 2 players will have the same exciting <em>Borderlands 4</em> experience as other platforms minus the split-screen option, and yes, it will have full crossplay with Epic, Steam, PlayStation 5, and Xbox X|S!"</p>
</blockquote>
<p>So, if you were hoping to enjoy some split-screen action on a single Switch 2 device, it seems you may need to instead consider the game on another console platform for this particular option.</p>
<p>It was also confirmed not long ago how the Switch 2 physical release of Borderlands 4 will require a download, so expect a Game-Key Card release. This game launches for this platform on <strong>3rd October 2025</strong>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:185551 @ 1755257752 -->
<p>How do you feel about this? Are you considering getting this version of the game? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://support.borderlands.com/hc/en-us/articles/43481582561939-Borderlands-4-Nintendo-Switch-2-FAQ#h_01K1XYNQ5NRRFJZ170AXZSQYQ7" rel="noopener" href="https://support.borderlands.com/hc/en-us/articles/43481582561939-Borderlands-4-Nintendo-Switch-2-FAQ#h_01K1XYNQ5NRRFJZ170AXZSQYQ7">support.borderlands.com</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://gonintendo.com/contents/51810-borderlands-4-on-switch-2-lacks-split-screen-co-op" rel="noopener" href="https://gonintendo.com/contents/51810-borderlands-4-on-switch-2-lacks-split-screen-co-op">gonintendo.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/0eb520756ca12e6e0c6437f560db6bba @ 1755256572 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/borderlands-4-on-switch-2-wont-support-split-screen-couch-co-op]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We Might Be Getting An Update About Sakurai's New Kirby Game Soon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/we-might-be-getting-an-update-about-sakurais-new-kirby-game-soon</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/we-might-be-getting-an-update-about-sakurais-new-kirby-game-soon.1270773/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>He's aware fans haven't even seen gameplay yet</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure><a title="Kirby Air Riders" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/56c21bd8dc43d/kirby-air-riders.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure><p>One of the many surprises during the Switch 2 reveal in April was the new game <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/kirby-air-riders">Kirby Air Riders</a>, a sequel to the GameCube outing.</p>
<p>It's scheduled to arrive later this year, so what's the latest? Game director Masahiro Sakurai has issued another small update <a href="https://x.com/Sora_Sakurai/status/1956187495991009776">via social media today</a>, mentioning how he thinks the team should be able to share some information about this game soon.</p>
<p>This small update on this project about Kirby's new game lines up with Sora's 20th anniversary in 2025 – with Sakurai thanking fans for their "continued support" over the years. Here's a rough translation:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Masahiro Sakurai:</strong> "It doesn't matter to most people, but today, Sora Co., Ltd. is celebrating its 20th anniversary. …That's a long time! Thank you for your continued support.</p>
<p>"The new game *Kirby Air Rider* hasn't even shown gameplay footage yet, but I think we'll be able to share some information soon. Please wait!"</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This latest update on Kirby Air Riders follows the game getting a <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/kirby-air-riders-has-been-rated-for-switch-2">classification last month</a>. Sakurai also mentioned in July how the title was "shaping up to be something great".</p>
<p>Again, Kirby Air Riders is scheduled for <strong>2025</strong>, so hopefully we'll at least get some gameplay footage soon. In the meantime, you can take another look at the announcement cinematic.</p>

<p>Are you looking forward to this game? Did you play the GameCube title? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/we-might-be-getting-an-update-about-sakurais-new-kirby-game-soon]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Scalpers Set Their Sights On World Championships Merch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/pokemon-scalpers-set-their-sights-on-world-championships-merch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-scalpers-set-their-sights-on-world-championships-merch.1270752/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Exclusive items are already being resold online</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="Pokémon Merch" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/06a969f02dc94/pokemon-merch.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: The Pokémon Company</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Scalpers are reportedly at it again, and this time they're targeting exclusive merch available at the 2025 Pokémon World Championships.</p>
<p>As <a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-world-championship-merchandise-scalper-reseller-2000617744">highlighted by Kotaku</a>, there are already eBay listings popping up for the commemorative Pikachu plush, themed TCG playmats, card binders, the <a href="https://x.com/JoeMerrick/status/1955663752457810413">jukebox</a> and various other items available at the event taking place in Anaheim, California this weekend.</p>
<p>Although there's a "one-per-person" rule in place at the venue, scalpers are still taking advantage of the fact the merch is currently exclusive to this event. Some of the community is already highlighting the scenes at the World Championships, as well as the resellers and online listings.</p><div><figure data-videoid="RLc1VHm8D80" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RLc1VHm8D80?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/RLc1VHm8D80?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RLc1VHm8D80?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed43f22fwkgrqm&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><figcaption><p><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RLc1VHm8D80" rel="noopener">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></p>
<p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>830k</span></a></p>
</figcaption></figure></div>
<p>Here's one post, in particular, that's been called out by the Pokémon community. And below this are some scenes from the Pokémon Center pop-up at the event.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Selling 2025 worlds bearwalker and shiny gyarados statue. $1000 on bearwalker and $600 on shiny gyarados statue. Payment up front. Zelle/PP FF/cashapp preferably. Pm me if interested. Thanks"</p>
</blockquote>






<p>It's sad to see this sort of behaviour, as it continues to ruin the hobby for many legitimate Pokémon fans and collectors.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, this follows a story earlier this week about McDonald's Japan having to <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/mcdonalds-japan-pulls-happy-meal-pokemon-cards-early-and-fans-blame-scalpers">pull its Pokémon TCG Happy Meal promotion</a> after 24 hours because of similar issues tied to scalping – with one customer supposedly attempting to buy 40 Happy Meals. The fast food giant even issued a formal apology.</p>
<p>If you want to find out more about the schedule for the 2025 Pokémon World Championships, check out our previous post.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/pokemon/related-articles:186466,186333 @ 1755258973 --></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://kotaku.com/pokemon-world-championship-merchandise-scalper-reseller-2000617744" rel="noopener" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-world-championship-merchandise-scalper-reseller-2000617744">kotaku.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/pokemon/related-info/4c60441fe7a879ce1dc5cb98ba327381 @ 1755257717 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/pokemon-scalpers-set-their-sights-on-world-championships-merch]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Scarlet & Violet 2025 Pokémon World Championships Distribution Live]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/pokemon-scarlet-and-violet-2025-pokemon-world-championships-distribution-live</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-scarlet-violet-2025-pok%C3%A9mon-world-championships-distribution-live.1270725/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure><a title="Pokémon Scarlet and Violet" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/da4456e93171e/pokemon-scarlet-and-violet.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: The Pokémon Company</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>If you happen to be heading to the 2025 Pokémon World Championships in Anaheim, California this weekend, you can receive a special <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pokemon_scarlet_and_violet">Pokémon Scarlet and Violet</a> distribution.</p>
<p>When you enter the badge pickup zone at the venue, you'll receive a unique code for a Toedscool. It's apparently "based on the Toedscool on this year's key art" for the World Championships (<a href="https://serebii.net/">thanks, Serebii.net</a>). You'll need to redeem this code in-game by <strong>August 29, 2025</strong>. Here's a look:</p>

<p>If we hear anything about an online distribution, we'll let you know. For now, if you want to get your hands on this, you'll need to attend this weekend's event, which takes place between <strong>August 15 - 17, 2025</strong>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:140671 @ 1755257775 -->
<p>Apart from this, the Pokémon World Championships will also be offering trainers a <a href="https://www.pokemon.com/us/pokemon-news/tune-in-to-worlds-to-get-luca-ceribellis-farigiraf-and-other-special-gifts">special Farigiarf this weekend</a>. It comes equipped with Psychic Noise, Foul Play, Helping Hand and Trick Room.</p><div><figure data-videoid="-mwkAYKvypQ" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-mwkAYKvypQ?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/-mwkAYKvypQ?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-mwkAYKvypQ?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed38f0a5hzvmjo&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><figcaption><p><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-mwkAYKvypQ" rel="noopener">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></p>
<p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>830k</span></a></p>
</figcaption></figure></div>
<blockquote>
<p>"Luca Ceribelli reached the top in the Masters Division of last year’s Video Game World Championships with the help of Farigiraf—and now you can have it join your team!...This special Farigiraf comes with the same moves and stats as Luca’s, so give it a try on your own competitive team!"</p>
</blockquote>
<figure><a title="Pokémon Scarlet and Violet" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/3f0286802d4ad/pokemon-scarlet-and-violet.large.png"></a><figcaption><em>Image: The Pokémon Company</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>To obtain this Pokémon, you'll need to watch the official 2025 Worlds livestream for a password you can then use in the Mystery Gift feature of Scarlet and Violet. The password can only be used one time "per save", and it expires on <strong>August 22, 2025</strong>.</p>
<p>You can see the full schedule for the 2025 Pokémon World Championships in our previous post. There's <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/pokemon-legends-z-a-playable-switch-2-demo-appearing-at-upcoming-events">also a Switch 2 demo</a> for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/pokemon-legends-z-a-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Pokémon Legends Z-A</a> at this event. This follows on from a free Switch 2 upgrade for Pokémon Scarlet and Violet in June, which included frame rate improvements and a higher resolution update.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:183189,186466 @ 1755257974 -->
<p>Have you tried out Scarlet and Violet on the Switch 2 yet? Will you be tuning into the World Championships this weekend? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/pokemon-scarlet-and-violet-2025-pokemon-world-championships-distribution-live]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>