<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2025 19:34:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Opinion: HD-2D Might Be Old News, But Octopath 0's City Building Has Me Buzzing]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/opinion-hd-2d-might-be-old-news-but-octopath-0s-city-building-has-me-buzzing</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/opinion-hd-2d-might-be-old-news-but-octopath-0s-city-building-has-me-buzzing.1285149/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure><a title="City Building RPGs" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/a3954838839a1/city-building-rpgs.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>Given that I love RPGs, I’m sure it’s no surprise that I’m <em>very</em> excited for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/octopath-traveler-0">Octopath Traveler 0</a>. What might shock you, however, is that it’s not the return to Osterra, or the excellent turn-based combat, or even the prospect of another new HD-2D game that has me jazzed, nope (I still love all of these things, though, be nice!). The thing I’m most looking forward to? I get to build my own town.</p>
<p>What is it about city building that I love? Is it the allure of making <em>my</em> own space? Is it a power fantasy, where I can make my town however I want, a way of expressing my creativity in a whole new way? Or is it simply that I grew up with <strong><a href="https://www.channel4.com/programmes/grand-designs">Grand Designs</a></strong> (a British TV show about people with money who build their own houses) on in the background?</p>
<p>Yet, doing it in real life is a complete pipe dream. Building a town — let alone a single <em>house</em> — in this economy? Nuh-uh. Thank god for video games.</p>
<p>While city building is its own genre (hello, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/snes/simcity">SimCity</a>), it’s the cosiness it fosters when part of an RPG that has always enraptured me. Need a break from the Dunan Unification War? Go recruit some pals and improve your base in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/suikoden-iandii-hd-remaster-for-nintendo-switch-2-gate-rune-and-dunan-unification-wars">Suikoden II</a>. Tired of getting rid of the monsters in Alefgard? Good thing <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/dragon_quest_builders">Dragon Quest Builders</a> is a <em>font</em> of creativity.</p>
<figure data-videoid="d2QQ4qo7qd0" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/d2QQ4qo7qd0?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/d2QQ4qo7qd0?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/d2QQ4qo7qd0?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501"></iframe><figcaption><p>Have you <em>seen</em> what people can do in that game?</p>
<p><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d2QQ4qo7qd0" rel="noopener">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></p>
<p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>832k</span></a></p>
</figcaption></figure>
<p>The first game that comes to mind where this unusual amalgamation is involved is one of the earliest and one of the most unique: <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/snes/actraiser">ActRaiser</a>. Here, though, you’re not doing any of the building yourself – simply facilitating it. Well, I suppose God shouldn’t meddle in everyday affairs, right?</p>
<p>But there’s a charm to flying around each map as your little angel, fighting off monsters as the humans build paths, settlements, and expand. Sometimes you’ll get advice from the townsfolk or have problems to solve — like famine — but for the most part, you need to defeat monsters and destroy forests and obstacles and guide the people towards sealing the magic seal.</p>
<figure><a title="ActRaiser Renaissance" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/a97aa39ca86f7/actraiser-renaissance.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo Life / Square Enix</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>One thing city building does is invite power dynamics. In ActRaiser, you’re the absolute: ‘The Master’ (the English name, but in Japanese it’s 'God', so not subtle). But in something like <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/xenoblade_chronicles_x_definitive_edition">Xenoblade Chronicles</a>, where you’re rebuilding Colony 6, it serves more as a hub, a place where, if you put the time in, you can get a lot out of it.</p>
<p>You don’t have any actual power or agency there besides putting money and materials in, but you can encourage others to move there. Colony 6 becomes a community project, something that can <em>only</em> happen with Shulk and Juju leading the way; its growth and expansion are a great mirror to the way Shulk and his friends develop during the course of the game.</p>
<p>Back to the SNES and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/snes/breath_of_fire_ii">Breath of Fire II</a> has a surprisingly robust, if simple, town-building aspect. Here, your town — later called TownShip (yes, the pun is deliberate) — starts off as one ruined building and, as Ryu hires the help of a carpenter, it grows from a small pile of rubble to a cosy little town with a laboratory which allows Ryu’s friends to fuse with Shamans to give them special powers.</p>

<p>I had no idea this quest existed until I watched my partner revisit the game earlier this year and, to my surprise, you even have to recruit villagers to move into the individual houses. And every single potential villager has their own function. The catch is that there’s only enough room for six people to move in, so you have to think wisely. Do you want to recruit someone who will sell rare weapons, or would you rather have poison protection for the next 30-odd fights?</p>
<p>It’s rare that a game makes its villagers feel like they have a purpose outside of being NPCs that you talk to, which makes TownShip feel particularly special to me. Imagine if I accidentally asked a man to move to my town and then your money disappears? I’d be pretty annoyed about that. And yes, that <em>can</em> happen – recruiting one potential villager causes all of your money to be stolen. You can get it back, luckily. And yes, it is annoying, but these kinds of events give these seemingly random characters a function, and a bit of personality.</p>
<p>Another game where every resident in your town — or in this case, sky island — has a purpose is <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/skies_of_arcadia_legends">Skies of Arcadia</a>. When Vyse eventually becomes the captain of his own ship and starts building up a crew of men and women (and a dog), he realises he needs a base. So, he reclaims the island that he crash-landed on earlier in the game: Crescent Isle. The more crew members you recruit, the more stuff you have access to at your new home.</p>

<p>An item shop, ship parts, and even a kitchen – all of these things provide unique or powerful items that’ll help Vyse on his quest to gather the Moon Crystals. And while I could just flap around the skies trying to find the best healing items or weapons, well, I also have access to everything in one place. And I can decorate the island however I like – I’ll <em>always</em> take the Cupil fountain.</p>
<p>But most of these games are about building up the community and letting them thrive, not the actual <em>building</em> of a town or city. That’s where I look to Level-5. Now that's a developer that <em>loves</em> letting us build cities. It all started back with the studio's first game, <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps2/dark_cloud">Dark Cloud</a> (yes, the "Zelda Killer"), where rebuilding towns and making the residents happy was front and centre. That, and its sequel, are PlayStation exclusives, though they set the template Level-5 RPGs.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/ni_no_kuni_ii_revenant_kingdom">Ni no Kuni II: Revenant Kingdom</a> is one of those, but instead of multiple little towns, you’re building your very own kingdom. Evermore starts off as a series of empty plots of land, but get some money, expand your coffers, and start investing, and you’ll soon have a fantasy metropolis that thrives on serving the king and his needs. Kingdom building is pretty on-rails – it’s both required for the story and gated by story requirements, and you can’t just build willy-nilly.</p>

<p>Every plot has a purpose, and you have to choose when to invest in those. Shops and a town square are easy early requirements, but eventually you’ll need resources like lumber, metal, and even ingredients. And you need people who are <em>good</em> at those things. There’s no point putting Floyd the cook in the Barracks when you have a Cookshop, after all.</p>
<p>Even though Ni no Kuni II is a little more strict with your creativity, I still got a real sense of joy watching Evermore expand and fill up. I love recruiting characters, so giving them tasks to actually do, which in turn rewards you with better items to buy or resources, is even more fulfilling. And then choosing what to invest research in to make that facility, and those staff, even better. Again, as King Evan of Evermore, I am the one with the power, but at least I’m making people happy.</p>
<p>But Level-5 has gone in the complete opposite direction in terms of creativity more recently with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/fantasy-life-i-the-girl-who-steals-time-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Fantasy Life i</a>. Now I’m not really building a city so much as populating an island… but I can build an art gallery, multiple homes, furnishings, island decorations, rivers, <em>and</em> terraform? It’s like playing a miniature version of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/animal_crossing_new_horizons">Animal Crossing: New Horizons</a> but with a massive RPG tacked on to it.</p>

<p>Outside of simply decorating and building for fun, customising your island doesn’t really serve much of a purpose. But it’s so easy and seamless that I just <em>had</em> to do it. Admittedly, it’s a bit of a mess right now, but I’m in post-game mode, so, y’know, resource gathering and all that. But it’s become a point of pride for me. Why shouldn’t all of my Buddies, who I’ve rescued throughout the course of the game, have a nice place to live?</p>
<p>Fantasy Life i gradually introduces new building mechanics, so while placing houses down might feel restrictive at first — I don’t know how many times I complained about the river — you can change things later down the line. I’ve gone from moving my favourite Buddies in to rotating them, completing crafting and delivery requests for them so they level up and improve their crafting, gathering, or combat techniques. I already have dreams to turn the island into some kind of cosy, forest-y nook with a little fountain and a town square.</p>
<p>But, like Crescent Island, like Evermore, and like Township, this island can act as a base for you as long as you level up your shop (situated inside the Guild Office) by completing deliveries and requests. Right now, I can get pretty much all the end-game resources from Marco, with only the rare and extremely rare items off-limits.</p>

<p>What encourages me to keep coming back to these cities, these locations that I’ve spent time building up, is that they eventually feel like a home away from home. Like a digital paradise. I’ve spent hundreds of hours in New Horizons perfecting the layout of my island, changing my mind, and redoing everything multiple times, because I want to create something that’s nice and comfortable for me, and somewhere that I think the digital inhabitants will like. It’s the same in all of these games – I’ll pore over every detail, every request, every need for my villagers, accommodating them while also trying to sneak in a little bit of my own flair.</p>
<p>I don’t know what Octopath Traveler 0’s town building will entail other than <em>beautiful</em> HD-2D houses and a new 'Architect' job, but I hope it puts community and creativity at the heart of it. I need another digital home away from home I can create and rejuvenate, and a pixel art one sounds perfect.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Do you like building cities in video games? Have a favourite? Let us know in the comments</em>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:185893 @ 1756666916 --></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/opinion-hd-2d-might-be-old-news-but-octopath-0s-city-building-has-me-buzzing]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hollow Knight: Silksong's Price Appears To Have Leaked]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/hollow-knight-silksongs-price-appears-to-have-leaked</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hollow-knight-silksongs-price-appears-to-have-leaked.1285131/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>It won't break the bank, either</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="Hollow Knight: Silksong's Price Appears To Have Been Leaked 1" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/b5f35ad3aaf48/hollow-knight-silksongs-price-appears-to-have-been-leaked-1.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Team Cherry</em></figcaption></figure><p>After a long wait and multiple delays, Team Cherry's anticipated release <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hollow-knight-silksong">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a> is <em>finally</em> releasing next month – and the cost of the eagerly awaited game appears to have been revealed (thanks, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hollow-knight-silksong-will-retail-for-less-than-2020-leak-suggests">Eurogamer</a>).</p>
<p>While it's not an official confirmation, <a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=I23MxTm2ku4&amp;mid=24348&amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fvideo-games%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fproducts%2Fhollow-knight-silksong---nintendo-switch%2F432032.html" rel="sponsored noopener">a now-deleted listing on Gamestop</a> that marked the game's price as $20 was <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/HollowKnight/comments/1n3hj7a/gamestop_listed_silksong_with_price/">spotted</a> by fans of the series.</p>
<p>Many assumed this was merely a placeholder price, but <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1n496oj/billbilkun_hollow_knight_silksong_price_is_1999/">Dealabs leaker</a> Billbil-Kun seems confident it's correct, and has even gone as far as to <a href="https://www.dealabs.com/magazine/hollow-knight-silksong-on-vous-devoile-le-prix-de-sa-version-pc-60443">reveal</a> not only the Steam price but also how much it will be sold for on the rival GOG digital storefront.</p>
<p>The leaker has at least confirmed that the game will sell for under $20 / £20, with the UK price potentially being as low as £16.75 on Steam; the US price is pegged at $19.99.</p>

<p>For the sake of comparison, the original Hollow Knight game is currently available on Nintendo's eShop for $15.00 / £10.99.</p>
<p>Sadly, the Switch and Switch 2 price points haven't been revealed, and Dealabs appears to be confident that, at this point in time, there's no physical version of the game planned – that will almost certainly change post-launch, we'd argue.</p>
<p>If you are wondering if you'll get your money's worth out of this title, the ideas for Silksong have apparently been stacking up for some time, with the team previously mentioning how it could have kept going but ultimately needed to complete the game. In saying this, the developer has already got <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/team-cherrys-already-got-ambitious-plans-for-hollow-knight-silksong-additional-content">amibitous plans for additional content</a>.</p>
<p>Hollow Knight: Silksong launches on September 4th, 2025. It's coming to Switch, Switch 2, PS4, PS5, Xbox One, Xbox Series and PC.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:187146,187061,187030 @ 1756667892 -->
<p>Please note that some external links on this page are affiliate links, which means if you click them and make a purchase we may receive a small percentage of the sale. Please read our <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/advertising">FTC Disclosure</a> for more information.</p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.dealabs.com/magazine/hollow-knight-silksong-on-vous-devoile-le-prix-de-sa-version-pc-60443" rel="noopener" href="https://www.dealabs.com/magazine/hollow-knight-silksong-on-vous-devoile-le-prix-de-sa-version-pc-60443">dealabs.com</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://www.eurogamer.net/hollow-knight-silksong-will-retail-for-less-than-2020-leak-suggests" rel="noopener" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hollow-knight-silksong-will-retail-for-less-than-2020-leak-suggests">eurogamer.net</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-info/266ead997a8a8c4ea4aced4742fc0218 @ 1756667388 --></div></article><div><p>Damien has been writing professionally about tech and video games since 2007 and oversees all of Hookshot Media's sites from an editorial perspective. He's also the editor of <a href="https://www.timeextension.com/">Time Extension</a>, the network's newest site, which – paradoxically – is all about gaming's past glories.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Damo"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/damienmcferran.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Damo');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/hollow-knight-silksongs-price-appears-to-have-leaked]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Feature: Nintendo Life eShop Selects (August 2025)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/nintendo-life-eshop-selects-august-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/feature-nintendo-life-eshop-selects-august-2025.1285068/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure><a title="eShop Selects August 2025" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/1f6ec6fdea44d/eshop-selects-august-2025.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>We're dreaming of crisp leaves, hot chocolate, and video games by the fire right now. Autumn approaches, but we have one more summer month to look back on in this edition of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/tags/eshop-selects">eShop Selects</a>!</p>
<p>August has been a bountiful one, with an <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/nintendo-indie-world-showcase-august-2025-every-announcement-game-reveal-and-trailer">Indie World</a> dropping some surprise hits and announcements. So there's been plenty to chew on alongside a couple of Nintendo highlights.</p>
<p>Before we dive in, let's remind you of the rules: Nintendo Life writers and contributors vote for their top three eShop exclusives for the month, from a list of games that we've reviewed. Afterwards, those games are scored (1 getting the most points, 3 the least) and tallied to determine the top three for the month.</p><div><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067jytvlz&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><figcaption><p><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C1rrCdi_XjA" rel="noopener">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></p>
<p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>832k</span></a></p>
</figcaption></figure></div>
<p>We've got a lot to get through, so let's not dilly-dally any longer.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/switch-eshop/related-articles:185808,186178 @ 1756667686 -->
<h3>Honourable mentions</h3>
<p>We've got a familiar story again this month: a certain ninja is missing in action. This time it's Shinobi: Art of Vengeance, as Switch codes were only sent out on the game's release date. You'll have to stay tuned for the verdict on that one.</p>
<p>Still, we have <em>14 games</em> to choose from in total — an Indie World will do that to you! All of the below scored at least a 7/10 with us, so let's have a look at what just missed out on the top three.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/apex-legends">Apex Legends</a> | Review: <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/apex-legends">9/10</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/discounty">Discounty</a> | Review: <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/discounty">7/10</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/drag-x-drive">Drag x Drive</a> | Review: <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/drag-x-drive">7/10</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/exit-8-nintendo-switch-2-edition">The Exit 8 - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</a> | Review: <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/the-exit-8-nintendo-switch-2-edition">7/10</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/gradius_origins">Gradius Origins</a> | Review: <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/gradius-origins">8/10</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/heretic_plus_hexen">Heretic + Hexen</a> | Review: <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/heretic-plus-hexen">9/10</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/herdling">Herdling</a> | Review: <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/herdling">7/10</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/is_this_seat_taken">Is This Seat Taken?</a> | Review: <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/is-this-seat-taken">7/10</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/off">OFF</a> | Review: <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch/off">8/10</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/shantae_advance_risky_revolution">Shantae Advance: Risky Revolution</a> | Review: <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/shantae-advance-risky-revolution">7/10</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/teenage_mutant_ninja_turtles_tactical_takedown">Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Tactical Takedown</a> | Review: <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-tactical-takedown">8/10</a></li>
</ul>
<div><div><h2><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/tiny_bookshop">3rd Place - Tiny Bookshop</a></h2>
<p>Just one of the many shadow drops we saw during Nintendo's Indie World Showcase in August, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/tiny_bookshop">Tiny Bookshop</a> sees you as the manager of a dinky little bookshop on wheels by the ocean. Pure bliss, right?</p>
<p>Well, because you're on wheels, you can park your little store wherever you want around the town of Bookstonbury. You get to decorate your wagon and choose just what books you can sell — oh, and every single book in-game is a real novel, so it might even inspire you to read.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/tiny-bookshop">We scored Tiny Bookshop a nice 8/10</a> — it's extremely satisfying, pleasant, and just a feel-good game all-round.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/switch-eshop/related-articles:186243 @ 1756667462 -->
</div><div><h2><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/roadwarden">2nd Place - Roadwarden</a></h2>
<p>Well, this one crept up on us out of nowhere. <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/roadwarden">Roadwarden</a> was announced just a week ahead of its release, and this award-winning text-based RPG lived up to the hype. It launched on PC back in 2022 and fans have been raving about it ever since. We can see why.</p>
<p>Incredible writing and lovely, simple pixel art help to illustrate a beautiful journey to the peninsula, layered with mysteries and choices that shape your experience. If you love storytelling, this is a must play.</p>
<p>We're so glad more people can experience this one, so check out <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/roadwarden">our 9/10 review</a> to see why we loved it so much.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/switch-eshop/related-articles:186821 @ 1756667462 -->
</div><div><h2><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/ufo_50">1st Place - UFO 50</a></h2>
<p>When Mossmouth's <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/ufo_50">UFO 50</a> shadow-dropped at the end of the Indie World Showcase earlier in August, we were elated. We'd been asking for this one since we played it at Summer Game Fest 2024 and we watched longing as the game racked up rave reviews on Steam. Fortunately, we had to wait less than a year.</p>
<p>UFO 50 is magical and a must-play experience for anyone who's grown up with video games. The craft and curation that's gone into the whole experience, from the variety of games the fictional story of UFO Soft. And yes, there really are 50 individual games in one package here.</p>
<p>So, congrats to Mossmouth — and UFO Soft — for winning eShop Selects with UFO 50 this month! For those who have yet to dive in, have a read of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/ufo-50">our glowing 9/10 review</a>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/switch-eshop/related-articles:186206 @ 1756667462 -->
</div></div><p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/nintendo-life-eshop-selects-july-2025"><strong>&lt; Nintendo eShop Selects - July 2025</strong></a></p>
<p><em>Do you agree with our ranking? Tell us about your favourite eShop releases of last month by voting in our poll and sharing your thoughts in the comments.</em></p>

<p><strong>How we decide our eShop Selects top three:</strong> As we reach the end of every month, the Nintendo Life staff vote on their favourite titles from a list of games selected by the editorial team. To qualify for this list, these games must have been released as a digital-only Nintendo Switch eShop title in that particular month, and must have been reviewed on Nintendo Life; we select the qualifying games based on their review scores.</p>
<p>Staff are then asked to vote for three games that they think deserve to sit right at the very top of that list; first choice gets three points, second choice gets two points, and third choice gets one point. These votes are then tallied to create a top-three list, with the overall winner taking that month's top prize.</p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/nintendo-life-eshop-selects-august-2025]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Poll: Box Art Brawl - Harvest Moon (SNES)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/poll-box-art-brawl-harvest-moon-snes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/poll-box-art-brawl-harvest-moon-snes.1285044/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure><a title="Harvest Moon - BAB" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/7ac80d9c62954/harvest-moon-bab.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>Hello everyone, and welcome to another edition of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/tags/box-art-brawl">Box Art Brawl</a>!</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/poll-box-art-brawl-duel-chibi-robo-park-patrol">Last time</a>, we looked at <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/chibi_robo_park_patrol">Chibi-Robo: Park Patrol</a>, in celebration of the launch of the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/chibi-robo">original game</a> on NSO for Switch 2. And let's be honest, we all knew which would win this one. Yes, with 77% of the vote, the far superior US variant won in a landslide. Good job.</p>
<p>This week, we're going all the way back to the SNES to check out the original <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/snes/harvest_moon">Harvest Moon</a>. Released in 1996, it would go on to spawn an enduring franchise that, since 2014, is now known as Story of Seasons. Yes, Harvest Moon still exists, but it's a whole different thing now... Long story.</p><div><figure data-videoid="JEHFv10kUS0" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JEHFv10kUS0?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/JEHFv10kUS0?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JEHFv10kUS0?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed38eeb6yxjqit&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><figcaption><p><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JEHFv10kUS0" rel="noopener">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></p>
<p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>832k</span></a></p>
</figcaption></figure></div>
<p>Anyway, it's a three-way brawl this week between North America, Europe, and Japan, so strap yourselves in folks; it's gonna be a belter.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/snes/related-articles:33221 @ 1756666382 -->
<h2>North America</h2>
<figure><a title="Harvest Moon - NA" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/399e3e3ee4df2/harvest-moon-na.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: <a href="https://gamesdb.launchbox-app.com/games/images/1821-harvest-moon13-chibi-robo-park-patrol">Natsume / LaunchBox</a></em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Okay, so this first one seems to be your pretty traditional Harvest Moon box art, showcasing the protagonist over on the right surrounded by a bunch of adorable creatures, and a typical farmyard setting in the background. It's simple, effective, and just... nice!</p>
<h2>Europe</h2>
<figure><a title="Harvest Moon - EU" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/a7a751d2f63f3/harvest-moon-eu.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: <a href="https://gamesdb.launchbox-app.com/games/images/1821-harvest-moonils/6413-chibi-robo-park-patrol">Natsume / LaunchBox</a></em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Ooh gosh, this is a real vibe, huh? Ditching the cartoon-y aesthetic for a slightly more realistic take, we've got a lovely landscape image of a farmer with his trusty doggy along with a cow and a horse. The figures look almost silhouetted against the gorgeous moonlight, and we love the blue/purple gradient used for the night sky.</p>
<h2>Japan</h2>
<figure><a title="Harvest Moon - JP" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/1e23ec56f90f1/harvest-moon-jp.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: <a href="https://gamesdb.launchbox-app.com/games/images/1821-harvest-moon">Natsume / LaunchBox</a></em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Japan's approach is similar to North America's, utilising the same main image of the protagonist and surrounding animals, albeit flipped. The portrait orientation means this can be placed front and centre with the game's title sitting just above. The background is gorgeous too! Man, this will be a tough one...</p>
<hr>

<p><em>Thanks for voting! W</em><em>e'll see you next time for another Box Art Brawl.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/poll-box-art-brawl-harvest-moon-snes]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands 4 Post-Launch Roadmap Outlines The "First Few Months"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/borderlands-4-post-launch-roadmap-outlines-the-first-few-months</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-4-post-launch-roadmap-outlines-the-first-few-months.1285026/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Free updates and paid DLC detailed</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="Borderlands 4" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/2f4fd782dc860/borderlands-4.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: 2K Games</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Gearbox has shared a roadmap of what's coming to <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/borderlands-4">Borderlands 4</a> in the "first few months" of its life.</p>
<p>This includes free and paid DLC content. After the launch, there's going to be some free content featuring new weapons, cosmetics and more, and then there'll be the first paid Bounty Pack. This follows with another dose of free content and after this in Q1 2026, there'll be <em>another</em> paid Bounty Pack DLC.</p>
<p>From here, there's a paid Story Pack, and beyond Q1 2026, there'll be more Bounty Packs, another Story Pack and "more". There'll even be weekly challenges along the way. Here's the full rundown:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"The team at Gearbox is already hard at work on a Vault-load of post-launch content—including lots of new story content and two new Vault Hunters—and in-game events that will keep your adventures on Kairos going strong!</p>
<p>"For now, as we prepare to wreak havoc against the tyrannical Timekeeper as one of four badass new Vault Hunters, we hope the roadmap above offers an exciting sense of what's incoming after launch. Below, we'll break down the types of post-launch content you can expect, including Paid Content via DLC packs and Free Content available for all players."</p>
</blockquote>
<figure><a title="Borderlands 4" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/486d60372156f/borderlands-4.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: 2K Games</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Gearbox has also detailed the Endgame content, including Ultimate Vault Hunter Mode, dedicated drops and more <a href="https://borderlands.2k.com/borderlands-4/news/endgame-overview/">on the game's official website</a>.</p>
<p>Borderlands 4 arrives on 12th September 2025 on PlayStation, Xbox and PC and will follow with a release for the Switch 2 on <strong>3rd October 2025</strong>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:186544,185543,185551 @ 1756665444 -->
<p>Will you be checking out Borderlands 4 when it arrives on Switch 2? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://borderlands.2k.com/borderlands-4/news/post-launch-roadmap/" rel="noopener" href="https://borderlands.2k.com/borderlands-4/news/post-launch-roadmap/">borderlands.2k.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/0eb520756ca12e6e0c6437f560db6bba @ 1756665708 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/borderlands-4-post-launch-roadmap-outlines-the-first-few-months]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>