<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 14:34:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What Are The 100 Best Nintendo Games? Here's The Chance To Make Your Voice Heard]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/what-are-the-100-best-nintendo-games-heres-the-chance-to-make-your-voice-heard</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what-are-the-100-best-nintendo-games-heres-the-chance-to-make-your-voice-heard.1346881/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>We've teamed up with IGN for the definitive ranking, but you can have your say, too</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="af10206becfb1"><a title="What Are The 100 Best Nintendo Games? Here's The Chance To Make Your Voice Heard 1" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/af10206becfb1/what-are-the-100-best-nintendo-games-heres-the-chance-to-make-your-voice-heard-1.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Gavin Lane / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>Nintendo has been in this business for a <em>long</em> time, so when you're attempting to decide on what the 100 best games released on its consoles and handhelds are, it's little wonder that it's <em>quite</em> the challenge.</p>
<p>However, we've teamed up with our friends over at <a href="https://www.ign.com/">IGN</a> to do just that – and we're in the process of concocting a list of the best games ever released on Nintendo's systems.</p>
<p>You may wonder how this list differs from the one <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/top-100-best-nintendo-games-of-all-time">already on this site</a>, but the remit here is somewhat different; this collaborative ranking will include third-party games that are either Nintendo hardware exclusives or are synonymous with Nintendo consoles.</p>
<p>"IGN and Nintendo Life have come together to build the definitive list of The 100 Best Nintendo Games of All Time," <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-100-best-nintendo-games-ever-faceoff">says IGN's Simon Cardy</a>. "We'll be rolling that ranking out from Monday, November 10 to Friday, November 14, revealing 20 picks a day until one game is crowned Number One."</p>
<p>Be sure to check out IGN's <a href="https://www.ign.com/watch/nintendo-voice-chat">Nintendo Voice Chat</a> for a rundown of the selected games. Who knows? You might even spot a familiar face...</p>
<p>Before the final list is published, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-100-best-nintendo-games-ever-faceoff">IGN is running a face-off campaign</a> that allows you to cast your votes and shape a separate, reader-curated list.</p>
<p>Ahead of the final list going live, why don't you make your voice heard by heading over to IGN and helping to determine the running order for this in a user-generated ranking – you might help get your favourite game to the top of the tree!</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-articles:149107,185286,175720 @ 1762524903 --></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.ign.com/articles/the-100-best-nintendo-games-ever-faceoff" rel="noopener" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-100-best-nintendo-games-ever-faceoff">ign.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-info/d41d8cd98f00b204e9800998ecf8427e @ 1762525140 --></div></article><div><p>Damien has been writing professionally about tech and video games since 2007 and oversees all of Hookshot Media's sites from an editorial perspective. He's also the editor of <a href="https://www.timeextension.com/">Time Extension</a>, the network's newest site, which – paradoxically – is all about gaming's past glories.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Damo"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/damienmcferran.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Damo');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/what-are-the-100-best-nintendo-games-heres-the-chance-to-make-your-voice-heard]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Digital Foundry Delivers Its Tech Verdict On Hyrule Warriors: Age Of Imprisonment]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/digital-foundry-delivers-its-tech-verdict-on-hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/digital-foundry-delivers-its-tech-verdict-on-hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment.1346761/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>How is it holding up?</p>
</section></header><section>

<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment">Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment</a> is out now for the Nintendo Switch 2, and our pals over at Digital Foundry have presented their tech verdict on the new title from developer AAA Games Studio.</p>
<p>In a nutshell, it's pretty decent! With its 40GB+ file size, the game utilises dynamic resolution scaling, with docked mode putting out anything between 720p and 900p, while handheld mode delivers between 468p to 648p. DF states that these resolution targets are generally pretty good considering the effects-heavy gameplay.</p>
<p>The Switch 2's improved specs over its predecessor means its able to render a whole bunch of overlapping effects alongside dozens and dozens of enemies on-screen, all running at 60fps. Meanwhile, enemy complexity is much improved over <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/hyrule_warriors_age_of_calamity">Age of Calamity</a>, and multiple effects light up the surrounding terrain impressively.</p>
<p>Frame rate, as mentioned, sticks to 60fps for the most part, however DF states you'll "easily" spot moments in which the performance drops slightly. It's nothing egregious, mind you, and you're not really going to get anything below 50fps, so it seems to be a pretty stable game overall.</p>
<p>It's also worth noting that if you jump into local co-op mode via split-screen, you're going to be getting 30fps instead of 60. That said, if you have two Switch 2 consoles at hand, or even if you use GameShare, you can play co-op with a much smoother 60fps.</p>
<p>For even more in-depth analysis, be sure to check out Digital Foundry's video and article down below. You might notice that we've not included such articles in our recent DF pieces, and that's because the team has recently joined forces with Hookshot Media to create its own website – huzzah! Congrats to all involved.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:193548,193425 @ 1762523116 -->
<p><em>Are you playing Age of Imprisonment at the moment? What are your thoughts on the game so far? Leave a comment in the usual place and let us know.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/digital-foundry-delivers-its-tech-verdict-on-hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>