<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 18:03:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Feature: "Demoralisation Is A Strong Word, But It Accurately Describes The Situation" - Why Do So Many Games Get Delayed?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/demoralisation-is-a-strong-word-but-it-accurately-describes-the-situation-why-do-so-many-games-get-delayed</link>
            <guid>1415113</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="b9902b88cb967"><a title="Delayed Games" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/b9902b88cb967/delayed-games.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><blockquote>
<p>"A message from the dev team:"</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Maybe in years past, such an intro would fill us with excitement and anticipation; after all, a peek behind the development curtain is always a welcome treat. But in 2026, the line is a signifier of bad news.</p>
<p>Said opening almost always leads to the following:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>"We've got some news today. As the launch date has approached, it's become clear that [GAME] needs a little more time to bring it to the quality that we want for it and that you deserve. Therefore, we've taken the difficult decision to delay the game until next year.</em><br>
<em>We know this is disappointing, and it's not a decision we make lightly. However, we're looking forward to sharing the game with you without compromise, with our original vision intact."</em></p></blockquote><div><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytC1rrCdi_XjA" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067xhsmlu&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>842k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div><blockquote>
</blockquote>
<p>Whether you have a casual interest in the industry or you are the most capital of Capital-G-Gamers, we'd wager that you've seen something like this at least once in the past 12 months. You probably saw a couple in the 12 months before that, too. And the year before that. And th...</p>
<p>Demand for games remains high, but delays seem to be cropping up more in recent years than ever before — heck, remember when Devolver Digital made a whole <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2023/08/devolver-will-reveal-all-games-pushed-to-2024-in-next-weeks-devolver-delayed-showcase">'Delayed' showcase</a> back in 2023? No one sub-group of developers or publishers is guiltier than any other, either. Indies and AAA releases alike are pushed from the planned launch to a later date, window or, occasionally, indefinitely. It feels like it's happening <em>all the time</em>.</p>
<h2>'Please Understand' - The Delay Cycle</h2>
<p>To illustrate our point, here are a handful of games we were really looking forward to that got delayed on Switch in the last 12 months alone:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/007-first-light">007 First Light</a> - <del>27th Mar 2026</del> 27th May 2026</li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/borderlands-4">Borderlands 4</a> - <del>3rd Oct 2025</del> TBA</li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/date_everything">Date Everything!</a> - <del>24th Oct 2024</del>, <del>14th Feb 2025</del>, 17th Jun 2025</li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/demonschool">Demonschool</a> - <del>2023</del>, <del>13th Sep 2024</del>, <del>3rd Sep 2025</del>, 19th Nov 2025</li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/elden-ring-tarnished-edition">Elden Ring: Tarnished Edition</a> - <del>2025</del>, 2026</li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/inazuma_eleven_victory_road">Inazuma Eleven: Victory Road</a> - <del>2019</del>, <del>Spring 2020</del>, <del>2023</del>, <del>2024</del>, <del>21st Aug 2025</del>, 13th Nov 2025</li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mina-the-hollower">Mina the Hollower</a> - <del>31st Oct 2025</del>, TBA</li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/old_skies">Old Skies</a> - <del>23rd Apr 2025</del>, 27th May 2025</li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/professor-layton-and-the-new-world-of-steam">Professor Layton and The New World of Steam</a> - <del>2025</del>, 2026</li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/system_shock_2_25th_anniversary_remaster">System Shock 2</a> - <del>26th Jun 2025</del>, 10th Jul 2025</li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/tales_of_the_shire_a_the_lord_of_the_rings_game">Tales of the Shire: A The Lord of the Rings Game</a> - <del>Q3/4 2024</del>, <del>25th Mar 2025</del>, 29th Jul 2025</li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/terminator_2d_no_fate">Terminator 2D: NO FATE</a> - <del>5th Sep 2025</del>, <del>31st Oct 2025</del>, <del>26th Nov 2025</del>, 12th Dec 2025</li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/witchbrook">Witchbrook</a> - <del>Winter 2025</del>, 2026</li>
</ul>
<p>That was just 2025 delays, and without mention of the giant <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/grand_theft_auto_6">GTA 6</a>-shaped hole in the middle of it all. So, when we say it feels like it's happening everywhere, we really mean it.</p>
<figure data-uuid="f88c54c4dc23f"><a title="Delay Messages" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/f88c54c4dc23f/delay-messages.large.jpg"></a><figcaption>No "Dear Gamers" Cyberpunk 2077 yellow in sight — <em><span></span> Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Don't get us wrong, we'd much rather that a game is delayed and launches in a good state, than being rushed out with missing features or more serious issues to boot. Our backlogs are long enough already, so hearing that something has been pushed back from a busy season isn't always the worst news. It's just confusing when it happens time and again.</p>
<p><em>Why</em> does it keep happening? The industry is hurting, the COVID-19 pandemic threw everything off, and economic factors obviously hold huge influence over decisions, but there has to be more to it. With <em>so many</em> games being delayed, it surely can't just be a case of unexpected bumps in the road to release, where project managers aren't learning from previous well-publicised mistakes.</p>
<p>"Most often, it stems from teams missing their production goals or not quite reaching the level of quality they want from their project," System Shock 2 producer <strong>Justin Khan</strong> tells us. "<a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/system-shock-2-suffers-unexpected-delay-on-switch">This delay</a> actually stemmed from our initial desire to upgrade the project from Unreal Engine 4 to Unreal Engine 5 for these ports. We spent several months on this exploration, during which we were unable to successfully deploy to the Switch and Switch 2 [...] With more time, I’m sure we could have made the engine upgrade work and deployed on all platforms, but production time was running short, and so we had to pivot quickly."</p>
<p>Experimentation was a similar time sink in Revolution Software's <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/broken_sword_-_shadow_of_the_templars_reforged">Broken Sword - Shadow of the Templars: Reforged</a>, which landed a <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2024/09/broken-sword-shadow-of-the-templars-reforged-lands-last-minute-delay-on-switch">last-minute Switch delay</a> back in 2024. "We initially used tools to help upscale and then over-draw," studio co-founder <strong>Charles Cecil</strong> tells us, "[but] we pretty quickly realised that artists recolouring the backgrounds from scratch resulted in a much higher quality than when attempting to use these tools."</p>
<figure data-uuid="48224afc51751"><a title="Broken Sword: Shadow of the Templars - Reforged" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/48224afc51751/broken-sword-shadow-of-the-templars-reforged.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Revolution Software</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>"Sometimes there isn’t a great explanation or nuanced message that could be written that wouldn’t be [better summarised] by a simple 'we need more time'," says Khan.</p>
<p>Sassy Chap Games echoed this sentiment when we <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/youve-gotta-make-it-more-sexy-final-fantasy-and-persona-voice-actors-have-made-a-dating-sim-for-everyone">spoke about Date Everything's second delay</a> last year ("It was absolutely a blessing that we had the delay to make sure that everything was ironed out and gone through"), as does <strong>Celia Schilling</strong> of Yacht Club Games' Mina the Hollower. "The team needed more time to apply some final polish and balancing to the game," she says. "We know that indefinite delay announcements can feel scary, especially in the indie scene, so we wanted to explicitly express that this delay wasn’t a major one."</p>
<p>The reason itself vary between projects, naturally, but what remains consistent across many of the dreaded delay messages is a genuine attempt to apologise and convince fans that it'll all be worthwhile in the end. Given the passion of fans and the familiarity of the delay announcement format, it's a difficult message to get right.</p>
<p>"We didn't want to do the big text screen jpeg that everyone shows on social media," Necrosoft's <strong>Brandon Sheffield</strong> says about Demonschool's last-minute delay message. "So we kept the statement short, and just tried to move along. We ignored all the people being mad at us as best we could."</p>
<p>It's easy to suggest that devs should just announce their games closer to release, but very few indie studios have the luxury of near-silence until launch that we see from a Team Cherry or ConcernedApe. For players, though, it's a disheartening experience when months of buzz and trailers leave you excited to play a game at a specific time (over a holiday or long weekend, let's say), only for that prospect to be taken away at the last second.</p>
<p>Rest assured, the developers are similarly disappointed. "In our case, it was a tough decision, but we unanimously agreed it needed to happen", says Schilling. Nightdive's Khan agrees:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Demoralisation is a strong word, but it accurately describes the situation when the team works incredibly hard, pulling long hours to meet an approaching deadline, only for the game to be delayed anyway. In those moments, it can feel like all that effort was for nothing. But the relief sets in quickly knowing that there is now additional time to polish things further and ensure the final product is as high quality as possible."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Even if a delay needs to happen, that's not to say that the dev necessarily wants it to. Aside from player expectations, which Sheffield describes as a "big worry" in the run-up to a delay announcement, there's also the team itself to think about. Though it can bring relief, a delay can also extend stress even longer.</p>
<p>"Overall I think the delay was good for us, but it did cause a lot of turmoil within the studio, and contributed to burnout, among other things," Sheffield says of Demonschool's second delay. "It was better for the game, and better for us in the long run, but it definitely wasn't fun, we didn't take it lightly, and we hope to not do anything like that again anytime soon!"</p>
<h2>Planning Problems vs. Outside Influence</h2>
<p>Nobody wants a delay to happen, so do we have to question the practice of choosing an initial release date instead? If devs know that bumps, experimentation, and polish time are likely, why pick a release date that underestimates them? At this point, surely there's enough project timeline data on the causes of delays to suggest that no, you're probably not going to hit that November launch.</p>
<p>For Nightdive, System Shock 2's release date "was forecasted by doing some optimistic time horizon math," with specific weekly targets that the team needed to hit to remain on track. For Yacht Club, it was based on how the game had performed at SteamNext Fest and SGF. Plus, "Halloween felt fitting, and it lined up perfectly with our plans."</p>
<figure data-uuid="25e4947969b82"><a title="System Shock 2" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/25e4947969b82/system-shock-2.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nightdive Studios</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>There's certainly an element of better scheduling practices needed. A delay by a couple of days/weeks/months is understandable, but what were you thinking with the original date otherwise?</p>
<p>Other bumps in the road can affect plans, too. Nintendo's eShop certification process is a long one (if you can believe it, with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/the-rise-of-scam-games-and-keyword-bingo-firms-flooding-switch-eshop">some of the titles</a> that end up on there), and we've heard of several developers getting caught in the bottleneck and missing their launch because they didn't have the final copy ready for Nintendo's approval in time — "a minimum of 30 days before your release date," according to Khan. It's a similar story told by Wadjet Eye Games' Dave Gilbert last year, when Nintendo's "frustrating" cert process meant the point-and-click adventure game Old Skies was <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/04/frustrating-nintendo-cert-process-causes-last-minute-switch-delay-for-old-skies">delayed at the eleventh hour</a> despite being submitted months before.</p>
<p>Such problems are multiplied on the physical front. Bitmap Bureau <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/terminator-2d-no-fate-has-been-delayed-on-all-consoles">pushed Terminator 2D: NO FATE</a> from its initial launch date three times due to "ongoing global trade and tariff changes that delayed shipment of the components for our Day One and Collector’s Editions". It's difficult to block out release windows when cart production and supply chain problems are out of your control.</p>
<p>Then, of course, there's the big issue that very few studios want to discuss outright: budget. Aside from being demoralising, a delay is an expensive affair, often requiring months' worth of extra funds from <em>somewhere</em> to get across the finish line.</p>
<p>"Previously, the ‘waterfall’ approach favoured by publishers locked scope, time, and cost into a rigid contract," Cecil says. "If any aspect of the work required was underestimated, then the only variable that could be cut back would be quality."</p>
<p>The nature of post-launch updates, promised fixes, and DLC down the line means things are slightly different these days, but a game's initial budget still usually dictates when work on a project must end. After all, how can you keep tweaking when all the funds have dried up?</p>
<figure data-uuid="6e2d82a902bc0"><a title="Mina the Hollower" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/6e2d82a902bc0/mina-the-hollower.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Yacht Club Games</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>While Schilling says she's confident Yacht Club's "financial runway is still there" for Mina, she admits that the team "had to make our operations costs stretch and cut back on expenses like our office space." A <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-12-02/creator-of-hit-game-shovel-knight-is-at-make-or-break-moment">Bloomberg</a> report last year confirmed that the studio planned to be fully remote by 2026. Likewise, Broken Sword's delay "pushed our finances to the limit," says Cecil, with the project relying on Kickstarter support to "achieve our desired level of ambition."</p>
<p>On the flip side, there are occasions where a delay sees the publisher pick up the slack, as was the case for Demonschool: "Basically if our publisher hadn't kindly decided to fund us during that delay it would've been impossible. So thanks to Ysbryd for that!"</p>
<p>Live service models aside, it seems clear that launch for many titles is increasingly a necessity to get some money rolling in so that post-launch development can continue - a form of Early Access without the label, essentially. If everything has been squeezed dry and the project <em>still</em> isn't up to snuff, what option do you have?</p>
<p>Of course, big players like Nintendo can silently sit on games for months before launch, but that's a huge anomaly in the industry at large. (Yes, before you say it, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/metroid_prime_4_beyond">Metroid Prime 4</a> is certainly an outlier.) In retrospect, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/legend_of_zelda_tears_of_the_kingdom">Tears of the Kingdom</a>'s delay felt as much a question of picking the perfect launch window for the marketing campaign as it did the game needing extra time in the oven.</p>
<p>And what about, after all that planning, something else comes along to disrupt the waters? Following <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/hollow_knight_silksong">Silksong</a>'s surprise launch a mere two weeks after its long-anticipated release date announcement, the likes of Demonschool and <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/baby_steps">Baby Steps</a> <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/demonschool-gets-last-minute-delay-to-avoid-silksong">were pushed back</a> to escape the blast radius.</p>
<p>"We had a special case in that 100% of the reason we delayed Demonschool was because Silksong announced it was releasing the day after us," Sheffield tells us. "We knew we couldn't compete with them for attention, so we were forced to delay."</p>
<h2>'Thank You For Your Patience' - What's The Answer?</h2>
<p>It's a multi-pronged problem, then. It would be easy to sit here and say that a delay could have been avoided with better planning at the jump, but certification woes, economic troubles, and budgetary constraints aren't as easily predicted as 'we might need more time to test XYZ'.</p>
<p>Not making an announcement until everything is set in stone feels like an obvious fix, but you need a <em>lot</em> of established street cred — and money in the bank — to pull off a shadow drop, and the marketing train has got to leave the station early if you're a small to mid-sized dev and you want your roguelike deckbuilder to stand out in the crowd.</p>
<figure data-uuid="a78b658c45f9a"><a title="Delayed Games" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/a78b658c45f9a/delayed-games.large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Those eShop views don't come easily — <em><span></span> Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>The <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/35-upcoming-nintendo-switch-1-and-2-games-to-look-forward-to-in-2026">2026 release calendar</a> is yet another year bolstered by its predecessor's delays. Scan through the list that we outlined at the start of this article, and you'll see a bunch of tentative '2026' dates still hanging on games that were slated for the year prior. No biggies have been pushed back in the early weeks of this year, but it's only a matter of time. Delays will come, and when they do, we won't be surprised.</p>
<p>So what's the solution? Every developer we spoke to seemed genuinely confident in their initial dates, and it was only once launch loomed that it became apparent all the pieces wouldn't fit together. 'More realistic scheduling' feels a little oversimplified.</p>
<p>With more layoffs and studio closures happening every month, the 'quick fix' of improved budgets and resources also seems unlikely. If studios could find a way to better handle the unexpected and land on their launch date with their project — and their well-being — still intact, brilliant! But without a radical shift in how profits are distributed amongst large companies, it's unclear where that money could come from.</p>
<p>"It’s all business at the end of the day, which is hardly ever just black or white," Khan says. There's no one-size-fits-all approach to stopping delays for good, but if indies and AAA behemoths are equally likely to succumb to deadline drama, then we can't see them going away any time soon.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Our thanks to <em>Brandon Sheffield</em>, Celia Schilling, <em>Charles Cecil,</em> and <em>Justin Khan</em> for taking the time to talk to us.</em></p>
<p><em>What do you make of the regularity of game delays? Is there a solution? Let us know your thoughts.<br></em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-articles:180920,176172 @ 1769277639 --></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/demoralisation-is-a-strong-word-but-it-accurately-describes-the-situation-why-do-so-many-games-get-delayed]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Poll: What Review Score Would You Give Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/poll-what-review-score-would-you-give-final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade</link>
            <guid>1415086</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Tifa and claws</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure data-uuid="5e54562985cf3"><a title="Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/5e54562985cf3/final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Square Enix</em></figcaption></figure><p>Switch 2 has been graced with a few 'impossible' ports in its first months on the market, and this week, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade">Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade</a> joined the ranks.</p>
<p>While playing Square Enix's acclaimed 2020 remake on Nintendo's old hybrid would have felt like a pipedream, FFVII looks, runs, and feels exceptionally good on Switch 2. Sure, there are some technical downgrades from the PS5 version here and there *<em>cough</em>* 30fps *<em>cough</em>*, but overall, this is a rather wonderful display of what the new hardware can muster.</p>
<p>At least, that's what our Alana thought in her <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade">9/10 review</a> of Square Enix's latest "remarkable" project. "For those who haven’t touched Final Fantasy VII before and are worried, don’t fret," she wrote, "even with some of the additions, the Switch 2 port is still an amazing way to experience (part of) one of the most influential games of all time."</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:196050 @ 1769275103 -->
<p>With the Switch 2 port now out in the wild, we want to know what you lovely lot make of it so far — whether this is your first time stepping into Midgar or if you're something of a seasoned professional by this point.</p>
<p>You can let us know your review score for Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade by using the poll below. Of course, we don't expect you all to have finished it just yet, but that's the magic of this poll, you can come back and change your vote whenever you'd like!</p>

<p><em>Thank you for voting! If you have anything else to say about your time with FFVII: Remake on Switch 2 so far, let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/poll-what-review-score-would-you-give-final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warframe Switch 2 Version Scheduled To Launch In Q1 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/warframe-switch-2-version-scheduled-to-launch-in-q1-2026</link>
            <guid>1415056</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>A release date will be announced next month</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="0fd5b2f9029cf"><a title="Warframe Switch 2" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/0fd5b2f9029cf/warframe-switch-2.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Digital Extremes</em></figcaption></figure><p>In case you missed the news, the free-to-play title <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/warframe">Warframe</a> is on its way to the Nintendo Switch 2 in 2026.</p>
<p>Digital Extremes held its <a href="https://youtu.be/nyrOvsRxTmM?t=1405">first Devstream of the year</a> this week, and the team has now narrowed down the launch window of this version to "later" in the first quarter of 2026. As for the exact release date on Nintendo's new hybrid platform, expect an announcement for this during the next stream in February.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Wield new ways to experience Warframe’s iconic fast-paced gameplay natively on the Nintendo Switch 2 later in Q1 2026"</p></blockquote><div><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytC1rrCdi_XjA" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067rjytvo&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>842k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div><blockquote>
</blockquote>
<p>Once again, this native version of Warframe for Switch 2 will run at 60fps, with 1080p resolution across both docked and handheld modes. It's also got improved load times and Switch 2 Mouse Mode is supported.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Expect smoother visuals, more responsive combat, and significantly improved overall gameplay fidelity. Stay tuned for more details."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>You can find out more about this free-to-play title in our original Switch review. And when the Switch 2 version's release date is announced, we'll provide an update.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:83309,193312,188743,187706 @ 1769276470 -->
<p>Will you be revisiting this title or finally giving it a go when it lands on the Switch 2? <em>Tell us below.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.digitalextremes.com/news/january-warframe-devstream-highlights" rel="noopener" href="https://www.digitalextremes.com/news/january-warframe-devstream-highlights">digitalextremes.com</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://www.rpgsite.net/news/19435-warframe-android-release-date-switch-2-resolution-frame-rate-mouse-controls" rel="noopener" href="https://www.rpgsite.net/news/19435-warframe-android-release-date-switch-2-resolution-frame-rate-mouse-controls">rpgsite.net</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/c62c9ea75efca3a2091ae03b336c7f30 @ 1769274518 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/warframe-switch-2-version-scheduled-to-launch-in-q1-2026]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Opinion: I'll Never Truly RIP Until 'The Séance Of Blake Manor' Comes To Switch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/opinion-ill-never-truly-rip-until-the-seance-of-blake-manor-comes-to-switch</link>
            <guid>1415032</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="a8773a64927b5"><a title="The Seance of Blake Manor" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/a8773a64927b5/the-seance-of-blake-manor.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Spooky Doorway</em></figcaption></figure><p>Spooky Doorway is an Irish dev studio that's already brought us lucky Switch gamers some seriously good point-and-click fun times in the form of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/darkside_detective_-_the_series_edition">The Darkside Detective</a> series.</p>
<p>This is a studio with form, and one that's already proven it knows how to serve up clever puzzle adventures that just <em>get</em> what makes this particular genre sing. I'm talking about delicious mysteries into which to sink your teeth, mysteries that are alive with all manner of supernatural and off-kilter aspects. Stories full of weirdo characters backed up by excellent writing, perfect location choices, and gameplay that gives you enough agency that you're sucked right into the whole thing for the duration.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/darkside_detective">The Darkside Detective</a>, and its follow-up, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/darkside_detective_a_fumble_in_the_dark">A Fumble In The Dark</a>, excelled at all of this, and with sinister style to spare. So, you'll have to forgive me (and doubly so as an Irishman) if I've been ever so excited and delighted by the arrival of the team's latest game, <strong>The Séance of Blake Manor</strong>.</p>
<p>This point-and-click horror mystery is set in 1897s Ireland — Connemara to be precise — and it's their best work to date by some margin. It's a game that, had it released on Switch when it landed on PC back in October, would absolutely have been sat in the number one spot for me, over all of the other things — <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/opinion-i-reviewed-25-switch-2-games-in-2025-and-these-are-my-top-3-picks">even all the Nintendo stuff (!)</a> — that I played in 2025. It's proper GOTY material, is what I'm saying, and I really, really, really (add lots more "reallys" here) want to see it come to Switch so all my Nintendo homies can get stuck into it too.</p>

<p>The titular Blake Manor is a hotel set in a remote spot in the west of Ireland, and if you've ever been to this part of the world, you'll know just how dramatic and how well lent to horror and mystery the scenery and wilderness is. Connemara is a wild and rugged spot, with its famous Twelve Pins, a range of Bens that can often be seen rising dramatically up and out of the ever-present mist of a morning - the same mist that settles over the area's many, many ancient bogs. Now add a great big Gothic hotel full of haunted stuff and weirdos, and we're in business.</p>
<p>It's the kind of place you want to set a nice big mystery like those snazzy ones with Daniel Craig in them, except make it tinged with cosmic horror and supernatural elements. It's also a setting that Spooky Doorway excels at manipulating into a story and set of puzzles that had me (a professional point-and-click expert, no less) glued to my PC monitor for the duration of my roughly 30-hour playthrough.</p>
<p>Assuming the role of Private Investigator, Declan Ward, you arrive at Blake Manor to investigate the disappearance of a young lady guest. It's a disappearance that's made all the more unsettling by the odd behaviour of the staff of the hotel, as well as its owner, and to add to the fun, a bunch of veteran mystics have just shown up to perform a weird Hallows' Eve ritual seance - so you're guaranteed a lot of strange conversations from the get-go.</p>
<p>It really is a delicious setup, and it's one that's carried off with aplomb, thankfully. I won't ruin it, it'd be a crime, but through interviewing suspects, keeping track of paper trails, getting stuck into all that amazing "Mind Palace" Sherlock-Holmes-style guff, solving well-designed puzzles, and exploring the labyrinthian (and secret-filled) hotel itself, you're kept more than busy.</p>

<p>Then we have the double-cherry on top of this one, the real finishing touches, in the form of a clever time management mechanic that sees your days count down as you work, adding a real sense of urgency to the entire endeavour...<em>and</em> the fact that the whole thing takes place from a first-person perspective. Oh yes, it's a real treat to explore this game from such a personal vantage point, make no mistake, and Blake Manor is brought to life in a way that wouldn't have been possible had the devs stuck with a more classic view of the genre at hand.</p>
<p>If you're into your gothic Victorian paranormal mysteries, and if you like your games stuffed to the gills with kooky characters, this one's 100% for you. By the same token, if you enjoy (or also enjoy) a bit of the auld Irish folklore and mythology — we do good folklore and mythology — and most certainly if you're into grand mysteries in the classic detective style, well, you need to play this. It really is that simple.</p>
<p>And so, I've got my rosary beads out for the lot of us. I'm praying hard for a miracle, mammy. Let's get this cracker on Switch consoles ASAP, as I reckon it's exactly the sort of thing I want to sit on my couch and play. Mostly because my TV is upstairs and I'm scared of ghosts now. And people. And stairs.</p>
<p>I reached out to Spooky Door for any word on plans for a Switch console release. No word back yet. However, perhaps they're keeping it for a surprise. Yes, yes, that's it. A surprise! Just don't go scaring me with any sudden noises if and when the announcement does finally roll around. I'm already petrified over here.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Have you played The Séance of Blake Manor? Enjoyed it? Waiting for it to hit Switch consoles? Make sure to let us know in the comments.</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:113761,74892,106869,79493 @ 1769274154 --></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/opinion-ill-never-truly-rip-until-the-seance-of-blake-manor-comes-to-switch]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Talking Point: What Are You Playing This Weekend? (24th January)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/talking-point-what-are-you-playing-this-weekend-24th-january</link>
            <guid>1414993</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="40b937d3cbf81"><a title="Sephiroth" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/40b937d3cbf81/sephiroth.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Square Enix</em></figcaption></figure><p>Well folks, you made it! The weekend is here again, which means it's time to get some all-important gaming done.</p>
<p>Before that though, let's quickly recap the week. Our <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade">big review</a> was for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade">Final Fantasy VII Remake</a> on the Switch 2, and as expected, it's a bit of a banger. We also <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/final-fantasy-vii-remakes-sequels-will-have-exactly-the-same-gameplay-as-other-consoles">heard from director Naoki Hamaguchi</a> who confirmed that the upcoming two sequels will have "exactly the same" gameplay as other platforms.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/donkey_kong_country_returns_hd">Donkey Kong Country Returns HD</a> got a <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/donkey-kong-country-returns-hd-gets-a-free-switch-2-update-and-adds-dixie-kong">surprise update</a>, which added in a bunch of improvements along with playable Dixie Kong. We got more information about <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/super-mario-bros-wonder-nintendo-switch-2-edition-plus-meetup-in-bellabel-park">Super Mario Bros. Wonder</a>'s Switch 2 update, and had a bit to say about its <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/random-mario-wonders-new-box-art-might-be-the-ugliest-switch-2-edition-cover-yet">ugly-as-heck box art</a>.</p>
<p>So let's see what we're all up to, hm?</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:196554,196505 @ 1769276371 -->
<h2>PJ O'Reilly, Staff Writer</h2>
<p>This weekend I'll be diving into <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/cult_of_the_lamb">Cult of the Lamb: Woolhaven</a>, which I'm quite excited about, as it's a chance for me to finally go back and finish the game - which I love, but I got distracted!</p>
<p>Beyond this, I'll be picking away at <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/cassette_boy">Cassette Boy</a>, which I'm also really enjoying, and making some time for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mio-memories-in-orbit">MIO: Memories in Orbit</a>, which I've yet to touch. Loads of great stuff. Have a good one!</p>
<h2>Ollie Reynolds, Staff Writer</h2>
<p>I'm still enjoying <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/star-wars-outlaws">Star Wars Outlaws</a>, and I know there's been a lot of talk recently about how good <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade">Final Fantasy Remake</a> looks on the Switch 2, and how its closest visual competitor is probably <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/cyberpunk-2077-ultimate-edition">Cyberpunk 2077</a>, but man... Outlaws looks <em>really good</em>, too. Please give it a shot, if you haven't already.</p>
<p>And as teased last week, I have indeed jumped back into Zelda with... <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Tears of the Kingdom</a>! Wheeey. Y'know what, I'm really enjoying it this time too. I'm just going slow, enjoying the sights and sounds, and not really bothering with much story stuff yet.</p>

<h2>Mai Ladyman, Video Producer</h2>
<p>How has another week gone by so quickly? My theme for this week was “cosy-grinding” as I spent most of it on <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/animal-crossing-new-horizons-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Animal Crossing New Horizons</a> or revisiting an old (and somewhat janky) favourite <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/my_time_at_portia">My Time at Portia</a>. I've been trying to work through my huge backlog and Portia is on the top of my list to finish. Saying that, it'll take me a while because it's one I tend to play in short bursts.</p>
<p>This weekend however, I'm hoping to change it up with the Final Fantasy VII remake!</p>
<h2>Jim Norman, Staff Writer</h2>
<p>I was too buried in everything else in 2020 to give Final Fantasy VII Remake a fair shot, so I have been counting down the days until I can properly dive into it on Switch 2. I’ll finally be seeing what it’s all about this weekend after the demo got me sufficiently intrigued a few weeks back, so I expect this will be my WAYP entry for a few weeks going forward.</p>
<p>See you on the other side, and all that!</p>

<h2>Gonçalo Lopes, Contributor</h2>
<p>A triple dose of indie gems to play this weekend: The critically acclaimed <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/despelote">despelote</a>, the visually-striking MIO: Memories In Orbit and the clever nostalgia inducing Cassete Boy. I believe I will be done with Wings! Remastered Edition soon since I’m already in 1918. <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/assassins-creed-shadows">Assassin’s Creed Shadows</a> will live in my head for a long time to come, truly an amazing achievement. What all those folks in the two hour long staff roll credits managed to pull of something special. It is now on the same level as my other favourite entry: <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/assassins_creed_iv_black_flag">Assassin’s Creed Black Flag</a>. I also picked up <strong>Rumble Roses XX</strong> on Xbox 360, another system exclusive game I always wanted to give a go.</p>
<p>Game of the week is to no surprise Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade. It has been a long time since this came out on rival platforms and an even longer time since I played the original on it’s European PS1 release. In my advanced age I no longer properly recall the plot, but... level up the flower-selling girl while giving her all the best materia and gear and Sephiroth does nothing wrong… right?</p>
<h2>Gavin Lane, Editor</h2>
<p>Would you believe it, ACNH has gone an got its claws in me again. Having avoided crafting as much as possible (and never having cooked a thing in the game), I've been getting back into the swing of things, making a few items, and customising some pieces for my house, specifically for my Ten Forward-themed top room, which now has some nice long windows looking out at the stars.</p>
<p>Since last week, my kids have tents in the game, too, and I'm introducing them to the controls. I expect we'll spend a couple of hours pottering around the island, while I spend thousands of Bells on the clothes they want in the Able Sisters' place. Time to plant some more money trees. Have a good one, folks.</p>
<h2>Kate Gray, Contributor</h2>
<p>I'm still playing <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/hundred_line_-_last_defense_academy">Hundred Line - Last Defense Academy</a>! I think I will be playing it forever. I have two endings so far, and no actual end in sight. I love it so much.</p>
<p>When I'm done with that, some time next century, I'm gonna give <strong>TR-49</strong> a go! I think I must be one of Inkle's biggest fans at this point, and after playtesting their last one, I made sure to go in almost completely blind to this one. Excited!</p>

<hr>
<p><em>That's our plans for the coming weekend. Now it's your turn to tell us yours, so make sure to get busy with our poll, and let yes know all about your weekend gaming plans in the comments!</em></p>
</section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/talking-point-what-are-you-playing-this-weekend-24th-january]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sonic Racing Open To Including More 'Deep Cut' Characters From Extended Sonic Universe]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/sonic-racing-open-to-including-more-deep-cut-characters-from-extended-sonic-universe</link>
            <guid>1414978</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Tangle and Whisper join the race next month</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="2fe69c5bdcd17"><a title="Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/2fe69c5bdcd17/sonic-racing-crossworlds.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: SEGA,</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Last November, Sega announced three more characters for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/sonic_racing_crossworlds">Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds</a>. This included the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/mastersystem/sonic_the_hedgehog">Sonic the Hedgehog</a> IDW duo, Tangle and Whisper.</p>
<p>Now, in a recent interview with <a href="https://mcvuk.com/">MCV Magazine</a>, Sonic Team boss Takashi Iizuka has reiterated how the team realises there is "a lot of passion around the extended Sonic universe" which goes beyond the video games, and is apparently open to including even more "deep cut characters if the opportunity feels right".</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Takashi Iizuka:</strong> "We want Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds to represent all eras of Sonic"</p></blockquote><div><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytC1rrCdi_XjA" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067rjytvo&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>842k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div><blockquote>
</blockquote>
<p>Some of the more surprising Sonic character cameos in Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds so far include select cast from the Netflix series <strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2022/12/round-up-the-reviews-are-in-for-sonic-prime#:~:text=%22Sonic%20Prime%20is%20yet%20another,is%20a%20lot%20of%20fun.">Sonic Prime</a></strong>, and the bonus racer <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/2009/02/sonic_unleashed_wii">Sonic the Werehog</a> from <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/sonic_unleashed">Sonic Unleashed</a>. Sega is also adding <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/super_monkey_ball">Super Monkey Ball</a>'s lead character to the cast, who will follow <a href="https://www.timeextension.com/games/saturn/nights_into_dreams">NiGHTS</a> as one of the free post-launch racers.</p>
<p>As for Tangle and Whisper, they are <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/sonic-racing-crossworlds-new-free-characters-update-coming-soon">scheduled to arrive as a free update</a> in Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds next month.</p>
<figure data-uuid="e1d487ca99724"><a title="Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/e1d487ca99724/sonic-racing-crossworlds.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: SEGA, IDW</em></figcaption></figure>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/sonic/related-articles:193753,195676,196392 @ 1769274804 -->
<p>What other Sonic characters would you like to see Sega surprise fans with in Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds? <em>Tell us below.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/sonic-boss-says-hes-open-to-adding-deep-cut-sonic-characters-as-crossworlds-dlc/" rel="noopener" href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/sonic-boss-says-hes-open-to-adding-deep-cut-sonic-characters-as-crossworlds-dlc/">videogameschronicle.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/sonic/related-info/877bf42dde43fd9c571de711bafb68de @ 1769277494 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/sonic-racing-open-to-including-more-deep-cut-characters-from-extended-sonic-universe]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>