<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 23:53:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dave The Diver Director Says "There's Nothing Indie" About Hit Game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/dave-the-diver-director-says-theres-nothing-indie-about-hit-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dave-the-diver-director-says-theres-nothing-indie-about-hit-game.1233360/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Mintrocket "didn't apply" for controversial Best Independent Game nom</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="Dave the Diver" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/30cf0aaf5317d/dave-the-diver.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oDhhP5MwL6Q&amp;ab_channel=MINTROCKET">Nexon</a></em></figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/dave_the_diver">Dave The Diver</a> is undoubtedly one of the best games of 2023, but it found itself caught in a bit of a storm during awards season as at The Game Awards of that year, the fantastic diving game and restaurant management sim <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2023/11/is-dave-the-diver-an-indie-game-the-game-awards-host-weighs-in">was nominated for Best Independent Game</a>, despite it being created by a subsidiary of the huge South Korean developer and publisher Nexon.</p>
<p>Now Mintrocket CEO and writer and director on the game, Jaeho Hwang, has directly addressed the controversy in an interview with <a href="https://www.4gamer.net/games/635/G063598/20250627083/">4Gamer</a> (translated by <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/dave-the-diver-director-addresses-controversial-best-indie-game-nomination-from-2023-theres-nothing-indie-about-us-we-didnt-apply-for-it/">Automaton Media</a>), stating that "it’s not like we applied for the award ourselves."</p>
<p>Hwang emphasises that the nominees for Best Independent Game are picked based on nomination system that developers cannot nominate themselves for. <a href="https://thegameawards.com/faq">The Game Awards</a> website states that all nominees, regardless of categories, are "chosen by an international jury of over 100 global media and influencer outlets, selected for their history of critical video game evaluation", with specialised juries set up for particular categories.</p>
<p>"We did not intend for it to have an indie game feel" Hwang tells the publication, saying that "it's made by Nexon, so there's nothing indie about it".</p>
<p>"I wonder if people mistook us for an indie studio just because we’re developing games as a small team, or just because our art styles and game systems tend to be unique." It is, admittedly, pretty hard to put Dave The Diver in a labelled box like many other games, but just because something uses pixel art and has a completely unique premise and gameplay loop, doesn't mean it's independent.</p>
<figure data-videoid="3yMR-2k127U" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3yMR-2k127U?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/3yMR-2k127U?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3yMR-2k127U?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501"></iframe><figcaption><p>The game just celebrated its 2nd anniversary</p>
<p><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3yMR-2k127U" rel="noopener">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></p>
<p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>825k</span></a></p>
</figcaption></figure>
<p>Back when the discussion was rumbling, The Game Awards host Geoff Keighley <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2023/11/is-dave-the-diver-an-indie-game-the-game-awards-host-weighs-in">shared his thoughts on the controversy</a> during a Twitch stream, where he said "independent can mean different things to different people," and that "we defer to our jury" on making those judgments. He did acknowledge that the studio itself comes from a "larger entity" but was (probably) created with a "relatively small budget".</p>
<p>All we'll say is that Dave The Diver is a fantastic game, and we loved it back on Switch. And we may well be revisiting it again soon as Mintrocket has confirmed that <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/dave-the-diver-is-getting-a-free-switch-2-upgrade-soon-says-mintrocket">the game is getting a free Switch 2 update "soon"</a>. It's also <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2024/12/dave-the-diver-in-the-jungle-dlc-swims-onto-switch-in-late-2025">getting some DLC</a>, but that's recently been delayed to 2026.</p>
<p><em>What do you think of Jaeho Hwang's comments? Let us know down below</em>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/switch-eshop/related-articles:184518,175835 @ 1751412749 --></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.4gamer.net/games/635/G063598/20250627083/" rel="noopener" href="https://www.4gamer.net/games/635/G063598/20250627083/">4gamer.net</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://automaton-media.com/en/news/dave-the-diver-director-addresses-controversial-best-indie-game-nomination-from-2023-theres-nothing-indie-about-us-we-didnt-apply-for-it/" rel="noopener" href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/dave-the-diver-director-addresses-controversial-best-indie-game-nomination-from-2023-theres-nothing-indie-about-us-we-didnt-apply-for-it/">automaton-media.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/switch-eshop/related-info/8b23bff10c8968b20c12e9fcf98a3635 @ 1751412444 --></div></article><div><p>Alana has been with Nintendo Life since 2022, and while RPGs are her first love, Nintendo is a close second. She enjoys nothing more than overthinking battle strategies, characters, and stories. She also wishes she was a Sega air pirate.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/AlanaHagues"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/alanahagues.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('AlanaHagues');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/dave-the-diver-director-says-theres-nothing-indie-about-hit-game]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After Croc, Argonaut Games Wants To Remaster This N64 Cult Classic]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/after-croc-argonaut-games-wants-to-remaster-this-n64-cult-classic</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/after-croc-argonaut-games-wants-to-remaster-this-n64-cult-classic.1233336/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<p>"Bump to the bump to the Bumble"</p>
</section><div><section>
<figure><a title="Buck Bumble" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/5128cf7379ad5/buck-bumble.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Ubisoft</em></figcaption></figure><p>Argonaut Games may be basking in the aftermath of the return of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/croc_legend_of_the_gobbos">Croc</a>, but the British-based developer isn't done revisiting its back-catalogue just yet. The newly-revived studio, who returned last year after being dissolved in 2007, are particularly keen to revisit an N64 cult classic: <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/n64/buck_bumble">Buck Bumble</a>.</p>
<p>Speaking in the latest issue of the <a href="https://mcvuk.com/">MCV Develop</a> magazine (via <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/croc-studio-argonaut-wants-to-remaster-cult-n64-shooter-buck-bumble/">VGC</a>), CEO and co-founder Jez San and Mike Arkin listed off a handful of titles the team, originally called Argonaut Software, worked on during its initial stint — Starglider ("it's my ‘first-born’" San explains) and I-Ninja both came up, but a certain third-person shooter stuck out to us, and others, the most.</p>
<p>“I-Ninja is a really well-regarded and underappreciated game and we’d love to revisit it. Buck Bumble too, but that was N64-only so less people know about it." San continues, reminiscing about the studio's output.</p>
<p>The reason Croc was chosen first was pretty obvious — it sold over 3 million copies when it launched on PlayStation and Sega Saturn in 1997 as it was "the first big platformer on the original <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/platforms/playstation/" title="Platforms > PlayStation [10,845 articles]">PlayStation</a> console".</p>
<p>"It’s also got broad appeal, both to men and women. Croc really appealed to everyone. It was the obvious choice." Concludes San, before Arkin jumps in to add yet another mention of the gun-wielding bee: "But we also hope that Buck Bumble will also have his day in the sun, eventually."</p>
<p>Buck Bumble is a curious little game that launched in 1998 on the N64 only. Taking place in the surrounding area of a then-futuristic London (2010... yes, really), you play a bee who has voluntarily been implanted with cyborg technology.</p>
<figure data-videoid="w8FQ-N0zb2U" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/w8FQ-N0zb2U?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/w8FQ-N0zb2U?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/w8FQ-N0zb2U?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501"></iframe><figcaption><p>If you've somehow never heard this... do yourself a favour.</p>
<p><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w8FQ-N0zb2U" rel="noopener">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></p>
<p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>825k</span></a></p>
</figcaption></figure>
<p>You need to save the world from a group of genetically-enhanced insects called the Herd using various weapons such as a laser, a stun gun, and a guided missile. With 19 missions to blast your way through, a multiplayer mode, and gameplay designed with the Rumble Pak in mind, it's a unique game from the N64's life.</p>
<p>Oh, and the music is fantastic — it's all speed garage, and all composed by Justin Scharvona, who posted the <a href="https://open.spotify.com/artist/033jTd9jqRN9mwuiJsKwwg">soundtrack on streaming services last year</a>. Ahh, memories...</p>
<p>But we might be waiting for a while to see the return of Buck Bumble, as it sounds like the next obvious step for Argonaut Games is, well, <em>extremely</em> obvious: <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps1/croc_2">Croc 2</a>.</p>
<p>"We’ve made no secret of the fact that if Croc does well in the market that the obvious next project is to remaster Croc 2," Arkin states, revealing that the team is already in the early stages of bringing the sequel back. Bear in mind, though, that the team has only done some early R&amp;D to "validate our approach" and it still needs the greenlight from the financial side.</p>
<p>So, we'll have to wait and see. You'll need to pick up a copy of the MVC Develop magazine yourself to check out the whole interview, but Buck Bumble is remembered fondly in Argonaut's mind.</p>
<p><em>Have you played Buck Bumble? Would you like to see a remaster of this unusual game? Let us know in the comments</em>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/retro/related-articles:179990,43185 @ 1751413573 --></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://mcvuk.com/" rel="noopener" href="https://mcvuk.com/">mcvuk.com</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/croc-studio-argonaut-wants-to-remaster-cult-n64-shooter-buck-bumble/" rel="noopener" href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/croc-studio-argonaut-wants-to-remaster-cult-n64-shooter-buck-bumble/">videogameschronicle.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/retro/related-info/a6e381af44c3422aff882d1eff3d9568 @ 1751412625 --></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/after-croc-argonaut-games-wants-to-remaster-this-n64-cult-classic]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donkey Kong Bananza Gets Smashing New Commercial]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/donkey-kong-bananza-gets-smashing-new-commercial</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/donkey-kong-bananza-gets-smashing-new-commercial.1233279/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>"Unleash your inner Kong"</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>If a day of previews and impressions aren't enough <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/donkey-kong-bananza">Donkey Kong Bananza</a> for you, how about a commercial? It's time to unleash your inner Kong.</p>
<p>Nintendo has dropped a brand new ad for the upcoming 3D platformer, incorporating the games central premises of music and smashing things up. You won't be able to stop yourself from humming the tune — or even chanting along with the actors.</p>
<p>The gameplay itself isn't anything new, but we're not complaining; there's plenty of smashing, running, and even a glimpse of DK's Bananza Transformation. This is the most love we've seen Donkey Kong get in a long while, and the wait over the next few weeks is going to be excruciating.</p>
<p>Fans in the comments are, of course, posting the lyrics to the DK Rap — that song <em>isn't</em> in this ad, but the "DK" chanting is certainly evocative of it. Also... is that a Lanky Kong reference at the end?</p>
<p>Anyway, if you missed it, we actually went <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/previews/donkey-kong-bananza-dks-getting-his-own-odyssey-and-its-a-helluva-trip">hands-on with the game very recently</a>, and even after only a few hours, we might be in love. Nintendo also confirmed to us that the team behind the game is indeed "the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/super_mario_odyssey">Super Mario Odyssey</a> team", so those comparisons are apt.</p>
<p><em>Are you excited for Donkey Kong Bananza on 17th July 2025? Let us know in the comments</em>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:184551,184075 @ 1751410905 --></section></article><div><p>Alana has been with Nintendo Life since 2022, and while RPGs are her first love, Nintendo is a close second. She enjoys nothing more than overthinking battle strategies, characters, and stories. She also wishes she was a Sega air pirate.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/AlanaHagues"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/alanahagues.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('AlanaHagues');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/donkey-kong-bananza-gets-smashing-new-commercial]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>