<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 05:34:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Talking Point: Where On Earth Are The Switch 2 Soundtracks On Nintendo Music?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/talking-point-where-on-earth-are-the-switch-2-soundtracks-on-nintendo-music</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/talking-point-where-on-earth-are-the-switch-2-soundtracks-on-nintendo-music.1266651/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure><a title="Nintendo Music" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/499efa333a40a/nintendo-music.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo Life / Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure><p><em>Ohhhhh, Zeebraaaa, Zeebraaaaa, ZEEBRAAAAA!~</em></p>
<p>Here I am, tapping out once again to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X6E0eAReCvU">the Zebra Bananza theme</a>. It's a song fit for Carnival, a blend of styles from all across Latin America — the Brazilian Samba, the Cuban Salsa, the Argentinian Tango. Every time DK beats his chest and transforms into the buffest Zebra you've ever seen, I attempt to sing along with Pauline, even though I don't understand the Kong language.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/donkey-kong-bananza">Donkey Kong Bananza</a> is a game all about music, but if I want to go and listen to it on my downtime or while out for a drive? Well, it's time to pull out the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/mobile/nintendo_music">Nintendo Music</a> app and rock ou... wait, <em>it's not on there?</em></p>
<p>Nintendo has a rich musical history, one that it's gradually celebrating and acknowledging via this app, which it introduced last year for NSO subscribers. It's a nice little bonus if you're already playing for those SNES and Game Boy games on your Switch.</p>
<figure><a title="Donkey Kong Bananza" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/2be9e29c54860/donkey-kong-bananza.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo Life / Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Ideally, I'd rather Nintendo just released its music on the likes of Spotify and Apple, but I completely understand that the company wants complete control of its extensive library. And it's done a good job of supporting it with weekly updates to the library from its deep catalogue of tunes. This week, we got <em>all</em> of the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/snes/pilotwings">Pilotwings</a> music, not just the SNES one. Last week, it was <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/snes/mario_paint">Mario Paint</a> to coincide with the NSO release. I regularly pop on <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/super_mario_galaxy">Super Mario Galaxy</a> or <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/animal_crossing_new_horizons">Animal Crossing: New Horizons</a> in the car.</p>
<p>But Nintendo is missing a trick. We know there's a gold mine of music to dig out from the archives, and far too many omissions to highlight. But where's the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a> soundtrack? Where's the multi-genre delights of the Switch 2's launch game?</p>
<p>Mario Kart World is already two months old, yet if I'm jonesing to jig down the streets to the funky sounds of Crown City or sway to the smooth and slow arrangement of Steam Gardens, I have to go to YouTube in the hopes that fan uploads haven't been taken down yet.</p>

<p>When publishers, developers, and composers choose to share and sell their music is obviously up to them. Big hitters like <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/death_stranding_2_on_the_beach">Death Stranding 2</a> drop their OSTs the same day as the game is out. Atlus is particularly good at getting its soundtracks up as soon as possible; <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/raidou-remastered-the-mystery-of-the-soulless-army">Raidou Remastered</a> was available on launch day, and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/persona-3-reload">Persona 3 Reload</a> followed its PlayStation and Xbox release just a few months later. And there are so many indie titles that you can stream day-and-date, <a href="https://bandcamp.com/discover/video-game">or pick up on Bandcamp</a>.</p>
<p>The newest game soundtrack on Nintendo Music is <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pikmin_4">Pikmin 4</a>'s, composed by Kenta Nagata, Asuka Hayazaki, and Soshi Abe — although you wouldn't know that from the app because the composers aren't credited. That game is two years old at this point; can you even buy the soundtrack in a store or online? Well, unless you can find and splash out on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C7mqZKKPr9F/?img_index=1">this lovely Mother Onion limited vinyl</a>, which contains 14 of the game's tracks? Nope. Admittedly, Nintendo is doing a lot better than it was when <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/talking-point-video-game-music-is-more-popular-than-ever-so-why-is-nintendo-so-behind">I ranted about video game music three years ago</a>. But its music app strategy is odd to me.</p>
<p>I don't really expect them to turn around and pop DK Bananza on there on Tuesday — that game just came out, and companies like Square Enix often wait a few months, sometimes years, before sharing game music on streaming services. I don't blame anyone for holding back on DK's melodic magic for a few months. But what better way to share the magic of something like Mario Kart World's open roads than dropping the Super Bell Hill rearrangement or the title music on the app? You don't even need to put the whole thing on there.</p>

<p>In the grand scheme of things, it's really just a tiny drop of annoyance in an ocean of problems. I care more about crediting artists, composers, and arrangers than having the shiny new music on my app, which I don't have to pay extra money for. And look, if Nintendo wants to charge an extra buck or two a month for NSO just to stick the brand new Switch 2 soundtracks on there? I'd consider it.</p>
<p>Nintendo could even pull a big Mario Paint and drop GameCube soundtracks along with NSO drops. <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/legend_of_zelda_the_wind_waker">Wind Waker</a> is already available, but we're missing <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/mario_smash_football">Super Mario Strikers</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/f-zero_gx">F-Zero GX</a>. Imagine getting both <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/fire_emblem_path_of_radiance">Fire Emblem: Path of Radiance</a> and its excellent soundtrack on the same day.</p>
<p>I do think Mario Kart World and Donkey Kong Bananza's music will eventually come to the app. It might take months, maybe a year, but they'll be there. More GameCube titles will also get their time in the sunlight, hopefully paired with their Nintendo Online release.</p>
<figure><a title="Mario Kart World Dino Dino Jungle" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/e35b0117669f5/mario-kart-world-dino-dino-jungle.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo Life / Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>I'd still love Nintendo to be a bit more proactive with its music, though. A video of the Kong Bananza song, complete with lyrics, on <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/mobile/nintendo_today">Nintendo Today</a> just isn't going to cut it. I need the Freezer Layer song to sparkle in my ears, or the Forest Layer theme to chill out to.</p>
<p>Plus, we've got a contender for one of the best soundtracks of the year in Mario Kart World, and maybe one of Nintendo's best OSTs of all-time, yet I can't even go out and buy the soundtrack, or any of the songs. Without fans, I'd be left scrambling to try and find how to listen to this music outside of the game. Is that really what video game music deserves?</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Do you want to see Mario Kart World and Donkey Kong Bananza on Nintendo Music? Vote in our polls below and let us know in the comments what you think.</em></p>



<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:173865,132200 @ 1754888174 --></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/talking-point-where-on-earth-are-the-switch-2-soundtracks-on-nintendo-music]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mini Review: Is This Seat Taken? (Switch) - Sit Down And Get Comfy With This Short, Simple Puzzler]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/is-this-seat-taken</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mini-review-is-this-seat-taken-switch-sit-down-and-get-comfy-with-this-short-simple-puzzler.1266606/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<p>Someone's sitting there, mate</p>
<p><strong>Version Reviewed:</strong> European</p>
</section><section><p>I'm the type of introvert who's made an art of choosing the right seat in public places. With such honed skills, I assumed a puzzler like <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/is_this_seat_taken">Is This Seat Taken?</a> would be second nature, and I was <em>mostly</em> right. This adorable indie might not bring anything radical to the table, but it's a perfectly pleasant pick-up-and-play experience, that will undoubtedly scratch any low-stakes puzzle itches.</p>
<p>Strung together by a loose story about a rhombus with dreams of treading the boards (yes, really), Is This Seat Taken is about organising people into the right spots so that everyone's preferences are satisfied. This might be at the cinema or museum, a taxi or a boat, but each person (well, "shape" might be more accurate) has their own conditions to meet, and they can be rather fussy.</p>
<p>Things start simple: slot this handful of shapes into a taxi, and make sure persons A and C are sitting by the window. But each stage brings a new challenge. In the cinema screen, some guests will use their phones or chat. On boats, you'll get party groups who need to be kept separate from those who just want to sightsee. And everyone wants to steer clear of guests who forgot to shower.</p>
<p>The idea of performing such feats of organisation in the real world is enough to break me out in a cold sweat, but Is This Seat Taken couldn't be more chilled. There's no timer and no punishment for putting somebody in the wrong place. Heck, you can even finish the level without everyone sitting comfortably — though you'd lose valuable 'thumbs up' points, and my respect, in the process.</p>
<p>Busier stages can feel a little trial-and-error-y, and the absence of any kind of hint system meant I had to pull everyone from their temporary places and start from scratch on more than one occasion; I would love an undo/reset button for this kind of thing. Fortunately, no puzzle outstays its welcome. I polished off every level (in which there are five or six stages) in around six hours, and stages themselves are broken down into micro-challenges, primed for anyone who wants to squeeze in 10 minutes of gaming while the pasta's cooking. It feels tailor-made for precisely this.</p>
<p>The onscreen cursor is smooth and intuitive, the characters are cute, and you can even use touchscreen controls in handheld. If it all sounds rather mobile puzzler, that's because it is — I appreciated every new challenge and tweak when I'd come back to the game, but two or three levels on the trot felt a little repetitive.</p>
<p>All in all, Is This Seat Taken is solid pick-up-and-play puzzler. It may not do anything new or unique, but the condition-meeting gameplay loop is primed for anyone after a low-stakes distraction. It won't keep you occupied for hours on end, but it'll do an almighty job of reminding you that your seating preferences are not to be scoffed at.</p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/is-this-seat-taken]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Poll: Box Art Brawl - Duel: WarioWare, Inc.: Mega Microgame$!]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/poll-box-art-brawl-duel-warioware-inc-mega-microgameusd</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/poll-box-art-brawl-duel-warioware-inc-mega-microgame.1266588/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Vote!</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure><a title="WarioWare GBA - BAB" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/63e63cef1fe2d/warioware-gba-bab.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>Welcome, cover fans, to another edition of Box Art Brawl!</p>
<p>Before we head into this week's match-up, let's have a quick reminder of what went down <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/poll-box-art-brawl-duel-the-hobbit-gba">last weekend</a>. It was a one-on-one face-off for the GBA's <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gba/hobbit">The Hobbit</a>, which saw the gloomy North American/European cover go up against the colourful Japanese variant. Somewhat surprisingly to us, it was the latter that walked away with a comfortable win, taking 68% of the vote and leaving the NA/EU cover with the remaining 32% — an unexpected journey indeed!</p><div><figure data-videoid="bhK3W_3CW7w" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bhK3W_3CW7w?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/bhK3W_3CW7w?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bhK3W_3CW7w?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed38e97fgqlhwv&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><figcaption><p><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bhK3W_3CW7w" rel="noopener">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></p>
<p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>830k</span></a></p>
</figcaption></figure></div>
<p>We've got another duel on our hands this time, as we mosey over to the first (and best) WarioWare game out there: <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gba/warioware_inc_mega_microgameusd">WarioWare, Inc.: Mega Microgame$!</a>. Perhaps the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/ufo-50-gets-a-surprise-shadow-drop-on-switch-today">surprise launch</a> of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/ufo_50">UFO 50</a> on Switch has put minigame collections on the brain (not that UFO 50 is anything like WarioWare, mind), but it got us in the mood to look back at this GBA classic, for which there are <em>two</em> drastically different covers.</p>
<p>It's another match-up between East and West this time, so let's get into it. Ready? Vote!</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/retro/related-articles:172660 @ 1754887603 -->
<h2>North America / Europe</h2>
<figure><a title="WarioWare GBA - NA/EU" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/4f68052b54add/warioware-gba-naeu.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: <a href="https://gamesdb.launchbox-app.com/games/details/3917-warioware-inc-mega-microgame">Nintendo / LaunchBox</a></em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Gosh, talk about iconic covers, eh? The design used in Europe and North America is all about colour. The WarioWare logo is put front and centre, but Wario and all of his minigame crew take up sections around it, with their distinct looks and bright colouring making each and every one a real eye-catcher.</p>
<h2>Japan</h2>
<figure><a title="WarioWare GBA - JP" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/a1e4db5c6cfff/warioware-gba-jp.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: <a href="https://gamesdb.launchbox-app.com/games/details/3917-warioware-inc-mega-microgame">Nintendo / LaunchBox</a></em></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Japanese cover goes for something... different. Gone is the <em>in-your-face</em> colour and multiple characters, here replaced by a calming light blue background, with Wario's distinct facial features adorning the middle. It's nothing like as hectic, nor as eye-catching, we'd say, but damn, it's a classy look.</p>
<hr>

<p><em>Thanks for voting! W</em><em>e'll see you next time for another Box Art Brawl.</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/retro/related-articles:146790 @ 1754887767 --></section></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/poll-box-art-brawl-duel-warioware-inc-mega-microgameusd]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[One Piece: Pirate Warriors 4 Officially Reveals Character Pass 3 DLC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/one-piece-pirate-warriors-4-officially-reveals-character-pass-3-dlc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/one-piece-pirate-warriors-4-officially-reveals-character-pass-3-dlc.1266570/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Following a fan survey earlier this year</p>
</section></header><div><section>

<p>We heard earlier this year how <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/one_piece_pirate_warriors_4">One Piece: Pirate Warriors 4</a> would be getting more DLC, and now we've got an official update.</p>
<p>Bandai Namco and the game's developer Omega Force have revealed Character Pass 3. It contains six playable characters and is available to purchase on <strong>11th August 2025</strong>. The first part, arriving in <strong>Fall 2025</strong>, kicks off with Rob Lucci (CP0) and will be joined by two other characters.</p>
<p>In addition to this, the special survey pack (<a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/02/one-piece-pirate-warriors-4-is-getting-new-dlc-will-be-decided-by-fan-votes">a result of the user surveys conducted earlier this year</a>) will add Enel, King and Z in <strong>Early 2026</strong>. There'll also be a purchase bonus in the form of an additional skill for Shanks.</p>
<figure><a title="One Piece Pirate Warriors 4" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/127c9552ae586/one-piece-pirate-warriors-4.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Bandai Namco</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>You can check out the official announcement trailer in the video above, and find out more about this game in our review:</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:97649 @ 1754887889 --></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/one-piece-pirate-warriors-4-character-pass-3-announced" rel="noopener" href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/one-piece-pirate-warriors-4-character-pass-3-announced">gematsu.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-info/cf0a29f41092d317a9bc963c6eda2364 @ 1754888423 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/one-piece-pirate-warriors-4-officially-reveals-character-pass-3-dlc]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>