<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 11:54:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Review: GRID Legends: Deluxe Edition (Switch 2) - Satisfying 'Simcade' Racing Works Best With A GC Pad]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/grid-legends-deluxe-edition</link>
            <guid>1417207</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section>
<figure><a title="GRID Legends: Deluxe Edition Review - Screenshot 1 of 7" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161545/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Docked)</figcaption></figure><p>For serious petrolheads, the Switch 1 wasn't exactly a <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/burnout_paradise_remastered">(Burnout)</a> paradise platform. In fact, given the size of the console's library, there's surprisingly little in the way of even semi-serious racing sims for those looking for more than kart racing, smaller-scale experiences that hone in on one aspect and expand (such as the excellent <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/art_of_rally">art of rally</a>), or more general arcade fare (like <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/hot_wheels_unleashed_2_turbocharged">Hot Wheels Unleashed</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/horizon_chase_turbo">Horizon Chase Turbo</a>).</p>
<p>These are all great games, for sure, but even now, with the Switch successor nearly eight months into its life, what are we looking at in terms of sim-styled stuff? <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/rush_rally_3">Rush Rally 3</a> and its follow-up, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/rush_rally_origins">Rush Rally Origins</a>, perhaps, but precious little. 2019's <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/grid_autosport">GRID Autosport</a> still stands out, though.</p>
<p>I know, Codemasters' 2014 racer (brought to Switch by Feral Interactive) isn't really a sim either, not purely, but it's a different level of racing experience to the others I've mentioned. You can have a big, serious career across multiple disciplines, and so it's a game that comes as close to the likes of <a href="https://www.purexbox.com/games/xbox-series-x/forza_motorsport">Forza</a> and <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps4/gran_turismo_7">Gran Turismo</a> as you'll currently get on a Switch. Indeed, it's the most impressive racing game port I've played on the console, giving you the full-fat package of single-player content to race through local and online multiplayer was added in post-launch updates), and with no major performance issues to speak of. It also looks great, even now.</p>
<figure><a title="GRID Legends: Deluxe Edition Review - Screenshot 2 of 7" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161546/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Now 2022's <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/grid-legends-deluxe-edition">GRID Legends</a>, the most recent series entry, has landed on Switch 2 and it's brought all the same graphics options and tweakable bells and whistles as its impressive predecessor — more about those in a bit — whilst also upping the ante in terms of the depth and scope of its solo content. Nice! However, does it have the bleedin' multiplayer at launch this time?</p>
<p>No, it doesn't. And whilst, yes, it's a shame, I have to say, as someone who owns this game on other platforms, you're not missing much. At all. In fact, given that online leaderboards <em>have</em> made the cut here, I'd go so far as to say you've still got the best and cleanest multiplayer element intact. It's unclear if multiplayer might be patched in later, like its predecessor.</p>
<p>However, Legends <em>is</em> aiming to please primarily by bringing narrative aspects and solo content to the fore. It feels like that rare sort of racer that's been made with single-player racing fans in mind, in fact. Its story and campaign modes are where it sings, mixing a little light drama with racing that can, and does, get fairly explosive on the regular. Also, this Deluxe Edition lands with all previously-released DLC, meaning there's loads more to dig into in these modes.</p>
<figure><a title="GRID Legends: Deluxe Edition Review - Screenshot 3 of 7" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161547/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Let's talk about the handling of the cars. The Grid games hit my own personal sweet spot (most of the time) for controls in an arcade-sim/simcade style. It immediately feels very satisfying to put your boot down and tear up a straight; to drift ferociously through corners or handbrake at the last second into a hairpin and swing your back around, ready to rinse and repeat step one. If you've played any modern arcade racer, you're immediately comfortable, and this game feels as good as any of its peers when you're on the track. In fact, I've been on a bit of a racer kick lately, and I can say that this one easily beats out <strong><a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps4/need_for_speed_heat">Need For Speed Heat</a></strong> <em>and</em> <strong><a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/need_for_speed_unbound">Need for Speed Unbound</a></strong>. Both lovely games, but this one wins on controls, it wins on content, and it wins on giving solo players loads that they'll feel the need to speed into. (Thank you.)</p>
<p>Now, let's reverse a bit, because I mentioned controls and whilst for some, the lack of a multiplayer suite will be the primary annoyance, it's Nintendo's choice of digital triggers on the Switch 2's controllers that bothers me most for this type of experience. It's not a complete killer, not at all, and I'm sure you've had plenty of experience with it in the past, but it's going to be an issue for some finesse fans who don't want to start considering new control setups or tweaking in order to attain the level of throttle control they enjoy.</p>
<p>Of course, and you'll know this if you've checked out our <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/all-nintendo-switch-1-and-2-games-with-analogue-trigger-compatibility-that-work-with-the-gamecube-nso-controller">recent guide to Switch 1 and 2 games with analogue trigger support for GameCube controllers</a>, you <em>can</em> also use your snazzy NSO GameCube pad to override this issue and enjoy the wonder of technology that's been around since the late '90s. With the GC controller plugged in, the game shines all the brighter.</p>
<figure><a title="GRID Legends: Deluxe Edition Review - Screenshot 4 of 7" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161538/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Docked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>I do also think, on balance, that the lack of analogue triggers on the default controllers isn't quite as important as it could have been. There's no way you're getting me around Monaco in an exacting F1 game with digital triggers, for example — I'm crashing 1000 times on the first bend — but it works fine for what's presented here.</p>
<p>Onto the modes on offer, and Grid Legends brings lots to the table. Besides the main story mode, which I'll get to in a bit, we've got a career that's split up over four unlockable levels, starting with a rookie program and ending in a gauntlet of pro challenges. With a total of nine disciplines to try to master, from touring and electric cars to open-wheeled vehicles, trucks, and high-performance GT stuff (my favourite), there are 128 motors and 137 track routes set in 22 different locations here. Yes, I did say it's a meaty one.</p>
<p>Free play mode then gives you single player quick races, single race events and custom cups for you to set up at your leisure, whilst Dynamic Events mode, as I briefly mentioned earlier, allow you to pit your online times against others via leaderboards.</p>
<figure><a title="GRID Legends: Deluxe Edition Review - Screenshot 5 of 7" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161539/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>As for the main course, that is the game's 'Drive to Glory' story mode, this roughly seven-hour affair sees you rise up the ranks through events and trials in a tale that's as rote as they come, but it does have an ace up its sleeve! And that ace, my friends, is live-action acting for the cutscenes and all the main parts of rival racers and team members, making for some utterly hammy, totally unnecessary, and really, actually, quite fun cutscenes.</p>
<p>I also vastly prefer the overall style of how this stuff gets delivered here; dropped in casually and quickly as we set up for races and arrive at paddocks, and so on, rather than cutting away for big chunks. It gives you a story, and it keeps you near to the action at all times. So, if you feel like the narrative aspects <em>might</em> get in the way of racing, fear not, as it's a well-balanced thing, and having voices and faces for opponents sure does bring a new level of competitiveness on the track, too. <em>"I really hate that guy!"</em> you'll scream as you ram into their car and make an enemy, or a 'rival', as the game labels it.</p>
<figure><a title="GRID Legends: Deluxe Edition Review - Screenshot 6 of 7" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161540/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Yes, the racing here once again incorporates the Grid series' slick nemesis system, and it's been improved in Legends, making for some seriously dirty races as you start to make <del>enemies</del> rivals who'll then make sure to get payback by spinning you out on a corner or shunting you at the worst possible moment. I love it, and you can toggle off the rough stuff if you're not a fan, as there are difficulty levels for everyone to enjoy here and options galore.</p>
<p>Speaking of options, this one has got all the graphics modes found in GRID Autosport. So, you've a choice between "Graphics" and "Performance" in TV mode (30/60fps, respectively). In handheld, we get both performance and quality as above, with the addition of a "Balanced" mode and a "Battery Saver" mode.</p>
<p>I've been messing with all of these and the visual quality mode, whilst fine, isn't worth the sacrifice for how smooth performance feels at a solid 60fps. I'll also say I've been pretty blown away by how great the performance mode looks on a big TV screen. There's no need to worry about awful textures and image quality at all with this, it looks fab.</p>
<figure><a title="GRID Legends: Deluxe Edition Review - Screenshot 7 of 7" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161541/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Docked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>In handheld, I've landed on the balanced mode after lots of experimenting. It feels that bit smoother than quality and looks sublime on the console's little screen. There are also options to turn on or off enhanced visual effects and to reduce rain intensity, so plenty to muck with, and the game delivers top-notch, highly enjoyable and responsive racing on the go as a result.</p>
</section><section id="conclusion"><h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>If you can make peace with a lack of multiplayer outside of online leaderboards, alongside the fact that digital triggers aren't ideal if you're after precision throttle control (grab a GameCube NSO pad to swerve this issue), Grid Legends on Switch 2 serves up an excellent package of slick and satisfying 'simcade' action that looks and plays wonderfully well in both docked and handheld.</p>
<p>With lots of options in terms of graphics and accessibility, and all previously-released DLC included, this is easily the best racing package of this type that's currently available on either of Nintendo's Switches and a real blast for solo racing fans.</p></section>

</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/grid-legends-deluxe-edition]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FUR Squadron Phoenix Brings All The Star Fox Vibes To Switch Next Month]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/fur-squadron-phoenix-brings-all-the-star-fox-vibes-to-switch-next-month</link>
            <guid>1417174</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Fur real</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Raptor Claw's <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/fur_squadron">FUR Squadron</a> rather proudly wore its <strong>Star Fox</strong> inspirations on its sleeve when it flew onto Switch back in 2023, and its sequel, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/fur_squadron_phoenix">FUR Squadron Phoenix</a>, isn't shying away from things either.</p>
<p>This on-rails space shooter arrives on the Switch eShop on <strong>25th February</strong>, and it looks every bit as McCloud-ian as we'd hoped. There's a crew of fluffy pilots, nimble space ships, an interplanetary "system" under threat from an evil force — yeah, this is Star Fox.</p>
<p>Much like its predecessor, however, there's a certain psychedelic sheen over the whole thing that stops FUR Squadron from feeling like a complete retread of things we've seen before. With neon visuals, CRT scan lines and mech battles (!!), there's a pretty intriguing vibe under all of the familiarity.</p>
<p>Here's a brief rundown of the game's key features and a handful of screenshots from its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2674650/FUR_Squadron_Phoenix/">Steam</a> page:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>- A roguelite campaign where every run reshuffles the levels, keeping the action fresh and unpredictable.<br>
- Upgradeable ships, unlockable weapons, and skill trees that let you craft your own path to becoming an ace pilot.<br>
- Massive bosses, dynamic environments, and intense battles across space, air, and sea.<br>
- A dazzling arsenal: unleash power beams, multi-missile barrages, and even a nuke strike. Forget the basics—this is war with style.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Raptor Claw claimed that the game was heading to Switch 2 last year, shortly after the console's first tease reveal, and while it will certainly be playable on the new system, Switch 1 owners won't miss out. Based on the studio's reply to a comment on the above trailer, FUR Squadron Phoenix has been designed for Switch 1, but will see "boosted performance" on the new hardware.</p>
<p>With Nintendo showing no sign of releasing a new Star Fox game anytime soon, we'll be relying on projects like this to fill the Lylat-shaped hole in our hearts.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/switch-eshop/related-articles:194363,178179 @ 1769513899 -->
<p><em>What do you make of FUR Squadron Phoenix? Do a barrel roll in the comments and let us know.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/fur-squadron-phoenix-brings-all-the-star-fox-vibes-to-switch-next-month]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Super Mario Galaxy Movie Gets Another Stunning Movie Poster]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/the-super-mario-galaxy-movie-gets-another-stunning-movie-poster</link>
            <guid>1417111</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Celebrating the "first look" at Yoshi</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure data-uuid="4408f68c380d7"><a title="The Super Mario Galaxy Movie" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/4408f68c380d7/the-super-mario-galaxy-movie.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo, Illumination</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Last weekend, Nintendo aired a special Direct presentation for its upcoming <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/the-super-mario-galaxy-movie-release-date-cast-trailers-everything-we-know-so-far"><strong>Super Mario Galaxy Movie</strong></a>, which is due out in cinemas this April.</p>
<p>This particular clip focused on Mario's pal Yoshi, who will join the crew in this new adventure, which takes place across all sorts of familiar locations. To celebrate this big reveal, Nintendo and Illumination have now released a new promotional poster, and it looks absolutely stunning.</p>
<p>In case you missed it, here's a look. As you can see, it shows Mario actually riding Yoshi:</p>
<figure data-uuid="8c1b96029652a"><a title="The Super Mario Galaxy Movie" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/8c1b96029652a/the-super-mario-galaxy-movie.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo, Illumination</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>This follows a <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/the-super-mario-galaxy-movie-gets-a-new-movie-poster">promotional poster released in November</a> last year featuring Mario and Luigi in what appeared to be the Sand Kingdom from <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/super_mario_odyssey">Super Mario Odyssey</a>. This looks to be the same location in the new trailer where Yoshi is discovered.</p>
<p>If you haven't already seen the new trailer, be sure to check it out in our previous post. This latest update from Nintendo and Illumination also notes how the movie's release date has shifted "in the US and many additional markets globally" and is now releasing at the very beginning of April.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/super-mario/related-articles:196611,196648,164056 @ 1769512347 -->
<p>What are your first impressions of the movie version of Yoshi a few days later? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/the-super-mario-galaxy-movie-gets-another-stunning-movie-poster]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rumour: Switch Online GameCube Releases Might Have Been Leaked]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/rumour-switch-online-gamecube-releases-might-have-been-leaked</link>
            <guid>1417078</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Is that...?</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure data-uuid="472087f9cc2e2"><a title="Switch 2 - GameCube" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/472087f9cc2e2/switch-2-gamecube.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>If you're wondering what could be on the way to the Switch Online's GameCube library in the future, you might want to read on...</p>
<p>What appears to be official promotional material for the Switch Online + Expansion Pack 'Nintendo Classics' library has been discovered on Walmart's website. Alongside multiple existing releases, there are two GameCube games featured that haven't even been announced for the service.</p>
<p>This includes <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/metroid_prime_2_echoes">Metroid Prime 2: Echoes</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/pikmin_2">Pikmin 2</a>, which were both locally released on the GameCube in 2004. Here's our own screen capture of this advertising material from the Walmart webpage. You can see Metroid Prime 2 towards the right corner of the top row, and Pikmin 2 is in the middle of the second row.</p><div><figure data-videoid="4gZSQE4poJM" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4gZSQE4poJM?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="yt4gZSQE4poJM" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/4gZSQE4poJM?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4gZSQE4poJM?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed402431wnogvt&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>842k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<figure data-uuid="51aaffd90401e"><a title="Walmart IMG" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/51aaffd90401e/walmart-img.large.png"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: <a href="https://www.walmart.com/brand/nintendo/10030719">via Walmart / Nintendo Life</a></em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Nintendo has <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/blurred-art-in-nintendos-n64-switch-online-trailer-suggests-exciting-upcoming-additions">accidentally leaked upcoming NSO games</a> in the past, so it wouldn't necessarily be a surprise if this latest discovery led to the eventual release of these titles on Switch 2's GameCube service. Of course, there's always a chance this could be some sort of blunder on Walmart's end.</p>
<p>There are currently eight titles available for the Switch 2's GameCube library, with three others confirmed to be on the way. These upcoming releases include <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/pokemon_colosseum">Pokémon Colosseum</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/pokemon_xd_gale_of_darkness">Pokémon XD: Gale of Darkness</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/super_mario_sunshine">Super Mario Sunshine</a>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:92427 @ 1769512699 -->
<p>Do you think we could see these games added to the GameCube library at some point? What other classics would you like to see join this paid service? <em>Tell us below.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/rumour-switch-online-gamecube-releases-might-have-been-leaked]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WarioWare's Original Soundtrack Has Been Added To Nintendo Music]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/wariowares-original-soundtrack-has-been-added-to-nintendo-music</link>
            <guid>1417033</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>It's Wario time!</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure data-uuid="542edee31dfe0"><a title="WarioWare" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/542edee31dfe0/warioware.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/mobile/nintendo_music">Nintendo Music</a> has already added a <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gba/fire_emblem">Fire Emblem</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/mario_and_luigi_brothership">Mario &amp; Luigi</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Zelda</a> soundtrack this year, and a new update today sees the arrival of the original <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gba/warioware_inc_mega_microgameusd">WarioWare</a> album.</p>
<p>This Game Boy Advance title debuted in 2003 and was composed by Ryoji Yoshitomi and Kyoko Miyamoto. Yoshitomi composed <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gba/wario_land_4">Wario Land 4</a> and also worked on <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gameboy/wario_land_super_mario_land_3">Super Mario Land 3</a>, and Kyoko Miyamoto helped out with a bunch of other GBA titles at the time, and assisted with voice work in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/warioware_touched">WarioWare Touched!</a>.</p>
<p>The soundtrack now available on Nintendo Music contains a whopping <strong>356 tracks</strong> and has a runtime of 2 hours and 15 minutes. Here are some track highlights, according to Nintendo:</p><div><figure data-videoid="bhK3W_3CW7w" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bhK3W_3CW7w?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytbhK3W_3CW7w" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/bhK3W_3CW7w?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bhK3W_3CW7w?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed38e97fsvipkw&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>842k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<blockquote>
<p>"Featuring tracks such as Sci-F (Dribble &amp; Spitz) - Drifting Away, Reality (Dr. Crygor) - Stage, and more"</p>
</blockquote>
<figure data-uuid="10e4187bc9f89"><a title="WarioWare" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/10e4187bc9f89/warioware.large.webp"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>If you would prefer to revisit the actual game, the good news is it's available via the Switch Online + Expansion Pack service.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-articles:173865,92427 @ 1769514738 -->
<p>To listen to this album on Nintendo Music, you'll need to have an active Switch Online membership and access to the app. What do you think of the latest soundtrack to join the service? What else would you like to see added in the future? <em>Tell us below.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/wariowares-original-soundtrack-has-been-added-to-nintendo-music]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kirby Air Riders Has Been Updated To Version 1.3.0, Here Are The Full Patch Notes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/kirby-air-riders-has-been-updated-to-version-1-3-0-here-are-the-full-patch-notes</link>
            <guid>1417024</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="04926b8059033"><a title="Kirby Air Riders" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/04926b8059033/kirby-air-riders.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure><p>We recently heard how <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/kirby-air-riders">Kirby Air Riders</a> would be getting its first update of 2026 (and possibly last major game update).</p>
<p>Well, the day is now here, and Version 1.3.0 has officially gone live on the Switch 2. To start with, GameShare is now supported - so you can play with a friend without a copy of the game. Along with this is a long list of balance adjustments to the riders and machines. And to add this there's a whole stack of bug fixes.</p>
<p>Just be mindful that replays from the previous updates are not compatible with the latest game data. You can see the official patch notes from Nintendo's support page below:</p>
<nav><ul><li><span title="On This Page"></span></li></ul>
</nav><div><figure data-videoid="M1hEbqIQJAc" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/M1hEbqIQJAc?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytM1hEbqIQJAc" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/M1hEbqIQJAc?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/M1hEbqIQJAc?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed6de8adiohlrw&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>842k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<h2 id="kirby-air-riders-ver-1-3-0-released-26th-january-2026">Kirby Air Riders: Ver. 1.3.0 (Released 26th January 2026)</h2>
<h3 id="general"><strong>General</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>GameShare is now supported.
<ul>
<li>Press the buttons at the bottom of the title screen to access the GameShare screen, where you can choose between People Nearby or GameChat.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>A new game mode, Grand Prix, is now available for Air Ride matches in paddocks.
<ul>
<li>Players will participate in multiple races where the winner is determined by overall points.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>A new rule set, Sub-In Series, is now available in paddocks.
<ul>
<li>This allows for continuous matches while subbing in players.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Two players can now participate in paddocks and Quick Matches from a single Nintendo Switch 2 system.</li>
<li>The “Popular” search condition in the Buy section of the Machine Market has been changed to “Random.”</li>
<li>The Transform Star’s bike-type form can now be edited in the My Machine Apply Decal screen.
<ul>
<li>Once a decal is applied to a Transform Star in either form, you will not be able to edit decals with the other form until all existing decals have been removed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>You can now delete individual records for each machine in Personal Best.</li>
<li>Previously, when swapping to a vacant machine or stealing a machine while your Special could have been triggered in City Trial, your Special gauge would decrease. Now the Special gauge will be maintained, so you will still be able to trigger your Special after swapping to or stealing a machine.</li>
<li>The lock-on range when swapping to a vacant machine in City Trial has been adjusted.</li>
<li>In City Trial, you can now tilt the Left Stick down or press the Down Button to discard a Copy Ability without triggering your Special.</li>
<li>The version is now displayed in the lower-left corner of the screen after crossing the finish line in Time Attack.</li>
<li>Withdrawing or otherwise disconnecting during an Online Match in a friends-only paddock will no longer subject you to penalties.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="balance-adjustments"><strong>Balance Adjustments</strong></h3>
<p>The performance of certain riders has been adjusted.</p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<th>Rider name</th>
<th>Adjustment details</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Waddle Dee</td>
<td>
<p>Affected modes: City Trial/Air Ride</p>
<ul>
<li>Raised Defense while Special is triggered.</li>
</ul>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Bandana Waddle Dee</td>
<td>
<p>Affected modes: City Trial/Air Ride</p>
<ul>
<li>Raised Special attack power.</li>
<li>Expanded Special attack range.</li>
<li>Raised gliding speed while Special is triggered.</li>
<li>Lowered fall speed while Special is triggered.</li>
</ul>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Waddle Doo</td>
<td>
<p>Affected modes: City Trial/Air Ride</p>
<ul>
<li>Raised automatic attack power.</li>
<li>Increased attack detection for automatic attack bullets.</li>
<li>Automatic attacks can now be triggered even at a slight distance away.</li>
<li>Raised Special attack power.</li>
<li>Increased attack detection for Special bullets.</li>
</ul>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Gooey</td>
<td>
<p>Affected modes: City Trial/Air Ride</p>
<ul>
<li>Lengthened Special range.</li>
<li>Increased attack detection for Special bullets.</li>
</ul>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Cappy</td>
<td>
<p>Affected modes: City Trial/Air Ride</p>
<ul>
<li>Increased durability of the mushroom cap.</li>
</ul>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Scarfy</td>
<td>
<p>Affected modes: City Trial/Air Ride</p>
<ul>
<li>Raised HP.</li>
<li>Raised Top Speed, Offense, and Defense while in angry state.</li>
<li>Lowered the amount of damage required to reach angry state.</li>
<li>Shortened time before you can become angry again after angry state is lifted.</li>
<li>Increased attack power of explosion caused by Special.</li>
<li>Expanded Special attack range.</li>
</ul>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Susie</td>
<td>
<p>Affected modes: City Trial/Air Ride</p>
<ul>
<li>Raised HP.</li>
<li>Raised Defense while Special is triggered.</li>
</ul>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Noir Dedede</td>
<td>
<p>Affected modes: City Trial/Air Ride</p>
<ul>
<li>Raised Offense.</li>
<li>Raised Defense while Special is triggered.</li>
</ul>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>The performance of some machines has been adjusted.</p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<th>Machine name</th>
<th>Adjustment details</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Shadow Star</td>
<td>
<p>Affected modes: City Trial/Air Ride</p>
<ul>
<li>Strengthened deceleration when hitting a wall with Quick Spin.</li>
</ul>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Wagon Star</td>
<td>
<p>Affected modes: City Trial/Air Ride</p>
<ul>
<li>Weakened forward acceleration when driving while skidding sideways.</li>
<li>Strengthened acceleration from low to medium speeds during normal driving.</li>
</ul>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Jet Star</td>
<td>
<p>Affected modes: City Trial/Air Ride</p>
<ul>
<li>Strengthened deceleration when hitting a wall with Quick Spin.</li>
</ul>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Wheelie Bike</td>
<td>
<p>Affected mode: City Trial</p>
<ul>
<li>Raised initial Top Speed and Turn values.</li>
<li>Raised growth rate for Top Speed and Turn values.</li>
</ul>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Hop Star</td>
<td>
<p>Affected modes: All modes</p>
<ul>
<li>Increased fall speed after Boost Charging in midair.</li>
<li>Expanded the attack range of the stomp attack.</li>
<li>Raised attack power of the stomp attack.</li>
</ul>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Vampire Star</td>
<td>
<p>Affected modes: City Trial/Air Ride</p>
<ul>
<li>Strengthened deceleration when hitting a wall with Quick Spin.</li>
</ul>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Tank Star</td>
<td>
<p>Affected modes: City Trial/Air Ride</p>
<ul>
<li>Raised Top Speed on the ground.</li>
<li>Increased charging speed during drifting.</li>
<li>Made it easier to carry over fall speed on Perfect Landings.</li>
</ul>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Hydra</td>
<td>
<p>Affected mode: Air Ride</p>
<ul>
<li>Weakened deceleration when hitting other machines.</li>
</ul>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3 id="bug-fixes"><strong>Bug Fixes</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Improved communication stability during online play.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where an error would occur when trying to open the Gummies screen in the Collection menu while having a specific number of Gummies.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where, after unlocking the last task in a Checklist page by using an Open Block, receiving the completion checkmark, then returning to the Checklist after transitioning to another screen via a specific set of actions, the completion mark would disappear and the completion rewards could not be received.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where an error would occur when trying to enter a paddock while possessing a specific My Machine.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where some stat displays were not properly reflected on the Machine/Rider selection screen.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with Transform Star where, when changing modes when getting the boost of acceleration gained after defeating an enemy, the acceleration effect would immediately be lost.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with Transform Star where, when touching a dash zone while changing modes at the same time, the acceleration effect would occur twice.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where Copy Abilities would not be removed when Transform Star would enter a cannon while performing a Quick Spin.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with Bulk Star and Hydra where their Top Speed would drop when obtaining Weight.
<ul>
<li>For all machines, Top Speed increases when obtaining Weight.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where Gooey’s tongue would sometimes not stretch out and be unable to capture certain enemies.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where, when Chef Kawasaki or Gooey captured an enemy, the icon that displays after defeating an enemy would not be displayed.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the BGM for a paddock remained the same as the BGM for the main menu when paddock decorations were changing.</li>
<li>Fixed issues where communication errors or disconnections for certain players mid-Team Relay in paddocks would sometimes trigger phenomena like another player warping/the number of laps not being properly counted/the same player making two laps, etc.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a user’s camera settings during a Team Relay match in a paddock may not be reflected depending on the turn order.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where, when racing in a Team Relay match with an FP (figure player) in paddocks, the stats of the FP and the player going afterward may change depending on the turn order.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where headwear was not reflected during matches when riders were randomized.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where legendary-machine parts and some events would become fixed when playing City Trial continuously via Local Play.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where CPU levels were sometimes not reflected in CPU Group Settings in City Trial via Local Play.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue for Swerve Star under Machines in Lessons where you would sometimes fail even though you performed actions correctly.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where, when decals were placed near the center of a Winged Star machine when customizing it in the My Machine menu, the decal designs would partially deteriorate when that My Machine appeared in City Trial.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where, when joining a paddock after playing Free Run, it was sometimes possible to select a legendary machine on the Machine/Rider selection screen.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue in Cyberion Highway where the camera would sometimes not return to a normal state after leaving the area where riders become smaller.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue in Machine Passage where some players were not able to enter the cannon on the course if a communication error or disconnection occurred for certain players.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue in the Top Ride course Crystal where, if you hit a wall while gliding in the air at a specific location, you could unintentionally rotate approximately 90°.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where, when playing Top Ride with multiple people, other players were sometimes unable to switch control types when certain players had set a Name.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where, when playing Top Ride with multiple people, it would become impossible to switch to Free Control after P2 switched to Steer Control while a Name was set.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where, after obtaining the item Flare Bursts in City Trial, the effect would sometimes not disappear as expected.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue in City Trial where the camera would sometimes not return to a normal state after the effects of the Size Down item ended.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue in City Trial where the camera would sometimes not return to a normal state after getting off grind rails.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue in City Trial where, when completing a legendary machine while the effects of the No Charge item were active, the player would sometimes continue to be unable to charge.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue in City Trial where, when performing specific operations after obtaining the Wheel Copy Ability, the Copy Ability would sometimes become unable to be removed.</li>
<li>Fixed a rare issue in online City Trial matches where a rival’s machine would sometimes become inoperable after stealing it.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where, during replays where a player is retired in certain Stadium events, an error would display when trying to post the replay.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where, when playing the VS. Gigantes Stadium event during an online match with 16 players, an error would occur when transitioning to the results screen when Lololo &amp; Lalala came in 1st place.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Note</strong>: Replays from Ver. 1.2.0 and earlier are not compatible with Ver. 1.3.0. Convert replays you want to keep to video files by selecting Record on the playback settings screen within Cached Data and Data Replay before downloading the update. (Note: A microSD Express card is required to use this function.)</p>
<hr>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:193790,195283,194185 @ 1769512164 -->
<p>Will you be returning to the track to try out this latest update for Kirby Air Riders? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://en-americas-support.nintendo.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/68635/~/how-to-update-kirby-air-riders" rel="noopener" href="https://en-americas-support.nintendo.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/68635/~/how-to-update-kirby-air-riders">en-americas-support.nintendo.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/f162c976b6f872e775432c8b88d5ff98 @ 1769514304 --></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/kirby-air-riders-has-been-updated-to-version-1-3-0-here-are-the-full-patch-notes]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>