<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - www.nintendolife.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for www.nintendolife.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 17:18:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Community: Pokémon Turns 30 Soon - Send Us Your Pocket Monster Memories]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/community-pokemon-turns-30-soon-send-us-your-pocket-monster-memories</link>
            <guid>1435534</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="4b32181d91b66"><a title="Pokemon" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/4b32181d91b66/pokemon.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Zion Grassl / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>27th February marks the anniversary of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gameboy/pokemon_red_and_blue">Pokémon Red</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gameboy/pokemon_green">Green</a> in Japan, but this year's event is an extra special one: the Pokémon series is turning 30 years old.</p>
<p>Yes, that little RPG about catching cute and not-so-cute monsters and doing battle with your pals has been going for three entire decades. In that time, it's evolved from mere gaming phenomenon that rejuvenated interest in Nintendo's Game Boy seven years after it launched to the world's biggest media property.</p>
<p>'If in doubt, stick a Pikachu in/on it' probably <em>isn't</em> a mantra at The Pokémon Company, but you'd be forgiven for thinking it is, given the proliferation of that particular 'mon across every facet of the franchise. The series' success, though, goes well beyond the near-universal appeal of the electric yellow mega mouse who became its mascot.</p>
<p>Anyone who's <em>ever</em> been a Pokémon fan has a story that sticks in their mind; a particular Pocket Monster you caught and named, a story moment that stuck with you, a tense, skin-of-your-teeth battle you triumphed in, or a more personal memory about where you were in your own life's story while playing Pokémon.</p>
<p>Or maybe something outside the games entirely! With the anime, TCG, and the wider world of Pikachu and co., it's become so much more than <em>just</em> the games.</p>
<figure data-uuid="2f551e2f5c031"><a title="Pokemon" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/2f551e2f5c031/pokemon.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Gemma Smith / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>With the anniversary approaching, we're asking you to send in your Pokémon memories for a special feature we'll publish in a few weeks. Over 30 years, we're positive you've got <em>hundreds</em> of memories you hold near and dear, and we'd love to highlight them on the site.</p>
<p>Now, Red/Green/Blue/Yellow recollections are more than welcome, but we want to hear from you <em>whenever</em> you jumped on the Pokéwagon, whether you were there with your DMG-01 Day One, hopped aboard with a dual-screen console, got into the series more recently on Switch, or anywhere in between.</p>
<p>If you'd like to contribute and be in with a chance of having your memory shared, check out the submission instructions below. Remember, short and sweet is the name of the game! (Actually, <strong>Pokémon Short &amp; Sweet</strong>... y'know, that's not bad.)</p>
<h2>Nintendo Life Pokémon Memories submission guidelines</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>100 words, maximum</strong> - We'd like to feature as many as possible in the finished article, so please keep things concise! (Remember, 100 is the <em>max</em> - it can be shorter!)</li>
<li><strong>Don't go crazy with multiple submissions</strong> - You've likely got many, many memories from playing this series, but please just pick the best one.</li>
<li><strong>Remember, we can't pick 'em all!</strong> - We imagine we'll have a <em>lot</em> to choose from, so please understand if yours doesn't feature in the finished article. We will be reading 'em all, though!</li>
<li><strong>Submissions close on Friday 20th February 2026</strong> - Make sure to get your message sent before the weekend arrives!</li>
</ul>
<h2>How to send a Pokémon Memory</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Head to Nintendo Life's</strong> <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/contact?subject=pokemon"><strong>Contact page</strong></a> <strong>and select the subject "Pokémon Memories"</strong> from the drop-down menu (it's already done for you in the link above). Type your name, email, and beautifully crafted submission into the appropriate box, hit send, and boom — you're done!</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p><em>We're looking forward to reading about your memories. We've got lots of things planned leading up to 'Pokémon Day 2026', so keep an eye out for Pokémoaaar soon.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/community-pokemon-turns-30-soon-send-us-your-pocket-monster-memories]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Want To Play MGS As An Octopus? Darwin's Paradox's Free Demo Can Help]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/want-to-play-mgs-as-an-octopus-darwins-paradoxs-free-demo-can-help</link>
            <guid>1435504</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>The full game inks onto Switch 2 in April</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Well, Konami certainly had a heck of a State of Play yesterday, didn't it? We got some big hitting names making their grand return, but also one or two new IPs, one of which we already knew about — <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/darwins-paradox">Darwin's Paradox!</a></p>
<p>Co-developed with French studio ZDT Studio, the unusual octopus-starring platformer is coming to Switch 2 and now has a release date of <strong>2nd April 2026</strong>.</p>
<p>But that's not the big news here at <em>all</em>, oh no. You can download a free demo on the eShop now and experience one of the game's levels, which is just one big <strong>Metal Gear Solid</strong> reference.</p>
<p>Yep, a stealthy octopus. Who knew?! And Darwin even gets a Snake-inspired skin in the demo, which will be available in the full game as an Easter Egg.</p>

<p>If this is your first time hearing about Darwin's Paradox, let's fill you in. Inspired by big-budget animated movies, Darwin is an octopus who is suddenly swept away from his ocean home by a beam of light. In his adventure to make it home, Darwin will uncover a conspiracy that could threaten the world, meaning he's the one who may have to save humanity.</p>
<p>Darwin's Paradox blends platforming and puzzle-solving where you'll get to explore creative worlds and meet colourful characters. It's something pretty different from Konami, and we're excited to check out the demo.</p>
<p>The game was originally planned for Switch 1, but the team moved development over <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/konamis-octopus-platformer-swims-onto-switch-2-next-year-while-switch-1-version-goes-mia">to focus exclusively on a Switch 2 release</a>. Perhaps the right move given the level of detail we've seen from the trailers so far.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Have you checked out the Darwin's Paradox demo yet? Looking forward to the full release? Let us know in the comments.</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:193392 @ 1771002979 --></section></article><div><p>Alana has been with Nintendo Life since 2022, and while RPGs are her first love, Nintendo is a close second. She enjoys nothing more than overthinking battle strategies, characters, and stories. She also wishes she was a Sega air pirate.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/AlanaHagues"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/alanahagues.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('AlanaHagues');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/want-to-play-mgs-as-an-octopus-darwins-paradoxs-free-demo-can-help]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gallery: We've Got The Virtual Boy Accessory For Nintendo Switch Online]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/gallery-weve-got-the-virtual-boy-accessory-for-nintendo-switch-online</link>
            <guid>1435411</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="6087ea604cbd1"><a title="Virtual Boy 1" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/6087ea604cbd1/virtual-boy-1.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Ollie Reynolds / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>Well, what a lovely surprise! Our local Royal Mail representative knocked on the door today and delivered a curious-looking box, and it turns out that it's none other than the Virtual Boy accessory for Nintendo Switch Online!</p>
<p>Yes, it seems like a whole bunch of people – in the UK, at least – are receiving their retail Virtual Boys early, and so we were lucky enough to get our very own purchased unit.</p>
<p>We've already gone <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/previews/five-takeaways-from-my-time-with-virtual-boy-on-nintendo-switch-online">hands-on with the peripheral and app</a> over at Nintendo of Europe in Frankfurt, so you should definitely check that out if you want a few thoughts on the experience itself.</p><div><figure data-videoid="aHspT9aiKKE" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aHspT9aiKKE?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytaHspT9aiKKE" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/aHspT9aiKKE?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aHspT9aiKKE?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed40228bvuptli&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>842k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>

<p>Of course, we've still got a few days to wait until the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/virtual_boy_-_nintendo_classics">Virtual Boy - Nintendo Classics</a> app launches (<strong>17th February</strong>), so we can't really get a whole lot of use out of the headset just yet. What we have been able to do, mind you, is see what <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/super_mario_odyssey">Super Mario Odyssey</a>'s VR mode looks like, and yeah, it's pretty wild stuff.</p>
<p>The main point is that it works – to a degree. Booting up the VR mode in Odyssey lets you view stages just like you could with the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/nintendo_labo_toy-con_04_vr_kit">Labo VR</a> set; just pick up the Virtual Boy and move your head around, job done.</p>
<p>The main issue is that you can't really control Mario at the same time, so unless you're willing to fashion a really big rubber band around your head to keep the headset locked in place, it's not an ideal solution.</p>
<p>It's also worth pointing out here that Nintendo offered a statement to confirm that <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/nintendo-clarifies-that-labo-vr-will-not-work-with-virtual-boy-for-switch-online">Labo VR won't be officially compatible with Virtual Boy</a>, but given these limited tests, we're of the mind that it will at least function to a certain degree. We'll be able to confirm one way or the other when the app itself launches.</p>

<p>As standard, the Virtual Boy comes with a red lens filter, which means that Odyssey had this weird, almost retro-inspired presentation clearly geared toward the upcoming NSO app. It's actually quite cool in practice, but we should note that you can quite easily remove the red lens from the headset, leaving you with a pair of clear lenses that look remarkably similar to Labo's.</p>
<p>With the red filter off, Odyssey looks just like it does when played with Labo, but again, moving your head around while controlling Mario unfortunately isn't really possible with the Virtual Boy.</p>
<p>Otherwise, it's, well... a Virtual Boy! I never owned the original, given that it never came out in the UK, so I can't really comment on the feel or heft of the thing, but in terms of presentation at least, it's a dead ringer.</p>
<p>It's pretty easy to lift the visor up to slot the Switch 2 inside, and the set also comes with an added bit of plastic to allow your original Switch to fit. Similarly, although removing the red lenses took a little bit of force at first, it was very easy to do once it's been taken out at least once.</p>


<p>We'll have a lot more coverage for you when the Virtual Boy app drops on Nintendo Switch Online next week. For now, we're going to clear a bunch of space off our office desk and display with pride.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:196665,196739 @ 1771000207 -->
<p><em>Have you received your own Virtual Boy yet? Will you be ordering one anytime soon? Let us know with a comment.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/gallery-weve-got-the-virtual-boy-accessory-for-nintendo-switch-online]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>