<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:55:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Daemon X Machina: Titanic Scion Lands New Paid DLC & Free Update Today]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/daemon-x-machina-titanic-scion-lands-new-paid-dlc-and-free-update-today</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/daemon-x-machina-titanic-scion-lands-new-paid-dlc-free-update-today.1353556/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Here are the full patch notes</p>
</section></header><div><section>

<p>Shortly after launch back in September, Marvelous revealed the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/daemon-x-machina-titanic-scion-roadmap-outlined">2025 roadmap</a> for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/daemon-x-machina-titanic-scion">Daemon x Machina: Titanic Scion</a>, and today, we've arrived at another stop on the journey.</p>
<p>The mech action/adventure has today landed its 'Into the Abyss' paid DLC, a story expansion that sees you sent out to explore an all-new map area, Survey Zone: Locus Initi. You can expect to find new enemies, new gear, and a whole new Axiom base to get your head around.</p>
<p>The 'Into the Abyss' DLC is now available to all those with the Digital Deluxe or Super Deluxe versions of the game. Alternatively, you can purchase the expansion separately on the <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/en-gb/DLC/Daemon-X-Machina-Titanic-Scion-Into-the-Abyss-2860504.html">Switch eShop</a> for <strong>£13.49 / $14.99</strong>. Do note that you'll need to have made it past Chapter 18 'Investigate the Facility's Depths' in the base game to see any of this bonus content.</p>

<p>But it's not just paid news for Titanic Scion today, since the game has also landed a free update to bump things up to ver. 1.2. There are a bunch of pesky bugs targeted by this one, as outlined in the full patch below (via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1342490/Daemon_X_Machina_Titanic_Scion/">Steam</a>).</p>
<h2>Daemon X Machina: Titanic Scion Ver. 1.2</h2>
<p><strong>Bug Fixes:</strong><br>
・Fixed an issue where the game sometimes could not be booted when the Online setting was On upon carrying over save data from the demo version.<br>
・Fixed an issue where personal progress would sometimes be corrupted after multiplayer.<br>
・Fixed an issue where the Rematch Simulator would sometimes become unusable after an abnormality occurred.<br>
・Fixed an issue where progress would sometimes be corrupted after playing the story mission "Assault the Axiom Towers (Versus Gaze)" in multiplayer.<br>
・Fixed an issue with the Rematch Simulator where sometimes after the battle/event "Battle Zeruchroar," the number of pages of the Reward screen changes.<br>
・Fixed an issue where sometimes patterns and decals that should be obtainable as a reward for your mercenary rank cannot be obtained.<br>
・Fixed an issue where sometimes the log could not be obtained after completing the mission "Subject: Messed-up factory!".<br>
・Fixed an issue where sometimes during the mission "Investigate the Facility's Depths", the battery ran out and a gate could not be opened.<br>
・Fixed an issue where the game would sometimes stop upon reloading a shotgun.<br>
・Fixed an issue where while playing "Escort Raven to the Base" in multiplayer, a retry sometimes leads to the screen fading to black and never returning.<br>
・Fixed an issue where when trying to join a party in multiplayer, the user sometimes gets the message "Cannot join because the party's privacy settings have changed." and cannot join.<br>
・Weapons that were only available through shops can now be obtained in the field after a certain point.<br>
・Fixed an issue where the number of foes grabbed was not counted when armed with certain weapons.<br>
・Fixed an issue where sometimes "Ambrosia" became undefeatable.<br>
・Fixed an issue where when the mission "Subject: Immortalization Testing Facility?" is completed on a certain route, the music data "Assault Impact" cannot be obtained.<br>
・Fixed some of the music data contents that were swapped.<br>
・Fixed an issue where development data comparison with inventory is disabled when equipped with a Gun Vambrace.<br>
・Fixed an issue where only the visual effect while stunned by Gaze's "Blood Bind" disappears when some Grand Entrance effects occur.<br>
・Fixed an issue in a rematch mission where "Dreadnought RT: β" would stay underground and never come out.<br>
・Fixed an issue in a rematch mission where "Dreadnought RT: β" would jump on the player at high speed.<br>
・Fixed an issue in the Sovereign Axiom Special Facility where sometimes "Lapis Lacrima" would go underground during a battle and never come out.<br>
・Fixed an issue where some mutations show when changing armor display in the hangar, even with mutations turned off.<br>
・Fixed an issue where the player's legs disappear when changing armor display in the hangar, with mutations turned off.<br>
・Fixed an issue where NPCs could not be rebooted as part of the effect of Grand Entrance "Encore."<br>
・Fixed an issue where reboots occurred as an unintended effect of a Grand Entrance.<br>
・Fixed multiple other bugs.</p>
<hr>
<p>We had a perfectly fine time with Titanic Scion when it arrived on Switch 2 earlier this year, but felt that it was let down by its performance issues, which made for a "janky experience in places, with mushy controls and limp feedback". Let's hope that this patch can help move things in the right direction.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:187024 @ 1763123402 -->
<p><em>Will you be picking up this paid DLC? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://store.steampowered.com/app/1342490/Daemon_X_Machina_Titanic_Scion/" rel="noopener" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1342490/Daemon_X_Machina_Titanic_Scion/">store.steampowered.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/98c5dede75c104fb98c94126b50ac703 @ 1763122646 --></div></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/daemon-x-machina-titanic-scion-lands-new-paid-dlc-and-free-update-today]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Today! App Update Adds A New Widget And News Filter]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/nintendo-today-app-update-adds-a-new-widget-and-news-filter</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-today-app-update-adds-a-new-widget-and-news-filter.1353505/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Oooh, exciting</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure data-uuid="88f5d2778a233"><a title="Nintendo Today!" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/88f5d2778a233/nintendo-today.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure><p>Stop the press, because the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/mobile/nintendo_today">Nintendo Today!</a> app has been updated, folks.</p>
<p>Yes, the 2.1.0 patch is here, and it adds... well, a couple of things. First up, we've got a new, smaller calendar app that no longer takes up the whole ruddy home screen, so that's nice if you like that sort of thing.</p>
<p>Second is a new filter that lets you streamline the news feed according to specific characters. You better believe we'll be laser-focused on anything to do with Samus for the next few weeks!</p>
<p>So let's check out the official patch notes:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Added Calendar Widget Sizes</strong></p>
<p>- Added a small widget you can use to check the weekly calendar.</p>
<p><strong>News and Browsing History Filtering</strong></p>
<p>- News and browsing history can now be filtered by character.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>So yeah, that's yer lot.</p>
<p>Nintendo has also recently released a separate app for its storefront, featuring games, accessories, and more. With the Nintendo Music and the Nintendo Switch apps, this is now totals four. Maybe it's time to combine these together in some way, Nintendo..?</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-mobile/related-articles:193440,193555 @ 1763121612 -->
<p><em>Are you using the Nintendo Today! app on a daily basis? How are you finding it? Let us know with a comment.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/nintendo-today-app-update-adds-a-new-widget-and-news-filter]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Story Of Seasons: Grand Bazaar Update Arrives On Switch 1 & 2, Here Are The Patch Notes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/new-story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-update-arrives-on-switch-1-and-2-here-are-the-patch-notes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-update-arrives-on-switch-1-2-here-are-the-patch-notes.1353493/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Bonus bingo rewards!</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="185d28bfe6480"><a title="Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/185d28bfe6480/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Marvelous</em></figcaption></figure><p>Marvelous has released another update for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/story_of_seasons_grand_bazaar">Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar</a>, boosting the game up to ver. 1.2.0 and adding in some cute new bonuses to boot.</p>
<p>The biggie this time is a new batch of 'Happy Bingo' rewards (the minigame introduced in the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaars-latest-update-is-now-live-here-are-the-full-patch-notes">last update</a>), which are all focused on some particularly stylish sushi chefs. If you've been thinking that your Grand Bazaar has been missing a little bit of shrimp sashimi, these are the ones for you.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, there's your usual handful of bug fixes and balancing adjustments to keep the game running smoothly. The full patch notes were shared on the game's <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2508780?emclan=103582791475080044&amp;emgid=627816563452412154">Steam</a> page, and we have gathered them together for you to check out below.</p><div><figure data-videoid="ylLGp-DIVlY" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ylLGp-DIVlY?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytylLGp-DIVlY" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ylLGp-DIVlY?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ylLGp-DIVlY?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed601436imsgvw&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>838k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<h2>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar Ver. 1.2.0</h2>
<p>・Added Deluxe Cards Vol. 2 to Happy Bingo<br>
・Balancing adjustments for some fishing rods<br>
・Added recipes for processing tea leaves at the Yellow Windmill<br>
・Fixed issue where warping home with the Travel Stone while triggering the initial Happy Bingo event would result in a progress blocker<br>
・Fixed issue where picking up items would occasionally result in a progress blocker<br>
・Fixed issue preventing bazaar donations and rank ups from functioning properly under select conditions<br>
・Other minor bug fixes</p>

<hr>
<p>We had a great time with Grand Bazaar when it arrived on Switch 2 earlier this year, and we were particular fans of how gosh darn charming the whole thing is: "Marvelous has really taken a lot of time to perfect the gameplay loop of Grand Bazaar, and that polish has also spilled out into the characters and the visuals." You'll find our full <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-nintendo-switch-2-edition">review</a> below.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:185763 @ 1763122165 -->
<p><em>What do you make of this latest update? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2508780?emclan=103582791475080044&amp;amp;emgid=627816563452412154" rel="noopener" href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2508780?emclan=103582791475080044&amp;emgid=627816563452412154">store.steampowered.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-info/64cc4e63dd52336db84783c100d9f5d9 @ 1763122165 --></div></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/new-story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-update-arrives-on-switch-1-and-2-here-are-the-patch-notes]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trails In The Sky 2nd Chapter Scheduled For 2026 Release]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/trails-in-the-sky-2nd-chapter-scheduled-for-2026-release</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/trails-in-the-sky-2nd-chapter-scheduled-for-2026-release.1353433/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>No platforms have been confirmed just yet</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="99eb0d3f7d8c4"><a title="Trails in the Sky SC" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/99eb0d3f7d8c4/trails-in-the-sky-sc.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nihon Falcom</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>In case you missed it, the recently released game <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/trails-in-the-sky-1st-chapter-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Trails in the Sky 1st Chapter</a> teased the second chapter.</p>
<p>Now, in an update via Falcom's <a href="https://www.falcom.co.jp/ir-data/20251112-1">latest financial report for September 2025</a>, the company has reportedly locked in a release window for the remake of The Legend of Heroes: Trails in the Sky SC – with the game scheduled to arrive by the fiscal year ending <strong>September 2026</strong>.</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/if-trails-in-the-sky-1st-chapter-doesnt-get-a-sequel-our-fans-will-go-youve-got-to-be-kidding-me-nihon-falcom-ceo-on-future-releases/">recent interview</a>, the Falcom president Toshihiro Kondo mentioned how a remake of the second entry had to happen. Once again, here's what he had to say (<a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/news/2025/09/second-trails-in-the-sky-remake-all-but-confirmed-by-falcom-boss">via Push Square</a>):</p><div><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytC1rrCdi_XjA" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067plmwzt&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>838k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<blockquote>
<p>"If we didn’t follow up with a remake of Trails in the Sky SC, people would go, ‘You’ve got to be kidding me.’ So, we do want to do a remake along the lines of Trails in the Sky 2nd Chapter."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>As our <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/news/2025/11/highly-anticipated-rpg-remake-trails-in-the-sky-2nd-chapter-confirmed-for-2026-release">colleagues at Push Square also note</a>, "the second Trails in the Sky game is widely considered to be one of the franchise's best instalments. It's got a gut-punching story and some fantastic character development — alongside some of the most memorable boss encounters in the series".</p>
<p>And without getting too far ahead, Kondo has previously stated how anything beyond this (<a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/news/2025/09/second-trails-in-the-sky-remake-all-but-confirmed-by-falcom-boss">as in a remake of the third instalment</a>) will likely come down to "fan demand". For now, no specific platforms have been confirmed for the second chapter just yet, so when there's an official announcement, we'll let you know.</p>
<p>The 1st Chapter was released on the Switch and Switch 2 on 19th September 2025, and since then, the Switch 2 version has received some "image quality and performance settings". There's also a demo you can download from the eShop.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:187947,187286,192398 @ 1763123390 -->
<p>How has your experience been with Trails in the Sky 1st Chapter on the Switch and Switch 2 so far? Ready for the second entry? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/trails-in-the-sky-2nd-chapter-to-launch-by-september-2026#:~:text=Falcom%20will%20release%20Trails%20in,fiscal%20year%20ended%20September%202025." rel="noopener" href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/trails-in-the-sky-2nd-chapter-to-launch-by-september-2026#:~:text=Falcom%20will%20release%20Trails%20in,fiscal%20year%20ended%20September%202025.">gematsu.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/a4ccdefe9c814d166c019a438fa557e3 @ 1763122433 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/trails-in-the-sky-2nd-chapter-scheduled-for-2026-release]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>