<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 22:06:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tales Of Arise Comes To Switch 2 In May, Includes Beyond The Horizon DLC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/tales-of-arise-comes-to-switch-2-in-may-includes-beyond-the-horizon-dlc</link>
            <guid>1427482</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Arisen for a new console</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>The <strong>Tales of</strong> series is on a bit of a roll at the moment, and Switch 2 owners have something to celebrate, as <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/tales-of-arise-beyond-the-dawn-edition">Tales of Arise - Beyond the Dawn Edition</a> is coming to the console on <strong>22nd May 2026</strong>. it's getting both a physical and digital release.</p>
<p>For those not in the know, <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/tales_of_arise">Tales of Arise</a> is the most-recent entry in Bandai Namco's action RPG series; it came out on other platforms back in 2021, with the <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/tales_of_arise_beyond_the_dawn">Beyond the Dawn</a> expansion following in 2023. The Switch 2 release will include the expansion as-standard.</p>
<p>Interestingly, this is the first Tales of game to get a native Switch 2 version — even <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/tales_of_berseria_remastered">Tales of Berseria Remastered</a>, which comes out at the end of the month, is only on Switch 1. But Tales of Arise also isn't part of the recent slate of remasters, making this a straight port of the critically-acclaimed game.</p>
<p>If you're curious, here are some more details on the game courtesy of Bandai Namco:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Tales of ARISE</strong> immerses players into a conflict between two worlds. For 300 years, <strong>Rena</strong> has ruled over <strong>Dahna</strong>, pillaging the planet’s resources and stripping its people of dignity and freedom.</p>
<p>The story begins with two individuals, born in different worlds, each looking to change their fate and create a new future. Featuring a diverse cast of characters, an intuitive and rewarding combat system, and a captivating story set in a lush world, <strong>Tales of ARISE</strong> delivers a first-class <strong>JRPG</strong> experience.</p>
<p>Players will follow <strong>Alphen</strong>, a masked amnesic man who can’t feel pain as he encounters <strong>Shionne</strong>, the cursed woman that inflicts agony upon everything she touches. They will both get to know each other and meet a varied cast of allies to take on the Renan Lords, powerful foes, in order to free <strong>Dahna</strong>.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>We've had four Tales games on Switch 1 and Switch 2 between the start of 2025 and 2026, with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/tales_of_graces_f_remastered">Tales of Graces f Remastered</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/tales_of_xillia_remastered">Tales of Xillia Remastered</a>, and the aforementioned Tales of Berseria Remastered and Tales of Arise. Where will the series take us next on Nintendo's hybrid console? We'll have to wait and see.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Are you looking forward to Tales of Arise on Switch 2? Take hold of fate in the comments and let us know.</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:120597,158029 @ 1770327007 --></section></article><div><p>Alana has been with Nintendo Life since 2022, and while RPGs are her first love, Nintendo is a close second. She enjoys nothing more than overthinking battle strategies, characters, and stories. She also wishes she was a Sega air pirate.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/AlanaHagues"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/alanahagues.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('AlanaHagues');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/tales-of-arise-comes-to-switch-2-in-may-includes-beyond-the-horizon-dlc]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pro-Evolution Soccer Successor 'eFootball' Is Getting A Switch 2 Exclusive Spin-Off]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/pro-evolution-soccer-successor-efootball-is-getting-a-switch-2-exclusive-spin-off</link>
            <guid>1427458</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Just in time for the World Cup</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Konami had a pretty presence during today's Nintendo Direct Partner Showcase. But Bomberman wasn't the only franchise making its appearance on Switch 2, as Konami announced <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/efootball-kick-off">eFootball: Kick-Off!</a>, which will be exclusive to Nintendo' newest console when it launches <strong>this summer</strong>.</p>
<p>Amazingly, this is the first time <strong>eFootball</strong> has appeared on a Nintendo console since it started in 2021, but the series has a much-bigger history. It's actually an evolution of Konami's iconic footy franchise, <strong>Pro Evolution Soccer,</strong> known as Winning Eleven in Japan.</p>
<p>And while this isn't the free-to-play mainline game, eFootball: Kick-Off! promises plenty of content, with a World Tour mode that allows you to create your own club and team, an International Cup mode (which is coming a DLC), Beginner-friendly modes, and local and online play.</p>
<p>Here's a rundown of the game from Konami:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Game Modes &amp; Features</strong></p>
<p><strong>-</strong> <strong>World Tour:</strong> Establish your own club team and compete in tournaments across the globe. Win matches to acquire players from defeated opponents or use currency earned through play to sign legendary footballers. Build your original team and aim to conquer the world.</p>
<p><strong>-</strong> <strong>International Cup:</strong> The world’s most prestigious international competition returns once every four years. Take charge of your national team and compete on football’s grandest stage, where history is written and global supremacy is decided.<br>
<em>*The ‘International Cup’ mode is scheduled for release as additional downloadable content.</em></p>
<p><strong>-</strong> <strong>Beginner-Friendly Modes:</strong> Jump into fun and accessible experiences such as 6-on-6 football, designed to create fast-paced action and plenty of goal-scoring opportunities. The Rank system evaluates performance and allows players to naturally progress as they improve.</p>
<p><strong>-</strong> <strong>Local &amp; Online Play:</strong> Enjoy matches anytime, anywhere, playing solo, challenge friends via local wireless, or test your skills against players worldwide in online competitions.</p>
<p>Built specifically for Nintendo Switch™ 2, eFootball™ Kick-Off! features responsive controls and pick-up-and-play gameplay that welcomes newcomers while still rewarding smart tactics and competitive mastery.</p></blockquote><blockquote>
<p>As the eyes of the football world turn to North America this summer, Nintendo players can find their own path to victory. Big goals, dramatic moments, and pure football fun define this new chapter.</p>
</blockquote>


<hr>
<p><em>Are you a PES fan? Will you be grabbing Kick-Off! ahead of the World Cup? Let us know in the comments</em>.</p></section></article><div><p>Alana has been with Nintendo Life since 2022, and while RPGs are her first love, Nintendo is a close second. She enjoys nothing more than overthinking battle strategies, characters, and stories. She also wishes she was a Sega air pirate.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/AlanaHagues"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/alanahagues.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('AlanaHagues');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/pro-evolution-soccer-successor-efootball-is-getting-a-switch-2-exclusive-spin-off]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Disney Dreamlight Valley Will Be Part Of Your Switch 2 World This March]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/disney-dreamlight-valley-will-be-part-of-your-switch-2-world-this-march</link>
            <guid>1427377</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>It's a free upgrade for Switch 1 owners</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Gameloft's smash hit Disney life sim, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/disney_dreamlight_valley">Disney Dreamlight Valley</a>, is getting a native <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/disney-dreamlight-valley-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</a> on 25th March 2026.</p>
<p>The game briefly popped up during today's Nintendo Direct Partner Showcase as part of the sizzle reel, confirming the tease that the developer dropped <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/its-official-disney-dreamlight-valley-is-getting-a-switch-2-version">last summer</a> along with a date.</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://disneydreamlightvalley.com/news/NintendoSwitchUpdate2026">blog post</a>, Gameloft shared some Switch 2 gameplay footage, featuring a character walking through the Valley and doing a bit of decorating.</p>
<p>In the post, the developer detailed that the game will feel "smoother and easier to enjoy" on the newer console. Improvements come in the form of better frame rates, higher resolution, faster load times, and a much higher item limit of 6,000.</p>
<p>Plus, if you already own the game on Switch, the upgrade will be completely free. That's pretty handy.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>have you played Disney Dreamlight Valley on Switch? Looking forward to the Switch 2 Edition? Let us know in the comments.</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:183691,137152 @ 1770328117 --></section></article><div><p>Alana has been with Nintendo Life since 2022, and while RPGs are her first love, Nintendo is a close second. She enjoys nothing more than overthinking battle strategies, characters, and stories. She also wishes she was a Sega air pirate.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/AlanaHagues"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/alanahagues.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('AlanaHagues');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/disney-dreamlight-valley-will-be-part-of-your-switch-2-world-this-march]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>