<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 09:59:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Check Out This Extended New Systems Trailer For Everybody's Golf Hotshots]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/check-out-this-extended-new-systems-trailer-for-everybodys-golf-hotshots</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/check-out-this-extended-new-systems-trailer-for-everybodys-golf-hotshots.1228773/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Wacky golf, world tour, and more...</p>
</section></header><div><section>

<p>As we reported just a little while ago, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/everybodys-golf-hot-shots-brings-the-par-tee-to-switch-this-september">Everybody's Golf will be swinging onto Nintendo Switch</a> this September 5th in the form of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/everybodys_golf_hot_shots">Everybody's Golf Hotshots</a>.</p>
<p>Following on from the reveal of the official release date, Bandai Namco has now dropped a juicy video showing almost five whole minutes of gameplay. You can check out the trailer above, and we have to say, it's all looking pretty much as expected for a series that certainly has its own unique thing going on.</p>
<p>Here's some delicious PR deets from Bandai Namco to tell us even more!</p><p><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><a id="yt-2" title="Play" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C1rrCdi_XjA"></a><figcaption>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>824k</span></a></figcaption><figcaption><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C1rrCdi_XjA">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></figcaption></figure></p>
<ul>
<li><em><strong>Tons of Customization</strong> - Customize stats, clubs and balls to match every character’s play style</em></li>
<li><em><strong>The Largest Roster</strong> – With a series-leading 25+ playable characters available, build up character loyalty to unlock new shots, including spin shots, homing shots and character-specific special shots.</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Caddie</strong> <strong>Support</strong> - Team up with caddies to get detailed play tips, support skills, and more.</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Challenge Mode</strong> Join tournaments in solo play to fight to the top! Unlock more characters, scenarios and even bigger tournaments to become the ultimate golfer.</em></li>
<li><em><strong>World Tour</strong> – Spanning 10 regions across the globe, discover charming character interactions unique to each player.</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Wacky Golf</strong> – This brand new mode brings chaos to the course with obstacles, challenges, and more in either solo or multiplayer mode, including Colorful, Scramble, Survival Golf and Dokkan Golf modes.</em></li>
</ul>
<p>Of course, Everybody's Golf Hotshots has raised a few eyebrows lately after its Steam page disclosed the minor detail that <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/news/2025/06/hot-shots-golf-fans-fume-at-use-of-generative-ai-in-ps5-revival">some of its background foliage is created using generative AI</a>, which is <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/smash-bros-director-sakurai-laments-unsustainable-aaa-game-dev-discusses-ai-and-uncertainty">certainly a hot topic of debate at the moment</a> (and not a good look, in all honesty),so it's up to you to decide where the line is drawn on that particular aspect of this one.</p>
<p>One thing we don't get any news on here, unfortunately, is whether or not we can expect any kind of Switch 2 version, but perhaps that's something for further down the line. We'll keep you posted!</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Looking forward to some Everybody's Golf Hot Shots on Switch? Be sure to swing by and let us know.</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:183127,180131,100045 @ 1750929302 -->
</section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.gamespress.com/TEE-UP-AND-PRE-ORDER-EVERYBODYS-GOLF-HOT-SHOTS-ON-NINTENDO-SWITCH-AND-" rel="noopener" href="https://www.gamespress.com/TEE-UP-AND-PRE-ORDER-EVERYBODYS-GOLF-HOT-SHOTS-ON-NINTENDO-SWITCH-AND-">gamespress.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-info/c36ac8a0a4edc354b409107b746c00ef @ 1750929901 --></div></article><div><p>PJ is a staff writer across Pure Xbox and Nintendo Life. He's been playing video games pretty much nonstop since the early 1980s, and enjoys boring people with tedious stories about how long ago that really is.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/PJOReilly"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/pjoreilly.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('PJOReilly');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/check-out-this-extended-new-systems-trailer-for-everybodys-golf-hotshots]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fans Reckon Nintendo Has "Killed" Mario Kart World With Its Latest Update]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/fans-reckon-nintendo-has-killed-mario-kart-world-with-its-latest-update</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fans-reckon-nintendo-has-killed-mario-kart-world-with-its-latest-update.1228761/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Ready for an intermission?</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Nintendo's latest update for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a> is now live, and the main change it's brought comes via the following patch note:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Adjusted courses selected in “Random” when selecting next course in a wireless “VS Race.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Okay, so what does this mean? Well, prior to the update, selecting a standard race when competing online would give you the option to choose either an intermission race from a set selection of three courses, or choose something at random. The random option would often ditch the intermission setup in favour of a standard 3-lap race around one of the game's excellent themed courses.</p>
<p>So if you happen to see the vast majority of players choosing 'random' when selecting a course, this is why.</p>
<p>The update has changed this, and according to many fans, it's proven to be a bit of a slap in the face. Basically, Nintendo is now doubling down on the intermission races, meaning you begin the race on a rolling start and drive across the roads toward the selected track. So while it <em>is</em> still possible to land a standard 3-lap race, the probability of doing so has plummeted.</p>
<p>So yeah, fans aren't particularly happy with the update, as demonstrated in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@TWD98">TWD98</a>'s YouTube video above. Folks are also voicing their concerns over on <a href="https://famiboards.com/threads/mario-kart-world-st-drift-of-the-wild.13952/page-50">Famiboards</a>, with user CoralSensei4 stating "I was genuinely having fun playing this game and perfecting the three lap tracks for online and this just ruined all of that practice".</p>
<p>Our very own community user <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/mario-kart-world-has-been-updated-to-version-1-1-2-here-are-the-full-patch-notes#comment8710259">Ade117</a> echoed this sentiment in our recent update article and said "What a downer of an update. I prefer to play 3 laps around a track, but Nintendo wants that to be as difficult as possible to do online".</p>
<p>Famiboards member hushh went one step further and said "Well that was basically a waste of money I guess. Won't touch this game until this tone deaf and idiotic decision is fixed".</p>
<p>We've no doubt Nintendo will continue to apply updates to Mario Kart World in the coming days, weeks, months, and even years. Here's hoping it takes feedback on board and makes standard 3-lap races an option for online play again.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:184405,184298 @ 1750930351 -->
<p><em>What do you make of Nintendo's latest update for Mario Kart World? Leave a comment with your thoughts down below.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/fans-reckon-nintendo-has-killed-mario-kart-world-with-its-latest-update]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tetris 99's New Maximus Cup Sees The Return Of Four Nintendo Themes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/tetris-99s-new-maximus-cup-sees-the-return-of-four-nintendo-themes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tetris-99s-new-maximus-cup-sees-the-return-of-four-nintendo-themes.1228710/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Try it out on the Switch 2 now</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure><a title="The Legend of Zelda: Skyward Sword" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/37e5fb9d4b1f5/the-legend-of-zelda-skyward-sword.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure><p>To mark the 47th Maximus Cup in the Switch Online battle royale <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/tetris_99">Tetris 99</a>, Nintendo will be revisiting multiple themes from tomorrow onwards. This also happens to be the first cup event for the Switch game since the arrival of the Switch 2.</p>
<p>Round one will kick off with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/super_mario_bros_wonder">Super Mario Bros. Wonder</a> and will be followed by <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/splatoon_3">Splatoon 3</a> (and the Expansion Pass paid DLC), <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pikmin_4">Pikmin 4</a>, and last but not least <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/legend_of_zelda_skyward_sword_hd">The Legend of Zelda: Skyward Sword HD</a>.</p>
<p>This time round you'll only need 20 points to earn each theme. This will once again kick off on <strong>27th June 2025</strong> and will run until the end of the month.</p><p><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067opyjml&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><figcaption>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>824k</span></a></figcaption><figcaption><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C1rrCdi_XjA">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></figcaption></figure></p>

<p>And in case you're wondering, Tetris 99 (and its online mode) can be played on the Switch 2. According to the official store page listing, it's 1.9GB download (which is the same as the file size listed for the Switch version).</p>
<p>Super Mario Bros. Wonder and Splatoon 3 have also recently received updates for the Switch 2.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:183800,183259 @ 1750928579 -->
<p>Will you be participating in this upcoming event? Would you like to see anything added or updated for this game now that the Switch 2 has been released? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/tetris-99s-new-maximus-cup-sees-the-return-of-four-nintendo-themes]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Switch 2 Exclusive 'Drag x Drive' Won't Include Local Multiplayer Support]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/switch-2-exclusive-drag-x-drive-wont-include-local-multiplayer-support</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/switch-2-exclusive-drag-x-drive-wont-include-local-multiplayer-support.1228653/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>But it will support 12 players online</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="Drag x Drive" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/83b515fc5533b/drag-x-drive.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure><p>Nintendo is bringing out a new "fast-paced" multiplayer game this August called <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/drag-x-drive">Drag x Drive</a>, where players will be able to "shoot hoops" with the Switch 2 Joy-Con 2 dual-mouse controls.</p>
<p>Following the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/nintendo-confirms-the-release-date-for-drag-x-drive-on-switch-2">release date announcement</a> earlier this week, the eShop listing for this upcoming title has now revealed this "3-on-3" sports title will actually support double this amount online, bumping the fun up to 12 players. Details about this have not been provided just yet.</p>
<p>While this is exciting news, local multiplayer will apparently be restricted to just one player. So even if you have an extra set of Joy-Con 2 or someone nearby who is ready for a local wireless session across two units, it seems you'll still need to team up online with an active Switch Online subscription. If we hear any changes or updates about this, we'll let you know.</p>
<p>Nintendo's page listing for Drag x Drive also reconfirms TV mode and Tabletop mode will be supported. You can find out more about Drag x Drive in our previous coverage here on Nintendo Life.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:184324,184341,184403 @ 1750930710 -->
<p>How do you feel about this game's multiplayer options? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.gonintendo.com/contents/50125-drag-x-drive-file-size-revealed-12-player-online-support-announced-no-local" rel="noopener" href="https://www.gonintendo.com/contents/50125-drag-x-drive-file-size-revealed-12-player-online-support-announced-no-local">gonintendo.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/29acde81b1e6a3314b399020340a42d3 @ 1750929550 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/switch-2-exclusive-drag-x-drive-wont-include-local-multiplayer-support]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mario Kart World Has Been Updated To Version 1.1.2, Here Are The Full Patch Notes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/mario-kart-world-has-been-updated-to-version-1-1-2-here-are-the-full-patch-notes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mario-kart-world-has-been-updated-to-version-1-1-2-here-are-the-full-patch-notes.1228635/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Update on the Switch 2 today</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="Mario Kart World" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/54b79c38cdbff/mario-kart-world.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure><p>Nintendo has been rolling out game updates every week since the Switch 2 arrived earlier this month, and we've now got a new patch for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a>.</p>
<p>This follows a small patch last week and bumps the game up to Version 1.1.2. It comes with some general adjustments and also resolves some more issues you may or may not have encountered during the game's races.</p>
<p>Here's the full rundown via Nintendo's official support page:</p>
<h3>Mario Kart World - Ver. 1.1.2 (Released June 25, 2025)<br></h3>
<p><strong>General</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Adjusted courses selected in “Random” when selecting next course in a wireless “VS Race.”</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Fixed Issues</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Made readjustments to fix an issue where rate fluctuations were sometimes displayed incorrectly in “Online Play” and “Knockout Tour.”</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where you sometimes can’t recover quickly after falling off the course in "Dino Dino Jungle".</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where you continually hit the wall near the finish line of “Boo Cinema” when transformed into Bullet Bill.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p>Dataminer 'OatmealDome' has shared <a href="https://x.com/OatmealDome/status/1938057415347343870">what else is going on behind the scenes</a> in this latest Mario Kart World update:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"The Random option can now also pick from the options you are given (i.e. courses with an intermission) in version 1.1.2. It *can* still choose to teleport everyone to a random course with 3 laps."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This follows an update for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/nintendo-switch-2-welcome-tour">Nintendo Switch 2 Welcome Tour</a> yesterday. Nintendo has also updated <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/super_smash_bros_ultimate">Super Smash Bros. Ultimate</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/super_mario_odyssey">Super Mario Odyssey</a> this week.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:184351,184352,184055 @ 1750928405 -->
<p>Have you downloaded this update yet? Notice anything else? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://en-americas-support.nintendo.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/68580/~/how-to-update-mario-kart-world" rel="noopener" href="https://en-americas-support.nintendo.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/68580/~/how-to-update-mario-kart-world">en-americas-support.nintendo.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/3e5b133501685c0a2330646cb7ca4830 @ 1750930092 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/mario-kart-world-has-been-updated-to-version-1-1-2-here-are-the-full-patch-notes]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Switch 2 'Drag x Drive' Estimated File Size Revealed By Nintendo]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/switch-2-drag-x-drive-estimated-file-size-revealed-by-nintendo</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/switch-2-drag-x-drive-estimated-file-size-revealed-by-nintendo.1228605/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Shoot some hoops this August</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Earlier this week, Nintendo surprised us with an <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/nintendo-confirms-the-release-date-for-drag-x-drive-on-switch-2">update about the release date</a> of the 3-on-3 sports game <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/drag-x-drive">Drag x Drive</a>, confirming it would be arriving on the Switch 2 this August.</p>
<p>Adding to this <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/drag-x-drive-switch-2-eshop-price-revealed">was a price reveal</a> and now in another update, we've got what appears to be the game's estimated file size. According to Nintendo's official store listing it will require a download of 1.7GB.</p>
<p>Unsurprisingly, it's nowhere near the size of the new <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/donkey-kong-bananza">Donkey Kong</a> or <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart</a> game and is instead closer to the file size of Nintendo's <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/nintendo-switch-2-welcome-tour">Welcome Tour</a> eShop title.</p>
<p>Once again, pre-orders are live for $19.99 (or your regional equivalent) and you can pre-load the title, so you'll be able to play it as soon as it launches.</p>
<p>The Switch 2 comes loaded with a total of 256GB storage, which is a huge step up on the Switch's internal space, but if you are running out of space, you can always <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/best-microsd-express-cards-for-nintendo-switch-2">expand your storage with a microSD Express card</a>.</p>
<figure><a title="Drag x Drive" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/25a4918e715f3/drag-x-drive.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:184324,184352,184341 @ 1750928357 -->
<p>Will you be checking out this game when it arrives this August? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/switch-2-drag-x-drive-estimated-file-size-revealed-by-nintendo]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>