<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 14:02:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Cult Classic 'Tokimeki Memorial' Hits Switch - But 30 Years On, It's Still Out Of Reach]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/opinion-cult-classic-tokimeki-memorial-hits-switch-but-30-years-on-its-still-out-of-reach</link>
            <guid>1393249</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="5edefd3fb51ce"><a title="Tokimeki" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/5edefd3fb51ce/tokimeki.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Konami</em></figcaption></figure>
<p><em>Over the holiday season, we're republishing some of the best articles from Nintendo Life writers and contributors from</em> <em><a data-sk="tooltip_parent" data-stringify-link="https://www.nintendolife.com/tags/best-of-2025" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/tags/best-of-2025">2025</a></em><em>. This article was originally published in April. Enjoy!</em></p>
<hr>
<p>True love lasts forever – and so do some games. <strong>Tokimeki Memorial: Forever with You</strong>, the legendary dating sim from 1995, is hooking up with Switch next month to celebrate 30 years on the scene.</p>
<p>Immaculately presented but bewilderingly complex, TokiMemo is a foundational piece of video game history that defined a whole genre, along with the increasingly universal mechanics of video game love. But for most players outside Japan, it fires nostalgia for <em>someone else</em>’s youth – and with no English release, it remains tantalisingly out of reach.</p>
<p>Its arrival is part of a bigger story. Switch has been Nintendo’s ultimate comeback kid, climbing from the Wii U stumble to contender for best-ever-selling console in eight short years. Its life has also coincided with a swell of gamers hitting mid-life nostalgia and an industry finding that bets on “new” have longer and longer odds.</p>
<p>The result? More comebacks. We’ve seen re-release after remaster after remake: <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/metroid_prime_remastered">Metroid Prime</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/live_a_live">Live A Live</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/dragon_quest_iii_hd-2d_remake">Dragon Quest</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/broken_sword_-_shadow_of_the_templars_reforged">Broken Sword</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/legend_of_zelda_links_awakening">Link’s Awakening</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/atari_50_the_anniversary_celebration">Atari 50</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/famicom_detective_club_the_missing_heir_and_famicom_detective_club_the_girl_who_stands_behind">Famicom Detective Club</a>…. The list goes on, from niche to mega-mainstream. And now, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/tokimeki_memorial_forever_with_you_emotional">Tokimeki Memorial: Forever with You – Emotional</a> is here to beam people back to CD-ROM '90s Japan.</p>

<p>Tokimeki Memorial has long been a prize of legend, at the same time unmissable and unobtainable. Revered for its groundbreaking social mechanics, emotional storytelling, intricate simulation, and (let’s face it) fascination with high school romance, it’s a seminal dating sim that remains tucked away behind a Japanese language barrier.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>eBay had it at the ready and, what’s more, I had learnt a bit of Japanese. Finally, it would be mine.</p></blockquote><blockquote>
</blockquote>
<p>Featuring writing by no less than Koji Igarashi (whose next project was <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps1/castlevania_symphony_of_the_night">Castlevania: Symphony of the Night</a> – the trailblazing entry in the series he went on to produce), it’s probably as widely experienced by word of mouth and hidden-gem lists as it is firsthand. And now, with a 30th-anniversary, Japan-only Switch port, the myth gets a new lease of life for another hundred million or so to wish they could play it.</p>
<p>Even if you haven’t played Tokimemo, you’ve likely felt its notoriously far-reaching influence. If you’ve ever arranged a study date in <strong>Persona</strong>, fretted over gift-giving in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds/fire_emblem_awakening">Fire Emblem</a>, or sweated a romance option in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/cyberpunk-2077-ultimate-edition">Cyberpunk 2077</a>, a short queue of commentators will tell you that Tokimeki Memorial is to thank for it.</p>
<p>And that’s why its reappearance on Switch is such a milestone: a wise old mentor is back. But does it have any more to say?</p>
<h2><strong>Down Memorial Lane</strong></h2>

<p>Like many of the luckier people during the COVID-19 lockdown, I found myself scouring eBay for retro games. Buying relics was an attempt to get my hands on something out of reach – the futile chase of nostalgia was a parallel to everyone and everything being physically inaccessible, no matter how nearby they seemed. Perhaps games in particular appealed because everything felt newly gamified by technology, from work to social interactions.</p>
<p>Whatever was behind it all, for me, the bug that bit was the original PlayStation. Specifically, I discovered that about half of the PlayStation’s 4,000-strong games catalogue was released exclusively in Japan.</p>
<p>I wanted to know what was out there.</p>
<p>One Japan-only title was Tokimeki Memorial: Forever with You, the 1995 PlayStation version of the previous year’s <strong><a href="https://www.timeextension.com/news/2024/05/anniversary-dating-sim-tokimeki-memorial-turns-30">Tokimeki Memorial</a></strong> on PC Engine. I think I half-remembered it from magazines as a kid, import reviews, or forum threads. That faint recollection of it sent my heart racing with wistful frustration, as Konami would surely never bring it to English-language audiences. But now, eBay had it at the ready and, what’s more, I had learnt a bit of Japanese. Finally, it would be mine.</p>
<p>However, when I navigated Tokimeki Memorial’s menus and carefully picked through its layers of dialogue, moving my lips as I read, I quickly discovered that while I was over the language barrier, the gameplay itself was a labyrinth of hidden rules and secret look-up tables that left me feeling impressed, overwhelmed, and really quite stupid. With bungling date etiquette, forgetting homework, and panicking through stingily one-and-done sports day events, I couldn’t really object when the humiliating 'loser' ending rolled after my first three-year stint at Kirameki High.</p>

<p>Even once I had got the hang of things and a girl confessed her love for me beneath the school’s tree of legend, where true love is destined to last forever, things were far from over. Beaming through the fog of digital teenagerhood is Shiori Fujisaki, the elusive, red-haired cover-girl-slash-final-boss.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>She’s inhumanly perfect, the Terminator of high school crushes</p></blockquote><blockquote>
</blockquote>
<p>Shiori demands perfection. Achieving the intricate mathematical balance of smarts, fitness, and popularity, wisely selecting your character’s blood type, avoiding rumour bombs from the other girls, and winning the three-legged race — all in one attempt — is like threading a needle on a bucking bronco.</p>
<p>Shiori smiles and blushes, then just stares matter-of-factly at you with these astronomical expectations, like a fairground automaton waiting for you to insert a coin. She’s inhumanly perfect, the Terminator of high school crushes – teasingly close to being won over, only for rejection’s charred endoskeleton to crawl out of the tanker explosion of your teenage affections.</p>
<p>As chance would have it, just as my fascination with the game took off, gaming celebrity Tim Rogers released <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xb-DtICmPTY">a six-hour Action Button video review of Tokimeki Memorial</a>, including two complete, translated playthroughs. His bottom line: <em>“Tokimeki Memorial objectifies love.”</em> He declared it a true cyberpunk artefact and deftly squelched any question of the propriety of high school dating simulation through comparison with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/mortal_kombat_11">Mortal Kombat</a> fatalities. Quickly racking up a million views, hype for the OG dating sim hit a new peak.</p>

<p>This buzz no doubt spurred on the completion of a fan translation of the (non-voice-acted) Super Famicom version. Brilliant as this was, Rogers dismissed it in an email to <a href="https://kotaku.com/tokimeki-memorial-english-translation-konami-snes-plays-1848525789">Kotaku</a> as “like watching a movie for the first time with the TV muted and two lines of subtitles displaying both the movie’s dialogue and the director’s commentary […] while waiting for your laundry to finish.”</p>
<p>Playing without voice acting probably does deaden the heart-thumping impact of a confession of love, or the humiliation of a post-date brush-off condescendingly delivered. But you can’t help but feel that even a full localisation with English voices would be somehow inadequate for this ultimate connoisseur, locking the game permanently into “you had to be there” territory.</p>
<p>You had to be there and you weren’t: this is a must-play game that you can’t play.</p>
<h2><strong>Modern Love</strong></h2>
<p>So what now, with the Switch hosting this revival? It’s on the Japanese eShop and importable, but will that actually bring it any closer to the average player?</p>
<p>Well, one of Nintendo’s specialisms is to give you something to hold in your hands — from hanafuda cards to toys like <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/mario_kart_live_home_circuit">Mario Kart Live</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/nintendo_labo_toy-con_01_variety_kit">Labo</a> — not just platform-agnostic software distributed digitally. Its dominance in handheld gaming is a big part of that, and placing TokiMemo in your hands on a nice big screen is not to be underestimated.</p>

<p>If there is one hint of international accessibility, it’s that you will be able to choose updated text, giving you higher-resolution kanji over the occasionally inscrutable clumps of pixels in earlier versions. Thankfully, this can be applied separately from the updated artwork, which at first glance makes the game look like one of its many modern descendants. The girls will say your name now, too, so that’s one word you can definitely understand.</p>
<p>Tokimeki Memorial: Forever With You – Emotional is more than a dating sim – it’s a time capsule from an era where gamified social interactions were new ground. Now, games are full of socialising, and socialising is equally full of games, from lockdown hang-outs in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/animal_crossing_new_horizons">New Horizons</a> to social media numbers going up, to just swiping right. Forever With You’s debut on Switch feels like a love letter still undeliverable after 30 years, an emblem of the persistent allure of unreachable classics, and yet now, maybe, a blip on the radar of an enormous global player base.</p>
<p>Some things will always be just out of reach, but nostalgia is the true love that lasts forever. If you’ve ever felt the pull of retro collecting or the urge to relive youth — even someone else’s — this release is a call to reminisce, rediscover things, and perhaps even to try decoding one of gaming’s most mythologised puzzles for yourself.</p>
<figure data-uuid="bd7b758ff1675"><a title="Tokimeki" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/bd7b758ff1675/tokimeki.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Konami</em></figcaption></figure>
<hr>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:181218,160144 @ 1766926836 --></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/opinion-cult-classic-tokimeki-memorial-hits-switch-but-30-years-on-its-still-out-of-reach]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["If Mario Starts To Show Up On PlayStation, That's The Apocalypse, Right?" - Ex-PlayStation Boss Thinks Console Exclusives Are Still Important]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/if-mario-starts-to-show-up-on-playstation-thats-the-apocalypse-right-ex-playstation-boss-thinks-console-exclusives-are-still-important</link>
            <guid>1393225</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>"If you do exclusives you can push every lever to 11 in that platform"</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="d10822e8c4072"><a title="&quot;If Mario Starts To Show Up On PlayStation, That's The Apocalypse, Right?&quot; - Ex-PlayStation Boss Thinks Console Exclusives Are Still Important 1" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/d10822e8c4072/if-mario-starts-to-show-up-on-playstation-thats-the-apocalypse-right-ex-playstation-boss-thinks-console-exclusives-are-still-important-1.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure><p>We find ourselves in an unusual position when it comes to console exclusives these days.</p>
<p>Once upon a time, titles like <a href="https://www.purexbox.com/games/xbox/halo">Halo</a>, <a href="https://www.purexbox.com/games/xbox-series-x/forza_horizon_6">Forza</a>, <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps4/death_stranding">Death Stranding</a><span><a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps4/death_stranding">,</a> and <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps4/god_of_war">God of War</a> would have been playable only on hardware produced by their respective owners. However, today, Microsoft is releasing its games on PS5,</span> while Sony is happy for its leading lights to hit PC.</p>
<p>Nintendo remains steadfast in its dedication to true exclusives, however, and ex-PlayStation boss Shawn Layden thinks that's the right approach, despite the market seemingly heading in the other direction.</p>
<p>Speaking on the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC_-9FAcLYBRB3misjrt2jBw">Pause for Thought</a> podcast, Layden addressed the topic of platform exclusives and says he feels they're still important (thanks, <a href="https://x.com/genki_jpn/status/2005065889755083113?s=46&amp;t=_ZthC0M-yfLcPVPyf_xLfQ">Genki</a>):</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"I don’t think every game has to be console exclusive. I don’t think every game should be console exclusive, but I do accept the fact that if you’re going to have platform companies like Sony and Nintendo largely. Microsoft is more of the Xbox everywhere, anywhere. There is a huge value to the brand of having strong exclusives.</p>
<p>If Mario starts to show up on PlayStation, that’s the apocalypse, right? Cats and dogs living together. And the same goes for Nathan Drake and Uncharted. I think they make the platform sing."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Layden makes another good point in relation to exclusives – they push the host platform to its limit:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"And of course the other thing with multiplatform, that I’m sure most people realize, is that when you do code across multiple platforms you do have to code to the lowest common denominator. But if you do exclusives you can push every lever to 11 in that platform."</p>
</blockquote>

<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-articles:194597,187017,179735 @ 1766926855 --></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cwH_otOCDmQ" rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cwH_otOCDmQ">youtube.com</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://x.com/genki_jpn/status/2005065889755083113?s=46&amp;amp;t=_ZthC0M-yfLcPVPyf_xLfQ" rel="noopener" href="https://x.com/genki_jpn/status/2005065889755083113?s=46&amp;t=_ZthC0M-yfLcPVPyf_xLfQ">x.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-info/d41d8cd98f00b204e9800998ecf8427e @ 1766926786 --></div></article><div><p>Damien has been writing professionally about tech and video games since 2007 and oversees all of Hookshot Media's sites from an editorial perspective. He's also the editor of <a href="https://www.timeextension.com/">Time Extension</a>, the network's newest site, which – paradoxically – is all about gaming's past glories.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Damo"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/damienmcferran.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Damo');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/if-mario-starts-to-show-up-on-playstation-thats-the-apocalypse-right-ex-playstation-boss-thinks-console-exclusives-are-still-important]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Square Enix Teases More For Dragon Quest, NieR and Final Fantasy In 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/square-enix-teases-more-for-dragon-quest-nier-and-final-fantasy-in-2026</link>
            <guid>1393198</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>But try not to get “too excited”</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="a03cd58198f12"><a title="Dragon Quest" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/a03cd58198f12/dragon-quest.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Square Enix</em></figcaption></figure><p>Next year marks even more anniversaries, and one other big one coming up is for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/dragon_quest">Dragon Quest</a>. This classic role-playing series will hit its 40th birthday, and in the same end-of-year wrap with 4Gamer.net (<a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/japanese-game-creators-discuss-2026-ambitions">via Gematsu</a>), Square Enix producer Yosuke Saito mentions how the company is looking forward to everyone joining in on the grand celebration of the series.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Next year marks the 40th anniversary of <em>Dragon Quest</em>! I’d be extremely happy if everyone could join in on a grand celebration.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/nierautomata_the_end_of_yorha_edition">NieR:Automata</a> will also celebrate its ninth anniversary! And the team is apparently preparing a “little something”, but temper your expectations.</p><div><figure data-videoid="O4v-ia_qhCE" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/O4v-ia_qhCE?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytO4v-ia_qhCE" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/O4v-ia_qhCE?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/O4v-ia_qhCE?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed405204gtvurz&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>841k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<blockquote>
<p>And for <em>NieR: Automata</em>‘s ninth anniversary, we’re also preparing ‘just a little something…’ so please don’t get too excited with anticipation! With that, I wish you all a happy New Year.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Director Kazutoyo Maehiro (<a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/final_fantasy_tactics_the_ivalice_chronicles">Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles</a>) also provided a brief teaser about <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/final_fantasy">Final Fantasy</a>, mentioning how the next “something” the team is preparing will be “content with a different approach”.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“In 2025, we released <em>Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles</em> on September 30 and <em>LOGOS: The World of Final Fantasy XVI</em> on December 16. While the game and book took different approaches, we put our all into both so that anyone who picks them up might feel, even just a little, ‘Games are fun, huh?’ The next ‘something’ we’re preparing will also be content with a different approach. We’re working hard to bring you a new gaming experience, so please wait a little longer until the day we can debut it.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In some other Square Enix news, the company is currently running a survey about the Final Fantasy series, where fans can share how they feel about the series.</p>
<p>And if you are looking for some more fun on the Switch 2, the demo for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade">Final Fantasy VII Intergrade Remake</a> is now live on the eShop. NieR has also recently got a backwards compatibility update.</p>
<p>Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade's Switch 2 release arrives next month, and Dragon Quest VII: Reimagined will follow in February 2026.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:195723,195373,194344,187804,188132 @ 1766929028 -->
<p>What are you hoping to see from Square Enix and its series in 2026? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.4gamer.net/games/999/G999905/20251219044/" rel="noopener" href="https://www.4gamer.net/games/999/G999905/20251219044/">4gamer.net</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/b631c44666bf424926e05b33445c56a5 @ 1766927572 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/square-enix-teases-more-for-dragon-quest-nier-and-final-fantasy-in-2026]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ICYMI: Stardew Valley - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Is Now Available, Will You Be Getting It?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/icymi-stardew-valley-nintendo-switch-2-edition-is-now-available-will-you-be-getting-it</link>
            <guid>1393189</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>The new version is now live</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure data-uuid="39688a9ce35de"><a title="Stardew Valley" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/39688a9ce35de/stardew-valley.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: ConcernedApe</em></figcaption></figure><p>In case you missed it, following ConcernedApe’s status update last week, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/stardew-valley-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Stardew Valley – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</a> is now officially available.</p>
<p>This particular version comes loaded with mouse controls, four-player split-screen as well as eight-player online multiplayer. There’s also GameShare support for Switch and Switch 2 users, so players without a copy of the title can still join in on the farming fun.</p>
<p>Admittedly, there have been some teething issues with this update. It's <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/surprise-stardew-valley-nintendo-switch-2-edition-is-now-available">already been acknowledged by the creator</a> and <a href="https://x.com/ConcernedApe/status/2004604445498429827">some issues</a> have now been fixed. The plan is to resolve the other problems as soon as possible.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>"I am aware that there are some issues with the Nintendo Switch 2 Edition that just dropped. I take full responsibility for this mistake. We will fix this as soon as possible"</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>It's also worth noting that this upgrade may not be live on your local eShop yet. Fortunately, it is available in locations such as the US.</p>
<p>Despite these issues, we’re sure many fans are still jumping into the Switch 2 version of Stardew Valley over the holiday season, so vote in our poll and let us know in the comments if you’re playing it (and how you’re finding the experience so far).</p>

<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:195498 @ 1766926847 -->

</section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/icymi-stardew-valley-nintendo-switch-2-edition-is-now-available-will-you-be-getting-it]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arcade Archives Celebrates 500 Retro Releases With Special Commemorative Game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/arcade-archives-celebrates-500-retro-releases-with-special-commemorative-game</link>
            <guid>1393183</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>The classic Space Invaders returns</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure data-uuid="c200d6f1bfa24"><a title="Arcade Archives" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/c200d6f1bfa24/arcade-archives.large.jpg"></a></figure>
<p>Last year in January, Hamster’s Arcade Archives series for the Switch and multiple other platforms reached 400 releases. Now, in an update at the end of 2025, it’s been officially confirmed that the retro-specialist has now hit 500 releases!</p>
<p>Arcade Archives originally began life on 15th May 2014, and more recently expanded to the Switch 2 and PlayStation 5.</p>

<p>To celebrate this <em>huge</em> milestone, the 1978 Taito game <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/arcade/space_invaders">Space Invaders</a> has been distributed. It will set you back $7.99 (or your regional equivalent). Here’s the full rundown via the eShop, along with a look:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>In 1978, we confronted the Invaders!</strong></p></blockquote><blockquote>
<div><p>"SPACE INVADERS" is a shooting game released by TAITO in 1978.<br>
The origin of the masterpiece that once captivated all of Japan has finally arrived on Arcade Archives!<br>
This title includes both the black-and-white and color versions, and the sound has been reproduced to the limit of how it sounded back then.<br>
Experience the timeless legend once again!</p><p>

The "Arcade Archives" series has faithfully reproduced many classic Arcade masterpieces.<br>
Players can change various game settings such as game difficulty, and also reproduce the atmosphere of arcade display settings at that time. Players can also compete against each other from all over the world with their high scores.<br>
Please enjoy the masterpieces that built a generation for video games.</p><p>

*The options menu and manual are available in Japanese, English, French, German, Italian, and Spanish.</p></div>
</blockquote>

<p>You can see the history of Hamster's Arcade Archives series in our full guide here on Nintendo Life:</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:97105 @ 1766930451 -->
<p>How many Arcade Archives games have you played and purchased over the years? Will you be revisiting Space Invaders? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/arcade-archives-celebrates-500-retro-releases-with-special-commemorative-game]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here Are Japan's Best-Selling Switch and Switch 2 eShop Games For 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/here-are-japans-best-selling-switch-and-switch-2-eshop-games-for-2025</link>
            <guid>1393156</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Mario Kart World and Pokémon top the list</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="131af7fc4ab59"><a title="Nintendo eShop" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/131af7fc4ab59/nintendo-eshop.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>It’s once again that time of year where companies sum up all sorts of things about the year that was, and with this in mind, Nintendo’s Japanese branch has revealed the best-selling games on the Switch and Switch 2 eShop in 2025.</p>
<p>This covers January through to December, and everything else in between. It also factors in digital sales across both the eShop and the My Nintendo Store. <em>N</em><em>ote: this also excludes free-to-play titles and games rated above CERO rating Z / IARC 16</em>).</p>
<p>On the Switch 2, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a> took out the top spot, and leading the charge on the Switch front was <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pokemon_legends_z-a">Pokémon Legends: Z-A</a>. Here are the top 20 best-selling games on each system, according to Nintendo’s digital store (<a href="https://www.perfectly-nintendo.com/japan-nintendo-eshop-sales-rankings-for-2025-switch-switch-2/">via Perfectly-Nintendo</a>):</p>
<h3>Nintendo Switch 2:</h3>
<ol>
<li><em>Mario Kart World</em></li>
<li><em>Pokémon Legends: Z-A – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</em></li>
<li><em>Kirby Air Riders</em></li>
<li><em>Donkey Kong Bananza</em></li>
<li><em>Inazuma Eleven: Victory Road – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</em></li>
<li><em>Dragon Quest 1 &amp; 2 HD-2 Remake</em></li>
<li><em>Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment</em></li>
<li><em>Momotarou Dentetsu 2 – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</em></li>
<li><em>Tamagotchi Plaza – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</em></li>
<li><em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</em></li>
<li><em>Street Fighter 6</em></li>
<li><em>Rune Factory: Guardians of Azuma</em></li>
<li><em>Nintendo Switch 2 Welcome Tour</em></li>
<li><em>Octopath Traveler 0</em></li>
<li><em>Shine Post Be Your Idol</em></li>
<li><em>Yakuza 0 Director’s Cut</em></li>
<li><em>Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</em></li>
<li><em>Super Mario Party Jamboree – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition + Jamboree TV</em></li>
<li><em>Hollow Knight: Silksong – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</em></li>
<li><em>Fantasy Life i: The Girl Who Steals Time – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</em></li>
</ol>
<h3>Nintendo Switch</h3>
<ol>
<li><em>Pokémon Legends: Z-A</em></li>
<li><em>Tamagotchi Plaza</em></li>
<li><em>Minecraft</em></li>
<li><em>Dragon Quest I &amp; II HD-2D Remake</em></li>
<li><em>Super Mario Party Jamboree</em></li>
<li><em>Animal Crossing: New Horizons</em></li>
<li><em>Fantasy Life i: The Girl Who Steals Time</em></li>
<li><em>Inazuma Eleven: Victory Road</em></li>
<li><em>Clubhouse Games: 51 Worldwide Classics</em></li>
<li><em>Mario Kart 8 Deluxe</em></li>
<li><em>Super Smash Bros. Ultimate</em></li>
<li><em>Power Pros 2024-2025</em></li>
<li><em>Urban Myth Dissolution Center</em></li>
<li><em>DRAGON QUEST III HD-2D Remake</em></li>
<li><em>Momotarou Dentetsu 2 ~Anata no Machi mo Kitto Aru~ Higashi Nihon-hen + Nishi Nihon-hen</em></li>
<li><em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar</em></li>
<li><em>Super Robot Wars Y Digital Ultimate Edition</em></li>
<li><em>Fitness Boxing 3: Your Personal Trainer</em></li>
<li><em>Super Mario Galaxy + Super Mario Galaxy 2</em></li>
<li><em>Splatoon 3</em></li>
</ol>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:195214,194331,193895,149107 @ 1766928682 -->
<p>What did you think of the top-selling games in Japan on the Switch and Switch 2 in 2025? How many of these games did you end up buying? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://store-jp.nintendo.com/feature/feature_year_dl_ranking_2025" rel="noopener" href="https://store-jp.nintendo.com/feature/feature_year_dl_ranking_2025">store-jp.nintendo.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/e8ba7dbb5255767129ba229b9d2d681d @ 1766927152 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/here-are-japans-best-selling-switch-and-switch-2-eshop-games-for-2025]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atlus Looks Forward To Persona's 30th Anniversary In 2026, Acknowledges Support For Persona 4 Revival]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/atlus-looks-forward-to-personas-30th-anniversary-in-2026-acknowledges-support-for-persona-4-revival</link>
            <guid>1393141</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>It can’t wait to make “another announcement”</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="afe2b1d2b24b1"><a title="Persona 3 Reload" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/afe2b1d2b24b1/persona-3-reload.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Atlus</em></figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/persona-3-reload">Persona 3 Reload</a> only arrived on the Switch 2 in October, but there’s plenty more to come...</p>
<p>Speaking to the Japanese website 4Gamer.net as part of its annual end-of-year developer interview feature recently, Atlus producer and director Kazuhisa Wada (who has worked on <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/persona_5_royal">Persona 5 Royal</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/persona-3-reload">Persona 3 Reload</a>) highlighted how the JRPG series will be celebrating its 30th anniversary in 2026.</p>
<p>To thank fans, the team is already preparing a "wide variety of initiatives on a global scale”. There’ll also apparently be some chances to talk about “future developments” for the series.</p><div><figure data-videoid="nhkdyt-h_Eo" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nhkdyt-h_Eo?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytnhkdyt-h_Eo" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/nhkdyt-h_Eo?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nhkdyt-h_Eo?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed5e7948itwjxl&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>841k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p>Here’s exactly what he had to say (<a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/japanese-game-creators-discuss-2026-ambitions">via Gematsu</a>):</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“The <em>Persona</em> series will celebrate its 30th anniversary in 2026. As a token of our gratitude to everyone, we’re preparing a wide variety of initiatives on a global scale, so please look forward to them…! Additionally, we believe there will be opportunities in 2026 to talk about future developments for the series. Preparations are steadily coming together, and all of us at ATLUS will be giving it our all to build excitement around <em>Persona</em>, so we sincerely ask for your continued support…!”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Fellow producer and director Shinjiro Takata also acknowledged how his team released <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/raidou-remastered-the-mystery-of-the-soulless-army">RAIDOU Remastered</a> in 2025 on the Switch and Switch 2. Apparently, patch support might not be done yet.</p>
<p>And last but not least, Persona 5 Royal and Persona 3 Reload producer Atsushi Nomura mentions how Atlus has received “a lot of support” for <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/persona_4_revival"><strong>Persona 4 Revival</strong></a>, and is looking forward to providing an update:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“We’re very much looking forward to the day we can make another announcement, so please continue to give us your support.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>So, that's what's on the menu for the Persona series next year. If you haven’t already tried out P3R on the Switch 2, there’s a demo you can download from the eShop. A patch for the game has also rolled out this week, which bumps the frame rate. You can find out more about this in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/persona-3-reload-switch-2-performance-update-now-live-targets-60fps-in-docked-mode">our previous story</a>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:195668,188439,183773,183583 @ 1766928542 -->
<p>What would you like to see from Atlus and the Persona series next year? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.4gamer.net/games/999/G999905/20251219044/" rel="noopener" href="https://www.4gamer.net/games/999/G999905/20251219044/">4gamer.net</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/78b35ded94b9ad8b1f0c45efc92b4374 @ 1766929932 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/atlus-looks-forward-to-personas-30th-anniversary-in-2026-acknowledges-support-for-persona-4-revival]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["A Knife Can Be Used For Cooking Or As A Weapon" - Level-5 Boss Defends GenAI In Game Development]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/a-knife-can-be-used-for-cooking-or-as-a-weapon-level-5-boss-defends-genai-in-game-development</link>
            <guid>1393087</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<p>"I hope creators and audiences alike can recognize AI as a tool"</p>
</section><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="8873a920c3842"><a title="&quot;A Knife Can Be Used For Cooking Or As A Weapon&quot; - Level-5 Boss Defends GenAI In Game Development 1" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/8873a920c3842/a-knife-can-be-used-for-cooking-or-as-a-weapon-level-5-boss-defends-genai-in-game-development-1.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Level 5</em></figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/level-5-ceo-sees-ai-as-tool-for-communication-and-efficiency-improvement">Back in June</a>, Level-5 CEO Akihiro Hino acknowledged that, like a great many companies working in the games industry, his firm was exploring the use of Generative AI as "a tool for communication and efficiency improvement."</p>
<p>Fast forward to the end of the year, and Hino's view of GenAI appears to have become a little more positive. As noted by <a href="https://kotaku.com/professor-layton-boss-wants-people-to-stop-demonizing-generative-ai-2000655721">Kotaku</a>, he <a href="https://x.com/AkihiroHino/status/2004439840868421650">posted a lengthy response</a> to the online “commotion surrounding AI,” pointing out that many companies in the gaming sector are now incorporating AI into their development process at some point.</p>
<p>He also addressed the misunderstanding that saw some people claim that Level-5 was using AI to write 80% of the code in its games:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“The truth of the matter is that there’s an unreleased title themed around AI, and for that specific title, a programmer mentioned they’re deliberately having AI handle the programming as well. They used that as an example to suggest that an era like that might be coming, and that’s what got blown out of proportion.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>However, Hino adds that "if they really were creating 80%–90% percent of the code with AI and successfully making games that way, it’d be incredibly impressive, and they’d be in high demand from the AI community," suggesting that he's put aside any concerns he might have about the ethical failings of GenAI, which is often trained on images, video and other data without the permission of the original creators.</p>

<p>"We haven’t reached that level yet," Hino admits. "That said, it’s also true that AI is enabling time savings that can’t be dismissed, and I believe this has the potential to upend common sense in game development. It might shift us from a world where developing the AAA games everyone wants to play takes 5–10 years to one where we get to enjoy them every two years."</p>
<p>Hino addresses the issue of copyright theft directly in the following passage, pointing out that GenAI is treated “like it’s synonymous with plagiarism." In fact, it seems that Hino has become something of an AI convert since his comments early in the year, saying:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"A knife can be used for cooking or as a weapon; a computer can create games or enable cybercrime. AI might produce plagiarized content if misused, but if used properly, it has the power to enrich the creative world even further.</p>
<p>I want to see games evolve even more in my lifetime. I want to experience and create dreamlike games that surpass the standards of today’s AAA titles. If we let the impression take hold here that ‘using AI is evil,’ it could seriously hinder the advancement of modern digital technology. I hope creators and audiences alike can recognize AI as a tool that people use to make their works. Here’s to hoping that various technological innovations lead to even greater growth in the game industry!”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>We recently asked you, our beloved readers, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/talking-point-does-it-bother-you-that-big-games-companies-are-using-genai">if Generative AI was a worry for you as a consumer</a>. 52% of you said you'd be concerned if developers used AI during any part of their pipeline, while 63% of you said you'd be "extremely disappointed" if Nintendo ever decided to utilise the controversial tech.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-articles:184379,168481,195525 @ 1766927812 --></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://x.com/AkihiroHino/status/2004439840868421650" rel="noopener" href="https://x.com/AkihiroHino/status/2004439840868421650">x.com</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://kotaku.com/professor-layton-boss-wants-people-to-stop-demonizing-generative-ai-2000655721" rel="noopener" href="https://kotaku.com/professor-layton-boss-wants-people-to-stop-demonizing-generative-ai-2000655721">kotaku.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-info/d41d8cd98f00b204e9800998ecf8427e @ 1766930395 --></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/a-knife-can-be-used-for-cooking-or-as-a-weapon-level-5-boss-defends-genai-in-game-development]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Feature: "It's Huge For Us" - Devs Talk Switch 2 Reactions, Dev-Kit Disparity, Future Plans]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/its-huge-for-us-devs-talk-switch-2-reactions-dev-kit-disparity-future-plans</link>
            <guid>1393042</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="a55ccab1a6a58"><a title="Switch 2 - Mario Kart World" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/a55ccab1a6a58/switch-2-mario-kart-world.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Damien McFerran / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p><em>Over the holiday season, we're republishing some of the best articles from Nintendo Life writers and contributors from</em> <em><a data-sk="tooltip_parent" data-stringify-link="https://www.nintendolife.com/tags/best-of-2025" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/tags/best-of-2025">2025</a></em><em>. This article was originally published in April. Enjoy!</em></p>
<hr>
<p>In case you somehow missed it, Nintendo has officially lifted the lid on Switch 2, cueing all sorts of excitement and apprehension from those of us who have been loyally playing our Switch 1s for the past eight years.</p>
<p>It's an exciting time to be a player, but how does it feel from a developer's standpoint? Is the Switch 2 everything they could have hoped for, or are there any anxieties that come with the uncertainty of a new console launch?</p>
<p>We spoke to a handful of developers and publishers from across the industry to hear their gut reaction to the console and their plans for the future. Here's who we spoke to:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Adam Tierney,</strong> <strong>James Montagna,</strong> <strong>Matt Bozon</strong> - WayForward (<a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/advance_wars_1plus2_re-boot_camp">Advance Wars 1+2: Re-Boot Camp</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/yars_rising">Yars Rising</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/shantae">Shantae</a>)</li>
<li><strong>Andy Pearson</strong> - PQube (<a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/potion_permit">Potion Permit</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/gal_guardians_demon_purge">Gal Guardians: Demon Purge</a>)</li>
<li><strong>Gavin Price</strong> - Playtonic (<a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/yooka-laylee">Yooka-Laylee</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/yooka-laylee_and_the_impossible_lair">Yooka-Laylee and the Impossible Lair</a>)</li>
<li><strong>Harris Foster</strong> - Big Fan Games</li>
<li><strong>Manfred Linzner</strong> - Shin'en (<a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/fast_rmx">Fast RMX</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds/nano_assault">Nano Assault</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/fast-fusion">Fast Fusion</a>)</li>
<li><strong>Sophie Smart</strong> - No More Robots (<a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/lets_build_a_zoo">Let's Build A Zoo</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/fashion_police_squad">Fashion Police Squad</a>)</li>
<li><strong>Tomm Hulett</strong> - WayForward (<a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/contra_4">Contra 4</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/contra_operation_galuga">Contra: Operation Galuga</a>)</li>
<li><strong>???</strong> - Another dev wished to remain anonymous "for fear of being on a flagged list" — their responses are marked below as <strong>Anon</strong>.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Note. Not everyone answered every question, and we've edited some responses that cover the same ground.</em></p>
<h2><strong>What did you make of the Switch 2 reveal, and which feature excited you the most?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>Harris Foster (Big Fan Games):</strong> Nintendo’s hardware reveals are special because you can always count on seeing a stand-out idea that breaks console expectations and gets your imagination flowing. The Switch 2’s mouse capabilities in the new Joy-Con controllers is particularly interesting to me — as someone who plays the occasional mouse-controlled game from the couch, I’m excited to see how Nintendo’s approach can improve this experience.</p>
<p><strong>Matt Bozon (WayForward):</strong> I really enjoy playing with my current Switch in handheld mode, so it’s exciting to have a larger screen and more power for gaming on the go. I always look forward to playing Nintendo’s newest generation of games; they never fail to be fun and inspiring!</p>
<figure data-uuid="8dad9baff0119"><a title="Metroid Prime 4" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/8dad9baff0119/metroid-prime-4.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Manfred Linzner (Shin'en):</strong> We were super happy to see the first-party titles like <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/donkey-kong-bananza">Donkey Kong Bananza</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/metroid-prime-4-beyond-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Metroid Prime 4</a>. Great quality and fresh ideas from Nintendo, as expected.</p>
<p><strong>Sophie Smart (No More Robots):</strong> I really enjoyed watching it! It felt the appropriate length for such an anticipated announcement and was jam-packed with explanations of the console itself, how things will work now with games between Switch and Switch 2, and new and existing titles! However, I do feel that Nintendo played it safe and stuck with the winning formula of the Switch, whereas we are used to Nintendo completely reinventing itself between generations.</p>
<p>The main feature which I feel is most ‘Nintendo’ and out there is the Joy-Con turning into mice to control parts of games. Since we have <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/hypnospace_outlaw">Hypnospace Outlaw</a>, a '90s internet simulator, in our game catalogue at No More Robots, it makes me excited to see whether we can organise a port to utilise the technology to feel like you are actually browsing the web!</p>
<p><strong>Adam Tierney (WayForward):</strong> I’m excited about the multiplayer features to better connect players to one another online. Being able to see each other’s screens in games, chat with each other, and even see video of each other could all be very interesting going forward, from a developer perspective.</p>
<p><strong>Gavin Price (Playtonic):</strong> I loved it. I’ve got my pre-order in, let’s put it that way (and I’ve not been a day-one purchaser of any console for a few generations)! I’m interested in the 120Hz refresh rate and how that can enable more options for players to enjoy games their way.</p>
<p><strong>Anon:</strong> As a consumer, I’m excited as [it] seems like games that would have skipped the Switch are coming, but I also own a Steam deck and would probably purchase there cheaper. I just want awesome exclusives. As a game designer, the dual mouse control has me most excited. [It] should open up some interesting new ways to play and even a few games we’ve developed that don’t work for controller but would be perfect for mouse.</p>
<p><strong>James Montagna (WayForward):</strong> The Switch 2 showcase was fantastic! From both a developer and gamer perspective, seeing the innovations Nintendo brought to the table genuinely fired me up. Knowing some of the talented Nintendo engineers personally and seeing the passion they put into their craft made the reveal feel even more special. It’s always inspiring watching Nintendo shape the future of gaming like only they can. For me, the enhanced HD Rumble 2 stood out the most. I'm already picturing how incredible it'll feel to dual-wield Joy-Con in mouse mode, experiencing subtle ticking, buzzing, pulsing, and sensations I can't even fully describe yet. That next-level immersion is exactly the kind of thing that excites me as a game creator.</p>
<p><strong>Andy Pearson (PQube):</strong> We're particularly enthusiastic about the more powerful processing capabilities, which means players can experience titles much closer to (or exactly as) their developers originally intended them to be played.</p>
<p><strong>Tomm Hulett (WayForward):</strong> Well, I'm a huge <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps4/bloodborne">Bloodborne</a> fan, so…. But besides <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/duskbloods">Duskbloods</a>, I was actually really happy to hear about the 'S2 Enhanced' edition games and to see how much content was being added to Nintendo's titles and potentially third parties as well. It's a really cool way to refresh older games and urge a replay.</p>
<h2><strong>Are there any unanswered questions you still have, or specific features you’d like to see added to the console?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>Harris Foster:</strong> With digital libraries becoming the norm on consoles, we’ve grown accustomed to our collection carrying forward — this will be my first time going through the process on a Nintendo platform, so I'm most curious about how it'll handle this. I think it’s safe to say that we’ve all amassed a large digital library of original Switch titles, so I’m keen to see how easy it will be to carry games and saves from Switch to Switch 2.</p>
<figure data-uuid="27a14e66ba5e0"><a title="Switch 2 - Mouse Mode" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/27a14e66ba5e0/switch-2-mouse-mode.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Damien McFerran / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>I am curious if it's technically possible to use that functionality for certain games that require two screens</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>Tomm Hulett:</strong> Since you can use the original Switch as a controller/share supported multiplayer games to Switch… I am curious if it's technically possible to use that functionality for certain games that require two screens. Maybe for consoles that aren't on NSO yet. Though I might just be craving the gamer cred of completing <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/contra_4">Contra 4</a> on such an unusual setup. But hey, maybe you could play <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/hotel_dusk_room_215">Hotel Dusk</a> while lying sideways in bed!</p>
<p><strong>Gavin Price:</strong> I think it’s clear to see what Nintendo believes should be standard for enjoying Nintendo Switch 2 experiences. I can only imagine how it might be thinking of how to make a game about chatting with other players! I kind of hoped for an interactive LED/second screen-fronted dock, but I can appreciate this would cause a disparity with how games can be enjoyed in docked mode uniquely vs handheld modes.</p>
<p><strong>Andy Pearson:</strong> While the hardware announcements have been impressive, we're eager to learn more about improvements to the digital storefront and whether Nintendo has plans to enhance discoverability features. As the eShop catalogue continues to grow, better navigation tools and recommendation systems would greatly benefit both players and developers. We're also curious about potential new social features and online capabilities and how they can be utilised in future games.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:177664 @ 1766929498 -->
<p><strong>Sophie Smart:</strong> Not features per se, however, I do feel that we might need to see a Switch 2.5 or a ‘Pro’ version sooner rather than later. I can imagine an OLED version or a version which is slightly more powerful or holds a longer battery life would be something people would want!</p>
<p><strong>James Montagna:</strong> Nintendo covered a ton of ground already, so nothing major jumps out. But the game-maker in me is always eager to dive deeper into those smaller technical details and subtle features that don’t always get headline space. Mostly, I’m just excited to keep exploring everything the Switch 2 has to offer. (Although, with all new social features, I admit I can’t help but secretly hope for a fresh take on <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds-eshop/nintendo_letter_box">Swapnote</a> [Nintendo Letter Box] — I miss the connection that comes with exchanging fun art and messages with friends.)</p>
<h2><strong>Do you have plans to support Switch 2? Is a Switch 2 release more important than a ‘Switch 1’ release in 2025?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>Andy Pearson:</strong> We will absolutely be supporting the Switch 2 with our upcoming titles. Rather than viewing it as "more important" than the original Switch, we see it as a positive evolution. The Switch 2's launch represents an exciting opportunity to reach new audiences while continuing to support the extensive existing player base.</p>
<p><strong>Sophie Smart:</strong> I would say a Switch 2 release would be super important to anyone right now! Mainly because there won’t be that many Switch 2 titles around launch, so it’ll allow your game to stand out and take advantage of the power. A lot of games no longer get a Switch port on release because of the low specs of the Switch, so this will open a lot more doors for games currently in development.</p>
<p><strong>Gavin Price:</strong> We do have plans, but when and how they manifest is too early to share. I am in no way smart enough to answer the second part of that question. Switch 1 has a huge following, and I’m sure early Switch 2 purchasers will be ravenous for new, unique experiences too.</p>
<figure data-uuid="d56ed12e15d74"><a title="Switch 2 - Joy-Con Comparison" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/d56ed12e15d74/switch-2-joy-con-comparison.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Zion Grassl / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Anon:</strong> I do think this will be like the PS4&gt;PS5 upgrade where people on day one will have access to new games and a huge back catalogue, so not the “gold rush” that existed when Switch came out, and there was a fresh new store.</p>
<p><strong>Manfred Linzner:</strong> Switch 1 was very important for us. On launch day we had Fast RMX available, and later we released (among other games) <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/touryst">The Touryst</a> for it, which was one of our finest games so far according to press and players. So Nintendo Switch was super important to us. And the same is true for Nintendo Switch 2. We will support it on launch day with Fast Fusion and already [have] two more projects [planned] for it.</p>
<p><strong>Adam Tierney:</strong> There’s no info we can provide right now, but suffice to say, WayForward loves working with Nintendo to develop new and original games for all its systems, and we’re very excited to develop games for the Switch 2!</p>
<h2><strong>Do you have Switch 2 dev kits, and if so, how long have you had them?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>Manfred Linzner:</strong> As we were developing a launch title, we had dev kits, but we can't reveal any details.</p>
<p><strong>Sophie Smart:</strong> We’re currently in discussions with Nintendo about securing a dev kit.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>[it's] hard to feel excited when we don’t have any insight into timing for [dev kits] either. We can't plan.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>Anon:</strong> We’re one of the many devs who don’t have access to dev kits. Even though [we're] working on a large title now which we feel would be worthy of a dev kit, we have zero info. Even post-reveal, we’ve been given zero info, as have many other devs (even larger and more prestigious than us). So, [it's] hard to feel excited when we don’t have any insight into timing for them either. We can't plan.</p>
<h2><strong>How much impact does Switch 2’s increased power have on your approach to game development?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>James Montagna:</strong> It’s huge for us. More powerful hardware doesn’t just mean prettier graphics; it dramatically expands the possibilities for innovative and complex gameplay ideas that previously were just out of reach. Having fewer constraints on performance means we can experiment more boldly, push boundaries, and bring ambitious concepts to life. As a creator, that freedom is incredibly exciting… and it really feels like we're stepping into fresh territory creatively.</p>
<p><strong>Sophie Smart:</strong> At the end of the day, the power upgrades are not hugely rivalling other competitors. However, it will help us to make better versions of our existing games on Switch for Switch 2 and have versions of our less intensive games on Switch 2, which may not have been able to run on Switch.</p>
<figure data-uuid="ef5d00af12bae"><a title="Switch 2" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/ef5d00af12bae/switch-2.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Manfred Linzner:</strong> For Fast RMX on Nintendo Switch, there were only a few technical options for us on how to make a detailed yet high-performance game. On Nintendo Switch 2, we now have broader technical possibilities and much more power. We already learned a lot by creating Fast Fusion for Nintendo Switch 2, but we are looking forward to finding new untapped potential that is only possible with the new hardware.</p>
<p><strong>Andy Pearson:</strong> The increased power of the Switch 2 has a substantial impact on our development approach. It enables us to more faithfully preserve creators' original visions for their games, which is tremendously exciting for our team. The original Switch, while revolutionary in many ways, presented certain technical challenges when we aimed for simultaneous multi-platform releases.</p>
<p><strong>Gavin Price:</strong> For our last release, Yooka-Laylee &amp; The Impossible Lair, we set targets for Nintendo Switch early and other platforms followed on from it. We’ll probably take the same approach again moving forward for our multiplatform releases.</p>
<p><strong>Harris Foster:</strong> Any gain in power is a win for developers — whether it be the opportunity to throttle up visuals or increase performance under the hood. While we don’t have any specific Switch 2 anecdotes to share at this time, we’re feeling very positive about the spec bump the system is promising.</p>
<p><strong>Tomm Hulett:</strong> I wouldn't say it changes my approach to design at all because I tend to follow interesting ideas or compelling gameplay, but it will certainly be more pleasant asking my lead programmer to implement some of my wilder ideas! Anything that keeps the lead programmer happy is a plus in my book.</p>
<h2>Do you plan to support physical releases on Switch 2, and has your approach to this changed since the last console generation?</h2>
<p><strong>Andy Pearson:</strong> Yes, physical releases remain a core speciality for our company, and we intend to continue supporting this format with as many of our Switch 2 titles as possible. We recognise the importance of physical media to collectors and many Nintendo fans, and this commitment hasn't changed from the previous console generation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I do feel that we might need to see a Switch 2.5 or a ‘Pro’ version sooner rather than later</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>Sophie Smart:</strong> The physical landscape for games has tumbled over recent years. In our experience, it doesn’t always lead to profit. However, we still like to do it for some games because it’s really cool to have a physical box with art which you can hold in your hands of the thing you’ve worked on! We’ll likely end up taking the same approach with Switch 2.</p>
<figure data-uuid="3a309d43b2844"><a title="Switch Games" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/3a309d43b2844/switch-games.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Gemma Smith / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Adam Tierney:</strong> WayForward loves developing content that users can enjoy both digitally and physically. It’s our intention to continue that tradition with the Switch 2 and all future consoles.</p>
<p><strong>Gavin Price:</strong> We love physical, so I’m sure we will consider it when we have the chance. Our approach hasn’t changed, I think the physical market is still how it has been the past five or so years, with strong appetite amongst a very passionate fanbase plus a broader gaming audience who like to purchase and have something tangible for themselves or to gift others with.</p>
<p><strong>Manfred Linzner</strong><strong>:</strong> We love physical releases. For instance, Nintendo published our <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu-eshop/fast_racing_neo">FAST Racing NEO</a> on Wii U disc, and we had a couple of special releases with Super Rare Games for Nintendo Switch. However, as an indie developer with low-priced games, it is not easy to support physical releases, but we will keep trying where it makes sense.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>These responses have been edited for brevity and clarity.</em> <em>Thank you to everyone who took the time to talk to us.</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:176172,181060 @ 1766930520 --></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/its-huge-for-us-devs-talk-switch-2-reactions-dev-kit-disparity-future-plans]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Talking Point: Does Switch 2 Have Nintendo's Best Launch Line-Up Ever?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/talking-point-does-switch-2-have-nintendos-best-launch-line-up-ever</link>
            <guid>1392979</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="144beb58b1035"><a title="Switch 2 Launch Games" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/144beb58b1035/switch-2-launch-games.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p><em>Over the holiday season, we're republishing some of the best articles from Nintendo Life writers and contributors from</em> <em><a data-sk="tooltip_parent" data-stringify-link="https://www.nintendolife.com/tags/best-of-2025" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/tags/best-of-2025">2025</a></em><em>. This article was originally published in April. Enjoy!</em></p>
<hr>
<p>I don't know about you, but I'm already giving my shelf space a worried look as I consider the number of Switch 2 launch titles I want to pick up.</p>
<p>It's been just about a week since Nintendo revealed the Switch 2 and its 21 separate <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/nintendo-switch-2-launch-games-all-day-one-releases">launch games</a> (24 if you include those dropping on the NSO GameCube library), which, the more you think about it, is a truly wild number. Just for reference, the only Nintendo consoles that have pulled together a bigger launch line-up are the GBA in Japan (23 releases on day one) and the North American release of the Wii U (29). The big difference is that Switch 2 doesn't have the crutch of movie tie-ins to pad out its day one roster — no shade to stone-cold classics like the Wii's <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/happy_feet">Happy Feet</a> there.</p>
<p>The 5th June release schedule is packed with ports and re-releases, it's true, but the likes of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/cyberpunk-2077-ultimate-edition">Cyberpunk 2077</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/kunitsu-gami-path-of-the-goddess">Kunitsu-Gami: Path of the Goddess</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/split-fiction">Split Fiction</a> are all demonstrations of what the OG Switch couldn't do, with bigger worlds, better visuals, and snappier controls. Don't even get me started on the fact that there will be <em>two</em> improved Zelda games to revisit on launch day, too — that doesn't even count the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/04/pokemon-scarlet-and-violet-is-getting-a-free-performance-upgrade-on-switch-2">free patches some Switch games will be getting, either</a>.</p>
<p>On top of all that, there's a smattering of new releases to whet the whistle. Everyone and their dog is going to be playing <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a>, but <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/fast-fusion">Fast Fusion</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/deltarune">Deltarune</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/nintendo-switch-2-welcome-tour">Nintendo Switch 2 Welcome Tour</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/survival-kids">Survival Kids</a> will all be sitting there as well. The cup runneth over, indeed.</p>
<p>It all amounts to a pretty strong launch line-up, and while it might be a little light on first-party newbies, it pretty much bundles in something for everyone.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:183377 @ 1766929929 -->
<p>The question is, where does it rank among Nintendo's previous day-one attempts? Console launches aren't all Mario, Zelda and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/wii_sports">Wii Sports</a>, you know and, looking back at every other Nintendo launch line-up, Switch 2 might be up there with the best of them.</p>
<p>But we want to hear what you lovely lot think. We're sure that a learned bunch like yourselves will remember every launch title since the mid-80s, but just in case you need a refresher (heck, we did), we have listed 'em all from the NES to the Switch 2. We've kept the following limited to the consoles' North American launch line-ups for tidiness, but we'll point out any notable additions in Europe and Japan as we go.</p>
<p>So, which of these comes out on top?</p>
<nav><ul><li><span title="On This Page"></span></li></ul>
</nav>
<h2 id="nintendo-entertainment-system">Nintendo Entertainment System</h2>
<figure data-uuid="46dd404832807"><a title="NES" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/46dd404832807/nes.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Zion Grassl / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/arcade_archives_10-yard_fight">10-Yard Fight</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/baseball">Baseball</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/clu_clu_land">Clu Clu Land</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/duck_hunt">Duck Hunt</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/excitebike">Excitebike</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/golf">Golf</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/gyromite">Gyromite</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/hogans_alley">Hogan's Alley</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/ice_climber">Ice Climber</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/kung_fu">Kung Fu</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/pinball">PINBALL</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/soccer">Soccer</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/stack-up">Stack-Up</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/super_mario_bros">Super Mario Bros.</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/tennis">Tennis</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/wild_gunman">Wild Gunman</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/wrecking_crew">Wrecking Crew</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Some very big hitters to start things off there, with Duck Hunt, Super Mario Bros. and Excitebike headlining. Heck, the fact that they <em>all</em> came from Nintendo is quite the feat, too. Sure, the majority of them might not be all that astonishing, but it's a hell of a way to come out of the gate swinging.</p>
<p>Japan's Famicom release included none of the above, but it did launch with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/donkey_kong">Donkey Kong</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/donkey_kong_jr">Donkey Kong Jr.</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/popeye">Popeye</a>, so that's something.</p>
<h2 id="game-boy">Game Boy</h2>
<figure data-uuid="eaccc4934da72"><a title="Game Boy" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/eaccc4934da72/game-boy.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Zion Grassl / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gameboy/alleyway">Alleyway</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gameboy/baseball">Baseball</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gameboy/super_mario_land">Super Mario Land</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/tennis">Tennis</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gameboy/tetris">Tetris</a></li>
</ul>
<p>A lot smaller and far less influential of a line-up, but it does have Tetris, so move that up or down your scale as you please.</p>
<h2 id="super-nintendo-entertainment-system">Super Nintendo Entertainment System</h2>
<figure data-uuid="37b19c14178dd"><a title="SNES" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/37b19c14178dd/snes.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Zion Grassl / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/snes/f-zero">F-Zero</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/snes/gradius_iii">Gradius III</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/snes/pilotwings">Pilotwings</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/snes/simcity">SimCity</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/snes/super_mario_world">Super Mario World</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Having Super Mario World, Pilotwings and F-Zero right from the jump is an impressive play, but there's nothing much else to chew on. The European version also added <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/snes/super_tennis">Super Tennis</a>, but that's no all-timer.</p>
<h2 id="virtual-boy">Virtual Boy</h2>
<figure data-uuid="78b4ec388895c"><a title="Virtual Boy" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/78b4ec388895c/virtual-boy.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Damien McFerran / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/virtualboy/galactic_pinball">Galactic Pinball</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/virtualboy/marios_tennis">Mario's Tennis</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/virtualboy/red_alarm">Red Alarm</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/virtualboy/teleroboxer">Teleroboxer</a></li>
</ul>
<p>... We won't dwell on this one. Mario Tennis debuted, at least?</p>
<h2 id="nintendo-64">Nintendo 64</h2>
<figure data-uuid="f163e3ee4b4b5"><a title="N64" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/f163e3ee4b4b5/n64.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Zion Grassl / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/n64/pilotwings_64">Pilotwings 64</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/n64/super_mario_64">Super Mario 64</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Wow, one of the most influential games of all time and... Super Mario 64. We're joking, but it was slim pickings for the NA N64 launch line-up. <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/n64/cruisn_usa">Cruis'n USA</a> was almost part of that launch too, before it failed to meet Nintendo's standards and was pulled. It arrived later, at least...</p>
<p>The likes of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/n64/star_wars_shadows_of_the_empire">Star Wars: Shadows of the Empire</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/n64/turok_dinosaur_hunter">Turok</a> would make the European launch roster, but even then, it's a short list for one of the Big N's most fondly remembered consoles.</p>
<h2 id="game-boy-color">Game Boy Color</h2>
<figure data-uuid="060717d065264"><a title="Game Boy Color" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/060717d065264/game-boy-color.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Zion Grassl / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gbc/pocket_bomberman">Pocket Bomberman</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gbc/tetris_dx">Tetris DX</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Backwards compatibility obviously helped with the appeal of the GBC's launch line-up, because without replaying some oldies, the list of new releases is pretty slim.</p>
<h2 id="game-boy-advance">Game Boy Advance</h2>
<figure data-uuid="fa6c45498f81d"><a title="GBA" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/fa6c45498f81d/gba.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Zion Grassl / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<ul>
<li><strong>Army Men Advance</strong></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gba/castlevania_circle_of_the_moon">Castlevania: Circle of the Moon</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gba/chuchu_rocket">ChuChu Rocket!</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gameboy/earthworm_jim">Earthworm Jim</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/snes/super_fire_pro_wrestling">Fire Pro Wrestling</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gba/f-zero_maximum_velocity">F-Zero Maximum Velocity</a></li>
<li><strong>GT Advance Championship Racing</strong></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gba/iridion_3d">Iridion 3D</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gba/konami_krazy_racers">Konami Krazy Racers</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gba/namco_museum">Namco Museum</a></li>
<li><strong>Pinobee: Wings of Adventure</strong></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gba/pitfall_the_mayan_adventure">Pitfall: The Mayan Adventure</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gba/rayman_advance">Rayman Advance</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/n64/ready_2_rumble_boxing_round_2">Ready 2 Rumble Boxing: Round 2</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gba/super_dodge_ball_advance">Super Dodge Ball Advance</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gba/super_mario_advance">Super Mario Advance</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gba/tony_hawks_pro_skater_2">Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 2</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Say what you will about the specifics, but the GBA launch line-up is pretty stacked. There are an awful lot of ports, it's true, but you can't tell us that seeing the likes of Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 2 and Super Mario Advance running on that tiny handheld isn't impressive.</p>
<p>Adding fuel to the fire, the Japanese and European launches also landed <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gba/kuru_kuru_kururin">Kuru Kuru Kururin</a>, and if you've played that on NSO, you <em>know</em> it's a gem.</p>
<h2 id="gamecube">GameCube</h2>
<figure data-uuid="46134f5516622"><a title="GameCube" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/46134f5516622/gamecube.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Zion Grassl / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/all-star_baseball_2002">All-Star Baseball 2002</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/batman_vengeance">Batman: Vengeance</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/crazy_taxi">Crazy Taxi</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/dave_mirra_freestyle_bmx_2">Dave Mirra Freestyle BMX 2</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/disneys_tarzan_untamed">Disney's Tarzan: Untamed</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/luigis_mansion">Luigi's Mansion</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/madden_nfl_2002">Madden NFL 2002</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/nhl_hitz_20-02">NHL Hitz 2002</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/star_wars_rogue_squadron_ii_rogue_leader">Star Wars Rogue Squadron II: Rogue Leader</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/super_monkey_ball">Super Monkey Ball</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/tony_hawks_pro_skater_3">Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/wave_race_blue_storm">Wave Race: Blue Storm</a></li>
</ul>
<p>At the time, Luigi's Mansion seemed like the strangest title to launch a console with, but it's grown into one of our favourite series from the Big N. Six separate sports titles is certainly a move (and a sign of a changing demographic), but it's difficult to be too snarky when our beloved Rogue Squadron II is sitting right there.</p>
<p>The European release also added the likes of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/sonic_adventure_2_battle">Sonic Adventure 2: Battle</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/pac-man_world_2">Pac-Man World 2</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/espn_international_winter_sports_2002">ESPN International Winter Sports</a>.</p>
<h2 id="ds">DS</h2>
<figure data-uuid="67f9f0baa51ae"><a title="DS" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/67f9f0baa51ae/ds.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Damian McFerran / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/asphalt_urban_gt">Asphalt: Urban GT</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/project_rub">Project Rub</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/madden_nfl_2005">Madden NFL 2005</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/metroid_prime_hunters_first_hunt">Metroid Prime Hunters: First Hunt</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/spider-man_2">Spider-Man 2</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/super_mario_64_ds">Super Mario 64 DS</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/urbz_sims_in_the_city">The Urbz: Sims in the City</a></li>
</ul>
<p>On paper, a new Metroid Prime and 3D Mario make for a dynamite launch line-up. In practice, First Hunt and Mario 64 DS really aren't the cream of the crop.</p>
<p>The European and Japanese releases also included <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/rayman_ds">Rayman DS</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/pokemon_dash">Pokémon Dash</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/warioware_touched">WarioWare Touched!</a></p>
<h2 id="wii">Wii</h2>
<figure data-uuid="9a236027b5a5d"><a title="Wii" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/9a236027b5a5d/wii.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Zion Grassl / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/avatar_the_last_airbender">Avatar: The Last Airbender</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/call_of_duty_3">Call Of Duty 3</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/cars">Cars</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/dragon_ball_z_budokai_tenkaichi_2">Dragon Ball Z: Budokai Tenkaichi 2</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/excite_truck">Excite Truck</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/grim_adventures_of_billy_and_mandy">The Grim Adventures of Billy &amp; Mandy</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/gt_pro_series">GT Pro Series</a></li>
<li><strong>Happy Feet</strong></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/madden_nfl_07">Madden NFL 07</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/marvel_ultimate_alliance">Marvel: Ultimate Alliance</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/monster_4x4_world_circuit">Monster 4x4 World Circuit</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/need_for_speed_carbon">Need For Speed: Carbon</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/rampage_total_destruction">Rampage: Total Destruction</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/rayman_raving_rabbids">Rayman Raving Rabbids</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/red_steel">Red Steel</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/spongebob_squarepants_creature_from_the_krusty_krab">SpongeBob SquarePants: Creature from the Krusty Krab</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/super_monkey_ball_banana_blitz">Super Monkey Ball: Banana Blitz</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/tony_hawks_downhill_jam">Tony Hawk's Downhill Jam</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/legend_of_zelda_twilight_princess">The Legend of Zelda: Twilight Princess</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/trauma_center_second_opinion">Trauma Center: Second Opinion</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/wii_sports">Wii Sports</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Ah, the age of the movie tie-in. Despite the cash grabs, the Wii did launch with Twilight Princess and Wii Sports — the latter of which might just be one of the most iconic launch titles of all time.</p>
<h2 id="h3ds">3DS</h2>
<figure data-uuid="80e8d4ed5ad8b"><a title="3DS" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/80e8d4ed5ad8b/3ds.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Zion Grassl / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds/asphalt_3d">Asphalt 3D</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds/bust_a_move_universe">Bust-A-Move Universe</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds/combat_of_giants_dinosaurs_3d">Combat of Giants: Dinosaurs 3D</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds/lego_star_wars_iii_the_clone_wars">LEGO Star Wars III: The Clone Wars</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds/madden_nfl_football">Madden NFL Football</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds/nintendogs_plus_cats">nintendogs + cats: Golden Retriever &amp; New Friends</a></li>
<li><strong>nintendogs + cats: French Bulldog &amp; New Friends</strong></li>
<li><strong>nintendogs + cats: Toy Poodle &amp; New Friends</strong></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds/pilotwings_resort">Pilotwings Resort</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds/pro_evolution_soccer_2011_3d">Pro Evolution Soccer 2011 3D</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds/rayman_3d">Rayman 3D</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds/ridge_racer_3d">Ridge Racer 3D</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds/samurai_warriors_chronicles">Samurai Warriors: Chronicles</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds/steel_diver">Steel Diver</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds/super_monkey_ball_3d">Super Monkey Ball 3D</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds/super_street_fighter_iv_3d_edition">Super Street Fighter IV 3D Edition</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds/sims_3">The Sims 3</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds/tom_clancys_ghost_recon_shadow_wars_3d">Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon: Shadow Wars 3D</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds/tom_clancys_splinter_cell_3d">Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell 3D</a></li>
</ul>
<p>There's a decent amount of fun in the above list, but no real killer apps. Thank goodness for DS backwards compatibility, hey? It's no wonder Nintendo launched the Ambassador Program shortly afterwards...</p>
<h2 id="wii-u">Wii U</h2>
<figure data-uuid="9a9eed386b868"><a title="Wii U" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/9a9eed386b868/wii-u.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Zion Grassl / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/assassins_creed_iii">Assassin’s Creed III</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/batman_arkham_city_armored_edition">Batman: Arkham City Armored Edition</a></li>
<li><strong>Ben 10: Omniverse</strong></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/call_of_duty_black_ops_ii">Call of Duty: Black Ops II</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/darksiders_ii">Darksiders II</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/disney_epic_mickey_2_the_power_of_two">Disney Epic Mickey 2: The Power of Two</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/espn_sports_connection">ESPN Sports Connection</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/fifa_13">FIFA 13</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/funky_barn">Funky Barn</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/game_party_champions">Game Party Champions</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/just_dance_4">Just Dance 4</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/madden_nfl_13">Madden NFL 13</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/mass_effect_3">Mass Effect 3</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/nba_2k13">NBA 2K13</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/new_super_mario_bros_u">New Super Mario Bros. U</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/ninja_gaiden_3_razors_edge">NINJA GAIDEN 3: Razor’s Edge</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/nintendo_land">Nintendo Land</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/rabbids_land">Rabbids Land</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/scribblenauts_unlimited">Scribblenauts Unlimited</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/sing_party">SiNG Party</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/skylanders_giants">Skylanders Giants</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/sonic_and_all-stars_racing_transformed">Sonic &amp; All-Stars Racing Transformed</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/tank_tank_tank">Tank! Tank! Tank!</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/tekken_tag_tournament_2">TEKKEN TAG TOURNAMENT 2 Wii U Edition</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/transformers_prime">Transformers Prime</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/warriors_orochi_3_hyper">Warriors Orochi 3 Hyper</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/wipeout_3">Wipeout 3</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/your_shape_fitness_evolved_2013">Your Shape Fitness Evolved 2013</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/zombiu">ZombiU</a></li>
</ul>
<p>New Super Mario Bros. U was a nice addition, ZombiU was a fine display of the GamePad's features, and Nintendo Land was one of the best games on the console. Sure, everything else is a bit naff, but it's a shame this cadence died out so quickly.</p>
<h2 id="switch">Switch</h2>
<figure data-uuid="748cef2e480c3"><a title="Switch" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/748cef2e480c3/switch.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Damien McFerran / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/1-2-switch">1-2-Switch</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/fast_rmx">Fast RMX</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/i_am_setsuna">I Am Setsuna</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/just_dance_2017">Just Dance 2017</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/shovel_knight_specter_of_torment">Shovel Knight: Specter of Torment</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/shovel_knight_treasure_trove">Shovel Knight: Treasure Trove</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/skylanders_imaginators">Skylanders Imaginators</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/snipperclips_-_cut_it_out_together">Snipperclips - Cut It Out Together!</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/super_bomberman_r">Super Bomberman R</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/legend_of_zelda_breath_of_the_wild">The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild</a></li>
</ul>
<p>One of the greatest games of all time, a couple of little gimmicks, and a beloved indie don't make for a bad launch line-up, we'll admit. <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/mario_kart_8_deluxe">Mario Kart 8 Deluxe</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/super_mario_odyssey">Super Mario Odyssey</a> were real killers a few months later, but we're looking at <em>day one only</em> here, people.</p>
<h2 id="switch-2">Switch 2</h2>
<figure data-uuid="eb6b7847894ea"><a title="Switch 2" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/eb6b7847894ea/switch-2.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Zion Grassl / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/arcade-archives-2-ridge-racer">Arcade Archives 2: Ridge Racer</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/bravely-default-flying-fairy-hd-remaster">Bravely Default: Flying Fairy HD Remaster</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/cyberpunk-2077-ultimate-edition">Cyberpunk 2077: Ultimate Edition</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/deltarune">Deltarune</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/fast-fusion">Fast Fusion</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/fortnite">Fortnite</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hitman-world-of-assassination-signature-edition">Hitman World of Assassination - Signature Edition</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hogwarts-legacy">Hogwarts Legacy</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/kunitsu-gami-path-of-the-goddess">Kunitsu-Gami: Path of the Goddess</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/nintendo-switch-2-welcome-tour">Nintendo Switch 2 Welcome Tour</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/nobunagas-ambition-awakening-complete-edition">NOBUNAGA'S AMBITION Awakening Complete Edition</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/puyo-puyo-tetris-2s">Puyo Puyo Tetris 2S</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/rune-factory-guardians-of-azuma-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Rune Factory: Guardians of Azuma</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/sid-meiers-civilization-vii-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Sid Meier's Civilization VII - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/split-fiction">Split Fiction</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/street-fighter-6-years-1-2-fighters-edition">Street Fighter VI: Years 1-2 Fighters Edition</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/survival-kids">Survival Kids</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-nintendo-switch-2-edition">The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-nintendo-switch-2-edition">The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/yakuza-0-directors-cut">Yakuza 0: Director's Cut</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Ports, first-party newbies and 'Nintendo Switch 2 Edition' rereleases. It makes for quite the day-one line-up, no?</p>
<hr>
<p><em>So, come on then, it's time to vote! Which Nintendo console do you think had the best launch line-up? You can make your choice in the following poll, but be sure to head to the comments afterwards to let us know what you picked.</em></p>
</section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/talking-point-does-switch-2-have-nintendos-best-launch-line-up-ever]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>