<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 14:03:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Square Enix Details Octopath Traveler 0's Switch 2 Performance And Resolution]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/square-enix-details-octopath-traveler-0s-switch-2-performance-and-resolution</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/square-enix-details-octopath-traveler-0s-switch-2-performance-and-resolution.1288677/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Safe travels</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="Octopath Traveler 0" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/ac9d54fdc8d0f/octopath-traveler-0.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Square Enix</em></figcaption></figure><p>We still have a couple of months to go before <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/octopath-traveler-0">Octopath Traveler 0</a> lands on Switch 2, but Square Enix has lifted the specs lid early, so we all know what to expect from a performance and resolution standpoint.</p>
<p>The info was shared in a new update to the game's <a href="https://www.jp.square-enix.com/octopathtraveler0/">Japanese website</a> (thanks for the heads up, <a href="https://www.jp.square-enix.com/octopathtraveler0/">Nintendo Everything</a>), in which the dev posted an info table containing everything you need to know about the game on all platforms.</p>
<p>Fortunately, things are looking rather good for those with the latest Nintendo hardware. The Switch 2 version of the game will run at up to <strong>60fps</strong>, with a <strong>1920x1080</strong> resolution. The Switch 1, on the other hand, keeps things slightly lower and will play at up to <strong>30fps / 1280x720p</strong>. The site doesn't currently specify any handheld/docked discrepancies, so we might have to wait until release to see the differences in action.</p><div><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067jgrtsw&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><figcaption><p><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C1rrCdi_XjA" rel="noopener">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></p>
<p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>833k</span></a></p>
</figcaption></figure></div>
<p>Another interesting addition to the performance table is the row that specifies how each version will fare in the game's town builder mode. The Switch 2 will allow up to 400 buildings to be placed in one area, while the Switch 1 edition will only allow up to 250.</p>
<p>For those wondering, this puts the Switch 2 version on the same level as the Octopath Traveler 0 PS4 release. The PS5 and Xbox Series X will muster up to 120fps at 3840x2160, with the opportunity to customise town with up to 500 buildings, while the Series S boasts 120fps at the slightly lower 1920x1080p with the same 500-buildings option.</p>
<p>It's always nice to get an idea of these numbers early, and the boosted frame rate and resolution should make the Switch 2 version play like a dream if the former runs smoothly — heck, look at how wonderful the first two games appeared on Switch 1.</p>
<p>Octopath Traveler 0 will launch on Switch 1 and 2 on <strong>4th December</strong>. Square Enix has announced that there are <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/octopath-0-is-a-game-key-card-on-switch-2-and-square-enix-has-no-plans-for-a-switch-1-upgrade-option">no plans for an upgrade path</a> between the two, and the S2's physical will arrive as a Game-Key Card (because of course it will).</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:187027,185910 @ 1756993515 -->
<p><em>What do you make of these performance numbers? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.jp.square-enix.com/octopathtraveler0/" rel="noopener" href="https://www.jp.square-enix.com/octopathtraveler0/">jp.square-enix.com</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://www.jp.square-enix.com/octopathtraveler0/" rel="noopener" href="https://www.jp.square-enix.com/octopathtraveler0/">jp.square-enix.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/6e33688a151d8f97e5249eb01b86f75c @ 1756993515 --></div></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/square-enix-details-octopath-traveler-0s-switch-2-performance-and-resolution]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Round Up: Pour One Out For These 6 Brave Games Launching On 'Silksong Day']]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/round-up-pour-one-out-for-these-6-brave-games-launching-on-silksong-day</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/round-up-pour-one-out-for-these-6-brave-games-launching-on-silksong-day.1288605/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure><a title="Other Games - Silksong Day" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/085fd316af72f/other-games-silksong-day.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>For many of you, today – <strong>4th September, 2025</strong> – will forever be known for one reason: the day that <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hollow-knight-silksong">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a> finally launched on Switch and Switch 2.</p>
<p>But of course, while Silksong will undoubtedly soak up a <em>heck</em> of a lot of attention, the day doesn't just belong to one game. In fact, there are quite a few titles launching on the Switch eShop, and we'd like to highlight a few that we think deserve a bit of attention.</p>
<p>Yes, the brave souls behind these games have decided, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/demonschool-gets-last-minute-delay-to-avoid-silksong">unlike others</a>, not to delay their intended release in order to avoid clashing with Silksong. That warrants the doffing of one's hat, if you ask us. We're not going to cover everything launching today, because frankly the Switch is still being bombarded with some rather questionable games, but there are definitely a few that are worth looking into.</p>
<p>So if you're <em>really</em> not keen on checking out Silksong, then perhaps one of the following might be more up your alley...</p>
<nav><ul><li><span title="On This Page"></span></li></ul>
</nav>
<h2 id="adventure-of-samsara"><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/adventure_of_samsara">Adventure of Samsara</a></h2>
<p>Atari's latest is a classic metroidvania that pays homage to the original <a href="https://www.timeextension.com/games/atari2600/adventure">Adventure</a> from the Atari 2600. Developed by Ilex Games, its heavy, slow-paced movement and combat are almost the exact opposite to Silksong's more free-flowing gameplay. Still, we thought it was decent and awarded it a <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/adventure-of-samsara">7/10</a> in our recent review.</p>

<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:186856 @ 1756991281 -->
<h2 id="camper-van-make-it-home"><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/camper_van_make_it_home">Camper Van: Make it Home</a></h2>
<p>One of our favourite games in recent weeks was <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/tiny_bookshop">Tiny Bookshop</a>, which we described as the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/tiny-bookshop">"epitome of cosy"</a>. Camper Van: Make It Home looks to provide the same kind of vibes, albeit with a lot more focus on meticulously decorating and rearranging the interior and exterior of your camper van. It looks lovely, and a fine way to escape from the drab reality of life.</p>


<h2 id="dark-deity-2"><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/dark_deity_2">Dark Deity 2</a></h2>
<p>Developer Sword &amp; Axe made a point of sticking to its guns and launching Dark Deity 2 alongside Silksong, and we commend such bravery. <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/dark_deity">The first game</a> was a lovely spin on <strong>Fire Emblem</strong>'s gameplay, and the sequel looks to take this even further. If you're into retro-inspired tactical RPGs, then this might be worth checking out.</p>

<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:187061 @ 1756994462 -->
<h2 id="fling-to-the-finish"><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/fling_to_the_finish">Fling to the Finish</a></h2>
<p>This one admittedly wasn't on our radar, but upon viewing the recent console trailer, it actually looks like a whale of a time. It's one of those multiplayer games where you have to work alongside a partner to reach the end of the level. The twist here is that you're literally tied together with an elastic band, and so you need to fling your partner up walls and across gaps to succeed. It's got local and online support with cross-platform compatibility.</p>

<h2 id="splatterbot"><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/splatterbot">Splatterbot</a></h2>
<p>Do you like <strong>Splatoon</strong>? Of course you do, for goodness' sake. Well, Splatterbot is remarkably similar in that you face off against up to three local competitors to make the most mess in each stage. So each player (or team) is designated a certain colour, and all you have to do is cover as much of the ground as possible while slamming into your enemies to knock them off-course. It looks awesome!</p>

<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:169277 @ 1756993568 -->
<h2 id="mandragora-whispers-of-the-witch-tree"><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/mandragora_whispers_of_the_witch_tree">Mandragora: Whispers of the Witch Tree</a></h2>
<p>Another action RPG to add to the list, Mandragora appeared on other consoles recently and has now joined the fray on the Switch. We're not completely sold on the visuals here, but the artistic design is solid and the gameplay looks like it could potentially scratch that <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/dark_souls_remastered">Dark Souls</a> itch.</p>

<hr>
<p>So that's yer lot! Reckon we've missed anything here? Then let us know with a comment down in the usual place. And no, we're not including <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/star-wars-outlaws">Star Wars Outlaws</a> here; that one's big enough on its own thanks to Ubisoft and Disney. We'll have a review for you soon though, don't worry about that!</p>

<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:187423,187328 @ 1756994462 --></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/round-up-pour-one-out-for-these-6-brave-games-launching-on-silksong-day]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>