<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 16:33:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anniversary: No Way Is Super Mario World 2: Yoshi's Island 30 Years Old Already]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/anniversary-no-way-is-super-mario-world-2-yoshis-island-30-years-old-already</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/anniversary-no-way-is-super-mario-world-2-yoshis-island-30-years-old-already.1262658/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Yep, seems like it</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure><a title="Yoshi's Island" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/1eb08540a0165/yoshis-island.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure><p>In yet another indication that time is indeed marching on and on, it seems that <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/snes/super_mario_world_2_yoshis_island">Super Mario World 2: Yoshi's Island</a> has somehow turned 30 years old.</p>
<p>Released in Japan on <strong>5th August 1995</strong>, Yoshi's Island marked a significant departure from its predecessor, yet received widespread critical acclaim regardless. It also happened to be the last 2D entry in the Super Mario series for over a decade before <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/new_super_mario_bros">New Super Mario Bros.</a> followed in 2006. And if we're being honest, the DS entry definitely lacked some of the ingenuity displayed in Yoshi's Island.</p>
<p>'Ingenuity' is really the key word here. The original <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/snes/super_mario_world">Super Mario World</a> had this in spades, so Yoshi's Island had an awful lot to live up to. But by shifting the gameplay to focus on Yoshi, who was once merely a secondary character, players could now execute several new abilities, including the 'flutter' jump, egg throwing, and simply gobbling up and spitting out your enemies.</p>

<p>If that wasn't enough, environments within the game could actually be destroyed, whether it be from a well-placed egg throw or from one of the game's many enemies. We make a big fuss about how well <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/donkey-kong-bananza">Donkey Kong Bananza</a> does environment destruction in 2025, but for those who perhaps weren't around 30 years ago, seeing something similar in an SNES game was simply astounding.</p>
<p>Oh, and let's not forget that you can turn in a helicopter. Amazing scenes.</p>
<p>So take a bow, Yoshi's Island. Amongst the likes of Super Mario World, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/super_mario_bros_3">Super Mario Bros. 3</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/super_mario_galaxy">Super Mario Galaxy</a>, you perhaps get forgotten a bit too often for our liking. But you're still one of our favourites, and you remain one of the greatest 2D platformers of all time (even if our beloved editor <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2020/08/soapbox_25_years_on_i_still_cant_get_into_yoshis_island">couldn't get on with it...</a>).</p>

<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/snes/related-articles:79426,91031 @ 1754411404 -->
<p><em>What are your favourite memories of Yoshi's Island on the SNES? Leave a comment in the usual place and let us know.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/anniversary-no-way-is-super-mario-world-2-yoshis-island-30-years-old-already]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mario Voice Actor Charles Martinet Will Appear At Comic Con In Birmingham]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/mario-voice-actor-charles-martinet-will-appear-at-comic-con-in-birmingham</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mario-voice-actor-charles-martinet-will-appear-at-comic-con-in-birmingham.1262616/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Event kicks off in November</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure><a title="Charles Martinet" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/fb7e2186602c9/charles-martinet.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>Charles Martinet may not be voicing Mario anymore, but that doesn't mean he isn't still deeply involved in the promotion of Nintendo's enduring mascot.</p>
<p>As such, the voice actor will be making an appearance at this year's MCM Comic Con in Bimingham from <strong>28th - 30th November, 2025</strong>. Martinet will be there for all three days providing photograph and autograph opportunities, alongside taking part in a panel on Saturday, 29th November at 12:30pm.</p>
<p>This will be free to all Saturday and Weekend ticket holders, and Martinet will be sharing vocal inspirations and techniques as well as stories behind the development of his games.</p>

<p>MCM Comic Con will take place at the NEC in Birmingham and will also include Neil Newbon as a guest on the Friday and Saturday, another voice actor known for his work on titles such as <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/baldurs_gate_3">Baldur's Gate 3</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/resident_evil_village_cloud">Resident Evil: Village</a>.</p>
<p>Tickets are available now via the <a href="https://www.mcmcomiccon.com/birmingham/en-us/tickets.html">official website</a>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/super-mario/related-articles:183748,171160 @ 1754410951 -->
<p><em>Will you be attending MCM Comic Con this year? Are you hoping to meet Mr. Martinet? Let us know with a comment.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/mario-voice-actor-charles-martinet-will-appear-at-comic-con-in-birmingham]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kirby And The Forgotten Land Switch 2 Trailer Showcases More New Mouthful Modes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/kirby-and-the-forgotten-land-switch-2-trailer-showcases-more-new-mouthful-modes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kirby-and-the-forgotten-land-switch-2-trailer-showcases-more-new-mouthful-modes.1262523/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Sign of the times</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Nintendo has released a brand new overview trailer for the catchily-titled <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/kirby-and-the-forgotten-land-nintendo-switch-2-edition-plus-star-crossed-world">Kirby and the Forgotten Land - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition + Star-Crossed World</a>, and it has given us our first look at a new batch of Mouthful Mode transformations.</p>
<p>We first locked eyes on Spring Mouth way back at the game's Switch 2 reveal, but Gear Mouth and Sign Mouth are completely new! Gear Mouth gives Kirb some sweet rolling abilities, granting him the power to stick to walls and roll across moving platforms with ease. Sign Mouth, meanwhile, turns the pink puffball into a makeshift sledge for top-speed downhill racing. Side note: we're a little bit in love with Sign Mouth.</p>
<p>Outside of these newbies, the trailer provides a bit of clarity on the game's Star-Crossed World expansion, making clear that you'll be able to dive right in after you've finished the first area. It also highlights the new Colosseum mode, Ultimate Cup Z - EX, which looks to provide a more challenging Boss Rush for those after an extra slice of difficulty.</p>
<p>We're also pleased to see the confirmation that the Switch 2's improved graphics and faster frame rates will be put to good use in the main game and not <em>just</em> the expansion — we're looking at you, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/super-mario-party-jamboree-nintendo-switch-2-edition-plus-jamboree-tv">Super Mario Party Jamboree - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition + Jamboree TV</a>.</p>
<p>Remember, this one arrives on Switch 2 on <strong>28th August</strong> as both a stand-alone purchase and an upgrade pack.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:180588 @ 1754409414 -->
<p><em>What do you make of these new Mouthful Modes? Do you have a new favourite, or is Carby still number one? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/kirby-and-the-forgotten-land-switch-2-trailer-showcases-more-new-mouthful-modes]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>