<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:59:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Rogue 'Em Up' Absolum's New Gameplay Trailer Is Packed With Fighting, Fantasy And Frogs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/rogue-em-up-absolums-new-gameplay-trailer-is-packed-with-fighting-fantasy-and-frogs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rogue-em-up-absolums-new-gameplay-trailer-is-packed-with-fighting-fantasy-and-frogs.1301748/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Arriving on Switch next month</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>We've been keeping an eye on <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/absolum">Absolum</a>'s roguelike / beat 'em up fusion since we first went <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/previews/hands-on-absolum-dead-cells-meets-streets-of-rage-4-in-an-effortlessly-stylish-rogue-em-up">hands-on</a> with it earlier this year. Ahead of its launch on <strong>9th October</strong>, publisher and co-developer Dotemu has today revealed a new gameplay trailer, and it looks every bit as stylish as we were expecting.</p>
<p>Aside from giving us a closer look at the fantasy beat 'em up action, the new trailer showcases some of the game's meta progression, helpful additions like co-op and recruitments, and explains how your path through the lands of Talamh can produce permanent game changes.</p>
<p>It's also a nice opportunity to get reacquainted with the four main Absolum heroes: sturdy gun-wielding dwarf Karl, well-rounded swordsman Galandra, acrobatic rogue Cider and ranged frog wizard Brome — yes, <em>frog wizard</em>.</p>
<p>If you want a closer look after checking out the above trailer, here's a handful of screens from Dotemu:</p>

<p>It looks like a blast, and if our brief hands-on time was anything to go by, it will be — assuming it scrubs up nicely on Switch. Every game under the sun seems to be coming our way in October, but this one might just be worth making some room for.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/switch-eshop/related-articles:178416 @ 1758213518 -->
<p><em>What do you make of Absolum? Will you be picking it up next month? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/rogue-em-up-absolums-new-gameplay-trailer-is-packed-with-fighting-fantasy-and-frogs]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Retro-Styled Isometric Puzzler 'Lumo 2' Dimension-Shifts Its Way Onto Switch This October]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/retro-styled-isometric-puzzler-lumo-2-dimension-shifts-its-way-onto-switch-this-october</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/retro-styled-isometric-puzzler-lumo-2-dimension-shifts-its-way-onto-switch-this-october.1301652/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Retro isometric puzzle sweetness incoming!</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>We really enjoyed <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/lumo">Lumo</a> when it launched on Switch back in 2017, awarding the isometric action-puzzler <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch/lumo">an 8/10</a> and saying that it "provides a modern isometric platformer, offering (as you'd expect) improved audio-visual presentation over the classics of the genre, whilst still providing the same kind of entertainment."</p>
<p>Numskull has announced that the sequel, aptly named <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/lumo_2">Lumo 2</a>, will launch on Switch on <strong>17th October</strong>.</p>
<p>Now, if you're around the same sort of age as this writer, you'll get a warm and fuzzy feeling inside whilst checking out the new trailer for the game (above), as just like its predecessor, Lumo 2 seems intent on reviving this lost-but-very-much-still-loved 'sub-genre' from an unnecessarily early grave. Yes, that's right, bring back the iso-action-puzzler, and do it this instant. Please.</p>
<p>Lumo 2 comes in both digital and physical flavours, with a deluxe physical edition rocking a soundtrack cassette and "other retro goodies", in an '80s-themed collector’s box. Digital will set you back <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/en-gb/Games/Nintendo-Switch-games/Lumo-2-2897116.html?srsltid=AfmBOoq1-0-59adaTlVn8ka3KrESQM846ZPam5ryA_Iu2Cf9KUagzP3d">£19.99 / €22.99 / $24.99</a>, whereas the standard physical comes in at £34.99 / €39.99. And that snazzy collector's box is £49.99 / €59.99.</p>

<p>With plenty of nods to classics of the genre, and gaming culture of the period, there should be plenty to enjoy here when the game drops in a few weeks. For now, though, here's more from the press release:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Lumo 2 is a love letter to the 8-bit era and to the Golden Age of British gaming – so expect collectibles galore and retro-inspired isometric visuals, all with the polished mechanics of a modern platformer.</p>
<p>In Lumo 2, players can experience:<br>
- Retro‑inspired puzzle platforming - A modern sequel built on the charm and artistry of early isometric British classics<br>
- Classic Collectibles - Collect 25 vintage cassettes and 20 ducks hidden in inventive locations, rewarding exploration and persistence<br>
- Evolving Gameplay - Traverse over 100 shifting dimensions and portals; mini-games and genre-bending levels surprise around every corner"</p>
</blockquote>

<p><em>Have you played Lumo? Looking forward to the follow-up as much as us? Let us know!</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:73021,71217 @ 1758213079 --></section></article><div><p>PJ is a staff writer across Hookshot Media. He's been playing video games pretty much nonstop since the early 1980s, which is ages ago. Favourite genres include RPGs, puzzle games and lovely big single player adventures of all kinds. The weirder the better.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/PJOReilly"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('PJOReilly');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/retro-styled-isometric-puzzler-lumo-2-dimension-shifts-its-way-onto-switch-this-october]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>