<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 16:57:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Boulder Dash 40th Anniversary Smashes Onto Switch This Summer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/boulder-dash-40th-anniversary-smashes-onto-switch-this-summer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/boulder-dash-40th-anniversary-smashes-onto-switch-this-summer.1216929/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/boulder-dash-40th-anniversary-smashes-onto-switch-this-summer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section>

<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2024/08/looks-like-classic-puzzler-boulder-dash-is-getting-a-40th-anniversary-re-release">We reported back last year</a> on the existence of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/boulder_dash_40th_anniversary">Boulder Dash 40th Anniversary</a>, and now we know that the game will launch on <strong>July 24th</strong> for Switch, and it'll only set you back £19.99/$19.99. Heck, this time you can even have a gander at how it all looks in motion in the above gameplay vid. Result!</p>
<p>Yes, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/arcade/boulder_dash">Boulder Dash</a>, which was first released all the way back in 1984 (when this writer was already busting heads in the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gba/bruce_lee_return_of_the_legend">Bruce Lee</a> game on his trusty C64), has seen a few re-releases before, including on its <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/boulder_dash_30th_anniversary">30th anniversary</a>, but this time it seems there are a few more changes to the classic formula, including a level editor for sharing your own creations online.</p><p><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><a id="yt-2" title="Play" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C1rrCdi_XjA"></a><figcaption>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>821k</span></a></figcaption><figcaption><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C1rrCdi_XjA">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></figcaption></figure></p>
<p>According to the game's official press release, this new effort features "Brand New Levels, New Design, New Challenges, New Worlds, Plus More!" That does sound exciting, to be fair.</p>
<p>With 180 levels to blast through in total, and with Rockford returning to his role as chief...eh...smasher of rocks (alongside what appears to be a few other selectable characters) this certainly looks the business, and although the art style is almost alarmingly crisp, it <em>does</em> harken back to the OG, and it looks as th</p>

<p>It seems as though the devs have been more than diligent too, with Boulder Dash world champions invited to play the game and Boulder Dashes 1, 2 and 3 all in the mix within this one revamp, as BBG explains;</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>“We pursued two goals: Firstly, we wanted to bring the first three parts Boulder Dash I, II and III to life as faithfully as possible on current machines. Secondly, we wanted to spice up the classic gameplay with contemporary visuals and suitable new ideas such as growing walls, slime, an enemy generator, eggs and other things.<br>
<em>On top we have integrated a level editor which allows the users to create, play and share all these levels to Boulder Dash players worldwide</em>..."</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>In the OG Boulder Dash games, as is the case here, your task is to open the exit on each screen, which sounds simple but is in fact an engrossing mix of puzzling, dodging and timing your moves to deal with foes. It was a revelation back in the day and, with the right treatment, the gameplay here should stand the test of time well.</p>

<p>Otherwise, leave you with a "fact's attack" from the press release and some screens to satiate long-time Boulder Dash fans in the meantime.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>- 6 new, never-before-seen worlds<br>
- 3 new worlds created by hardcore the fans<br>
- 180 completely new, balanced, and refined levels<br>
- Variety of new and unique items, including growing walls, slime, enemy generator, eggs, plus more<br>
- Construction kit to create, share, or download other players’ levels<br>
- Distinctive visual style that aims to blend original color schemes with contemporary themes<br>
- Option to select and play for one of the three main heroes, each crafted in line with the game’s original vision<br>
- Music and sounds composed by Germany’s most famous video game musician Chris Huelsbeck (Giana Sisters, Turrican, Star Wars Rogue Squadron, Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Splintered Fate and many more).</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p><em>Boulder Dash fan? Looking forward to this revamp? Be sure to let us know!</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:120610,96714,170208 @ 1749745802 --></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.gamespress.com/BOULDER-DASH-40th-Anniversary---The-Real-Mccoy" rel="noopener" href="https://www.gamespress.com/BOULDER-DASH-40th-Anniversary---The-Real-Mccoy">gamespress.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-info/ddc330fc8600e81258d5afc99b426408 @ 1749745765 --></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Japanese Charts: Switch 2 Crushes PS2 To Become Fastest-Selling Console Ever]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/japanese-charts-switch-2-crushes-ps2-to-become-fastest-selling-console-ever</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/japanese-charts-switch-2-crushes-ps2-to-become-fastest-selling-console-ever.1216833/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/japanese-charts-switch-2-crushes-ps2-to-become-fastest-selling-console-ever<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section>
<figure><a title="Mario Kart World - Switch" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/59bdf11a1b69a/mario-kart-world-switch.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>The latest Japanese boxed charts are here, courtesy of <a href="https://www.famitsu.com/article/202506/44654">Famitsu</a>, and golly gosh, would you believe it, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a> has stormed to the top with a total of 782,566 copies sold. That's simply incredible.</p>
<p>The next in line is the Switch 1 version of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/rune_factory_guardians_of_azuma">Rune Factory: Guardians of Azuma</a> with 45,703 copies sold. Truth be told, we're a little surprised that MK World wasn't immediately followed up by another Switch 2 game, but it seems the vast majority of buyers have opted for Nintendo's latest flagship title and left it at that. There's always digital sales to account for too, of course.</p>
<p>That said, both <strong>Zelda</strong> titles on Switch 2 have made the top ten, along with the Switch 2 version of Rune Factory and, of course, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/yakuza-0-directors-cut">Yakuza 0: Director's Cut</a>.</p>
<p>Here's a closer look at this week's Japanese top 10:</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Position</th>
<th>Game</th>
<th>Platform</th>
<th>Unit Sales (2nd - 8th June)</th>
<th>Total Unit Sales</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>1</td>
<td>
<p>Mario Kart World</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Switch 2</p>
</td>
<td>782,566</td>
<td>NEW</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2<a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/shin_megami_tensei_v_vengeance"><br></a></td>
<td>
<p>Rune Factory: Guardians of Azuma</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Switch</p>
</td>
<td>45,703</td>
<td>
<p>NEW</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3</td>
<td>
<p>Fantasy Life i: The Girl Who Steals Time</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Switch</p>
</td>
<td>17,180</td>
<td>111,904</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4</td>
<td>Natsume's Book of Friends: Hazuki no Shirushi</td>
<td>
<p>Switch</p>
</td>
<td>16,865</td>
<td>NEW</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>5</td>
<td>
<p>Elden Ring Nightreign</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>PS5</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>12,064</p>
</td>
<td>54,822</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>6</td>
<td>
<p>Rune Factory: Guardians of Azuma</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Switch 2</p>
</td>
<td>10,877</td>
<td>NEW</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>7</td>
<td>
<p>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Switch 2</p>
</td>
<td>7,992</td>
<td>NEW</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>8</td>
<td>
<p>The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Switch 2</p>
</td>
<td>7,529</td>
<td>NEW</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>9</td>
<td>
<p>Yakuza 0: Director's Cut</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Switch 2</p>
</td>
<td>7,486</td>
<td>
<p>NEW</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>10</td>
<td>
<p>Super Mario Party Jamboree</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Switch</p>
</td>
<td>6,771</td>
<td>1,317,174</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<hr>
<p>With hardware this week, as expected, the Switch 2 is off to a roaring start in Japan, but we weren't prepared for just <em>how</em> successful it would be. The console has sold a whopping 947,931 consoles at launch.</p>
<p>This means that the Switch 2 is comfortably the fastest-selling console in Japan of all time, smashing the previous record of 630,552 set by the almighty PlayStation 2. Similarly, the GBA managed to sell 611,000, the DS 468,000, and the original Switch 330,637.</p>
<p>To put this into further perspective, the Switch 2 has already outsold the Xbox Series X, Xbox Series S, Xbox Series X Digital Edition, <em>and</em> the PlayStation 5 Pro combined. It's also almost outsold the PlayStation 5 Digital Edition too, though it's still a little way off surpassing the standard disc version.</p>
<p>We imagine these numbers will only continue to skyrocket in the coming weeks, so long as Nintendo maintains decent stock, and frankly we can't wait to see where the Switch 2 ends up by the end of the year.</p>
<p>Here's your look at the latest Japanese hardware sales in full:</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Position</th>
<th>Console</th>
<th><strong>Unit Sales (2nd - 8th June)</strong></th>
<th>Lifetime Unit Sales</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>1<br></td>
<td>Switch 2</td>
<td>947,931<br></td>
<td>NEW<br></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2<a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/shin_megami_tensei_v_vengeance"><br></a><br></td>
<td>
<p>PlayStation 5</p>
</td>
<td>14,535<br></td>
<td>
<p>5,690,661</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3<br></td>
<td>
<p>Switch OLED Model</p>
</td>
<td>8,040<br></td>
<td>9,060,680<br></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4<br></td>
<td>Switch Lite</td>
<td>6,089<br></td>
<td>6,581,795<br></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>5<br></td>
<td>
<p>PlayStation 5 Pro</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>4,230</p>
</td>
<td>218,056<br></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>6<br></td>
<td>
<p>Switch</p>
</td>
<td>2,482<br></td>
<td>20,109,545<br></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>7<br></td>
<td>
<p>PlayStation 5 Digital Edition</p>
</td>
<td>2,017<br></td>
<td>974,094<br></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>8<br></td>
<td>
<p>Xbox Series S</p>
</td>
<td>163<br></td>
<td>337,686<br></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>9<br></td>
<td>
<p>Xbox Series X</p>
</td>
<td>113<br></td>
<td>
<p>320,660</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>10<br></td>
<td>
<p>Xbox Series X Digital Edition</p>
</td>
<td>57<br></td>
<td>20,820<br></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>11</td>
<td>PlayStation 4</td>
<td>24</td>
<td>7,929,628</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/05/japanese-charts-konamis-new-visual-novel-triumphs-in-the-pre-switch-2-lull">&lt; Previous charts</a></p>
<p><em>What do you make of this week's sales? Let us know down below.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.famitsu.com/article/202506/44654" rel="noopener" href="https://www.famitsu.com/article/202506/44654">famitsu.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-info/dbc4a8c17d4aaa7f9fa1507a236f86ab @ 1749746988 --></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>