<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 17:05:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video: Kirby And The Forgotten Land Is A Dream On Switch 2 - Here's Our Side-By-Side Comparison]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/video-kirby-and-the-forgotten-land-is-a-dream-on-switch-2-heres-our-side-by-side-comparison</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/video-kirby-and-the-forgotten-land-is-a-dream-on-switch-2-heres-our-side-by-side-comparison.1282080/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>It's a mouthful</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Kirby's big 3D adventure is getting the ol' Nintendo Switch 2 Edition treatment tomorrow as <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/kirby-and-the-forgotten-land-nintendo-switch-2-edition-plus-star-crossed-world">Kirby and the Forgotten Land + Star-Crossed World</a> arrives on the newer console.</p>
<p>Our verdict is already in — and we think this is now, definitively, Kirby's very best outing — but besides the expanded content and new levels, this upgrade also delivers a 60fps performance boost to the base game.</p>
<p>So, how does it compare to <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/kirby_and_the_forgotten_land">the Switch 1 release</a>? The indomitable Felix Sanchez has done the maths and put the Switch 1 version up against the Switch 2. From just watching, things should become crystal clear.</p>
<p>Load times, performances, and draw distance are all greatly improved here, with better grass and water textures throughout. We've got a variety of footage for you, from cutscenes to gliding levels, so why not check out the video up-top.</p>
<p>Don't forget, if you want to get the Nintendo Switch 2 Edition, you'll either need to buy the upgrade pack for $20 or, if you don't own the game at all on Switch 1, you can buy the full version physically when it launches tomorrow, 28th August 2025.</p>
<p><em>Let us know if you'll be getting Kirby and the Forgotten Land on Switch 2, and what you're most excited about, in the comments below.</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/kirby/related-articles:186479 @ 1756314007 --></section></article><div><p>Alana has been with Nintendo Life since 2022, and while RPGs are her first love, Nintendo is a close second. She enjoys nothing more than overthinking battle strategies, characters, and stories. She also wishes she was a Sega air pirate.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/AlanaHagues"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/alanahagues.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('AlanaHagues');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/video-kirby-and-the-forgotten-land-is-a-dream-on-switch-2-heres-our-side-by-side-comparison]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>