<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - www.nintendolife.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for www.nintendolife.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:24:24 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Poll: So, Do You Prefer Hollow Knight Or Silksong?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/poll-so-do-you-prefer-hollow-knight-or-silksong</link>
            <guid>1431355</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="afbb73de2ace7"><a title="Hollow Knight vs Silksong" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/afbb73de2ace7/hollow-knight-vs-silksong.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>Despite pledging that we'd take a break from games of this ilk when we finished pouring blood, sweat and tears into <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hollow-knight-silksong-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Silksong</a> last year, Team Cherry has somehow found a way of dragging us back in with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hollow-knight-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Hollow Knight - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</a>.</p>
<p>Yes, we put the halls of Hallownest behind us for good many years ago now, but the promise of buttery smooth performance had us flying back to it like a Markoth to a flame — <em>mmm, "additional effects"</em>. The more we played, the more we remembered just how much we love this world, these characters, this floaty little knight.</p>
<p>'Oh no,' we suddenly realised, ' without the performance argument in our arsenal, there's nothing stopping us from asking the ultimate question: do we prefer Hollow Knight or Silksong?'</p>
<p>When Silksong launched last year, it felt like a foregone conclusion. In this sequel, Team Cherry had done everything in its power to take what made the first game so wonderful, and make it even <em>wonderfuller</em>. Hornet is quicker and more acrobatic than the Knight. Her tools open more combat possibilities than we ever thought possible. The map makes Hallownest feel piddly.</p>
<p>We even said as much in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/hollow-knight-silksong-nintendo-switch-2-edition">our 10/10 review</a>: "It elevates map design and purposeful challenge effortlessly, and is an improvement on Hollow Knight in every single way." And yes, for reference, we <em>only</em> awarded its predecessor a <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/hollow-knight">9/10</a>.</p>
<p>But, returning to Hallownest on Switch 2 in recent days, our preference isn't quite as clean cut as it was back in September, when the long-awaited Silksong was still so shiny and new in our hands. The map may be smaller, but it feels just as dense. The overarching narrative of the fallen kingdom is sublimely woven into your surroundings, with a simplicity that's tough to knock. And can anything ever truly replicate the feeling of pure dread experienced with your first steps into Deepnest?</p>
<figure data-uuid="2ec88e322390e"><a title="Hollow Knight / Silksong Bench" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/2ec88e322390e/hollow-knight-silksong-bench.large.jpg"></a><figcaption>So... come here often? — <em><span></span> Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Honestly, there are voices for both sides of the argument here at Nintendo Life Towers, so we thought it was only right to throw it out to you, our lovely readers. Do Silksong's improvements leave it at the top spot in your mind, or is Hollow Knight still your number one? You can cast your <del>Zote</del> vote in the following poll.</p>

<p><em>Which game is your favourite? Let us know which you voted for and why in the comments.</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:197171,195258,195359 @ 1770742803 --></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/poll-so-do-you-prefer-hollow-knight-or-silksong]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Round Up: The Reviews Are In For Mario Tennis Fever]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/round-up-the-reviews-are-in-for-mario-tennis-fever</link>
            <guid>1431247</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="f277304b26af4"><a title="Mario Tennis Fever" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/f277304b26af4/mario-tennis-fever.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>September 2025 feels like an awful long time ago. It was in this Direct that we first locked eyes on <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mario-tennis-fever">Mario Tennis Fever</a>, and while the marketing hasn't been all that in-yer-face in the months since, the occasional trailer drop or <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/mobile/nintendo_today">Nintendo Today!</a> update has kept us eager to learn what Mario's latest sporting escapade would bring to the table.</p>
<p>Fortunately, there's not long to wait. Fever launches on Switch 2 later this week on <strong>12th February</strong>, and today, we can start to get an idea of the critical consensus as the reviews start rolling in.</p>
<p>Here at Nintendo Life, we had a great time with just about everything the game served up to us. While the wonderful PJ O'Reilly was a little let down by the single-player Adventure Mode in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/mario-tennis-fever">our 8/10 review</a>, he found that there was a lot to like about the central tennis matches and their wacky Fever mechanics.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>It's lucky, given the disappointing adventure offering, that the tennis here is so sweet, and easily the sort of thing I reckon has a long online life ahead. It helps, too, that it looks superb, never dropping a notable frame in docked or handheld</p>
</blockquote>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:196982 @ 1770742566 -->
<p>But of course, we're not the only ones with a review out there. Below, we've assembled a roundup to help you see the breadth of opinions at a glance — and yes, there are quite a few different takes on this one.</p>
<p>Kicking things off at the top with <a href="https://www.gamingbible.com/reviews/mario-tennis-fever-review-scores-ace-pinpoint-precision-507991-20260210">GAMINGbible</a>, which awarded Fever a 9/10 thanks to its fun-filled whimsy and the "pleasant surprise" of its short-but-sweet Adventure Mode:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>With its surprisingly charming Adventure Mode and more match variations than you could possibly imagine, <em>Mario Tennis Fever</em> is a bountifully delightful release that conjures up the pure, whimsical escapism that only Nintendo so wonderfully nails</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://www.dexerto.com/gaming/mario-tennis-fever-review-3315802/">Dexerto</a> was similarly optimistic in its 4/5 review, describing Fever as "the most fun sports game in years":</p>
<blockquote>
<p>As chaotic as Mario Kart, it stands alongside the likes of Mario Golf Toadstool Tour and Mario Strikers Charged as the best Mario sports games. It’s completely thrilling</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/mario-tennis-fever-review-bringing-the-heat/1900-6418460/">GameSpot</a> also came in with an 8/10, praising the arcade-y addition of the special-powered rackets and the sheer variety of gameplay options:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Mario's various dalliances into sports have been inconsistent, often because they feel so bare-bones and perfunctory. Mario Tennis Fever breaks this trend with a multitude of modes and a playful, flexible gimmick that makes it more wild and unpredictable while also testing your tennis skills in a new way</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Things were marginally lower in <a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/mario-tennis-fever/running-hot">Game Informer</a>'s 7.5/10 review, which still found a lot to like about Fever despite an all-too-short Adventure Mode and some occasional stutters in the review-period online matches:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Mario Tennis Fever is hardly a revolutionary entry, but it nails the series' most important element by offering a well-rounded experience with myriad ways for players of all skill levels to enjoy the game of tennis</p></blockquote><blockquote>
</blockquote>
<p>For many of the same reasons, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-tennis-fever-review">IGN</a> awarded Fever a 7/10, where the stellar party vibes and stacked character roster are only let down by the single-player content and occasional repetitiveness of certain modes:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>After 20 hours, I already feel like I’ve had my fill, and I see it as more of a fun distraction to play for a few minutes here and there while my group warms up for something else rather than one that’s going to get a serious amount of playtime</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Finally, we have <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/review/mario-tennis-fever/">VGC</a>, which gave Fever a "solid" 3/5 on account of that much-discussed Adventure Mode and the risk of things becoming rather unbalanced in online matches:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Before long, you’ll realise that of the 30 rackets on offer, less than a third of them can have a major impact on the game. I’d imagine that once the online community turns up, it’ll only be a matter of time before the metagame kicks in and the vast majority of these rackets are dismissed in favour of the handful that have the most obvious advantage</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p>There you have it, not the most divisive game in recent memory, but certainly a good range of opinions — it currently sits at a <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/mario-tennis-fever/">Metascore</a> of 77 based on 64 critic reviews.</p>
<p>You'll be able to see it all for yourself later this week, when Mario Tennis Fever arrives on 12th February.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:196982,197216 @ 1770742866 -->
<p><em>Are you still excited for Mario Tennis Fever after seeing the critical consensus? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/round-up-the-reviews-are-in-for-mario-tennis-fever]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>