<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 14:06:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Hunter x Hunter: Nen x Impact' Brings 3v3 Anime Fighting To Switch Today]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/hunter-x-hunter-nen-x-impact-brings-3v3-anime-fighting-to-switch-today</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hunter-x-hunter-nen-x-impact-brings-3v3-anime-fighting-to-switch-today.1245993/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<p>We are no different from the ants, no we are far worse!</p>
</section><section>

<p>Arc System Works Europe has just announced that the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2024/10/hunter-x-hunters-fighting-game-delayed-until-2025-now-adding-rollback-netcode">ever-so-slightly-delayed</a> 2D fighter, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/hunter_x_hunter_nen_x_impact">Hunter x Hunter: Nen x Impact</a>, releases today on Nintendo Switch.</p>
<p>Developed by <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/browse?title=company%3Abushiroad">Bushiroad Games</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/companies/eighting">Eighting</a>, this one has got some pedigree in that Eighting has given us some well-known fighters in the past, including <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/naruto_clash_of_ninja">Naruto: Clash of the Ninja.</a> With Hunter x Hunter: Nen x Impact, you get down and dirty in 3v3 tag-team-styled action, which is detailed in the official press release thusly:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"HUNTERxHUNTER: NENxIMPACT is a 3-on-3 fighting game based on the iconic anime and manga series HUNTERxHUNTER, written and illustrated by Yoshihiro Togashi. In this game, players create a team of 3 characters and battle against the opposing team with a tag system: calling out their allies for an assisting attack, or for swapping characters on the fly!</p>
</blockquote>
<p>For those not in the loop, Hunter x Hunter is one of those incredibly long-running anime comics that's got a legion of hardcore fans, although it's not quite in the same league as the likes of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/dragon_ball_fighterz">Dragon Ball</a> or <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/naruto_x_boruto_ultimate_ninja_storm_connections">Naruto</a> - which also get much flashier, big-budget games to boot. First printed in Weekly Shonen Jump all the way back in 1998, the manga, written and illustrated by Yoshihiro Togashi, focuses on a young boy named Gon Freecss who discovers that his father, now missing, is a world-renowned Hunter.</p>
<p>This 2D fighter uses the universe of the comics to bring some beefy-looking scraps to life. We're always down for some tag-team action, and whilst it's not going to be winning any awards for sharpest graphics, there's an interesting core combat experience here that could provide ample cover for any presentation shortcomings. Indeed, any fighters we've played from Eighting in the past have been right bangers in the mechanics department.</p>

<p>Alongside the digital edition, which is priced at £49.99 (or whatever that translates to where you are!) there's also a physical edition that comes in standard and limited edition flavours, with the limited containing the following extras:</p>
<ul>
<li>Full Game</li>
<li>Special Box</li>
<li>Artbook</li>
<li>Acrylic Stand</li>
<li>Season 1 Pass</li>
<li>Alternate Costume Pack Hisoka &amp; Kurapika</li>
</ul>
<figure><a title="hunter x hunter release" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/4b25a90a23f24/hunter-x-hunter-release.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Arc System Works/Bushiroad/Eighting</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>This limited edition, which comes in a very nice box, will set you back £84.99.</p>
<p>Hunter x Hunter has made the news a few time already in this game form, having been <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2024/10/hunter-x-hunters-fighting-game-delayed-until-2025-now-adding-rollback-netcode">delayed to add rollback net code,</a> as well as finding itself <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2024/12/new-switch-anime-fighter-due-out-in-2025-refused-classification-down-under">banned in Australia for including material deemed "inappropriate"</a>.</p>
<p>You can check out the trailer for the game at the top of this very article and, whilst it's definitely not a particular looker in comparison to some other Switch fighters, if it's got it where it counts — in the actual fighting dept. — and you're a fan of the anime already, this one could well be worth a shout.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Interested in Hunter x Hunter: Nen x Impact? Let us know how pumped you are for this spin-off fighter!</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:84285,178260 @ 1752760817 --></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/hunter-x-hunter-nen-x-impact-brings-3v3-anime-fighting-to-switch-today]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mini Review: tomtoc FancyCase-G05 For Switch 2 - A Slim Case That Nails The Fundamentals]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/mini-review-tomtoc-fancycase-g05-for-switch-2-a-slim-case-that-nails-the-fundamentals</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mini-review-tomtoc-fancycase-g05-for-switch-2-a-slim-case-that-nails-the-fundamentals.1245927/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>

<p>Sometimes simplicity is key, and when such simplicity is available for a decent price (<a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DT46HMRB?th=1&amp;tag=nlife-20" rel="sponsored noopener">$36.99 on Amazon</a> at the moment), that’s an even sweeter peach to sink your teeth into. Don’t bite the tomtoc FancyCase G05, mind you, although in all likelihood you wouldn’t do any damage to the console inside.</p>
<p>Yes, it might look simple from the outside (and it is), but this little case is well worth a look if you want to keep your Switch 2 console safe. The first thing you’ll notice is that this is a <em>slim</em> case. There’s very little wasted space at all, and when a gap is present, it’s for a good reason. There are even raised areas in the top in which your Joy-Con sticks can safely nestle themselves.</p>
<p>The exterior of the case is <em>reasonably</em> hard. I mean, it’s got a little bit of give to it, but in all honesty that’s not a bad thing, as it should help absorb any impact force from when you inevitably drop your console whilst waiting at the bus stop. Butterfingers.</p>
<p>There’s a handle at the top as well, which can double as a wrist strap should you want to use it. We’re not entirely sure why you would, but I suppose if it’s strapped to you directly you’re less likely to drop it whilst waiting at the bus stop.</p>

<p>Inside, the plush, velvet-like lining provides a nice little bit of cushioning for your device, including an extra bit of padding to make sure your shoulder buttons have adequate clearance, and the classic flap that folds over the screen also homes some elasticated slots in which you can store your games.</p>
<p>As a small bonus, mine even came with a few little dummy cards made of… well, card, that say ‘Name’ and ‘Contact’ on each side. Keep one of these in your case and should you lose it, whoever finds it should be able to get in touch with you. Assuming they’re honest, naturally.</p>
<p>All things considered, there’s not much to say about this case, but that’s a <em>good</em> thing. There’s nothing exceptional about it, but it gets the fundamentals absolutely bang-on. It’s the functional option, and that is no bad thing.</p>




<p><em>The sample used in this review was provided by the manufacturer.</em></p>
<p>Please note that some external links on this page are affiliate links, which means if you click them and make a purchase we may receive a small percentage of the sale. Please read our <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/advertising">FTC Disclosure</a> for more information.</p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/mini-review-tomtoc-fancycase-g05-for-switch-2-a-slim-case-that-nails-the-fundamentals]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>