<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 20:17:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yooka-Replaylee Gets A Launch Date On Switch 2, Full Physical Release Confirmed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/yooka-replaylee-gets-a-launch-date-on-switch-2-full-physical-release-confirmed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/yooka-replaylee-gets-a-launch-date-on-switch-2-full-physical-release-confirmed.1284363/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Get readee</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>After months of being drip-fed tiny nuggets of information regarding <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/yooka-replaylee">Yooka-Replaylee</a>, Playtonic Games has finally announced that the game will launch on Switch 2 on <strong>9th October 2025</strong>.</p>
<p>In addition, while a previous listing heavily hinted at the game receiving a proper physical release (i.e. no Game-Key Card), this has now been officially confirmed. Digital copies will be available via the Switch 2 eShop at <strong>$29.99</strong>, while physical copies will retail at <strong>$49.99</strong>.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, those who already own <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/yooka-laylee">Yooka-Laylee</a> on the Switch can bag a sweet 30% discount off the price of Yooka-Replaylee on the Switch 2.</p>
<p>It's about time though, right? It's good to know that we don't have to wait too long for the release now. Our only hope at this point is that the remaster improves upon the original in more ways than one. We certainly enjoyed it well enough, but it never quite matched up to the likes of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/n64/banjo-kazooie">Banjo-Kazooie</a>.</p>
<p>Here's a reminder of the key features:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Refined story:</strong> The events of the first game are relived and retold by the main characters, Yooka and Laylee. New sequences and plot points have been added throughout the adventure at key milestones, too.<br>
<strong><br>
Upgraded graphics:</strong> With an art and animations overhaul and enhanced performance and resolution, the favorite buddy duo has never looked or moved better.<br>
<strong><br>
Brand new Rextro’s Arcade:</strong> The old minigames are no more! Instead you'll jump into the feet of Rextro the dinosaur and undertake brand-new isometric platforming challenges for collectible rewards.<br>
<strong><br>
New collectible currency:</strong> Capital B's inept minions have dropped their hard-earned coins all over the place. Collect the official currency of the Hivory Towers to spend on video games' most beloved sentient vending machine.<br>
<strong><br>
Build your own playstyle:</strong> Tonics are back with all new flavors! With the option to equip multiple game changing enhancements, you can truly customize your playstyle. And as if that wasn't enough, Vendi has new lines of merchandise for the modern fashionable adventurer.<br>
<strong><br>
Navigate the world easily:</strong> Yooka-Replaylee introduces a brand-new map and collectibles tracker, making it easier for you to traverse the environments, track NPC and Pagie locations along with tracking their progress. We're also introducing a new character in the form of (book)Mark who acts as your warp point and guide.<br>
<strong><br>
Revamped controls and camera:</strong> The buddy-duo now has access to their entire move set from the start of the game and can sequence the moves together a lot smoother than in the original game. This, combined with the revamped camera controls, makes Yooka-Replaylee feel like a more modern, snappier experience, while also directly addressing player feedback on the original game.<br>
<strong><br>
A dreamy orchestral soundtrack:</strong> The original score from famed video game composers Grant Kirkhope (Banjo-Kazooie) and David Wise (Donkey Kong Country) returns but as a beautifully arranged orchestral score. Now seriously, clean out those ears!</p></blockquote><blockquote>
</blockquote>

<p>Pre-orders for the physical edition of Yooka-Replaylee are now live.</p>
<p>Please note that some external links on this page are affiliate links, which means if you click them and make a purchase we may receive a small percentage of the sale. Please read our <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/advertising">FTC Disclosure</a> for more information.</p>

<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:179592,177402 @ 1756497618 -->
<p><em>Are you excited to pick up Yooka-Replaylee on the Switch 2? Will you be opting for the physical edition? Let us know with a comment in the usual place.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/yooka-replaylee-gets-a-launch-date-on-switch-2-full-physical-release-confirmed]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Review: SHUTEN ORDER (Switch) - An Audacious Swing That Doesn't Quite Connect]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/shuten-order</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/review-shuten-order-switch-an-audacious-swing-that-doesnt-quite-connect.1284288/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section>
<figure><a title="SHUTEN ORDER Review - Screenshot 1 of 5" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/158313/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure><p>Leave it up to Kazutaka Kodaka to come up with one of the weirdest stories in gaming, huh?</p>
<p>Following on from the outrageously ambitious <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/hundred_line_-_last_defense_academy">The Hundred Line - Last Defense Academy</a>, the creator has now joined forces with developer Neilo on the new visual novel <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/shuten_order">Shuten Order</a>. I say ‘visual novel’, and that’s absolutely the overarching genre, but it also manages to feature five distinct sub-genres within its surprisingly lengthy story. Wild stuff.</p>
<p>Shuten Order itself is the titular cult obsessed with the idea that humanity itself is doomed. In fact, the cult not only believes that the end of times is at hand, but is actively <em>wishing</em> for it, rejecting any notion of an afterlife or an all-seeing deity. In what can only be described as divine intervention, however, its founder awakens following their brutal murder, seemingly resurrected to track down the culprit. If that’s not enough, two angels also accompany you throughout the game to provide advice and guidance. Could the cult be...wrong?</p>
<figure><a title="SHUTEN ORDER Review - Screenshot 2 of 5" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/158307/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch (Docked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>With just a few days on the clock before your resurrection ‘expires’, you’re tasked with completing ‘God’s Trial’: identify your murderer, get them to confess, and then, well… kill them. The potential suspects are limited to just five individuals: Shuten Order’s ministers, each of whom presides over a specific department. So you’ve got the Ministry of Justice, the Ministry of Education, and so on.</p>
<p>Once you’ve chosen which of the five ministers to accuse of your murder, you’ll have to pursue them and try to gain a confession, and it’s here where the gameplay diverges into one of five sub-genres.</p>
<p>I started with the Ministry of Security, which essentially sees you working to solve the mystery of a deadly entity called ‘Nephilim’, a grotesque creature that stalks its prey and gouges their eyes out. Lovely stuff. The Security path sees you navigate a series of labyrinths set in different locations as you progress through the story. It’s mostly a case of finding an item or activating a switch and then making it to a final destination without being caught by Nephilim, who constantly shuffles along the corridors. It’s shallow stuff with some pretty basic 3D visuals, and on its own doesn’t really hold up all that well.</p>
<figure><a title="SHUTEN ORDER Review - Screenshot 3 of 5" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/158308/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch (Docked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>In fact, the same could very well be said for every sub-genre: The Ministry of Education focuses on a romance story in which you need to woo three women within a typical school setting; The Ministry of Health is an escape adventure focused around a ‘death game’ that fans of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/danganronpa_decadence">Danganronpa</a> will no doubt appreciate; The Ministry of Justice is a straightforward investigation in which you need to gather clues and deduce the correct course of action; and finally, The Ministry of Science is a multi-perspective visual novel that features several ‘protagonists’.</p>
<p>None of the gameplay tropes feel particularly new, and pretty much all of them can be seen in Kodaka’s previous work, but I guess you could say that this is the first time they’ve all been cobbled together in one single game. With that in mind, if you’re familiar with the likes of Dangaronpa or <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds/zero_escape_virtues_last_reward">Zero Escape</a>, then much of Shuten Order will be pretty familiar territory.</p>
<p>Despite the marketing push to highlight the different sub-genres, the overarching story is really the main draw here. As you start to unravel the mystery, you’ll meet some seriously entertaining characters along the way, and Kodaka’s writing alongside illustrator simadoriru’s visual design is consistently striking and unique.</p>
<figure><a title="SHUTEN ORDER Review - Screenshot 4 of 5" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/158309/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch (Docked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Where Shuten Order begins to falter is in its execution of those sub-genres. Kodaka <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/unsettling-yet-captivating-shuten-order-creators-talk-cult-religion-and-dismemberment">has stated</a> his ambition to present a “culmination of all the visual novels I've ever read”, and it’s certainly an ambitious attempt, but the approach here screams ‘Jack of all trades’.</p>
<p>The five different branches wind up feeling little more than a novelty, and not a particularly compelling one. I mentioned how the Security path features basic visuals, but this is nothing compared to how simple and mundane the actual gameplay is. The devs want you to feel nervous as you avoid the gaze of Nephilim, but there's zero challenge, and it ends up just being a nuisance.</p>
<p>Similarly, the romance path has you searching (stalking?) for your potential date, with the game presenting multiple locations to visit, but not giving much indication as to where you actually need to go. So you wind up just guessing until you reach the right goal, forced to engage in random NPC conversations if you happen to search in the wrong place. This isn't a game that respects your time.</p>
<figure><a title="SHUTEN ORDER Review - Screenshot 5 of 5" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/158314/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>It’s not a short one, either. The length will vary depending on how much you’re willing to invest in the story and investigate every possible avenue, but each of the five narrative branches could easily take you 10 hours or so. At a total of 50, Shuten Order felt quite bloated and would have benefited from focusing on just one or two key gameplay hooks to tell its story. Coming off the back of The Hundred Line, which demonstrated an exceptionally strong combination of visual novel storytelling and tactical gameplay, the attempt to showcase several different genres here means that none of them are really able to shine.</p>
<p>What <em>does</em> shine, however, is the visual design. Shuten Order displays exceptional use of colour that really sets it apart from other visual novels, and the juxtaposition of the striking blues, yellows, and pinks against a story steeped in misery and despair is particularly notable.</p>
<p>Similarly, the music is consistently engaging, shifting in tone at all the right moments, while the Japanese voiceover work never falters. There’s no Western VO here, however, so you’re out of luck if you happen to prefer your Japanese visual novels dubbed.</p>
<p>In terms of performance, it all runs well on the Switch, with reasonably short load times. If you happen to be playing on the Switch 2, then you won't find any issues with performance, but you should note that character illustrations at certain distances can look almost pixelated, slightly – a simple symptom of blowing up the Switch 1 game's handled resolution on the larger 1080p screen. If you can, play it on the Switch OLED; the colours look simply marvellous on that stunning display.</p>
</section><section id="conclusion"><h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Shuten Order is an ambitious visual novel that tells an intriguing story with consistently engaging characters and more than a few twists and turns. Unfortunately, with the inclusion of five distinct forms of gameplay driving the story, it ultimately feels bloated and directionless, and not one of the sub-genre sections is polished enough to stand on its own two feet.</p>
<p>I wholeheartedly commend the audacious, multi-genre effort, but Shuten Order would have benefited from a lot more focus.</p></section>

</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/shuten-order]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>