<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 03:27:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Timed Xbox Exclusive Little Rocket Lab Appears To Be Releasing On Switch Soon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/timed-xbox-exclusive-little-rocket-lab-appears-to-be-releasing-on-switch-soon</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/timed-xbox-exclusive-little-rocket-lab-appears-to-be-releasing-on-switch-soon.1347991/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Classic building and resource management gets cosy</p>
</section></header><div><section>

<p>If you're a fan of cosy-style games and don't mind some classic building and resource management sim action, you might be interested in the upcoming Switch release <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/little_rocket_lab">Little Rocket Lab</a>. This game originally made its console debut in October on the Xbox.</p>
<p>After being <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/round-up-every-game-from-wholesome-snack-2024-coming-to-nintendo-switch">announced during the 'Wholesome Snack 2024' presentation</a> last December, it seems it might finally have a release date. According to the official store page on Nintendo's website and eShop, it will launch next month on <strong>10th December 2025</strong> for $19.99 (or your regional equivalent).</p>
<p>This game is compatible with the Switch 2 and will apparently take up 1.8 GB on both Switch systems. Here's the official description, and you can see the original announcement trailer above:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You play as Morgan, an aspiring engineer headed home to complete your family's dream project - a rocket ship! Finding home not quite how she left it, Morgan will need to research and build clever contraptions and sprawling factories to help the locals. From simple drills and furnaces to complex assemblers, cranes and miles of conveyor belts, you'll convert local resources into useful materials and bring industry back to sleepy St. Ambroise.</p>
<p>- Build clever contraptions and sprawling factories to solve puzzles and help the town<br>
- Get to know the locals, make lifelong friendships and become the heart of the community<br>
- Research and invent new machines, energy sources and mechanical friends<br>
- Discover a heartwarming story as Morgan, an aspiring engineer with high hopes for town!<br>
- Finally build your family's rocket ship!</p>
<p>Outside of smashing together crazy contraptions, you'll need to mine out resources, explore coasts, railyards, quarries and underground areas - each part of town has its own materials to inspire you! You'll need to complete challenges, incorporate electrical elements, water, cranes, furnaces, crafting, automate through robotics, and loads more to ensure St. Ambroise returns to its former glory. Are you ready to roll up your sleeves?</p>
<p><em>"Little Rocket Lab is a classic building and resource management sim, set in a cozy village filled with NPCs who want to help... and sometimes hinder. With friendships to rekindle, puzzles to solve and a huge world to explore, everything is in place to make this experience a blast from start to finish."</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Over on Steam, this title has received "Very Positive" user reviews, so if you're into this kind of game - it might be worth keeping tabs on.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:188116,175638 @ 1762657203 -->
<p>Would you be interested in playing this game on the Switch or Switch 2? Have you already played it on another platform? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://nintendoeverything.com/machine-building-rpg-little-rocket-lab-announced-for-nintendo-switch/" rel="noopener" href="https://nintendoeverything.com/machine-building-rpg-little-rocket-lab-announced-for-nintendo-switch/">nintendoeverything.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-info/79ac314c2d334454bd47dde9feccf9ba @ 1762657203 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/timed-xbox-exclusive-little-rocket-lab-appears-to-be-releasing-on-switch-soon]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rumour: New Crash Bandicoot Racing Artwork Has Some Fans Excited]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/rumour-new-crash-bandicoot-racing-artwork-has-some-fans-excited</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rumour-new-crash-bandicoot-racing-artwork-has-some-fans-excited.1347976/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Is Crash finally back?</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="56093ff1da2ad"><a title="Crash Team Racing" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/56093ff1da2ad/crash-team-racing.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Activision</em></figcaption></figure><p>Crash Bandicoot hasn't been sighted for a while now, but Crash fans think they might have spotted something that could be tied to a new game project or at least a return in some way or form.</p>
<p>This development comes from the <a href="https://x.com/BeenoxTeam">official Beenox social media account</a>. Beenox, in case you need a refresher, is the same team that worked on <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/crash_team_racing_nitro-fueled">Crash Team Racing Nitro-Fueled</a> and has also helped out with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/crash_bandicoot_4_its_about_time">Crash Bandicoot 4: It's About Time</a>.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, the developer <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/crashbandicoot/comments/1op4zhp/beenox_changed_his_banner_and_crash_appears_twice/">uploaded a banner featuring Crash in a kart</a> and then removed it shortly after. What's interesting about this is it appears to be based on Crash's character model from the fourth outing - a title that was released well after the most recent racing game.</p>

<p>So, that's it for now, but if there are any other significant updates or developments here, we'll be sure to let you know.</p>
<p>Interestingly, this happens to follow a rumour in October about Crash Bandicoot <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/rumour-sonic-prime-studio-reportedly-working-on-crash-bandicoot-animation-for-netflix">potentially getting his own animation on Netflix</a>. If you missed it, it's claimed WildBrain Studios - the same team behind Sonic Prime (and also helping out with the upcoming <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/minecraft">Minecraft</a> animated series on Netflix) is behind it. 2026 will also mark Crash's 30th anniversary.</p>
<p>For now, the current stories circulating about Crash Bandicoot are just rumours - so nothing has been officially confirmed or announced, and there's no guarantee this discovery will necessarily lead to a new project, reveal or update.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:193078 @ 1762656951 -->
<p>What would you like to see next from Crash? Have you played Crash 4 and Crash Team Racing? <em>Tell us in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.purexbox.com/news/2025/11/xbox-hasnt-given-us-a-crash-bandicoot-game-yet-but-beenox-might-be-working-on-something" rel="noopener" href="https://www.purexbox.com/news/2025/11/xbox-hasnt-given-us-a-crash-bandicoot-game-yet-but-beenox-might-be-working-on-something">purexbox.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-info/69fb9bfd844c2457df46fea05b738568 @ 1762657491 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/rumour-new-crash-bandicoot-racing-artwork-has-some-fans-excited]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anniversary: 20 Years Ago, 'GUN' Brought America's Old West (And An All-Star Cast) To GameCube]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/anniversary-20-years-ago-gun-brought-americas-old-west-and-an-all-star-cast-to-gamecube</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/anniversary-20-years-ago-gun-brought-americas-old-west-and-an-all-star-cast-to-gamecube.1347814/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="9c0289c7c8b27"><a title="GUN Anniversary" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/9c0289c7c8b27/gun-anniversary.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Activision</em></figcaption></figure><p>Ever feel like getting your video game cowboy on, but <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/red_dead_redemption">Red Dead Redemption</a> and its kinda bloated sequel, as good as they are, just take way too long to bed into?</p>
<p>You know what I mean. Rockstar's epics are the obvious go-to choices in this scenario. However, sometimes I just want to shoot stuff in the cowboy style, almost immediately if possible, and I don't want to waste time with hugely intricate plots and overwhelming world aspects that drag a playthrough out to a triple-digit hour count. Who has time for that in this economy? (Me, but that's probably best kept for another article on a different website.)</p>
<p>There are a few options for a faster six-shooter fix. Indeed, Rockstar's <a href="https://www.purexbox.com/games/xbox/red_dead_revolver">Red Dead Revolver</a> is much more in line with what I'm thinking. But you've more than likely played that, either at launch or once you'd made your way through Red Dead Redemption.</p>
<p>Enter <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/gun">GUN</a> <em>*kicks swinging saloon doors open*</em>, Neversoft's 2005 Western action effort, which is 20 years old today! Here's an oft-overlooked gem of a game that still has the capacity to serve you up exactly what you're after. Heck, it even still looks real purdy.</p>
<p>Now, we didn't review GUN back in the day, which is a shame <em>[<a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/site-news-nintendo-life-turns-20-today">The website <strong>was</strong> only a day old!</a> - Ed.]</em>, but it reviewed well across the board, and I have nothing but good things to say about it. With the passing of time, you could actually consider one of the biggest criticisms at release — a very empty and smallish open world — as one of its stronger points nowadays. Especially if, like me, you never want to see another sprawling, icon-laden world map in your life. Well, not for a few weeks anyway.</p>

<p>Let's start with my favourite bit of this one: the cast.</p>
<p>We've got Thomas Jane, Lance Henriksen, Ron Perlman, Brad Dourif, and none other than Kris "sort of a god" Kristofferson showing up in this Western tale, and they've not <em>just</em> shown up, either. They're not phoning it in and hightailing it out of there with their bag of swag. No. There's some solid acting going on, and as a result, the whole thing is given a completely unnecessary level of gravitas. The story here, written by Randall Jahnsen (of <strong>The Doors</strong> movie fame), is no match for Red Dead's hugely serious tale, make no mistake, but it isn't aiming for that. It's going for old-school tension, shocks, and twists that are more immediate in nature.</p>
<p>Jahnsen opted for a tale of revenge that plays it cold and ruthless in the classic <strong>Unforgiven</strong> vein. It revolves around Colton White (Jane) and his dad (Kristofferson) as they head off in search of Colton's dear Jenny (<strong>Rugrats</strong> alumni, Kath Souchie) who's been kidnapped by the murderous Reverend Reed (Dourif). Across the campaign, we're treated to violent shootouts, horseback action sequences and sweet on-rails sections that still play great today. I'm not just saying that either, I'm playing it right now, and it looks and feels very nice, thanks.</p>
<p>In fact, it plays much better than I remember, and the GameCube version is no slouch, running at a super smooth clip and looking every bit as nice as other ports. As I mentioned, the open world here is slight in its size and activities, a criticism in 2005, but now it means it's a much more straightforward and time-respectful sort of thing. There's no need to spend 100 hours picking flowers here, and you get to shoot stuff in the first couple of minutes. A win for common sense!</p>

<p>The shooting, which incorporates a de rigueur slo-mo six-shooter mechanic (here called QuickDraw), also comes off much better these days, I reckon. It was criticised — outside of those focused slo-mo parts — for being a little too tough to aim. However, I'm of the opinion that it's more authentic than tightly auto-aimed nonsense. You need to concentrate a bit and place your shots, and that works for me.</p>
<p>There's also a cracking lineup of era-authentic guns to collect from dead bosses and such along the way. Winchesters, Colts, Schofield rifles that blow heads into bloody pulp when aimed just so. You even get to do a little bit of archery, firing great big cannons. Have I mentioned that it's very bloody? Good.</p>
<p>So, the third-person pew-pew action, and the flow of the world, come off pretty great to this day, and it's a world that, despite its small scale, provides plenty of suitably epic vistas, alongside some impressive urban areas, whilst still managing to look fine in 2025. This is one of those 'early-noughties beige' numbers. You know, dusty and rusted in an attempt to seem adult, and as a result, it's got it where it counts in terms of atmosphere. It's very jaggy round the edges, for sure, but there's a level of detail and some proper cinematography going on, so it gets away with it.</p>

<p>Once the story kicks into gear, once Colton is on his way to Empire City to meet the likes of Mayor Hoodoo Brown (Perlman), and once all hell subsequently breaks loose, we're then treated to a lovely mix of shootouts, proper no-messing hard cowboy dialogue, and levels, such as a fantastic stagecoach one, that don't outstay their welcome. You also gotta turn up just to hear some classic gruff cowboy lines delivered with the swagger of this all-star cast, too.</p>
<p>GUN also benefits from a very edgy and 'of its time' attitude in some respects. It's a little subversive here and there (I won't spoil), and it even draws in some story influences from places you might not expect. It gets a bit...supernatural. So it's got a whole off-kilter thing going on, backed up by the weird awesomeness of that cast.</p>
<p>There <em>is</em> an attempt to make the world feel bigger through the ability to track down a few wanted criminals, hunting animals, or doing a spot of ranching, but these are the parts where GUN falls down. No, it's in the crazy assembly of amazingly talented actors, in that uniquely rust-tinged noughties atmosphere, and in some incredibly violent and pleasing shootouts that GUN excels.</p>

<p>At 20 years of age, plenty of video game cowboys have long since hung up their holsters. GUN, though, if you're willing to give it a shot, still has it all where it counts. If you're hankerin' for some straightforward cowboy roleplaying, with no need for 100 hours to spare, or a therapist to get you through Arthur Morgan's trauma, you'll have a fairly tough time finding many games that fill the role better than Neversoft's crack at America's Wild West.</p>
<p>Who'd have thought that the Tony Hawks dev team would serve so hard in this particular genre?</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Have you played GUN? Let us know if you remember it quite so fondly!</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/anniversary-20-years-ago-gun-brought-americas-old-west-and-an-all-star-cast-to-gamecube]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Civilization VII 'Tides Of Power Collection' Free DLC Now Available For Switch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/civilization-vii-tides-of-power-collection-free-dlc-now-available-for-switch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/civilization-vii-tides-of-power-collection-free-dlc-now-available-for-switch.1347715/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section>

<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/sid-meiers-civilization-vii-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Civilization VII</a> has received multiple updates since it launched earlier this year and alongside Update 1.3.0, Firaxis Games has now released the <strong>Tides of Power Collection</strong>.</p>
<p>This is <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/sid-meiers-civilization-vii-tides-of-power-collection-70070000031661-switch/">"free to claim" on the Switch and Switch 2 eShop</a> until <strong>5th January 2026</strong> and is "yours to keep permanently at no cost". After this date, you'll be required to purchase it.</p>
<p>Here's a quick rundown about what you can expect, along with an official graphic, and below this are the full details about the DLC (via the game's website patch notes):</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"<strong>Tides of Power Update:</strong> This is now fully claimable on Steam, PlayStation, Xbox, and Switch...Starting today, add Edward Teach, Republic of Pirates, and Tonga content packs to your game, and then receive the Sayyida al Hurra, Ottomans, and Iceland content packs in-game when they're released in December 2025. If you successfully claim this content by January 5, 2026 at 6:59AM PT, it's yours to keep; otherwise it will be available for individual purchase starting January 5, 2026."</p>
</blockquote>
<figure data-uuid="89c8df4a150e1"><a title="Tides of Power" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/89c8df4a150e1/tides-of-power.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: 2K</em></figcaption></figure>
<nav><ul><li><span title="On This Page"></span></li></ul>
</nav>
<h2 id="civilization-vii-tides-of-power-collection-4th-november-2025">Civilization VII: Tides of Power Collection (4th November 2025)</h2>
<h2 id="leaders">Leaders</h2>
<p><strong>(Tides of Power DLC**) Added new leader Edward Teach.</strong></p>
<p>Edward Teach, better known as Blackbeard, was an English pirate whose name sparked dread in the captains of the Caribbean. In 1716, he joined the crew of Benjamin Hornigold, a leader of the Flying Gang, and quickly gained his own ships. With his impressive height, his long beard (decorated with, at times, lit fuses), and reputation for violence, he stalked the sea-lanes of the Caribbean and the nightmares of sailors. He outlived the Flying Gang and moved his operation to the Outer Banks of present-day North Carolina, where a pirate hunter, Robert Maynard, finally caught up with him.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Attributes</strong>: Militaristic, Economic</li>
<li><strong>Unique Ability – Blackbeard</strong>: All Naval Units gain the Pirate Ability, allowing them to cross borders of other civilizations, Plunder Trade Routes from non-Allied civilizations, and attack Naval Units of non-Allied civilizations without declaring war. Defeating any Naval Units with your own Naval Units provides Gold equal to a set percentage of its Combat Strength and captures that Unit. Increased Gold maintenance costs for all Naval Units.</li>
<li><strong>Agenda – Queen Anne’s Revenge</strong>: Increase Relationship by a Small Amount with Leaders that build Naval Units. Decrease Relationship by a Small Amount with Leaders that neglect to build Naval Units.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="civilizations">Civilizations</h2>
<p><strong>(Tides of Power DLC**) Added a new Exploration Age civilization Republic of Pirates.</strong></p>
<p>Where there is wealth, there is greed. The scramble for new world riches in the early 18th century brought English, Spanish, French, and Dutch fleets – but the prospect of quick riches also brought pirates. These were rarely organized, but in 1706, one band, the Flying Gang, took over the island of New Providence in the Bahamas and set up a short-lived republic for all who sought fortune... and came with few scruples.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Attributes</strong>: Economic, Militaristic</li>
<li><strong>Unique Ability – Flying Gang</strong>: Increased Yields from Pillaging and Coastal Raiding with Naval Units. Settler Units cannot be trained or purchased, but you can capture other civilizations' Settlers. Naval Units, Treasure Convoys, and Buccaneer Units can move into other civilizations' borders without being at war or having Open Borders.</li>
<li><strong>Unique Civilian Unit – Buccaneer</strong>: Unique Commander Unit. Gains a set number of charges to use the 'Raiding Party' Action every set number of Promotions.
<ul>
<li><strong>Action - Raiding Party</strong>: Targets an adjacent Treasure Resource. This Settlement instantly spawns a Treasure Convoy under your control equal to the number of Treasure Resources; this does not reset until another Treasure Convoy is available.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Unique Military Unit – Sloop</strong>: Unique Naval Unit (replaces Privateer). Can cross other civilizations' borders, Pillage Trade Routes between non-Allied civilizations, and attack Units of non-Allied civilizations without going to war. Can move after attacking and has a set amount of Movement.</li>
<li><strong>Associated Wonder – Havana Harbor</strong>: Gold Base. This Settlement generates Treasure Convoys worth a set amount of Treasure Fleet points in the Exploration Age (effect scales based on game speed). Increased Economic Attribute. Must be built in Distant Lands on Coastal Tiles adjacent to non-Lake tiles.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>(Tides of Power DLC**) Added a new Antiquity Age civilization Tonga.</strong></p>
<p>Into the endless blue, in search of new lands on scattered islands, the Polynesians sailed, settling the island of Tonga nearly three thousand years ago. Around 1000 CE, though, came another expansion, the Tu’i Tonga Empire – a struggle for dominance, tribute, and fealty over the Pacific. The Tongan kings maintained this system of hierarchical lordship over the islands until it, too, splintered.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Attributes</strong>: Expansionist, Diplomatic</li>
<li><strong>Unique Ability – Lords of the South</strong>: Increased Influence on City Halls and the Palace if adjacent to Coast tiles. Cannot incorporate City-States.</li>
<li><strong>Unique Civilian Unit – Tehina</strong>: Unique Scout Unit. Can enter Ocean tiles (without taking damage) and embark at the start of the Age. Cannot disembark in Distant Lands, but can use Coastal Raid on adjacent Discoveries.</li>
<li><strong>Unique Military Unit – Kalia</strong>: Increased Combat Strength against Districts.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="wonders">Wonders</h2>
<p><strong>(Tides of Power DLC**) Added four new Wonders:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Great Lighthouse – Antiquity</strong>
<ul>
<li>Gold Base. Grants a free Merchant when built. +15 Water Trade Route Range in all Settlements. +1 Sight to all Naval Units. Must be built on a Coast tile adjacent to Land.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Nan Madol – Exploration</strong>
<ul>
<li>Provides +3 Culture, +3 Production, and +3 Happiness on the Palace and City Hall on Islands (a landmass with a maximum of 15 tiles). Must be built in an Island City on Coast adjacent to Land</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Great Blue Hole – Natural Wonder</strong>
<ul>
<li>+2 Science and +4 Happiness. Adjacent sea rural tiles receive +2 Culture. Placed on the Coast adjacent to 6 coast tiles.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Mapu'a Vaea Blowholes – Natural Wonder</strong>
<ul>
<li>+2 Production and +4 Happiness. +2 Culture to all Coastal land tiles in this Settlement. Impassable.</li>
<li>Placed on the Coast adjacent to Cliffs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<hr>
<p>Firaxis has also included some platform-specific updates tied to the Switch and Switch 2 in Update 1.3.0. This includes the following:</p>
<p><strong>Switch / Switch 2</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>HDR options now appear when undocking Switch.</li>
<li>Addressed a reported issue where the last character entered with the virtual keyboard would appear incorrectly.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p>You can find out more about Update 1.3.0 and what else it includes in the update notes on the <a href="https://civilization.2k.com/civ-vii/game-update-notes/">official Civilization website</a>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:178138,182946,183270 @ 1762657815 -->
<p>Have you tried out this game on the Switch or Switch 2? Will you be downloading this DLC? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/sid-meiers-civilization-vii-tides-of-power-collection-70070000031661-switch/" rel="noopener" href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/sid-meiers-civilization-vii-tides-of-power-collection-70070000031661-switch/">nintendo.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/3a0b41435e8e3d15e0cc9e6c3b0b3115 @ 1762657329 --></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/civilization-vii-tides-of-power-collection-free-dlc-now-available-for-switch]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>