<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:07:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former Nintendo Of America President Doug Bowser Joins Hasbro's Board Of Directors]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/former-nintendo-of-america-president-doug-bowser-joins-hasbros-board-of-directors</link>
            <guid>1410841</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>King of the Kenner</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="12a6d697a504d"><a title="Hasbro / Doug" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/12a6d697a504d/hasbro-doug.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>Following his retirement as President and COO of Nintendo of America, Doug Bowser has now joined the board of directors for toy manufacturer Hasbro.</p>
<p>This news come <a href="https://newsroom.hasbro.com/news-releases/news-release-details/hasbro-announces-additions-board-directors">directly from Hasbro</a> itself, with the firm confirming the appointment of Bowser alongside Carla Vernón, CEO of The Honest Company, a digital-first consumer goods company founded by actress Jessica Alba.</p>
<p>Hasbro, of course, is much more than a mere toy manufacturer, and owns the trademarks and products of Kenner, Milton Bradley, Parker Brothers, and Wizards of the Coast. The latter company is responsible for the ludicrously popular <strong>Magic: The Gathering</strong> and <strong>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</strong>, while huge brands like <strong>Transformers</strong> and <strong>G.I. Joe</strong> also fall under Hasbro.</p>
<p>Here's what Rich Stoddart, Chair of Hasbro's Board of Directors, had to say:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“We are delighted to have Doug and Carla join our seasoned and dynamic Board of Directors. Doug and Carla bring extensive leadership experience across consumer brands and franchise management. Their expertise and guidance will be invaluable as Hasbro continues to execute its long-term innovation and growth strategy.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Meanwhile, Doug Bowser's successor at Nintendo, Devon Pritchard, has kicked off 2026 as Nintendo of America's new President and COO. <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/im-excited-to-meet-you-devon-pritchard-makes-her-first-public-appearance-as-president-of-noa">She made her first public appearance</a> in the role at the 15th Annual New York Game Awards, delivering a pre-recorded message to praise the event and the nonprofit 'Playing With Purpose' writing programme.</p>
<p>Chances are we won't see much of Doug Bowser in the months and years ahead as he works behind the scenes at Hasbro, but hey, maybe he'll have a say in whether <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/baldurs_gate_3">Baldur's Gate 3</a> comes to the Switch 2, huh?</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-articles:196363,188448 @ 1768920303 -->
<p><em>What do you make of this news? Reckon this is a good fit for Mr. Bowser? Let us know with a comment.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://newsroom.hasbro.com/news-releases/news-release-details/hasbro-announces-additions-board-directors" rel="noopener" href="https://newsroom.hasbro.com/news-releases/news-release-details/hasbro-announces-additions-board-directors">newsroom.hasbro.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-info/d41d8cd98f00b204e9800998ecf8427e @ 1768917993 --></div></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/former-nintendo-of-america-president-doug-bowser-joins-hasbros-board-of-directors]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>