<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 13:30:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Review: Survival Kids (Switch 2) - Konami's NS2 Debut Is Cosy, Competent, Kid-Friendly Co-op]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/survival-kids</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/review-survival-kids-switch-2-konamis-ns2-debut-is-cosy-competent-kid-friendly-co-op.1213179/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/survival-kids<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section>
<p>A treasure map: a voyage. The ocean sploshing happily at your makeshift raft. Then a ferocious storm! Shipwrecked, alone, starving, surely doomed.</p>
<p>Well, not exactly. The happy sploshing part, yes — and technically a shipwreck — but then you’re in for a calypso-tinged, cosy hangout with friends. <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/survival-kids">Survival Kids</a> offers a gentle change of pace in the fervour of the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/nintendo-switch-2-guide-ultimate-resource">Switch 2</a> launch, and a jolly fun jaunt it is, too.</p>
<p>Developed by Unity — as in the game engine company, in its first foray into end-to-end game development — this is an update of a dormant Konami IP that goes right back to the Game Boy in 1999. <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gbc/survival_kids">That game</a>, made available recently on Nintendo’s Game Boy app on Switch, was an early example of survival mechanics, including stabbing animals to death in a you-or-them scrap, before cooking up the flesh to eke out another day without starving to death. Over the years, through half a dozen or so sequels and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/lost_in_blue">spin-offs</a> and a lengthy hiatus, the edges have softened, culminating in this gentle, cooperative exploration and puzzle game.</p>
<figure><a title="Survival Kids Review - Screenshot 1 of 4" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/156662/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Docked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>The setup is lighthearted. Yes, stranded in a shipwreck – but on the back of a giant turtle called a 'whurtle'. Your mission is to fix up your raft and set off back home. However, each new voyage leads to another wreck on another whurtle – another level with the same mission to repair and escape. If that sounds repetitive, well, <em>it really is</em> – it’s whurtles all the way down. But, although solo play is available, this is fundamentally a multiplayer game, and cooperating and collaborating to complete the simple errands on the to-do list keeps everything fresh.</p>
<p>As for getting multiplayer set up, you have a few options: splitscreen for two players, online up to four, and an early example of Nintendo’s <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/nintendo-switch-2-gameshare-guide-how-to-share-games-locally-and-online">GameShare</a> feature, where up to three players can play with a single copy of the game. For this last option, however, you are limited to a local configuration, where all the Switches are in the same room. Since the Switch 2 streams the game to the other consoles (including the original Switch if you’ve held on to one), <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/konamis-switch-2-launch-title-will-have-3-player-local-co-op-via-gameshare">the frame rate drops to 30fps</a>, and some latency creeps in. Add to this the big black border around the play area on each device and it’s not an ideal way to play, but it’s passable.</p>
<p>In my testing, splitscreen on the telly was the way to go. Online with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/nintendo-switch-2-gamechat-guide-how-does-it-work">GameChat</a> could probably be a good laugh, but I don’t have any friends (<em>with this game</em>, thank you) to test that. Even if you are set up for GameChat, I doubt it could compete with couch co-op, particularly because your ideal co-survivor is probably about 5-10 years old – more on that in a minute.</p>
<figure><a title="Survival Kids Review - Screenshot 2 of 4" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/156663/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Anyway, however you recruit them, once your crew is ready to set sail with the game, the process of repairing your raft boils down to gathering scattered items and carrying them to the wreckage. Reaching those items requires a bit of light puzzling, such as casting a fishing line to grab a distant piece of machinery or blowing items into place with a leafy fan. Said fishing line and fan also need to be constructed by gathering items and bringing them to base camp. All in all, it’s a game about searching and fetching.</p>
<p>Experienced gamers may find the very basic actions a bit tedious after the first couple of islands. However, put Survival Kids in front of a newer gamer — in my testing, a six-year-old — and the novelty doesn’t wear off so promptly. In fact, it was a gleeful time through to the end of the game and beyond.</p>
<p>And the enduring fun wasn’t just because the ideas were new to my fellow strandee; more than that, he was able to enjoy them thanks to the very dependable and generous controls. Chopping trees, for example, sends wood flying about, and those little bits all need to be gathered and lugged around. Larger items need to be dragged, and everything bobbles about for some physics-based fun. It’s a recipe for disaster, really, since repetition plus fidgetiness equals agonising gameplay. But not to fear: a quick and reliable push of the 'A' button grabs whatever’s nearby with a delightful pop, and since you can only stack alike items in your hands, mashing 'A' will always gather the right resource from a pile as long as you start with the one you’re after.</p>
<figure><a title="Survival Kids Review - Screenshot 3 of 4" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/156666/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Docked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>The same holds for some simple platforming. The kids’ yelping bounds are a bit floaty and inelegant as jumps go, but the island parkour was clear and easy to execute, with a quick reset just in case, and no real punishment if you miss the target.</p>
<p>'No real punishment' could be the game’s motto, in fact. Working together completes tasks faster, but it’s not too slow on your own. You need to eat to increase your strength, but you won’t really suffer for running out. The simple fishing can be messed up, snapping your line, but there are always plenty more fish in the sea, so to speak.</p>
<p>Overall, there’s little resistance to completion, even if your partner doesn’t feel like doing anything constructive. Mine appointed himself the cook every time — whether food was needed or not — but we always got our raft sorted in the end.</p>
<figure><a title="Survival Kids Review - Screenshot 4 of 4" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/156664/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Docked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Our rather dilly-dallying approach to island life made the game last about 12 hours for us. I’m confident experienced gamers could finish it off in half that time. There are star rewards to go back for on each level — for time gates and hidden items — but replaying the same level only amplified the tedium for me. We reached the last level to find it gated behind a 25-star requirement. We called it a day, and I spent an hour grinding stars on my own after bedtime so we could finish the game in the morning. That was the least fun part of the experience by a nautical mile.</p>
</section><section id="conclusion"><h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Survival Kids is a thoroughly competent, cosy game of cooperative gathering and crafting. It’s not much of a looker, and its ideas aren’t mind-blowing, but it’s all good stuff thanks to its robust controls and easy-to-grasp loop. I’m not sure I’d want to be stuck with it on a desert island, but it’s good company for several happy hours with a friend – especially a less experienced gamer. If you plan to get shipwrecked with a little one and giggle your way through it, go ahead and add a point to the score.</p></section>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Clock Tower: Rewind To Receive "Switch 2 Exclusive Features," Says Limited Run]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/clock-tower-rewind-to-receive-switch-2-exclusive-features-says-limited-run</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/clock-tower-rewind-to-receive-switch-2-exclusive-features-says-limited-run.1213131/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/clock-tower-rewind-to-receive-switch-2-exclusive-features-says-limited-run<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>And other games, once they've got them working</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure><a title="clock tower switch 2" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/4c281b165adeb/clock-tower-switch-2.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Limited Run Games, Wayforward</em></figcaption></figure><p>Limited Run Games has been chatting to our sister site, <a href="https://www.timeextension.com/">Time Extension</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/limited-run-games-addresses-carbon-engine-compatibility-issue-on-switch-2">regarding an annoying bug</a> that's currently causing issues with its Carbon Engine on Switch 2. Don't worry, gang, they are on a fix!</p>
<p>In the statement to TE, Josh Fairhurst from Limited Run also dropped the fact that <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/snes/clock_tower">Clock Tower</a>, that old chestnut from back in ye Super Nintendo days of yore, and more recently seen on Switch in its <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/clock_tower_rewind">Clock Tower: Rewind</a> form, will receive some "Switch 2 exclusive features" through a patch in the near future:</p><p><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067gpzkwj&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><figcaption>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>820k</span></a></figcaption><figcaption><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C1rrCdi_XjA">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></figcaption></figure></p>
<blockquote>
<p>"...we are also preparing patches for a few of our older games, but this may take some time as we also plan to add some Switch 2 exclusive features in games like Clock Tower."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>New features for Clock Tower...but what could they be? Of course, Clock Tower: Rewind on Switch 1 added a whole bunch of new stuff, such as a new opening movie, new songs, save states, interviews and comics — amongst other things — so it'll be interesting to see what could possibly be jammed this time.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/clock-tower-rewind">We gave Clock Tower: Rewind a 7/10 in our review on Switch</a>, saying that "we feel comfortable recommending to survival horror enthusiasts who wish to experience absolutely everything the genre has to offer." However, our review does point out that the game looks fairly archaic at this stage, so maybe we are in for a nice lick of paint? Seems ambitious, but let us dream. We'll be sure to let you know of any further announcements.</p>
<p>And in other old-game news, Fairhurst also mentioned that a certain soon-to-be-re-released gecho should be performing perfectly on Nintendo's new console soon:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"As a heads up, we have already submitted a patch to Nintendo that ensures our upcoming release of GEX Trilogy works flawlessly on the Switch 2."</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p><em>Looking forward to playing some Clock Tower on your Switch 2? Let us know!</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:183641,173817,182136 @ 1749472236 --></section></article><div><p>PJ is a staff writer across Pure Xbox and Nintendo Life. He's been playing video games pretty much nonstop since the early 1980s, and enjoys boring people with tedious stories about how long ago that really is.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/PJOReilly"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/pjoreilly.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('PJOReilly');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Officially Enters The Handheld Space, But Nintendo Won't Be Worried]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/xbox-officially-enters-the-handheld-space-but-nintendo-wont-be-worried</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-officially-enters-the-handheld-space-but-nintendo-wont-be-worried.1213104/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/xbox-officially-enters-the-handheld-space-but-nintendo-wont-be-worried<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>This feels as niche as it gets</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="Xbox Ally" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/2684be8ef110c/xbox-ally.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SOKm9dDOSC8">Xbox</a></em></figcaption></figure><p>Xbox has officially entered the handheld space with the announcement of two new devices: the <strong>ROG Xbox Ally</strong> and the <strong>ROG Xbox Ally X</strong>.</p>
<p>Launching toward the end of 2025, the new portable systems are the result of a collaboration between Xbox and Asus. They aim to take advantage of Xbox Play Anywhere, a service that lets you play across console, PC, and supported handhelds.</p>
<p>The standard ROG Xbox Ally comes with 16GB RAM and 512GB SSD storage, while the ROG Ally X rocks 24GB RAM and 1TB SSD storage. The latter also benefits from the AMD Ryzen AI Z2 Extreme Processor, a step up from the Ally's Z2 A Processor.</p>
<p>Aesthetically, the two look pretty similar, with grips that take inspiration from the Xbox controller and face buttons that will look instantly familiar to those well-acquainted with Microsoft's console line. The main difference is that the Ally X comes in black and the standard Ally in white.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>ROG Xbox Ally:</strong> powered by the AMD Ryzen™ Z2 A Processor - balancing performance and power consumption to maximize battery life without sacrificing gameplay quality - 16GB of RAM and 512GB of SSD storage.</p>
<p><strong>ROG Xbox Ally X:</strong> features the AMD Ryzen™ AI Z2 Extreme processor - allowing us to bring new experiences to life including greater frames-per-second, sharp visuals and increased intelligence - double the storage to have more native games at your fingertips, and 24GB of high-speed RAM and 1TB of SSD storage.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>To be clear, though, as highlighted by our pals over at <a href="https://www.purexbox.com/news/2025/06/no-the-rog-xbox-ally-handheld-doesnt-play-native-console-games">Pure Xbox</a>, these devices are Windows PC handhelds first and foremost. They don't play console games, but rather native PC titles on Xbox. So essentially, with Xbox Play Anywhere (which boasts <a href="https://www.purexbox.com/news/2025/03/microsoft-shares-updated-xbox-play-anywhere-games-list-as-it-unifies-console-and-pc">over 1000 compatible titles</a>), you get a PC version of a game for free when you buy it on an Xbox console.</p>
<p>What's not clear yet, however, is how much these things will cost. Xbox recently <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/05/xbox-is-raising-the-price-of-consoles-accessories-and-games-worldwide">raised its prices across the board</a>, and given the specs on these things, we can't imagine either of them will come in at anything less than £500.</p>
<p>Keeping in mind the potential price, the rather niche appeal of the systems, <em>and</em> the fact that <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/04/nintendo-has-been-a-great-partner-phil-spencer-reiterates-switch-2-support">Microsoft is keen to support the Switch 2</a>, we can't imagine Nintendo is even remotely concerned about the new ROG Ally devices. Regardless, we'll be keeping a close eye on future developements and how other companies take inspiration from Xbox's new handhelds.</p>

<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:183055 @ 1749475054 -->
<p><em>What are your thoughts on Xbox's new ROG Ally handhelds? Are you interested in getting one of them? Let us know with a comment down below.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.purexbox.com/news/2025/06/xbox-handheld-is-called-rog-xbox-ally-releases-holiday-2025" rel="noopener" href="https://www.purexbox.com/news/2025/06/xbox-handheld-is-called-rog-xbox-ally-releases-holiday-2025">purexbox.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/69b1d31e4a00cdde809c26b29239ba08 @ 1749472446 --></div></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Freak's Upcoming Action RPG Looks Awesome, But Don't Expect It On Switch 2 Yet]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/game-freaks-upcoming-action-rpg-looks-awesome-but-dont-expect-it-on-switch-2-yet</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/game-freaks-upcoming-action-rpg-looks-awesome-but-dont-expect-it-on-switch-2-yet.1213077/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/game-freaks-upcoming-action-rpg-looks-awesome-but-dont-expect-it-on-switch-2-yet<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>

<p>Game Freak has made games other than Pokémon before. It has also released games on non-Nintendo platforms before. Yet whenever it spices up a launch schedule with either of these curveballs, it never fails to catch us off guard.</p>
<p>Yesterday, the Pokémon dev popped up at the Xbox Games Showcase to reveal <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/beast_of_reincarnation">Beast of Reincarnation</a>, the action RPG previously <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2023/05/pokemon-studio-game-freak-is-partnering-with-private-division-on-project-bloom">revealed back in 2023</a> under the codename 'Project Bloom'. It looks awesome, it's arriving at some point in 2026, and Switch / Switch 2... don't appear to be invited to the party right now.</p>
<p>Beast of Reincarnation has been confirmed for launch on Xbox Series X and S, PC and PS5, and, from the little we've seen so far, it certainly seems to be making the most of the beefier consoles' power.</p>
<p>Described as "an expansive one-person, one-dog action RPG built around demanding, technical combat," Beast of Reincarnation will see you exploring a post-apocalyptic Japan, on a mission to take down a gruesome beastie that brought about mankind's demise. Soooo, <em>not</em> catching cute little bug creatures in the tall grass, then?</p>
<p>Here's a brief summary and a handful of screenshots from the game's Steam page:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In post-apocalyptic Japan, a land ruined by corruption and crawling with monstrous beasts, humanity’s last hope may rest with Emma—an outcast cursed as a Blighted One—and Koo, her loyal canine companion.<br>
Survive a journey across an ominous, ever-changing world where dangerous forests can erupt in the wasteland. As Emma and Koo push deeper into the unknown, their bond strengthens—and with it, strange powers bloom.<br>
Explore what it means to be human in Beast of Reincarnation, an expansive one-person, one-dog action RPG built around demanding, technical combat.<br>
What awaits at journey’s end?</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This one was initially announced as a partnership between Game Freak and Private Division, but the latest reveal has a new studio, 'Fictions,' on publishing duties — presumed to be the team built by <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/01/ex-annapurna-interactive-staff-reportedly-pick-up-private-division-portfolio-under-new-studio">former Annapurna Interactive staff</a>.</p>
<p>It all looks very big and impressive, with a scale that we're sure would prove too much for Switch 1. Switch 2, on the other hand, might be able to handle things — it can handle <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/cyberpunk-2077-ultimate-edition">Cyberpunk</a>, for crying out loud — but it's still missing from the launch line-up for the time being. Keep those fingers crossed for another announcement soon then, eh?</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-articles:149173,176586 @ 1749472347 -->
<p><em>What do you make of Beast of Reincarnation so far? Are you hoping to see it on Switch 2? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>