<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 14:20:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dark Souls Narrator Pik-Sen Lim Has Passed Away]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/dark-souls-narrator-pik-sen-lim-has-passed-away</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dark-souls-narrator-pik-sen-lim-has-passed-away.1219494/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/dark-souls-narrator-pik-sen-lim-has-passed-away<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>"Heat and cold, life and death..."</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure><a title="Pik-Sen Lim death" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/03392d0c0bc67/pik-sen-lim-death.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Bandai Namco</em></figcaption></figure><p>Pik-Sen Lim, the Penang-born British actress who most of us gamers will know immediately as the legendary narrator of the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/dark_souls_remastered">Dark Souls</a> series, has passed away at the age of 80.</p>
<p>As reported by <a href="https://www.malaymail.com/news/showbiz/2025/06/13/malaysian-born-actress-pik-sen-lim-known-for-roles-in-mind-your-language-doctor-who-and-johnny-english-reborn-dies-at-80/180215#google_vignette">the Malay Mail</a> (thanks <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/dark-souls/dark-souls-narrator-and-prolific-actor-pik-sen-lim-has-died/">PC Gamer</a>), the actress, who moved to the UK to pursue a hugely successful stage and screen acting career in 1961, passed away on Monday 9th June. Lim was a big star during the '70s and '80s on both British and Malaysian TV, with her credits including <strong>Dr Who</strong>, <strong>Coronation Street</strong>, <strong>The Bill</strong>, and her most prominent role in the sitcom <strong>Mind Your Language</strong>, which aired in the UK during the late 1970s.</p><p><figure data-videoid="A1xI46KxTIU" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/A1xI46KxTIU?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><a id="yt-2" title="Play" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A1xI46KxTIU"></a><figcaption>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>822k</span></a></figcaption><figcaption><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A1xI46KxTIU">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></figcaption></figure></p>

<p>Of course, without Lim, the Souls games just wouldn't feel the same, would they? The opening narration to Dark Souls, in particular, is just one of those video game moments that sticks in your brain forever after. It's delivered with such artistry that it immediately signals a game you're about to get lost in big time. And oh boy, did we.</p>
<p>As a first sample of FromSoftware's world, and the vibe the developer wished to convey, it's hard to imagine anyone could have rocked it as hard as Pik-Sen Lim did. In fact, let's check it out more more time in her honour...</p>

<p>What a performance. Rest in peace.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Have any favourite Pik-Sen Lim moments from the Dark Souls and Dark Souls 3 intros, or from her extensive acting career on stage and screen? Make sure to let us know.</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:99812,82148 @ 1750080604 --></section></article><div><p>PJ is a staff writer across Pure Xbox and Nintendo Life. He's been playing video games pretty much nonstop since the early 1980s, and enjoys boring people with tedious stories about how long ago that really is.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/PJOReilly"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/pjoreilly.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('PJOReilly');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exclusive: Cosy Roguelike 'Into The Emberlands' Looks Super Cute In Debut Switch Trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/exclusive-cosy-roguelike-into-the-emberlands-looks-super-cute-in-debut-switch-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/exclusive-cosy-roguelike-into-the-emberlands-looks-super-cute-in-debut-switch-trailer.1219428/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/exclusive-cosy-roguelike-into-the-emberlands-looks-super-cute-in-debut-switch-trailer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>We didn't start the fire</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Those looking for something to relax and unwind to after a tough day of Knockout Tour might want to check out <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/into_the_emberlands">Into The Emberlands</a>, a "cosy roguelike" from developer Tiny Roar (<a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/xel">XEL</a>) and publisher Daedalic Entertainment that will be arriving on the Switch eShop on <strong>2nd July</strong>.</p>
<p>This one launched on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2856370/Into_the_Emberlands/">Steam</a> earlier this year and, to put it simply, it looks <em>super</em> cute. Into the Emberlands will see you play as a Lightbearer tasked with reuniting the titular world after it became swamped in a malicious miasma. To do so, you'll have to journey out into the fog with your Ember Lantern, collecting resources and rehoming the adorable little Knacks (the species you'll see in the above trailer) you'll encounter along the way.</p><p><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><a id="yt-2" title="Play" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C1rrCdi_XjA"></a><figcaption>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>822k</span></a></figcaption><figcaption><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C1rrCdi_XjA">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></figcaption></figure></p>
<p>You only have a limited number of steps per day — room for a little more <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/blue_prince">Blue Prince</a>, anyone? — and the gameplay loop will restart if you run out, with your previous Lightbearer setting up camp to be found on a future run.</p>
<p>It's combat-free, all about helping others, and colourful enough that we can imagine it being an all-round wholesome experience — and we could all do with a little of that every now and then.</p>
<p>You'll find a rundown of the game's key features and a handful of screenshots below from the <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/en-gb/Games/Nintendo-Switch-download-software/Into-The-Emberlands-2848916.html">eShop listing</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Explore<br>
- Embark on your journey that starts in the village of the charming Knacks<br>
- Explore an ever-sprawling world full of small adventures and big surprises<br>
- Traverse various biomes in a procedurally generated world with endless replayability<br>
- Discover the scenery hidden by the glooming Miasma which is teeming with life and secrets</p>
<p>Encounter<br>
- Encounter quirky and mystical creatures<br>
- Support the various inhabitants of the Emberlands and they’ll aid your journey with resources and valuable upgrades to your equipment!<br>
- Keep an eye out for the Knacks that lost their way in the Miasma and guide them safely home to the light of your village</p>
<p>Expand<br>
- Rebuild and expand your village to a thriving safe haven for your people!<br>
- Use the resources you gathered to upgrade your village by building new homes and amenities<br>
- Lay the foundation for future adventures, as each new building and vendor will give you a head-start on your next quest</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Into the Emberlands arrives on the Switch eShop on 2nd July for <strong>£5.49 / €6.59</strong>, and there's even a 20% discount available for all those who pre-order before launch day.</p>
<p><em>What do you make of this one? Will you be taking it for a spin next month? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>