<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 12:35:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GameSir And Hyperkin Reveal A Modular Pad With GameCube And N64 Layouts]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/gamesir-and-hyperkin-reveal-a-modular-pad-with-gamecube-and-n64-layouts</link>
            <guid>1399171</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Fully compatible with Switch and Switch 2</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Accessory manufacturers GameSir and Hyperkin have joined forces to produce a fully modular controller that's compatible with the Switch and Switch 2: the <strong>GameSir x Hyperkin X5 Alteron</strong>.</p>
<p>Ignoring the terrible name for a moment, this thing actually looks pretty neat. Utilising an extendable telescopic arm design, you can clip it onto your Switch, Switch 2, iPhone, iPad, or Android devices for instant handheld play. It also comes with Bluetooth technology to allow for PC gaming, if you wish.</p>
<p>The biggest draw, however, is the modular design. You can swap out the front modules to completely customise your controller's layout, with options ranging from a fight pad design to faithful (ish) recreations of the GameCube and N64 controllers.</p>
<p>It also comes with a host of modern features that you'd come to expect from controllers these days, including triggers that can swap between tactile, micro-switch functionality to full Hall Effect analogue functionality. Similarly, the capacitive sticks come with the ability to alter their height to ensure maximum comfort for each individual player.</p>
<p>It all sounds lovely on paper, but we do wonder if this 'Jack of all Trades' approach will work out for Gamesir and Hyperkin. CES 2026 attendees can get an in-person view of an early model of the X5 Alteron, but we'll have to wait and see if this thing can be a legitimate contender in a world jam-packed with third-party controllers.</p>

<p>There's no word on when the X5 Alteron will launch, but we'll keep you posted as soon as we hear more.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:183944,85997 @ 1767789227 -->
<p><em>What do you make of this new controller from GameSir and Hyperkin? Leave a comment with your thoughts and let us know.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/gamesir-and-hyperkin-reveal-a-modular-pad-with-gamecube-and-n64-layouts]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil Requiem's Latest Trailer Teases Bustling City Environment]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/resident-evil-requiems-latest-trailer-teases-bustling-city-environment</link>
            <guid>1399072</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>How will it hold up on Switch 2?</p>
</section></header><div><section>

<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/resident-evil-requiem">Resident Evil Requiem</a> arrives on the Switch 2 and multiple other platforms next month, and ahead of the anticipated release, new footage has surfaced at CES 2026 this week.</p>
<p>During Nvidia's PC showcase of the title featuring path tracing and DLSS 4 with multi frame generation, a new setting in the series has reportedly been revealed. As <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/resident-evil-requiems-nvidia-trailer-includes-a-big-tease-at-a-new-environment/">highlighted by VGC</a>, it's a glimpse at a "new city environment" and what's believed to be the fictional location Wrenwood, where the game unfolds.</p>
<p>What's so unique here is it's a big contrast to what we're used to seeing in the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/resident_evil">Resident Evil</a> series. Instead of chaos and zombies in every direction, as you can see, it's actually a lively place, with humans and vehicles making their way through the streets. Of course, we don't know for sure how much activity will take place here, but it's an exciting glimpse!</p>
<figure data-uuid="71948ed41df8d"><a title="Resident Evil Requiem" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/71948ed41df8d/resident-evil-requiem.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Capcom, Nvidia</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>As the source further notes, <a href="https://x.com/AestheticGamer1">Resident Evil enthusiast Dusk Golem</a> (who has a history covering Capcom-related rumours) has previously mentioned how Requiem could contain some "big open levels". It follows the news last month that the legend and video game icon <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/leon-kennedy-is-confirmed-for-resident-evil-requiem">Leon Kennedy would be returning</a> in the latest outing. You can check out Nvidia's full clip above, which shows the new protagonist and FBI intelligence analyst Grace Ashcroft walking around the city.</p>
<p>As for the game's performance and visuals on the Switch 2, Nintendo Life contributor Lowell Bell went <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/previews/hands-on-resident-evil-requiem-switch-2-footage-a-surprisingly-tense-port">hands on with the handheld build at the Tokyo Game Show</a> in 2025 - mentioning at the time how this version still "looked amazing" (even though there was a "visual downgrade") and didn't notice any "dropped frames". So, hopefully, the final build for Switch 2 launches in a good state when this title arrives on <strong>27th February 2026</strong>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:188518,195265,194052,195893 @ 1767788423 -->
<p>Are you ready to jump back into the world of Resident Evil next month? Are you planning to get this game on the Switch 2? <em>Tell us in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/resident-evil-requiems-nvidia-trailer-includes-a-big-tease-at-a-new-environment/" rel="noopener" href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/resident-evil-requiems-nvidia-trailer-includes-a-big-tease-at-a-new-environment/">videogameschronicle.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/8414387bafe35b8c5e0800218ba7da2a @ 1767788141 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/resident-evil-requiems-latest-trailer-teases-bustling-city-environment]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>