<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 08:59:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Champions Confirmed For Switch 2, Includes "Free-To-Start" And "Paid" Digital Version]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/pokemon-champions-confirmed-for-switch-2-includes-free-to-start-and-paid-digital-version</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-champions-confirmed-for-switch-2-includes-free-to-start-and-paid-digital-version.1272417/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>More details will be "shared in the future"</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure><a title="Pokemon Champions" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/c17b007658401/pokemon-champions.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: The Pokémon Company</em></figcaption></figure><p>We've just had an update about the new battle-focused game <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pokemon_champions">Pokémon Champions</a> at the World Championships, and apart from <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/pokemon-champions-is-the-main-battle-game-for-the-2026-world-championships">the news it will lead as the main title for the VGC</a> next year, along with a Mega Evolution update, we've also got details about platforms and pricing.</p>
<p>According to the latest press release, it's coming to not only the Switch and mobile devices in <strong>2026</strong> but also the Switch 2.</p>
<p>As for the pricing models, it will be available as a "free-to-start game" but it's also been confirmed by The Pokémon Company that more details about "a paid digital version" for Switch and Switch 2 systems will be shared in the future. Here's this part of the PR in full:</p><div><figure data-videoid="RLc1VHm8D80" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RLc1VHm8D80?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/RLc1VHm8D80?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RLc1VHm8D80?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed43f22fpsvwix&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><figcaption><p><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RLc1VHm8D80" rel="noopener">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></p>
<p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>830k</span></a></p>
</figcaption></figure></div>
<blockquote>
<p>"Pokémon Champions is a free-to-start game coming to Nintendo Switch 2, Nintendo Switch, and mobile devices in 2026. More details on a paid digital version of Pokémon Champions on Nintendo Switch 2 and Nintendo Switch systems will be shared in the future."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The official English game site has provided some information about this upcoming release as well – reiterating how there's cross-play support between Switch and mobile devices, and noting how Pokémon can be brought from <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/pokemon_home">Pokémon HOME</a> into Pokémon Champions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Starting in 2026, Pokémon Champions will be used as the VGC software for the Pokémon World Championships and for Championship Series events leading up to Worlds. Pokémon can be brought from Pokémon HOME into Pokémon Champions to assemble powerful teams. Cross-platform support will also permit players to compete on either Nintendo Switch systems or mobile devices."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>You can find out about the other announcements for Pokémon Champions in our previous post here on Nintendo Life.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:186645,186643 @ 1755505319 -->
<p>What are your thoughts about this news? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/pokemon-champions-confirmed-for-switch-2-includes-free-to-start-and-paid-digital-version]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Teases New 'Pokémon XP' Event]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/pokemon-teases-new-pokemon-xp-event</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-teases-new-pok%C3%A9mon-xp-event.1272408/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Taking place in "downtown San Francisco"</p>
</section></header><div><section>

<p>One mystery reveal at this year's World Championships event for Pokémon was the announcement of PokémonXP.</p>
<p>This news was revealed alongside the confirmation of an "epic arena experience" for Championship Sunday next year at the Chase Center, San Francisco between <strong>28th - 30th August, 2026</strong>, with passes going on sale on <strong>17th September 2025</strong>.</p>
<p>According to the official PR, this event will take place alongside the World Championships on <strong>28th August, 2026</strong> at the Moscone Center in the heart of San Francisco. Here's some additional information from the official website:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"PokémonXP brings an expansive selection of Pokémon experiences and partners together in one place. Come join a celebration of community and all things Pokémon as you enjoy featured panels, unique workshops, special guests, exclusive merchandise, and so much more at the first event of its kind. PokémonXP will take place at the same time as the 2026 Pokémon World Championships, so Pokémon fans have an opportunity to attend two iconic Pokémon experiences."</p>
<p>"Join the fun at the Bay Area’s Moscone Center and Yerba Buena Gardens with a range of Pokémon-centric festivities including workshops, panels, performances, opportunities to meet special guests, a Pokémon Center pop-up store, and more! Check back in spring of 2026 for more details."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>You can check out the <a href="https://pokemonxp.com/en-us">official PokémonXP website</a> for more details about the pricing, registration and activities. You can also sign up to <a href="https://pokemonxp.com/en-us">Pokémon emails</a> for updates about this event.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/pokemon/related-articles:186643 @ 1755505248 --></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://pokemonxp.com/en-us" rel="noopener" href="https://pokemonxp.com/en-us">pokemonxp.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/pokemon/related-info/4c60441fe7a879ce1dc5cb98ba327381 @ 1755504675 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/pokemon-teases-new-pokemon-xp-event]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Champions Is The Main Battle Game For 2026 World Championships, Mega Evolutions Confirmed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/pokemon-champions-is-the-main-battle-game-for-2026-world-championships-mega-evolutions-confirmed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-champions-is-the-main-battle-game-for-2026-world-championships-mega-evolutions-confirmed.1272396/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>The VGC shifts to the new battle entry</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>We've got another update about <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pokemon_champions">Pokémon Champions</a> today, and it confirms the video game competition will shift to this battle entry at next year's World Championships. The 2025 tournament was played on <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pokemon_scarlet_and_violet">Pokémon Scarlet and Violet</a>.</p>
<p>Alongside this was a look at multiple Mega Evolutions featured in the game, along with some information about how trainers will be able to use the Omni Ring.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Mega-Evolved Pokémon will feature in the first set of regulations for Ranked Battles in Pokémon Champions!</p></blockquote><blockquote>
<p>Use your Omni Ring in the heat of battle to Mega Evolve your Pokémon, including the newly revealed Mega Dragonite featured in Pokémon Legends: Z-A!</p>
<p>Be sure to get all the practice you can, because Pokémon Champions will be used for VGC at Worlds 2026. Stay tuned to learn more!</p>
</blockquote>
<figure><a title="Pokemon Champions Mega Evolutions" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/eb0ee4465df04/pokemon-champions-mega-evolutions.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: The Pokémon Company</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>The official website for Champions also goes into detail about how Pokémon from <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/pokemon_home">Pokémon HOME</a> can be brought into this new entry, with cross-platform support between mobile and Switch devices confirmed as well.</p>
<p>In fine print, it's also mentioned how "in certain regions" Pokémon Scarlet and Pokémon Violet may still be used for Championship Series events.</p>
<p>Last but not least, it's been confirmed Champions is on its way to Switch 2 in 2026, and the PR for this latest announcement has confirmed this title is "free-to-start" with a "paid digital version" on the way. You can read more in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/pokemon-champions-confirmed-for-switch-2-includes-free-to-start-and-paid-digital-version">our latest story here on Nintendo Life</a>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:186647,186643 @ 1755504303 -->
<p>What are your thoughts about this news? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/pokemon-champions-is-the-main-battle-game-for-2026-world-championships-mega-evolutions-confirmed]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Legends: Z-A Unveils New Multiplayer Battle Mode For Up Four Trainers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/pokemon-legends-z-a-unveils-new-multiplayer-battle-mode-for-up-four-trainers</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-legends-z-a-unveils-new-multiplayer-battle-mode-for-up-four-trainers.1272393/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>The first rule of Battle Club...</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure><a title="﻿Pokémon Legends: Z-A" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/0fcf4b662e776/pokemon-legends-z-a.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: The ﻿Pokémon Company</em></figcaption></figure><p>During the 2025 Pokémon World Championships, it was announced Link and Ranked Battles would be coming to <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pokemon_legends_z-a">Pokémon Legends: Z-A</a> for the Switch and Switch 2 as part of the Z-A Battle Club.</p>
<p>These battles will allow up to four trainers to join in on battles where they attempt to defeat as many of each other's Pokémon within a set time limit of 3 minutes. You'll need to make full use of a variety of moves as well as Mega Evolutions as you "go on the offensive".</p>
<p>Here's the official PR, and you can check out the latest trailer below this:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Trainers will be able to jump into the Z-A Battle Club in the <em>Pokémon Legends: Z-A</em> game in the newly revealed Link and Ranked Battles. In the Z-A Battle Club (Link Battles), up to four players will race to defeat as many Pokémon as possible within the time limit to take the top spot.</p>
<p>In Ranked Battles, up to four Trainers can compete online from around the world to earn points. When players earn enough points, they will rise in rank. Trainers will start off at Rank Z and can be promoted all the way up to the ultimate Rank A.​</p>
<p>Players can earn in-game rewards when a battle ends or when their rank increases, with additional rewards granted based on their final rank when the season ends after a set time period. Since rewards vary by season, active participation is necessary to climb the ranks and earn rewards. Players will also be able to enjoy Private Battles with their friends using local communicationor with those farther away online.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Pokémon Legends: Z-A arrives for the Switch and Switch 2 on <strong>16th October 2025</strong>, with pre-orders now officially live. This includes a Nintendo Switch 2 + <em>Pokémon Legends: Z-A</em> bundle offer.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:186643,186647,183867 @ 1755504483 -->
<p>What do you think of this latest reveal? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/pokemon-legends-z-a-unveils-new-multiplayer-battle-mode-for-up-four-trainers]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Round Up: Everything Announced At The 2025 Pokémon World Championships Closing Ceremony]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/round-up-everything-announced-at-the-2025-pokemon-world-championships-closing-ceremony</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/round-up-everything-announced-at-the-2025-pok%C3%A9mon-world-championships-closing-ceremony.1272378/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure><a title="The Pokémon Company" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/ad59e3f0b7264/the-pokemon-company.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: The Pokémon Company</em></figcaption></figure><p>The Pokémon Company president and CEO Tsunekazu Ishihara made an appearance at this year's Pokémon World Championships closing ceremony and shared updates about multiple Pokémon games, and even some event news.</p>
<p>If you weren't able to catch the event live, don't worry - because we've put together the full round up of every announcement here. This includes links to standalone stories, which provide even more information about what's on the way to select Pokémon titles in the future.</p>
<p>Here's the full rundown of everything announced at the 2025 Pokémon World Championships:</p>
<nav><ul><li><span title="On This Page"></span></li></ul>
</nav>
<h3 id="pokemon-go"><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/mobile/pokemon_go">Pokémon GO</a></h3>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/mobile/pokemon_go">Pokémon GO</a> sees the arrival of Eternatus, along with the introduction of Max Battles featuring this same Pokémon.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Both will make their global debut with GO Pass: Max Finale, launching later this month during the Dark Skies event."</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="pokemon-trading-card-game-pocket"><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/mobile/pokemon_trading_card_game_pocket">Pokémon Trading Card Game Pocket</a></h3>
<p>Mega Evolution is coming to <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/mobile/pokemon_trading_card_game_pocket">Pokémon Trading Card Game Pocket</a> this Fall.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Pokémon ex cards, including Mega Gyarados ex, Mega Blaziken ex, and Mega Altaria ex will be debuting in Pokémon Trading Card Game Pocket. Fans can stay tuned for more details on <a href="https://tcgpocket.pokemon.com/">Pokemon.com/TCGPocket</a>."</p></blockquote><blockquote>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="pokemon-unite"><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/pokemon_unite">Pokémon Unite</a></h3>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/pokemon_unite">Pokémon Unite</a> just celebrated its fourth anniversary and there are multiple character updates on the way. Empoleon, Dhelmise and Vaporeon will the game soon, starting with Empoleon on <strong>19th September 2025</strong>.</p>

<h3 id="pokemon-trading-card-game">Pokémon Trading Card Game</h3>
<blockquote>
<p>"The Pokémon Trading Card Game pulled back the curtain on Mega attack rare, an all-new card rarity that features attack names in katakana, reminiscent of the original Mega Evolution Pokémon-<em>EX</em> cards from the <em>XY</em> Series. Mega attack rare cards coming to the Pokémon TCG include Mega Charizard X ex, Mega Gardevoir ex, and Mega Lucario ex.</p></blockquote><blockquote>
<p>"Trainers also received a first look at Mega Dragonite, as seen in the upcoming <em>Pokémon Legends: Z-A</em> video game, which will be coming to the Pokémon TCG as a new Pokémon ex."</p>
</blockquote>


<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:186644 @ 1755505230 -->

<blockquote>
<p>The Z-A Battle Club is ready for its newest Link Battle entrants! Up to four players can take part in battles where they attempt to defeat as many of each other’s Pokémon as they can within the time limit.<br>
Make full use of a variety of moves and Mega Evolutions and go on the offensive!​</p></blockquote><blockquote>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="pokemon-champions"><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pokemon_champions">Pokémon Champions</a></h3>
<p>The latest news for Pokémon Champions includes the confirmation it will be the main game for VGC at next year's World Championships. Along with this is a Switch 2 confirmation, a look at Mega Evolutions, and news about how it's being made available to trainers.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:186647,186645 @ 1755505497 -->

<h3 id="pokemonxp">PokémonXP</h3>
<p>Alongside the news about the 2026 Pokémon World Championships, which are being held in San Francisco, a new event called PokémonXP has also been teased.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"On Aug. 28, 2026, the Pokémon World Championships will level up with the addition of an all-new fan experience: PokémonXP. This event will take place alongside the 2026 Pokémon World Championships competitions at the Moscone Center in the heart of San Francisco, welcoming Trainers from across the world to celebrate their fandom with a variety of unique offerings and engaging activities, with something for every fan."</p>
</blockquote>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:186646 @ 1755504744 -->

<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:186466 @ 1755505230 -->
<p><em>What do you think of these latest announcements?</em> <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/round-up-everything-announced-at-the-2025-pokemon-world-championships-closing-ceremony]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Review: ANTANK S3 MAX TV Dock Station For Nintendo Switch 2 - A Decent Little Travel Dock]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/antank-s3-max-tv-dock-station-for-nintendo-switch-2-a-decent-little-travel-dock</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/review-antank-s3-max-tv-dock-station-for-nintendo-switch-2-a-decent-little-travel-dock.1272216/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure><a title="SIWIQU S3 MAX TV Dock Station For Nintendo Switch 2 1" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/0706b57b5d6ff/siwiqu-s3-max-tv-dock-station-for-nintendo-switch-2-1.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Gavin Lane / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>Nintendo's own dock is a non-nonsense device that just works. You slide your console in, crack the Joy-Con off, and boom, you're off to the races. Given the larger size of Switch 2, though, its dock is a substantial slab of black plastic and various third-party firms have stepped in with offerings that are a little more portable.</p>
<p>Antank is one such company, and the S3 MAX TV Dock Station for Nintendo Switch 2 — also known as the SIWIQU Dock Station in some parts — is certainly smaller than the dock that comes with the console. Weighing in at 109 grams (compared to 383 grams), you'll barely notice you're carrying it in your satchel, backpack, or anywhere else you care to secrete your hardware.</p>
<p>Antack sent me the standard model for review, although they have another one that includes an Ethernet port for wired internet connection. Otherwise, on the back of the dock, you get the expected ports: two USB-A slots, a USB-C port for the power, an HDMI port going to your TV, and a button to switch between TV-out and the Switch 2's own display. Beyond the dock itself, in the box you get a little foldout manual with the tiniest text I've ever seen, and that's your lot.</p>

<p>For $35.99 / £28.99, it should come as no surprise that you're not getting Nintendo-level build quality and materials, and the lightness here doesn't help sell the S3 as a premium bit of kit, either. But it's fine; the red and blue end caps match up with the accents around the Joy-Con, and sitting beside your TV, it looks pleasant enough.</p>
<p>You're also not getting an AC power adapter, the requisite cable, or an HDMI cable, and Antack recommends using Nintendo's official gear. If you've got a Switch 2, you'll obviously have that already, but if you're buying this as a cheap dock for a second room, you'll need to factor into your budget another $34.99 / £24.99 for the power adapter, plus an HDMI 2.1 cable (the ultra high speed variety).</p>
<p>Setup is as simple as you'd expect. Connect the cables, turn your TV on, and boom. It works. In fact, I had to reconnect the console a couple of times — apparently a quirk that's been ironed out with <a href="https://antank.net/pages/s3-max-firmware-update">a firmware update</a> I've subsequently run according to the <a href="https://antank.net/pages/s3-max-firmware-update-guide-for-windows">instructions on Antack's website</a> — but then it just functioned as advertised.</p>

<p>A little blue LED on the front indicates that everything's powered up. The S3 supports 4K (8K, in fact, according to the blurb, although you won't get that out of your Switch and I've got no way to display 8K content) and up to 120Hz output - although the Switch 2 can only manage 120fps at 1080p, and you'll need a 120Hz+-capable TV, naturally. Several hours of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/donkey-kong-bananza">Donkey Kong Bananza</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/ufo_50">UFO 50</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/drag-x-drive">Drag x Drive</a> delivered image quality on a 55-inch LG OLED that looked indistinguishable from the official dock to my eyes. HDR fired up just as with the standard offering, and everything just worked.</p>
<p>Back to the unit itself, Antank's website blurb mentions a "spring-buffered docking port", although I can't see any evidence of a spring on my unit. The connection at the bottom is totally rigid and fits the console port snugly once you seat the thing correctly, which can take a couple of tries.</p>
<p>Having the system 'unsheathed', you'll definitely note the heat it's pumping out in a way you may not when it's resting in Nintendo's dock. The S3 effectively blocks the console's air intakes along the bottom edge, which gave me pause, but temperature-wise, the fact that the system isn't wrapped in black plastic helps disperse heat from the casing and "provides better cooling than the original charging dock", according to Antank. I don't have the equipment to measure that, unfortunately, and I'd question if the cooling is 'better' than Nintendo's dock, but it seemed roughly the same to me from a volume and temperature perspective.</p>
<p>Switching to handheld mode by hitting the round button on the rear, I noticed the console's fan whirring up more in the summer heat. Given the fact that you can charge via the top USB-C port anyway, I'd prefer to have those intakes uncovered in tabletop mode, personally. Yes, a cable sticking out the top isn't aesthetically pleasing, but I'd rather not tax my still-relatively-new system more than necessary when it's not outputting to the TV. Perhaps I'm being overly cautious, but honestly, I don't see much point in the tabletop button when that's built into the console as-is.</p>

<p>The size reduction is a boon, certainly, but the S3 does come with some minor irritations. Firstly, you'll need to hold the dock down before pulling to remove the console - there's no slide-in/slide-out here. The tight fit means that the S3 doesn't work with third-party cases, either, so you'll need to remove them beforehand. Also, the dock doesn’t seem to communicate with the TV to wake it from standby, if that’s something you’re used to with the standard dock.</p>
<p>While three rubber 'feet' prevent it from slipping, the dock relies on the power and HDMI cables being connected to provide stability and prevent everything toppling backwards at the slightest touch. Obviously, the Switch 2 has its own kickstand, so using the S3 as a makeshift stand doesn't make sense anyway - just be cautious when you're setting things up and don't put your system in the dock until the cables are connected.</p>
<p>And that's it. It's definitely more of a travel accessory in my eyes; if I were in the market for a second dock for the home, I'd probably pay the extra for the slide-in/out convenience (and the necessary cables) of the official option. If you're the kind of person eager to travel as light as possible, or who feels a missed opportunity when playing your Switch 2 in the shadow of a big hotel-room TV, the S3 might be for you, though.</p>
<p>And even factoring in the necessary extras, you're still a fair way off the $124.99 / £92.99 that Nintendo wants for a second dock with those essentials included. For the budget-conscious gamer, then, or travellers who fancy being able to hook up on the fly, it's a good option.</p>



<p>Please note that some external links on this page are affiliate links, which means if you click them and make a purchase we may receive a small percentage of the sale. Please read our <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/advertising">FTC Disclosure</a> for more information.</p>

<p><em>Thanks to Antank for supplying the sample used in this review.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/antank-s3-max-tv-dock-station-for-nintendo-switch-2-a-decent-little-travel-dock]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mattel Adds Special Edition Pauline To Its Mario Kart Hot Wheels Line]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/mattel-adds-special-edition-pauline-to-its-mario-kart-hot-wheels-line</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mattel-adds-special-edition-pauline-to-its-mario-kart-hot-wheels-line.1272156/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Pre-orders are now live</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="Pauline Hot Wheels" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/89fdfc6bbc608/pauline-hot-wheels.large.jpg"></a></figure>
<p>Mattel has already released a whole bunch of Mario Kart vehicles and next up is a "special edition" Pauline release, which was originally revealed at San Diego Comic-Con this year.</p>
<p>It's arriving on <strong>26th September 2025</strong> and will be available for <strong>$22.00 / £20.00</strong>, with <a href="https://creations.mattel.com/en-gb/products/hot-wheels-mario-kart-pauline-vehicle-jjp81">pre-orders now live.</a></p>
<p>It comes with the Hot Wheels Mario Kart Pauline, the vehicle body colour is "Rhodamine red", it's got a premium packaging style (and is packaged in a "displayble window box"), and the scale is 1:64.</p>
<p>Here are some more details from the official Mattel Creations website:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Our special-edition Pauline figure, joining our line for the first time, is ready to take on the world of Hot Wheels Mario Kart. Racing on Moonview Highway in the Badwagon Kart, she speeds through the city while rocking her signature sparkly red dress and black heels. This daring and dazzling mayor of New Donk City is ready to zoom past the competition."</p>
</blockquote>


<figure><a title="Pauline Hot Wheels" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/33875ab67de8e/pauline-hot-wheels.large.png"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Mattel, Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>This follows on from Pauline's recent appearances in the Switch 2 exclusives <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/donkey-kong-bananza">Donkey Kong Bananza</a>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/mario-kart/related-articles:184766,134664,180580 @ 1755504829 -->
<p>Have you purchased any vehicles in the Mario Kart Hot Wheels line? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://creations.mattel.com/en-gb/products/hot-wheels-mario-kart-pauline-vehicle-jjp81" rel="noopener" href="https://creations.mattel.com/en-gb/products/hot-wheels-mario-kart-pauline-vehicle-jjp81">creations.mattel.com</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://gonintendo.com/contents/51833-hot-wheels-special-edition-mario-kart-pauline-figure-set-for-release-sept-26th-2025" rel="noopener" href="https://gonintendo.com/contents/51833-hot-wheels-special-edition-mario-kart-pauline-figure-set-for-release-sept-26th-2025">gonintendo.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/mario-kart/related-info/7a998bc39721279c55570150f5e24b9f @ 1755506594 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/mattel-adds-special-edition-pauline-to-its-mario-kart-hot-wheels-line]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>