<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:12:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Review: Hades 2 - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition - A Bewitching Sequel That's A Spell Off Perfect]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/hades-ii-nintendo-switch-2-edition</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/review-hades-2-nintendo-switch-2-edition-a-bewitching-sequel-thats-a-spell-off-perfect.1308432/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section>
<p><em>“Can time not be stopped?”</em> That’s the question <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hades-ii-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Hades II</a> asks you every time you clear a run. The stakes are bigger in Supergiant Games’ first-ever sequel: This is no longer <em>just</em> about family drama, it’s about a dysfunctional family defending all they have against the clutches of the Titan of Time. It’s a story of tragedy, of failings, and of the Unseen, headed up by the Princess of the Underworld Melinoë, attempting to save her home.</p>
<p>I love Hades II, though I love just about everything Supergiant Games has ever made. It was the original <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/hades">Hades</a> that sent me down the path of checking out the studio’s back catalogue. An Ancient Greek soap opera about Zagreus attempting to defy his father and escape Hell. It’s extremely personal, using Greek myth to expertly spin a yarn around a roguelike structure.</p>
<figure><a title="Hades II - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Review - Screenshot 1 of 6" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/159141/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Docked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Hades II once again showcases a horde of beautifully written characters and stories amidst that roguelike cycle. The writing is the star here, with tons of new characters for the writers to sink their teeth into, and they do it fantastically. Even returning characters have a few surprises up their sleeves, whether in how they conduct themselves during the war, their brand new — and almost always gorgeous — designs, or their impeccably realised voices.</p>
<p>I <em>have</em> to talk to every character after every run, because they always have something different to say and something to react to. Nemesis might chide me for dying too early one run, while the next might be jealous as I managed to conquer Chronos. Hecate, Melinoë’s mentor, is always looking for more from the Princess, but is equally ready to praise.</p>
<p>And, this time around, the Gods and Goddesses are never shy about what they dislike about mortals, even Melinoë. Surprise! It turns out that Greek deities suck, actually, and that leads to some very interesting discussions about greed or misunderstanding of the human need for hope and the like.</p>
<p>I’m glad Supergiant’s character writing is still on form, as the narrative itself fell a little flat for me. The game uses Greek Tragedy as a framework for Melinoë’s plight fantastically, but her war on the Titan of Time began to feel a little rushed towards the end, and I missed that emotive connection. Family is still key here, as with any good tragedy, but it all feels a little more at arm's length.</p>
<figure><a title="Hades II - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Review - Screenshot 2 of 6" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/159146/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Docked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Those little narrative trip-ups are easy to overlook, though, as the game is staggeringly beautiful, particularly on Switch 2. Jen Zee’s character art truly shines, with every portrait featuring little flicker animations to highlight their specialities or traits, and environments that hide secrets where the attention to detail screams at you. It doesn’t matter if you’re playing docked or handheld, either, Hades II is utterly faultless, though the 120fps docked has a slight edge for me (handheld is locked at 60fps).</p>
<p>The gameplay still has magic, too. Initially, everything felt extremely familiar, but after fumbling or getting greedy a few times, I quickly realised that I needed to completely rethink how I approached the sequel. You can’t play it like it’s Hades; that’s been true since Early Access (I transferred my save data over from Steam seamlessly), and it took me time to adjust to Melinoë’s moveset. She’s not just the Princess of the Underworld, she’s also a Witch, and Magick is the key difference between her and her brother.</p>
<p>While almost all of her actions are the same, each one acts differently; the Cast in particular took me <em>forever</em> to nail down. I was so used to firing magic missiles from range or setting up icy laser beams that the idea of getting down-and-dirty with a more fragile, slower-attacking character, before dashing away again, was hard to overcome. But I became obsessed with it; it’s now my favourite part of Melinoë’s kit.</p>
<figure><a title="Hades II - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Review - Screenshot 3 of 6" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/159138/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>I spent hours running different builds focusing just on the Cast - there was one where I stacked different explosive skills from Hephaestus and Apollo with one of the Moonstone Axe’s aspects: I’d drop the ring down on a huge group of enemies, dash away, and charge up a special which would cause the ring to blow up.</p>
<p>Another build let me regenerate Magick all the time I stood in the ring, so I slapped on Zeus’ lightning or Hera’s Hitch effects to do extra damage or enfeeble enemies all so I could dash through and backstab them with the twin blades inside the ring while they’re afflicted. There’s so much flexibility, I keep finding new ways to ensnare foes with <em>just this</em>.</p>
<p>And, this is only one part of Melinoë’s moveset. When you combine everything together, Hades II’s mechanical richness is staggering. Omega attacks (one for Attack, Special, and Cast) are affected by every weapon type, aspect, and every deity has a boon that affects each of these. Magick management becomes a vital part of every encounter that can be managed with Boons and other things. Melinoë can bring a familiar with her helps gather resources or attack and enhance her own skills. I can even call upon Selene’s moon magic to briefly turn invulnerable or revive dead foes and have them fight for me. Admittedly, this feels like a bit of an afterthought on most builds, and is easily the part of my kit I dug into the least. Sorry, Selene. Your design is beautiful, though.</p>
<figure><a title="Hades II - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Review - Screenshot 4 of 6" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/159139/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Docked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Time and time again, I embarked on a run, tried some new weapons, boons, keepsakes, aspects, and felt the familiarity and comfort of Hades return, just in new wrapping. But this time, there isn’t just one run – there are two different paths: one to the Underworld, the other to the top of Mount Olympus.</p>
<p>The former eventually suffers a bit from that familiar Hades structure — though the Fields of Mourning’s open environments make for a good change of pace — and eventually felt easier than the first game's runs ever did. The Surface, however? Oh boy. I still get my backside handed to me every so often.</p>
<p>Surface runs change things up in a number of ways, such as the City of Ephyra presenting at least ten different doors in one room, allowing you to choose six and strategise your build more carefully early on. The Rift of Thessaly lets you jump between ships and fight multiple waves of enemies in the same location. The last couple of biomes are structured more like Underworld runs, but everything hits a <em>lot</em> harder. There are still times I get caught out by the third big boss of the Surface, and the final one? <em>Ouch</em>.</p>
<figure><a title="Hades II - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Review - Screenshot 5 of 6" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/159137/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>

<p>If I ever got bored with one run, I’d swap and go for the other. You have to do them both multiple times anyway, and given how differently each boss and encounter can and should be approached, it’s good practice. And with every death, with every failure to stop time, you get a little better. Plus, there’s always the joy of hearing Darren Korb’s outstanding soundtrack wherever you go; I could probably write an entire review about Scylla and her band as she belts out tunes during battles with Melinoë about clawing my eyes out and drowning me to death, but that would be discounting the rest of the music. It’s a must-listen.</p>
<p>After every run, you’ll bring back a handful of resources, some of which you forage along the way, while others are rewards. These are required to cast Incantations (which often help out in your runs or are story-related), buy items or Nectar, decorate the Crossroads, and so on. But there are way too many of these to manage, and some are more scarce; every biome has its own flower, seed, metal, fish, etc. And then there’s excess currency I can sell for another currency. When there’s already so much stuff to play with, I could do with fewer resources or currencies to manage.</p>
<figure><a title="Hades II - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Review - Screenshot 6 of 6" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/159147/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Docked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>So, there’s a <em>lot</em> going on — a little too much — though almost all of it is exceptional. To be honest, I’m amazed that Supergiant has largely managed to live up to the towering heights of Hades with this sequel; there’s no doubt that, mechanically, this is a huge improvement. I was worried about the team continuing with the formula, but there are plenty of fresh ways to approach every run that make the whole game so moreish. I’ve varied my playstyle far more than I ever did with Hades, and I feel like I’ve got so much more to discover beyond the credits.</p>
</section><section id="conclusion"><h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Supergiant Games is five-for-five with Hades II, a huge, triumphant sequel that manages to diverge mechanically and offer more challenges and variety than its predecessor. It helps that it’s nearly faultless on Switch 2 in particular.</p>
<p>Sometimes there’s a bit <em>too</em> much going on, and in shooting for a bigger, more tragic story, I think it’s lost a bit of heart. But, quite frankly, I don’t want time to stop because if it does, I won’t be able to play Hades II anymore.</p></section>

</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/hades-ii-nintendo-switch-2-edition]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade Director Highlights The Speed Problem With Switch 2 Game Cards]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade-director-highlights-the-speed-problem-with-switch-2-game-cards</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade-director-highlights-the-speed-problem-with-switch-2-game-cards.1308390/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<p>"Among developers, the discussion about the keycard format is perhaps a bit different"</p>
</section><div><section>
<figure><a title="ff7 remake key cards" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/c85095d27f296/ff7-remake-key-cards.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: SQUARE ENIX</em></figcaption></figure><p>As you're doubtless well aware at this point, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade">Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade</a> is winging its way onto Switch 2 on 22nd January 2026, and we are super, super (add a few more supers) excited about it. Especially this writer, in fact, because he's managed to start the remake several times on other systems and has yet to actually finish it. Portable play will remedy this.</p>
<p>In the build-up to the release of the Switch 2 version of Square Enix's masterpiece, its director, Naoki Hamaguchi, has been chatting to German site <a href="https://jpgames.de/2025/09/final-fantasy-director-hofft-dass-ihr-game-key-cards-eines-tages-moegen-koennt/">JPGames</a> (thanks for the heads up, <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/final-fantasy-7-remake-director-understands-players-qualms-about-switch-2-game-key-cards-but-for-aaa-devs-its-a-way-to-overcome-loading-speed-limitations/">Automaton</a>) about those dreaded Game-Key Cards, and it seems he's of the opinion that they are a necessary evil, thanks to the a speed drawback with Nintendo's Switch 2 carts.</p>
<p>During the interview, Hamaguchi is quoted saying that, “Among developers, the discussion about the keycard format is perhaps a bit different to what fans maybe expect," pointing out that whilst the actual storage size of carts is important, it's the speed of loading high-end, AAA games and their huge assets that's the key issue.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"I think perhaps the biggest issue for developers, certainly for people like us who make high-end HD games, is the loading speed, because you compare that to the solid-state drive and the speed you can get from loading from that, it’s going to be inferior to that, it just has to be, that’s the way the media works, physically. So that’s the bigger issue, really, in terms of making games, making high-end games for the Switch 2, and what it allows, obviously, by doing a semi-download version of the game, you can then use the SSD and rely on that for that smoother loading. So that’s perhaps the bigger issue in terms of a developer."</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Hamaguchi is careful to clarify that he understands gamers' reaction to the Game-Key Card solution. "I really get where people are coming from in terms of their negativity towards it," he says, "and there are good reasons and debates to have there."</p>
<p>We recently <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/ubisoft-employee-explains-why-star-wars-outlaws-is-a-game-key-card">heard from a Star Wars Outlaws dev</a> about how the use of Game-Key Cards for that <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/star-wars-outlaws">stellar port</a> helped with streaming assets, loading, and all of the benefits you'd expect from a faster storage and information-streaming system versus having that data transferred from a separate cart.</p>
<p>And so it would seem that, as far as Game-Key Cards go, and as much as Hamaguchi says he can sympathise with how players feel, the controversial 'physical' option will continue to be used as a necessary part of getting big Switch 2 games on store shelves. Be sure to check out the director's entire response at <a href="https://jpgames.de/2025/09/final-fantasy-director-hofft-dass-ihr-game-key-cards-eines-tages-moegen-koennt/">JPGames.de</a>.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>How do you feel about Game-Key Cards now that devs are airing their thoughts on how running the game off internal memory benefits the porting of AAA games? Has your opinion changed? Let us know below.</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:187479,187863,180896 @ 1758799803 -->
</section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://jpgames.de/2025/09/final-fantasy-director-hofft-dass-ihr-game-key-cards-eines-tages-moegen-koennt/" rel="noopener" href="https://jpgames.de/2025/09/final-fantasy-director-hofft-dass-ihr-game-key-cards-eines-tages-moegen-koennt/">jpgames.de</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://automaton-media.com/en/news/final-fantasy-7-remake-director-understands-players-qualms-about-switch-2-game-key-cards-but-for-aaa-devs-its-a-way-to-overcome-loading-speed-limitations/" rel="noopener" href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/final-fantasy-7-remake-director-understands-players-qualms-about-switch-2-game-key-cards-but-for-aaa-devs-its-a-way-to-overcome-loading-speed-limitations/">automaton-media.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/bf81f9ca5b5a6b9df3125e3fc2e920d5 @ 1758800249 --></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade-director-highlights-the-speed-problem-with-switch-2-game-cards]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Get Your First Proper Look At C. Viper Gameplay In Street Fighter 6]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/get-your-first-proper-look-at-c-viper-gameplay-in-street-fighter-6</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/get-your-first-proper-look-at-c-viper-gameplay-in-street-fighter-6.1308345/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Plus, Mech Zangie-F returns</p>
</section></header><div><section>

<p>Ahead of her debut on <strong>15th October 2025</strong>, C. Viper gets the spotlight with a brand new gameplay trailer for Street Fighter 6.</p>
<p>Available as part of the <strong>Year 3 Ultimate / Character Pass</strong>, C. Viper (or Crimson Viper) was originally introduced to the series in the 2008 entry <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds/super_street_fighter_iv_3d_edition">Street Fighter IV</a>. She retains her signature moves such as Burning Kick, Thunder Dash, Knuckled Pursuit, and Seismic Hammer. A brand new move called Focus Force has also been introduced, allowing you to bring up a protective barrier before launching your counterattack.</p>
<p>In addition to her standard outfit, C. Viper will also boast her Street Fighter IV attire for those who want to inject a bit of nostalgia into their gaming. As for the new outfit, Capcom has provided two pieces of artwork in its recent <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1364780/view/544495527868235881">blog</a> to give you a good glimpse at Viper in all her glory.</p>
<figure><a title="C. Viper 2" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/9c38f7ff28d0b/c-viper-2.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Capcom</em></figcaption></figure>

<p>In addition to a brand new character, the Year 3 Pass also introduces an extra outfit for Zangief. This is based directly on Mech Zangie-F from <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/arcade/marvel_super_heroes_vs_street_fighter">Marvel Super Heroes vs. Street Fighter</a>, though its overall design has been updated accordingly for this new release. It looks pretty awesome.</p>

<p>The additional outfit will be available on 15th October alongside C. Viper, but that's not all. Owners of the Year 3 Pass can also look forward to two addition characters in the coming months: Alex and Ingrid.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:188219,182899 @ 1758800755 -->
<p><em>Will you be testing out C. Viper when she launches next month? How about that new Zangeif outfit? Let us know your thoughts with a comment down below.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1364780/view/544495527868235881" rel="noopener" href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1364780/view/544495527868235881">store.steampowered.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/8414590b85f9d3a79a850d5e5c704df3 @ 1758799364 --></div></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/get-your-first-proper-look-at-c-viper-gameplay-in-street-fighter-6]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>