<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 15:12:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Talking Point: How Do You Play NES Games These Days?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/talking-point-how-do-you-play-nes-games-these-days</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/talking-point-how-do-you-play-nes-games-these-days.1328515/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="7d1cb8ea3e6c1"><a title="NES" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/7d1cb8ea3e6c1/nes.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Damien McFerran / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>The NES — specifically the Nintendo Entertainment System, <em>not</em> the Famicom — turns 40 today.</p>
<p>The console's staggered rollout across the US makes its launch a bittier affair than the orchestrated, worldwide drops we're used to these days. But four decades ago, the first units were purchased in the United States and Western gamers began playing with power.</p>
<p>Europe saw similarly piecemeal launches in the years that followed. Mario became a household name there, too, although the NES wasn't the same, all-conquering hit across the pond, where SEGA had a stronger foothold.</p><div><figure data-videoid="1cjcr-XtVQw" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1cjcr-XtVQw?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/1cjcr-XtVQw?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1cjcr-XtVQw?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed38f68bwouxpn&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>836k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p>Still, with such a strong library from Nintendo itself, plus third-party powerhouses like Capcom and Konami delivering brilliant games while British dev Rare established itself as a premier Nintendo partner, the grey-brick-box carved out mindshare all the same. You couldn't play Mario on a Mega Drive, could you?</p>

<p>For decades, the NES has had a monopoly on the retro video gaming space in a popular sense, thanks to a mix of undeniable quality, the console's sales success, and sheer nostalgia that comes with a system so many people enjoyed as a kid. But is the latter is falling off a tad? Is this platform's outsized mindshare being chipped away by Father Time?</p>
<p>Years pass, new gamers are born and raised, and there's now a generation of video-game-loving parents for whom the Nintendo Entertainment System <em>wasn't</em> a formative console. When their kids go digging through wardrobes, they won't find a dusty NES and a box of frayed cardboard boxes buried in the back. Asking about this titanic 40-year-old system may well elicit quizzical looks these days, even from Nintendo fans. Do you have any NES carts in your collection? How many of you reading were even born in 1985?</p>

<p>Naturally, over a long enough time scale, familiarity and enthusiasm fall off. Not <em>respect -</em> there's still plenty of that. You're being deliberately obtuse to deny the transformative effect of the console and its library. But actual, card-carrying fans with firsthand affection for the NES? It feels like they're on the decline - at least if the genial shrugs of the people I've asked in the run-up to the 40th anniversary are anything to go by!</p>
<p>With the wealth of video games available and the enormous history of the medium to digest, no wonder people's passions are shifting as the medium ages. Anyone gatekeeping or dismissing younger players who — <em>tsk</em> — haven't done their homework and played OG <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/super_mario_bros">Super Mario Bros.</a> before <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/super-mario-bros-wonder-nintendo-switch-2-edition-plus-meetup-in-bellabel-park">Wonder</a>, or for whom the DS is 'their' first Nintendo, needs a talking to.</p>
<p>The NES is also possibly the most discussed and dissected console in video game history. Every five years since the turn of the millennium, we've seen retrospective blowouts and generational deep-dives across every strata of games media. <em>Haven't we been there and done all that on the 15th, 20th, 25th, 30th, and 35th anniversaries!?</em></p>
<p>Well, perhaps. But as we move forward, there's always worth in reviewing where we've been - and it's never been easier to sample the 8-bit bottle. This vintage is drinking now, so pour on, garçon!</p>
<figure data-uuid="f1a55772114d0"><a title="NES" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/f1a55772114d0/nes.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Zion Grassl / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Looking around at the official options to play NES games in 2025, there's always room for improvement, but Nintendo is doing a fair job of surfacing its 8-bit library with a <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/every-nintendo-switch-online-nes-game-ranked">79-game-strong selection</a> of first- and third-party titles on Nintendo Switch Online, ranging from classics to curios to <em>Somebody picked up a cheap licence, hmm?</em> to <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/urban_champion">Urban Champion</a>.</p>
<p>Some of us, though, the possibility of access being unceremoniously revoked — which has happened with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/snes/super_soccer">one Super NES game</a> at the time of writing — makes us wary of relying on access through subscription services like NSO.</p>
<p>Fortunately, there are innumerable ways to play NES games 40 years on. Perhaps you're rocking an NES Classic Mini conveniently sitting under the telly. Maybe you've taken the MiSTer route or grabbed an Analogue NT or another FPGA system - or maybe a rough-and-ready clone console. Hell, you can play these games in a browser these days. (I'd say they deserve better than <em>that</em>, but of course I would.)</p>
<p>Or do you — <em>shocker</em> — still play on your original console? Have you gone down the retro rabbit hole and invested the price of a PS5 Pro in an incredible upscaling setup?</p>
<p>Or do you just <em>not</em> play NES games these days?</p>
<figure data-uuid="2553c32ff0dff"><a title="NES Mini" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/2553c32ff0dff/nes-mini.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Damien McFerran / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>No judgement here! We're just interested to get a temperature check on how you tend to enjoy Nintendo's 8-bit output in 2025. Let us know in the poll below, and join Team NL in wishing Nintendo's little (read: actually quite large) grey box the happiest of birthdays. Why not go retro this weekend, hmm?</p>
<p><em>*goes and turns on <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/ufo_50">UFO 50</a>*</em></p>
<p>Close enough. Look, GOTY's coming, you know!? Tick tock.</p>

<figure data-uuid="1239a0e9cc2d9"><a title="NES" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/1239a0e9cc2d9/nes.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Zion Grassl / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/retro/related-articles:187366,106207,192284 @ 1760799626 --></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/talking-point-how-do-you-play-nes-games-these-days]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Talking Point: What Are You Playing This Weekend? (18th October)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/talking-point-what-are-you-playing-this-weekend-18th-october</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/talking-point-what-are-you-playing-this-weekend-18th-october.1328431/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="890ee7fa9c62e"><a title="Xenotilt / Ball x Pit" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/890ee7fa9c62e/xenotilt-ball-x-pit.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>Ahoy chums!</p>
<p>It's the weekend, so it's time to recap some of the biggest stories from this week before we dive into some good ol' gaming.</p>
<p>First up, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/pokemon-legends-z-a-nintendo-switch-2-edition">our review</a> for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/pokemon-legends-z-a-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Pokémon Legends: Z-A - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</a> went live, and while we certainly enjoyed our time with it, the game just doesn't quite match up to <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pokemon_legends_arceus">Legends: Arceus</a>. We've also published our <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/pokemon-legends-z-a-walkthrough">ongoing guide</a> for the game, so if you're finding yourself in a bit of a bind, then definitely check it out.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hollow-knight-silksong-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a> received <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/hollow-knight-silksong-receives-another-update-here-are-the-patch-notes">a new update</a>, while Takashi Iizuka explained why <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/sonic-racing-crossworlds">Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds</a> was <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/takashi-iizuka-explains-why-sonic-racing-crossworlds-was-delayed-on-switch-2">delayed on the Switch 2</a>. Meanwhile, a hacking group known as 'Crimson Collective' <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/notorious-group-crimson-collective-claims-to-have-hacked-nintendo">claimed it had breached Nintendo</a>, but then the latter publicly confirmed that <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/nintendo-responds-to-reported-crimson-collective-hack-with-official-statement">no data had been compromised</a>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:191762,192390 @ 1760800184 -->
<h2>Ollie Reynolds, Staff Writer</h2>
<p>I'm playing with lots of balls this weekend. That is to say, I'll be booting up <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/xenotilt_hostile_pinball_action">Xenotilt: Hostile Pinball Action</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/ball_x_pit">BALL x PIT</a>.</p>
<p>Both games are relentlessly addictive, and I'm hesitant to say which I prefer, but I'd probably lean a little closer to Xenotilt at the moment. It's just <em>so</em> damn good. My review will be live at some point today (Saturday), so be sure to check that out if you'd like to find out more.</p>
<h2>Jim Norman, Staff Writer</h2>
<p>Oh no, much to my surprise, I am having a good time playing Pokémon Legends: Z-A. It’s been a long time since I’ve felt this with a new mainline entry, so I’m going to ride the wave for as long as possible.</p>
<p>Will I be tired of it by Monday? Maybe, but that’s a risk I’m willing to take for as long as I get to see my beloved Totodile waddle around next to me.</p>
<h2>PJ O'Reilly - Staff Writer</h2>
<p>This weekend I’m really hoping to spend a lot more personal gaming time than usual on the Switch 2 as I’ve gone mad and bought a bunch of new games for it. My haul includes <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/trails-in-the-sky-1st-chapter-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Trails in the Sky 1st Chapter</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/absolum">Absolum</a>, both of which I’ve yet to start, but am very, very excited about!</p>
<p>I’ve also added BALL x PIT to the mix, and Ollie has gone and got me well up for trying some Xenotilt, so that’s most likely gonna get snapped up too, before I forget about it due to just how many games are starting to pile in now. <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hades-ii-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Hades II</a> should be getting a shot too, but what hope do I have keeping up with all this lot? We’re gonna need more hours added to days soon.</p>
<h2>Kate Gray, Contributor</h2>
<p>I'm helping to judge a games award this month, which means playing lots of games that came out this year (and some that aren't out yet!) I can't talk about most of them, but it did give me a chance to finally play <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/strange_antiquities">Strange Antiquities</a>, and I had actually forgotten how clever the first game was.</p>
<p>The puzzles are really well-designed, with very thoughtful logic, and there are tons of neat features in Antiquities that make it even easier and more pleasurable to play. I had no idea what I was doing for the first few minutes (there isn't much of a tutorial, and I think it suffers for it) but exploring the small shop ends up being its own reward, anyway. It's really good!</p>

<h2>Alana Hagues, Deputy Editor</h2>
<p>I'm basically only playing Pokémon Legends: Z-A right now, all for you lovely lot. I wish I enjoyed it as much as others seem to, but alas, I might just have to accept that Pokémon isn't for me anymore. Keep an eye out for some more helpful tips from yours truly, of course.</p>
<p>I have my eyes on Ball X Pit and Absolum, though — as soon as I have the time... Have a good weekend!</p>
<h2>Gonçalo Lopes, Contributor</h2>
<p>Since I haven’t really been a part of the Pocket Monster madness from the beginning, I will be entertained in a galaxy far, far away. <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/star-wars-outlaws">Star Wars Outlaws</a> is still delivering a ton of fun when searching off the main road. Super happy to finally have Xenotilt: Hostile Pinball Action on Switch because I can’t rotate my giant TV to play this in tate mode so portable mode it is (make sure you check the previous game <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/demons_tilt">Demon’s Tilt</a> if you missed it). Still dabbing at Hades II and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/gearbits">Gearbits</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/ufo_50">UFO 50</a> report: 36 of 50 games played. More amazing stuff from this endless package, with the arena rogue light run’n’gun Overbold, the sequel to Campanella and the belt action Fist Hell being particular highlights.</p>
<p>Game of the week is BALL x PIT. I was already sold on the entire thing thanks to a recent STEAM fest demo but now, both on TV and on the go this is one seriously addictive game! Yee be warned!</p>
<h2>Nile Bowie, Contributor</h2>
<p>I recently picked up Xenotilt, the endlessly replayable new pinball game with sharp cyberpunk aesthetics from the makers of the acclaimed Demon's Tilt. And it's a feast for the senses, to say the least. It's approachable, integrating fresh ideas like activating gun turrets and bullet hell mechanics with your ball, but deceptively technical—especially if you want to see all the table has to offer. I'll be playing a lot of that this weekend.</p>
<p>Likewise, I've just grabbed BALL x PIT, published by Devolver Digital. I haven't jumped in yet, but I've been extremely intrigued by this title ever since I saw the trailer for it. It's been described as a mix of Vampire Survivors and Breakout, with influences from other puzzle games and roguelikes, and I'm just a hundred percent on board with this. It really looks like nothing else, and the reviews have been very encouraging—so I wouldn't object to getting totally sucked in.</p>

<hr>
<p><em>Well, that's what we have planned for this weekend, but what about you? Let us know your picks in the following poll.</em></p>
</section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/talking-point-what-are-you-playing-this-weekend-18th-october]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8BitDo Announces 'NES40 Collection' Of Peripherals, And They're Up For Pre-Order Today]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/8bitdo-announces-nes40-collection-of-peripherals-and-theyre-up-for-pre-order-today</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/8bitdo-announces-nes40-collection-of-peripherals-and-theyre-up-for-pre-order-today.1328422/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Celebrate four decades of play, design and memory</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure data-uuid="d3138bcbb383c"><a title="nes40" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/d3138bcbb383c/nes40.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: 8BitDo</em></figcaption></figure><p>8BitDo has announced a brand new 'NES40 Collection' of products which incorporates an Ultimate 2 Bluetooth controller, 68-key Retro Keyboard, and a rather fetching Retro Cube 2 speaker.</p>
<p>The new range, which is now available to <a href="https://www.8bitdo.com/nes-40th-anniversary">pre-order over at 8BitDo's official website</a> today certainly looks stunning, and it manages to add a few nice little touches to a line-up that stick to the look and feel of previous "Retro" offerings from the company.</p>
<p>The keyboard (which this writer is 100% getting) is Windows and Android compatible and due to release in early 2026. At <strong>$499</strong>, it's certainly an enthusiast-level sort of deal, taking the excellent retro design from their past offerings and adding a very snazzy aluminium alloy shell, along with some lovely detailing and a fancy pouch.</p>
<p>It also comes with those super cool turbo buttons that we've been loving since we picked up our first <a href="https://www.timeextension.com/reviews/8bitdo-retro-mechanical-keyboard-mario-teaches-typing">8Bitdo Retro Keyboard</a>.</p>

<p>The Switch 1 and 2 compatible NES40-themed Ultimate 2 controller, which <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/8bitdo-pro-3-bluetooth-controller-tmr-sticks-and-hall-effect-triggers-elevate-this-switch-2-compatible-pad">follows the company's Pro 3 Bluetooth controller</a> in including TMR joysticks and Hall effect sticks, releases on <strong>15th November 2025</strong>, and is also looking mighty slick as you can see below.</p>
<p>Set to retail at <strong>$79.99</strong>, it also comes with a bunch of changeable thumbstick pads, a keychain and a few other bits and bobs. Yeah...looking at these pics, we're probably gonna need one of these, too.</p>

<p>The final part of the collection is the Retro Cube 2, a dinky little portable speaker that's an upgraded version of its predecessor, and connects via bluetooth, 2.4G and USB. T</p>
<p>he speaker uses a D-pad design for its controls, which is rather cool, and has its very own charging dock to boot. This comes in at <strong>$49.99</strong>, and will release on 1<strong>2th December 2025</strong>.</p>

<p>The 8BitDo Collection is available to pre-order a little later today, and you can hit up the official site to go grab yours if they've tickled your fancy.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Interested in the NES40 Collection from 8BitDo? Let us know in the comments.</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:187367,186817,186028 @ 1760798832 -->
</section></article><div><p>PJ is a staff writer across Hookshot Media. He's been playing video games pretty much nonstop since the early 1980s, which is ages ago. Favourite genres include RPGs, puzzle games and lovely big single player adventures of all kinds. The weirder the better.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/PJOReilly"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('PJOReilly');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/8bitdo-announces-nes40-collection-of-peripherals-and-theyre-up-for-pre-order-today]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Poll: Which Starter Pokémon Did You Choose In Pokémon Legends: Z-A?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/poll-which-starter-pokemon-did-you-choose-in-pokemon-legends-z-a</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/poll-which-starter-pok%C3%A9mon-did-you-choose-in-pok%C3%A9mon-legends-z-a.1328419/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>I choose you...</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure data-uuid="6d011b4255bda"><a title="Pokemon Legends Z-A" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/6d011b4255bda/pokemon-legends-z-a.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>For some trainers, one of the most difficult decisions in a new Pokémon game is your starter Pokémon pick.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pokemon_legends_z-a">Pokémon Legends: Z-A</a>, the same traditions apply, where you pick from one of three Pokémon. This time you have a choice of Chikorita (the Grass-type), Totodile (the Water-type), and Tepig (the Fire-type Pokémon).</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"After arriving in Lumiose, certain events will lead you to befriending a Pokémon that will become your adventuring partner, thus beginning your journey as a Pokémon Trainer. Which Pokémon will you set off on your adventure with: Chikorita, Tepig, or Totodile?"</p></blockquote><div><figure data-videoid="2LcP6TZzqhM" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2LcP6TZzqhM?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/2LcP6TZzqhM?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2LcP6TZzqhM?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed635c59gjtquo&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>836k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div><blockquote>
</blockquote>
<figure data-uuid="e5f229369723c"><a title="Pokemon Legends Z-A" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/e5f229369723c/pokemon-legends-z-a.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: The Pokémon Company</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Now that the new game is available on the Switch and Switch 2, we're curious to know who you decided to add to your party in the end. Did you end up going with the same Pokémon you planned to <em>before</em> the game released, or did you go with someone else at the last minute?</p>
<p>So, vote in our poll and let us know in the comments.</p>

<p>And just one other thing...<strong>spoiler alert</strong>...you can eventually get all three of these starter Pokémon in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pokemon_legends_z-a">Pokémon Legends: Z-A</a>, but the catch is you'll have to wait until the end of the game. We'll be sharing more about this in our guide, so stay tuned.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:192632,192692,183867 @ 1760797417 --></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/poll-which-starter-pokemon-did-you-choose-in-pokemon-legends-z-a]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Two More Switch Games Have Received Compatibility Updates On Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/two-more-switch-games-have-received-compatibility-updates-on-switch-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/two-more-switch-games-have-received-compatibility-updates-on-switch-2.1328407/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Issues with Star Wars and PvZ have been resolved</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="009144bc6673c"><a title="Nintendo Switch 2 Nintendo Switch" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/009144bc6673c/nintendo-switch-2-nintendo-switch.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Zion Grassl / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>At the end of September, Nintendo released a <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/nintendo-switch-2-system-update-20-5-0-is-now-live-here-are-the-full-patch-notes">new system update</a> for the Switch 2 that included <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/more-switch-games-get-switch-2-compatibility-fixes">some compatibility fixes</a> for a handful of titles.</p>
<p>Now, a few more games have apparently been fixed and are now working on Nintendo's new hybrid system. This includes the RPG <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/star_wars_knights_of_the_old_republic_ii_the_sith_lords">Star Wars: Knights of the Old Republic II: The Sith Lords</a> and the third-person team-based shooter <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/plants_vs_zombies_battle_for_neighborville_complete_edition">Plants vs. Zombies: Battle for Neighborville</a> (via Nintendo Everything).</p>
<p>The source also notes how this latest fix is an "interesting development" as it appears Switch games can be fixed for the Switch 2 at "any point". As part of this update, both titles are now also available to purchase on the Switch 2's eShop.</p>
<p>Once again, this follows a recent batch of fixes that resolved issues with games such as the free-to-play title <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/warframe">Warframe</a>. If we hear about any other Switch game updates for the Switch 2, we'll be sure to let you know. Earlier this week, Nintendo also released new game updates for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/captain_toad_treasure_tracker">Captain Toad: Treasure Tracker</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/splatoon_2">Splatoon 2</a>, fixing issues with both titles.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:192542,192604,164338 @ 1760798932 -->
<p>How are you finding Switch games on the Switch 2 so far? Are there any particular Switch games you would like to see improved on Nintendo's new system? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://nintendoeverything.com/star-wars-knights-of-the-old-republic-2-plants-vs-zombies-battle-for-neighborville-fixed-on-nintendo-switch-2/" rel="noopener" href="https://nintendoeverything.com/star-wars-knights-of-the-old-republic-2-plants-vs-zombies-battle-for-neighborville-fixed-on-nintendo-switch-2/">nintendoeverything.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/9ed113af6386c02e48d0d3c6ef33ee88 @ 1760798932 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/two-more-switch-games-have-received-compatibility-updates-on-switch-2]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ask Iwata Is Getting A Paperback Release In Summer 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/ask-iwata-is-getting-a-paperback-release-in-summer-2026</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ask-iwata-is-getting-a-paperback-release-in-summer-2026.1328374/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Words of wisdom from Nintendo's legendary CEO</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure data-uuid="1fc9f76f433f4"><a title="Ask Iwata" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/1fc9f76f433f4/ask-iwata.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>If you never got around to reading Ask Iwata or just want an excuse to revisit it, VIZ Media has announced it's releasing an English paperback version in Summer 2026.</p>
<p>This book, edited by Hobonichi, compiles the former Nintendo president and CEO's famous interviews into a "motivational collection". Iwata touches on a range of diverse subjects, such as how success breeds resistance to change and why programmers should never say no.</p>

<p>Below is a sample of Nintendo Life's book review when the hardcover English version of Ask Iwata was released in 2021. When we find out more details about the paperback release, we'll let you know.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"This is a book that should be read by all — not just Nintendo fans, or video game fans — simply because Iwata espoused an attitude and outlook on the world that put happiness above all else, even when it was an aspiration in tough times. He wouldn't always succeed, as no-one does, but he'd keep trying. In a world that can often be cynical, his outlook is a welcome and hopeful beacon."</p></blockquote><blockquote>
</blockquote>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-articles:113769,185052 @ 1760798600 -->
<p>Would you be interested in a paperback version of this book? Have you already read the hardcover release? <em>Tell us below.</em></p></section></article></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/ask-iwata-is-getting-a-paperback-release-in-summer-2026]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>