<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 16:03:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["My Staff Have Had Customers Threatening To Rip Their Heads Off" - Retailers And Collectors Tell Of Pokémon TCG Woes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/my-staff-have-had-customers-threatening-to-rip-their-heads-off-retailers-and-collectors-tell-of-pokemon-tcg-woes</link>
            <guid>1376149</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>"Scalpers are making it impossible to find cards"</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="f1b87a2f0c3f3"><a title="&quot;My Staff Have Had Customers Threatening To Rip Their Heads Off&quot; - Pokémon Card Collecting Has A Serious 'Millennial' Problem 1" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/f1b87a2f0c3f3/my-staff-have-had-customers-threatening-to-rip-their-heads-off-pokemon-card-collecting-has-a-serious-millennial-problem-1.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Damien McFerran / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>The fact that the Pokémon Trading Card Game has created its own mini-economy isn't new news – back when it launched in the late '90s, there were accusations that it was encouraging gambling amongst kids, with many schools banning the cards from their playgrounds.</p>
<p>In more recent years, however, the market for collectable cards has risen to hitherto unseen levels of insanity, driven by the fact that the children who grew up with Pokémon in the '90s and 2000s are now adults and can invest heavily in picking up the rarest examples – and the high prices have predictably encouraged in opportuniustic scalpers moving in, drawn by the promise of turning small purchases into hundreds of dollars.</p><div><figure data-videoid="RLc1VHm8D80" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RLc1VHm8D80?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytRLc1VHm8D80" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/RLc1VHm8D80?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RLc1VHm8D80?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed43f22fxrmtlg&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>840k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p>The end result, rather sadly, is that younger Pokémon fans are being denied the chance to grab cards for themselves.</p>
<p>British news outlet <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2025/dec/08/how-pokemon-cards-became-a-stock-market-for-millennials">The Guardian</a> has been speaking to retailers and fans to get their take on the current state of the Pokémon Trading Card Game in the UK, and it's not particularly pleasant reading.</p>
<p>Ben Thyer, the owner of the independent store BathTCG, says:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"My staff have had customers threatening to come back and rip their heads off. It’s become quite unpleasant at times. I’ve heard of other stores where people have been attacked or there have been robberies. We’ve even seen people who buy our products and list them immediately on Facebook, while still in our carrier bags, or sell it right outside the shop. We’re even anxious to put stuff on the shelf for the public because we just don’t want to entice that sort of behaviour. We used to sell whole boxes of booster packs but now we’ve had to stop doing that, and even place limits on the individual packs."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Demand has consistently outstripped supply in the world of Pokémon TCG for a few years now, but Thyer thinks a correction is perhaps on the way – although it may not last for very long:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"There are signs of the market cracking – prices of singles are coming down, sealed products are coming down. People aren’t as ferocious as they once were. There’s also a lot of people now thinking, ‘Christmas is soon and I need some money because I’ve not made what I was hoping for [from reselling cards]’. So we’ll see it dip, but then early 2026 brings Pokémon’s 30th anniversary, so I think we’ll see another crazy period."</p>
</blockquote>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/pokemon/related-articles:186333,185825,185162 @ 1765207803 --></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.theguardian.com/games/2025/dec/08/how-pokemon-cards-became-a-stock-market-for-millennials" rel="noopener" href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2025/dec/08/how-pokemon-cards-became-a-stock-market-for-millennials">theguardian.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/pokemon/related-info/4c60441fe7a879ce1dc5cb98ba327381 @ 1765209367 --></div></article><div><p>Damien has been writing professionally about tech and video games since 2007 and oversees all of Hookshot Media's sites from an editorial perspective. He's also the editor of <a href="https://www.timeextension.com/">Time Extension</a>, the network's newest site, which – paradoxically – is all about gaming's past glories.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Damo"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/damienmcferran.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Damo');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/my-staff-have-had-customers-threatening-to-rip-their-heads-off-retailers-and-collectors-tell-of-pokemon-tcg-woes]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GameStop Hints At Another Playable Character For Resident Evil Requiem]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/gamestop-hints-at-another-playable-character-for-resident-evil-requiem</link>
            <guid>1376071</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>But it's not who you think it is</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="1e3b54a528e26"><a title="Requiem" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/1e3b54a528e26/requiem.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Capcom</em></figcaption></figure><p>Although Capcom has remained tightlipped on the prospect of Leon Kennedy cropping up in the upcoming <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/resident-evil-requiem">Resident Evil Requiem</a>, a good number of fans are adamant that the veteran character will indeed appear.</p>
<p>However, <a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=I23MxTm2ku4&amp;mid=24348&amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fpc-gaming%2Fpc-games%2Fproducts%2Fresident-evil-requiem-deluxe---pc%2F20023062-2a094304.html" rel="sponsored noopener">a new listing</a> over on GameStop drops some new information regarding the Deluxe Edition of the game which, if accurate, seems to hint at a completely different playable character: Rosemary Winters (thanks, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-requiem-gamestop-listing-leaves-fans-bewildered-by-mentioning-a-shock-second-character-and-its-not-leon">IGN</a>).</p>
<p>Rose Winters is, if you remember, the protagonist in the <strong>Shadows of Rose</strong> DLC for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/resident-evil-village-gold-edition">Resident Evil: Village</a>, having previously appeared in the main game as, uh... a bunch of dismembered limbs. Look, it's a pretty wild story.</p>
<p>The listing from GameStop specifically mentioned some cosmetic items for Rose, including the 'Morphic Visor' and 'Shadow Walker' costume pack.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The Deluxe Edition includes the PC Steam Digital Code, a SteelBook Case, and the following digital content:</p>
<p><strong>"The Sanctuary" Expansion Pass:</strong> Includes 2 new story scenarios and a major Mercenaries mode update.<br>
<strong>"Morphic Visor" Cosmetic Filter:</strong> A unique cosmetic look for Rose's visor.<br>
<strong>"Shadow Walker" Costume Pack:</strong> 3 exclusive outfits for Rosemary Winters.<br>
<strong>Digital Artbook &amp; Official Soundtrack</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is all very bizarre indeed, not least because of how old Rose would be in Requiem's story. The new game is said to take place in 2028, which would essentially make her seven or eight years old. The Shadows of Rose DLC shot the story forward to the year 2037 in which she was portrayed as a teenager.</p>
<p>So if Rose does indeed appear as a child, would she really wear a visor of some sort? Would she wear a 'Shadow Walker' costume set? We're not so sure. Either way, the listing from GameStop is still up at the time of writing, so there seems to be at least some modicum of accuracy to it.</p>
<p>The listing also seems to imply that the popular Mercenaries Mode will also make a return in Requiem, while two new story scenarios are also being planned for the future.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:194255,194200 @ 1765208708 -->
<p><em>What do you make of this? Would you want to see Rose Winters again in Requiem? Let us know with a comment.</em></p>
<p>Please note that some external links on this page are affiliate links, which means if you click them and make a purchase we may receive a small percentage of the sale. Please read our <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/advertising">FTC Disclosure</a> for more information.</p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.gamestop.com/pc-gaming/pc-games/products/resident-evil-requiem-deluxe---pc/20023062-2a094304.html" rel="noopener" href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=I23MxTm2ku4&amp;mid=24348&amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fpc-gaming%2Fpc-games%2Fproducts%2Fresident-evil-requiem-deluxe---pc%2F20023062-2a094304.html">gamestop.com</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-requiem-gamestop-listing-leaves-fans-bewildered-by-mentioning-a-shock-second-character-and-its-not-leon" rel="noopener" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-requiem-gamestop-listing-leaves-fans-bewildered-by-mentioning-a-shock-second-character-and-its-not-leon">ign.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/7a07c139f9104d20758a2a94acb1827e @ 1765208862 --></div></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/gamestop-hints-at-another-playable-character-for-resident-evil-requiem]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Poll: What Review Score Would You Give Metroid Prime 4: Beyond?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/poll-what-review-score-would-you-give-metroid-prime-4-beyond</link>
            <guid>1376038</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Worth the wait?</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure data-uuid="10dd960605bdb"><a title="What Score - Metroid Prime 4" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/10dd960605bdb/what-score-metroid-prime-4.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>Now that <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/metroid-prime-4-beyond-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</a> is finally here, and given that many of us will have spent our weekends absolutely leathering its main campaign on Switch 2 (or even <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/metroid_prime_4_beyond">Switch 1</a>), we reckon now's the time to start gauging how you lot feel about Samus Aran's latest outing.</p>
<p>Of course, our very own Ollie Reynolds has already delivered his <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/metroid-prime-4-beyond-nintendo-switch-2-edition">9/10 verdict in his Switch 2 review</a> saying that Beyond "manages to replicate that magical sense of discovery from the GameCube original while pushing the series in some incredible new directions".</p><div><figure data-videoid="6TAq6m9hxyY" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6TAq6m9hxyY?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="yt6TAq6m9hxyY" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/6TAq6m9hxyY?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6TAq6m9hxyY?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed76f4cejoqmku&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>840k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p>The lovely Alex Olney served up a similarly positive summary of the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch/metroid-prime-4-beyond">Switch 1 version</a>, which manages to hold up well beyond (pun intended, of course) some loading time extensions and graphical downgrades, scoring it an 8/10. As Alex puts it: "if you’re not looking to upgrade anytime soon and you’re keen to jump into Samus’ latest adventure, it's well worth picking up, as there's a fantastic game to be had."</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:194214,194215 @ 1765209586 -->
<p>So, now that you know where we stand on both Switch console versions of this one, it's time to find out how you've been getting on with it all via the following poll. Have you been loving this graphically resplendent return to all things Metroid, or are you finding the new gameplay elements take the shine off?</p>
<p>Maybe you've already beaten the game, or maybe you're soaking <em>everything</em> in in this stunner; wherever you are, you can give us your score in the polls (for either version) below now, and if you change your mind later or when you beat the game, you can come back and amend it! That's pretty nice of us.</p>


<hr>
<p><em>As always, thanks for voting, and make sure to let us know any other thoughts you have on Metroid Prime 4: Beyond in the comments!</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:194688,194403 @ 1765209672 --></section></article><div><p>PJ is a staff writer across Hookshot Media. He's been playing video games pretty much nonstop since the early 1980s, which is ages ago. Favourite genres include RPGs, puzzle games and lovely big single player adventures of all kinds. The weirder the better.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/PJOReilly"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('PJOReilly');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/poll-what-review-score-would-you-give-metroid-prime-4-beyond]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exclusive: System Shock Remake Hacks Onto Switch & Switch 2 Later This Month]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/exclusive-system-shock-remake-hacks-onto-switch-and-switch-2-later-this-month</link>
            <guid>1375984</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Welcome to my portable world, insect</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Nightdive Studios is bringing its awesome <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/system-shock">System Shock</a> remake to the Switch and Switch 2, and we can now exclusively reveal that it'll be available to play from <strong>18th December 2025</strong>.</p>
<p>Originally released in 2023, System Shock is a comprehensive yet faithful remake of the 1994 FPS from Looking Light Studios. Development was lengthy and somewhat troubled, with Nightdive striving to reboot the original with more modern design principles.</p>
<p>In the end, however, to deliver on the promises of its initial Kickstarter campaign, the team chose to lean more towards a remake, keeping the core elements of the original intact while introducing a plethora of quality-of-life updates.</p>
<p>Ultimately, Nightdive succeeded in its goal, and System Shock received mostly positive critical acclaim upon release. Taking place in the year 2072, you play as an unnamed hacker who awakens in a station under total control of SHODAN, an AI completely removed from its moral and ethical restraints. Grotesque mutations and cyborgs roam the station, and it's up to you to defeat SHODAN.</p>
<p>With visuals blending pixel art textures and modern lighting technology, the System Shock remake is, to put it lightly, a <em>vibe</em>. It's a significantly different experience compared to System Shock 2, which Nightdive also released on the Switch earlier this year. If you're curious, we definitely recommend giving it a shot. For those on Switch 2, the game will offer up both gyro aiming and optional mouse controls.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>- Unravel the chilling story of SHODAN's rise and explore the mysteries of Citadel Station, piecing together the truth in this atmospheric sci-fi world</p>
<p>- Face perilous traps, puzzles, and a legion of hostile and mutated creatures — created and controlled by the villainous SHODAN herself</p>
<p>- Choose between a male or female-presenting Hacker protagonist</p>
<p>- Improved gyro aiming and Joy-Con 2 mouse support adds gameplay versatility for both controller and mouse and keyboard players</p>
</blockquote>

<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:184947,187219 @ 1765209713 -->
<p><em>Will you be picking up the System Shock remake on Switch or Switch 2? Let us know your thoughts with a comment down below.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/exclusive-system-shock-remake-hacks-onto-switch-and-switch-2-later-this-month]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>