<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:20:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Review: MIO: Memories In Orbit (Switch 2) - An Accomplished, Visually Stunning, But Familiar Metroidvania]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/mio-memories-in-orbit</link>
            <guid>1410070</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section>
<figure><a title="MIO: Memories in Orbit Review - Screenshot 1 of 6" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161511/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Docked)</figcaption></figure><p>Team Cherry set a new genre standard with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/hollow_knight">Hollow Knight</a>. That legacy has recently been reaffirmed by the long-awaited <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hollow-knight-silksong-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Silksong</a>, a release that developers and publishers alike are now clamouring to match. These are beautifully animated combat platformers, built around tight controls and striking art direction. Players explore compelling, labyrinthine spaces in search of answers, upgrades, and increasingly brutal challenges.</p>
<p>Douze Dixiemes looks to emulate that success with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mio-memories-in-orbit">MIO: Memories in Orbit</a>. The French indie studio's game is sumptuously designed, dripping with atmosphere and built around a compelling central mystery. There is a lot in this complex science fiction fable that feels a little too familiar. Even so, the little robot hero, MIO, is a strong candidate to carry the gauntlet thrown down by The Knight and Hornet.</p>
<figure><a title="MIO: Memories in Orbit Review - Screenshot 2 of 6" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161507/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Docked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Awakening on what looks like an operating table as a giant creature skitters away, MIO wanders out into the Vessel. This gigantic collection of biomes is filled with deadly flora and automatons, both hostile and friendly. Picking away at the mystery behind the Vessel’s collapse, she is tasked with finding and reactivating the Pearls, guardian AIs of this strange place.</p>
<p>MIO plays out like a very typical Metroidvania, with MIO (the game’s name matching the protagonist’s may get confusing) exploring areas of the Vessel and gaining abilities that allow her to push further.</p>
<p>The Vessel itself is a gorgeous place to inhabit. Grand architecture is fused with technology and pastel-coloured vegetation. Bio-organic masses weave in and out of stone constructs and metal pipes, while creatures stir in the shadows. Those shadows, and the lights that spread across surfaces, look like charcoal sketches. Each biome is distinct, and discovering a new area frequently inspires awe.</p>
<figure><a title="MIO: Memories in Orbit Review - Screenshot 3 of 6" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161503/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Gorgeous sound design complements the painterly visuals. The enchanting synth score ebbs and flows, transitioning into frantic techno beats during moments of action. The dreamlike background themes emphasise the intimidating size of the Vessel, reinforcing just how small you feel within its vast interior.</p>
<p>Despite the grandeur, the overall tone is one of melancholy. Scattered around the Vessel are robots that pine for their loved ones and lament the downfall of this once thriving home. Helping them will slowly uncover the story behind this world and MIO’s purpose.</p>
<p>Not all the bots wandering around the Vessel are nice, however, and there is some nicely twitchy combat to enjoy alongside the exploration. Enemy types are varied, although the roster leans a bit too heavily toward aerial threats.</p>
<p>MIO has some basic slashing combos that combine with her floaty jump, letting her attack bots from all angles. A dodge is unlocked early on that adds to combat variety. Bosses escalate nicely. Some are punishing, but runbacks are merciful.</p>
<figure><a title="MIO: Memories in Orbit Review - Screenshot 4 of 6" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161508/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Those runbacks, as well as general traversal, require skill and timing to navigate the many hazard-strewn routes of the Vessel. MIO can double jump from the beginning, which gets her through the opening areas with relative ease. Later, she obtains a grapple (here called the hairpin) that allows her to latch onto anchor points and enemies to gain height and reach more of the environment.</p>
<p>When she unlocks the ability to refresh her jump and hairpin, things get a bit more fiddly. Team Cherry veterans can attest that there is nothing more frustrating than whiffing a hit and breaking a long jump chain.</p>
<p>Love it or hate it, this kind of platforming is a staple of the genre now. It can be deeply satisfying to master, but rage-inducing when you just can't get the hang of it. That said, there is an undeniable satisfaction in clearing hazard-filled vertical climbs and being gifted a merciful shortcut back to a hub area or boss encounter.</p>
<figure><a title="MIO: Memories in Orbit Review - Screenshot 5 of 6" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161506/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Alongside a forgiving map structure, MIO’s combat and survival abilities are bolstered by mods. This gameplay-altering upgrade system is not unlike the chip abilities found in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/nierautomata_the_end_of_yorha_edition">Nier Automata</a>. Every aspect of her offence and defence can be buffed by installing mods scattered throughout the Vessel.</p>
<p>These modifications can tweak core elements of the experience. One even strips away the UI entirely, offering a cleaner view of the game’s lovely environmental design. Others focus on more direct boosts to offence and defence. The most powerful upgrades often come with a debuff attached, helping balance out the boon without undercutting its usefulness. Much like with Nier, mods are limited by capacity, so there is a nice juggling act at play. You will be building different versions of MIO to get past specific challenges.</p>
<p>There’s been an emphasis on other titles here, which may have distracted from judging the game on its own merits, but the comparisons are very hard to avoid. Ultimately, MIO wears its influences proudly, and it delivers enough atmosphere and polish to stand on its own. Its ideas and execution do lack originality, but that is not a dealbreaker.</p>
<figure><a title="MIO: Memories in Orbit Review - Screenshot 6 of 6" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161509/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>As a Switch 2 title, it ran smooth as butter both docked and undocked, never dipping below 60fps on the larger display. Consistent performance is crucial given how much precision the boss fights and platforming demand. The experience is rounded out nicely by assist options and difficulty tweaks that restore some of MIO’s health when she’s stationary and weaken bosses after each attempt. These options don’t dilute the overall experience, instead offering a more accessible entry point for players who found the game’s contemporaries a bit too unforgiving.</p>
</section><section id="conclusion"><h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>MIO is a compelling adventure with solid platforming and combat. The Vessel is a great place to explore and the mod system adds versatility. A great Metroidvania, then, though its similarities to genre heavyweights stop it from being essential. If you are in the mood for another tightly designed Metroidvania on Switch, however, this is an easy recommendation.</p></section>

</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/mio-memories-in-orbit]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Switch 1 & 2 Dominate Famitsu's Best-Selling Games Of 2025 List]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/switch-1-and-2-dominate-famitsus-best-selling-games-of-2025-list</link>
            <guid>1410031</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="350e2021755c6"><a title="Switch 2" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/350e2021755c6/switch-2.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Damien McFerran / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.famitsu.com/article/202601/63539">Famitsu</a> has shared its rundown of 2025's best-selling games in Japan, and it'll come as a surprise to no one to hear that it was yet another good year for Nintendo.</p>
<p>You might recall that Nintendo revealed the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/here-are-japans-best-selling-switch-and-switch-2-eshop-games-for-2025">most-downloaded eShop titles</a> in the region at the end of last year, but Famitsu's list accounts for the industry at large, giving PlayStation and Xbox titles a chance to get in on the fun.</p>
<p>That said, only one non-Switch release was able to make the 2025 top 10, with <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/monster_hunter_wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> breaking in at fourth with some PS5 representation.</p><div><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytC1rrCdi_XjA" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067yomzin&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>841k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p>As you might expect, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a> led the proceedings, with over 2.5 million sales in the region since the Switch 2 launched in June. <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pokemon_legends_z-a">Pokémon Legends: Z-A</a> was a big enough hitter on Switch 1 and 2 that it occupied the remaining spots on the podium, and other Switch 2 exclusives like <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/donkey-kong-bananza">Donkey Kong Bananza</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/kirby-air-riders">Kirby Air Riders</a> snagged a spot too.</p>
<p>Oh yes, and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/mario_kart_8_deluxe">Mario Kart 8 Deluxe</a> is still outselling <em>most</em> new games in Japan, too. Because of course it is.</p>
<p>Here's Famitsu's full list of the best-selling games in Japan in 2025:</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Position</th>
<th>Game</th>
<th>Platform</th>
<th>Unit Sales (2025)</th>
<th>Total Unit Sales</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>1</td>
<td>Mario Kart World</td>
<td>Switch 2</td>
<td>2,668,381</td>
<td>NEW</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2</td>
<td>Pokémon Legends: Z-A</td>
<td>Switch</td>
<td>1,529,823</td>
<td>NEW</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3</td>
<td>Pokémon Legends: Z-A - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</td>
<td>Switch 2</td>
<td>1,004,154</td>
<td>NEW</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4</td>
<td>Monster Hunter Wilds</td>
<td>PS5</td>
<td>838,319</td>
<td>NEW</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>5</td>
<td>Super Mario Party Jamboree</td>
<td>Switch</td>
<td>498,397</td>
<td>1,452,658</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>6</td>
<td>Donkey Kong Bananza</td>
<td>Switch 2</td>
<td>435,206</td>
<td>NEW</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>7</td>
<td>Kirby Air Riders</td>
<td>Switch 2</td>
<td>424,837</td>
<td>NEW</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>8</td>
<td>Minecraft</td>
<td>Switch</td>
<td>346,606</td>
<td>4,109,192</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>9</td>
<td>Mario Kart 8 Deluxe</td>
<td>Switch</td>
<td>342,866</td>
<td>6,510,483</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>10</td>
<td>Dragon Quest I &amp; II HD-2D Remake</td>
<td>Switch</td>
<td>316,439</td>
<td>NEW</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<hr>
<p>As you might expect from those numbers, the Switch and Switch 2 also nabbed the top two spots in Famitsu's total hardware sales for 2025. The new system came out on top, naturally, with almost 3.8 million units to its name since launch (over half of <em>all</em> home consoles sold in the region last year), but the Switch 1 clung onto second while the PS5 sat in third.</p>
<p>Here's Famitsu's list of the best-selling consoles of 2025 in Japan — note, the 'Switch' entry includes sales for the Lite and OLED models, 'PS5' comprises base, Digital and Pro editions, 'Xbox Series X|S' also accounts for the Series X Digital Edition, and 'PS4' adds in any Pro sales:</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Position</th>
<th>Console</th>
<th>Unit Sales (2025)</th>
<th>Total Unit Sales</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>1</td>
<td>Switch 2</td>
<td>3,784,067</td>
<td>NEW</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2</td>
<td>Switch</td>
<td>1,520,384</td>
<td>36,416,143</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3</td>
<td>PlayStation 5</td>
<td>879,204</td>
<td>7,298,210</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4</td>
<td>Xbox Series X|S</td>
<td>31,226</td>
<td>688,927</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>5</td>
<td>PlayStation 4</td>
<td>1,087</td>
<td>9,505,874</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>All of this means that Japan's game market is in a pretty healthy position thanks to the last 12 months. Famitsu estimates that the market has grown by 38.8% in the last year, with hardware spending at 282.69 billion yen (up 49.3%) and software spending at 135.44 billion yen (up 21%).</p>
<p><em>What do you make of Japan's best-selling games and consoles of 2025? Are there any surprises? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.famitsu.com/article/202601/63539" rel="noopener" href="https://www.famitsu.com/article/202601/63539">famitsu.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-info/0cafcdd7980df7d2201dfb7a9cfa2992 @ 1768838767 --></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/switch-1-and-2-dominate-famitsus-best-selling-games-of-2025-list]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>