<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 03:55:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Octopath Traveler 0 Has Been Rated For Switch And Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/octopath-traveler-0-has-been-rated-for-switch-and-switch-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/octopath-traveler-0-has-been-rated-for-switch-and-switch-2.1262085/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Out this December</p>
</section></header><div><section>

<p>Last week, during Nintendo's partner showcase, Square Enix lifted the lid on <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/octopath-traveler-0">Octopath Traveler 0</a>, a new entry in the HD-2D series where you'll customise and play as your own character.</p>
<p>Square Enix has already shared quite a bit about this upcoming release, and now it seems it's been rated by the Entertainment Software Rating Board ahead of its arrival this December. It's 'T' for 'Teen' and contains blood, fantasy violence, language and suggestive themes.</p>
<p>Here's the official ESRB description:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"<em>Octopath Traveler 0</em> is rated T for Teen by the ESRB with Blood, Fantasy Violence, Language, and Suggestive Themes. This is a role-playing game in which players assume the role of a traveler searching for sacred rings. As players explore a fantastical world, they assemble companions to engage in turn-based battles against human, animal, and monster enemies. Graphics are highly pixelated, with gameplay and cutscenes taking place from a distant perspective. Players use bladed weapons and elemental attacks to deplete opponents' health/hit points; combat is highlighted by impact sounds and light effects. Cutscenes depict additional violence involving small, pixelated characters: characters holding knives to their throats; cultists repeatedly stabbing a character; a man strangling a woman; a villain killing an unarmed civilian. Some characters are depicted with bloodstained clothing; a handful of scenes depict rooms with bloodstained corpses. The game contains some suggestive/sexual material: text describing a prostitute character (e.g., “sold their little sister to a brothel in a far-off land...In a distant land, their sister sold her body for coin.”); other dialogue (e.g., “Did you pleasure my old man last night you dirty wh*re”); stylized female monsters wearing revealing outfits (e.g., large amounts of cleavage/breasts). The word “sh*t” appears in the game."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>As previously mentioned, the Switch 2 release is a Game-Key Card and unfortunately Square Enix says there are no plans to allow the Switch version to be upgraded in the future.</p>
<p>Octopath Traveler 0 will release on the Switch, Switch 2 and multiple other platforms on <strong>4th December 2025</strong>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:185893,185910 @ 1754364725 -->
<p>Will you be checking out this title when it launches on the Switch 2? How about the Switch? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.esrb.org/ratings/40640/octopath-traveler-0/" rel="noopener" href="https://www.esrb.org/ratings/40640/octopath-traveler-0/">esrb.org</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/6e33688a151d8f97e5249eb01b86f75c @ 1754364725 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/octopath-traveler-0-has-been-rated-for-switch-and-switch-2]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pilotwings SNES, N64 And 3DS Albums Soar Onto 'Nintendo Music' In New Update]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/pilotwings-snes-n64-and-3ds-albums-soar-onto-nintendo-music-in-new-update</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pilotwings-snes-n64-and-3ds-albums-soar-onto-nintendo-music-in-new-update.1262064/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Here's what you can expect</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure><a title="Pilotwings 64" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/afcded5bbe875/pilotwings-64.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure><p>Following the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/mobile/nintendo_music">Nintendo Music</a> app being updated to Version 1.3.0, Nintendo has this week added the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/snes/pilotwings">Pilotwings</a> soundtracks.</p>
<p>This update includes not only the Super Nintendo album, but also the soundtracks for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/n64/pilotwings_64">Pilotwings 64</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds/pilotwings_resort">Pilotwings Resort</a> on the 3DS.</p>
<p>The SNES release contains 21 tracks with a total run time of 19 minutes, the N64 album contains 30 tracks and a runtime of 46 minutes, and Pilotwings Resort has 24 tracks and a runtime of 36 minutes.</p>

<p>To access this music, you'll need to have an active Switch Online subscription, although as of the latest update, some features of this app are still accessible when your subscription is cancelled.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-articles:186017,173865 @ 1754364256 -->
<p>What do you think of the latest update Nintendo Music? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/pilotwings-snes-n64-and-3ds-albums-soar-onto-nintendo-music-in-new-update]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apex Legends Switch 2 Performance And Resolution Upgrade Detailed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/apex-legends-switch-2-performance-and-resolution-upgrade-detailed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/apex-legends-switch-2-performance-and-resolution-upgrade-detailed.1262052/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Drop in this week</p>
</section></header><div><section>

<p>One of the many announcements during last week's Nintendo's Partner showcase was the Switch 2 upgrade for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/apex-legends">Apex Legends</a>.</p>
<p>With the game now available for the Switch 2 this week, Respawn Entertainment has outlined the game's performance details on this platform. Here's the full rundown:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>- Enjoy up to 60 FPS, depending on monitor/hardware capability and compatibility (1920x1080 docked, 1792x1008 undocked)</p>
<p>- When you login, you’ll be redirected to the eShop to download Apex Legends on Nintendo Switch 2. You’ll be able to delete “Apex Legends for Nintendo Switch” after you login to the updated version.</p></blockquote><blockquote>
</blockquote>
<p>And if you log into your Apex Legends account on the Switch or Switch 2 before 16th September 2025, you'll receive the "P.A.T.H." Pathfinder Skin!.</p>
<p>You can see the full patch notes for this latest update on EA's website. Once again, this game is a free download on the Switch 2. In terms of file size it requires <strong>31.7 GB</strong>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:185896,185917,185892 @ 1754362573 -->
<p>Will you be checking out this game on the Switch 2? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.ea.com/games/apex-legends/apex-legends/news/showdown-patch-notes" rel="noopener" href="https://www.ea.com/games/apex-legends/apex-legends/news/showdown-patch-notes">ea.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/944b98fa1e5f78cd95c77f0477fb964b @ 1754362573 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/apex-legends-switch-2-performance-and-resolution-upgrade-detailed]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tetris & Metroid Composer 'Hip' Tanaka Is Getting Back Into Video Game Music]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/tetris-and-metroid-composer-hip-tanaka-is-getting-back-into-video-game-music</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tetris-metroid-composer-hip-tanaka-is-getting-back-into-video-game-music.1261848/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<p>And he'd love to make another soundtrack, "if asked"</p>
</section><div><section>
<figure><a title="hip tanaka" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/156b6e5e3f525/hip-tanaka.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A6S7C9Sh7xE&amp;ab_channel=ChipTanaka">Hip Tanaka</a></em></figcaption></figure><p>Those lovely folks over at <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/legendary-nintendo-composer-hip-tanaka-says-hed-love-to-make-another-full-game-soundtrack-if-asked/">VGC</a> spoke to the one and only Hirokazu Tanaka — better known as 'Hip' or 'Chip' Tanaka — at Bitsummit's Indie Game Event in Kyoto last month and, it seems, the main man may well be up for making some sweet new music, if somebody asks. Would somebody just let him make some new music quickly, please, for crying out loud!</p>
<p>Tanaka, who you might know as the composer behind soundtracks for the likes of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gameboy/super_mario_land">Super Mario Land</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/metroid">Metroid</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/kid_icarus">Kid Icarus</a> and the Game Boy version of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gameboy/tetris">Tetris</a>, to name just a few things he's got on the old CV. He worked on the soundtracks for both <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gba/mother_3">Mother</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/snes/earthbound">EarthBound</a>. Oh, and he also played a key role in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/poca-is-a-game-boy-camera-photobook-adventure-and-a-heartfelt-homage-to-hip-tanaka">creating and designing the Game Boy</a>. So, yeah, he's kind of a big deal.</p>
<p>Mr Tanaka, who was in-house with Nintendo working on music all through the 8- and 16-bit eras, left the company and ended up as President of Creatures Inc after his work on the <strong>Pokémon</strong> anime became a conflict of interest for Nintendo.</p>
<p>And so it's delightful to hear, and doubly so given that Chip's work has shifted away from music somewhat since the move from Nintendo, that he's all in on returning to it. Speaking to VGC, when asked if he'd be into making another videogame soundtrack, he said:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Actually, if somebody came up to me and said ‘hey, do you want to make music for a game?’ I’d say ‘yeah, sure, sounds like fun...There’s a studio called 17-Bit making a game called <strong>Awaysis</strong>, created by a guy called Jake (Kazdal), and I actually made a track for that game. I’m not the only person making music for that game, there’s a bunch of us, but I created a track for it, and I’m playing it tomorrow.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>When then asked if he'd prefer to make single tracks or a full soundtrack, the musical maestro responded that:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Actually, to correct that [previous answer], I didn’t just do one song for Awaysis, I’m doing 70-80% of the game...But I think, for me, I spent my 20s to around 40 or so just making game music, and since then I’ve spent about 20 years where I haven’t really made any, so it’s kind of (about) getting back into it right now."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Tanaka also confirmed that he actually composed a track for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/street-fighter-6-years-1-2-fighters-edition">Street Fighter 6</a> saying, <em>“So if anybody comes up to me and says ‘hey, can you do this’, I’d be like ‘yes, I’d love to’.</em> Now, let's check out Mr Tanaka's contribution to Street Fighter 6, 'Glorious Match'!</p>

<hr>
<p><em>So, who's gonna give the man a job writing a new soundtrack? Let us know your thoughts!</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/legendary-nintendo-composer-hip-tanaka-says-hed-love-to-make-another-full-game-soundtrack-if-asked/" rel="noopener" href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/legendary-nintendo-composer-hip-tanaka-says-hed-love-to-make-another-full-game-soundtrack-if-asked/">videogameschronicle.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-info/6379486596b4f1fca4bc435abe3d36c6 @ 1754365890 --></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/tetris-and-metroid-composer-hip-tanaka-is-getting-back-into-video-game-music]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>