<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - remapradio_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/remapradio_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for remapradio_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 20:50:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can You Build a Community Around Video Game Guides?]]></title>
            <link>https://remapradio.com/articles/can-you-build-a-community-around-video-game-guides/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/can-you-build-a-community-around-video-game-guides.1203102/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://remapradio.com/articles/can-you-build-a-community-around-video-game-guides/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		<p>In desperation, the extraordinary becomes possible.</p><p>It’s how I felt when <em>VICE</em> told me that seven years was, well, long enough. Many of my colleagues had started their own businesses, but I was not a business person. I can write, I can podcast, I can stream. Numbers? That’s what a calculator is for. Many times, I’ve stayed at a bad job because a bad job was better than hustling for a new one. </p><p><em>Own</em> my own company? No.</p><p>Except, over time, no became “maybe” and then with some nudging, maybe became “yes.” Two years later, one of the best things that ever happened to me was losing my job, striking out on my own, and owning fate. It’s weird to think that failure on your own terms is less of an existential threat than failure because some random executive decided they weren’t interested in your contributions anymore.</p><p>These moments go in cycles, and now, it’s <em>Polygon</em>’s turn.&nbsp;</p><p>In early May, the popular video game (and over time, like many others, entertainment) publication <em>Polygon</em> was acquired by a company of vultures known as Valnet. Nothing good comes from Valnet. Nothing good was going to come by Valnet buying <em>Polygon</em>. Naturally, Valnet’s first move as <em>Polygon</em>’s owner <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/gaming-industry/polygon-sale-valnet/?ref=remapradio.com"><u>was to enact mass layoffs</u></a>. <em>Polygon</em> hasn’t been shut down, but it’s a fundamentally different place.</p><p>The thing about working at a big company is you often become more than colleagues with the people you work with but <em>friends</em>, folks you share interests and values with. It’s why we continued <em>Waypoint</em> as <em>Remap</em>, and why some from <em>Polygon</em> are headed down a similar path.</p><p>Just recently, former <em>Polygon</em> EIC Chris Plante launched (to much personal jealousy, as it’s long been an idea I’ve had, as well) <a href="https://postgame.substack.com/?ref=remapradio.com"><u>an <em>NPR</em>-style podcast called <em>Post Games</em>.</u></a> But today, I’m chatting with the folks behind another spin-off, and it’s an idea I haven’t seen tried before.</p><p>Ryan Gilliam and Jeffrey Parkin were, until recently, guides producers at <em>Polygon</em>. For years now, guides have been the financial underbelly of many websites, a mashup of tasty SEO bait that search engines like Google love <em>and</em> beloved by people who just want to know how to find that weird collectible in a game that they’ve spent an hour looking for.</p><p>Now, Gilliam and Parkin are launching<em> Big Friendly.Guide</em>, a publication <em>focused</em> on guides and trying to foster a community <em>around</em> guides. </p><p>Can it work? That’s what I decided to ask Gilliam.</p><p>Before we get to that conversation, though, here’s how to find and support <em>Big Friendly.Guide</em>, which obviously I'd recommend you do:</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.patreon.com/bigfriendlyguide?ref=remapradio.com"><u>Patreon</u></a></li><li><a href="https://bigfriendly.guide/?ref=remapradio.com"><u>Website</u></a></li><li><a href="https://www.paypal.com/donate/?hosted_button_id=SYGY9ZEMZ5LBN&amp;ref=remapradio.com"><u>PayPal Donation</u></a></li><li><a href="http://ko-fi.com/bigfriendlyguide?ref=remapradio.com"><u>Ko-fi Donation</u></a></li></ul><p>Now, onto the interview.</p><p><em>The conversation below has been lightly edited.</em></p><hr><figure><figcaption><span>Photo by </span><a href="https://unsplash.com/@gpthree?ref=remapradio.com"><span>George Pagan III</span></a><span> / </span><a href="https://unsplash.com/?utm_source=ghost&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=api-credit"><span>Unsplash</span></a></figcaption></figure><p><strong>Remap: Talk me through that final day at <em>Polygon</em>. When did you realize things were going wrong, and when did you realize it was one of the worst case scenarios?</strong></p><p>Ryan Gilliam: I actually found out that the website was being sold first, through my other Union co-workers. I was scrolling through our Union Slack when I saw everyone saying their jobs were eliminated. Then I saw people from my team saying they were eliminated. And then looked at my DMs to see Jeff—my co-founder of <em>BigFriendly.Guide</em>, who was also a Guides Producer— telling me to check my email. And that's where I saw that I was also being eliminated. I was in the middle of getting footage for a Destiny guide I was about to write that morning.</p><p>The second I saw the sale, I was worried, because we had fought so long and hard for our Union contract, and I couldn't imagine a <em>Polygon</em> without it. And then the dread of seeing that it didn't matter ... it hit twice for me. The industry sucks, and I've survived more layoffs than I can count—we were up to like two a year there for a while—but <em>Polygon</em> was usually safe. And then inside that bubble, in guides, I felt as safe as possible. In all the bad ways I saw it going down, this wasn't even on the radar for me. It was shocking.</p><p><strong>Remap: I remember what it felt like when the <em>VICE</em> layoff happened: ah, well, it finally came for me. I felt numb. There have been so many layoffs at so many places that while it seemed inevitable I’d also get laid off, all that mental preparation made it difficult to process the reality of it. Where was your head at? Was there a moment that it all sunk in?</strong></p><p>Gilliam: I finally felt pretty safe. After a long, long time of worrying about making myself essential and all that, I had developed skills with the guides team that made me valuable. And I saw how important the guides engine was to the success of the site. There was no reality for me where <em>Polygon</em> would exist with fewer guides people than we had, as it was already a pretty lean team. And, somehow, we had all missed this possibility of a bloodbath sale. Nobody I talked to was prepared or thought this was how it would go down. We thought, if anything, we'd eventually get cut down to a small staff site and guides would churn in the background.</p><p>I used to say that guides would be like the <em>Polygon</em> cockroach, and that they'd move us to some obscure team on another website before they'd give up traffic for the next Persona, Animal Crossing, or GTA, but didn't exactly nail that one.</p>
		<div>
	<h2>This content is for registered subscribers only</h2>
	<p>Register now to access  "Can You Build a Community Around Video Game Guides?".</p>
	<p><a href="https://remapradio.com/signup/">Sign up now</a>
	<small>Already have an account? <a href="https://remapradio.com/#/portal/signin/">Sign in</a></small>
</p></div>
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>