<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - remapradio_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/remapradio_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for remapradio_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 23:27:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Week at Remap]]></title>
            <link>https://remapradio.com/articles/this-week-at-remap-98/</link>
            <guid>1376533</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			<div>
					
					
					

					<article>
	
	<div>
		<p>Never been in a situation where the heartbreak from yet another Bears loss to the Packers actually felt...good? Like, I know moral victories are what losers tell themselves to feel better at night, but honestly, the Packers are a Super Bowl contender and we took them all the way down to the final seconds and came up short. I'm fully prepared for Rob to be a wet blanket about this team, but I'm into it. Also, none of it mattered because I became an uncle over the weekend. Win win.</p><p>-pk, who made $5 betting the Bears would punt on first possession lol</p><hr><figure></figure><ul><li><strong>PODCAST:<em> </em><em>Sports! </em></strong>– We've been waiting for a big moment to weigh in on the Bears season again, and the latest entry in the Bears/Packers "rivalry," aka the game where people talk about a rivalry before the Bears inevitably lose in embarrassing fashion for the millionth time, as the moment. It delivered. I'm just waiting for Rob to return home from an errand and we'll record this one.</li><li><strong>STREAM:</strong> <em>RV There Yet?</em> – Papa Rob is going to yell at his young children who can't do anything right, while trying to make it to the other side of a mountain.</li><li><strong>PODCAST: </strong><em>Routine Developer Interview</em> – Has it really been 12 years? But hey, <em>Routine</em> is a real video game, you can play it right now. I had a chance to chat with a few of the game's devs about the emotional journey they've been on.</li><li><strong>STREAM: </strong><em>Wheel of GeForce NOW</em> – It's time for a winter wheel.</li><li><strong>STREAM: </strong><em>The Game Awards</em> – Janet will actually be <em>at</em> the awards, but you can come hang with me, Chia, and Rob as we sip beers and watch many trailers.</li><li><strong>ARTICLE:</strong> <em>Letter Series</em> – Topic TBD, as per usual.</li></ul><p><em>If you have any support issues, send details to </em><a href="https://remapradio.com/r/53613e2c?m=c2a53baa-518b-4385-90e8-62545232c3f6"><em><u>support@remapradio.com</u></em></a></p>
		<p><em>Patrick Klepek (he/him) is an editor at Remap. In another life, he worked on horror movie sets, but instead, he also runs&nbsp;<a href="https://crossplay.news/?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Crossplay</em></a>, a newsletter about parenting and video games. You can follow him on&nbsp;<a href="https://www.twitter.com/patrickklepek?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Twitter</em></a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.threads.net/@patrickklepek?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Threads</em></a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://mastodon.social/@patrickklepek?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Mastodon</em></a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/patrickklepek.bsky.social?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Bluesky</em></a>.</em></p>
			</div>
</article>

				</div>
			<div id="notifications">
	<p>You’ve successfully subscribed to Remap</p>
	<p>Welcome back! You’ve successfully signed in.</p>
	<p>Great! You’ve successfully signed up.</p>
	<p>Success! Your email is updated.</p>
	<p>Your link has expired</p>
	<p>Success! Check your email for magic link to sign-in.</p>
</div>
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://remapradio.com/articles/this-week-at-remap-98/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>