<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - remapradio_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/remapradio_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for remapradio_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 18:47:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Week at Remap]]></title>
            <link>https://remapradio.com/articles/this-week-at-remap-55/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-week-at-remap.1093044/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://remapradio.com/articles/this-week-at-remap-55/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			<div>
					
					
					

					<article>
	
	<div>
		<p>First of all, congratulations to Austin's Eagles. </p><p><em>Please</em> go beat the damn Chiefs.</p><p>I am writing this wondering if danger is on the horizon. This morning, my four-year-old woke up with a sniffle. She seemed fine otherwise—but you never know. It's a dangerous time of year to be a parent, where those pesky germs are always afoot. I recently joked to my wife that we're due to get sick—we have dodged everything that's taken down our kids this winter season—but I'm crossing my fingers, folks!</p><p>-pk, who cannot believe how boring <em>Gladiator 2</em> was, what the heck</p><hr><figure></figure><ul><li><strong>PODCAST: </strong><em>Remap Interview</em> — Ah, this one is a delight. I'm glad this game together, and hope we have Chris on in the future, as well. When Chris got on the call, he started by saying some version of "Ah, man, I'm sorry" and I was confused on why. Turns out I've tuned out so much of the early Trump bullshit that I wasn't even aware that I'd booked a recording time with the inauguration that was happening at the same time moment. I preferred this version of events, even if we were also talking about a lot of awful things here, too.</li><li><strong>STREAM:</strong> <em>New on Steam</em> – We'll probably change the title of this, but I experimented with this idea recently, where there is <em>so much stuff</em> added to Steam on a daily basis—and so much goes unnoticed. Yes, a lot of it isn't very good and <em>a shocking amount</em> is porn, but my hope is that we can find some diamonds hidden about. Join us as we scroll through Steam and find games!</li><li><strong>ARTICLE: </strong><em>Remap Recommends</em> – It's the end of the month, which means we'll run through some of the games that have stuck around our brains.</li><li><strong>STREAM:</strong> <em>Motorsports Manager</em> – Once more, into the racing breach.</li><li><strong>PODCAST: </strong><em>Remap Radio</em> – Yep, we're doing a third GOTY pod. My hope is that half of the podcast will also be a normal Remap Radio podcast. Stay tuned!</li><li><strong>ARTICLE: </strong><em>Letter Series</em> – There will be words exchanged between myself and Rob. I need to figure out what the idea is for this week. This is also...stay tuned!</li></ul><p><em>If you have any support issues, send details on the issue to </em><a href="https://remapradio.com/r/53613e2c?m=c2a53baa-518b-4385-90e8-62545232c3f6"><em><u>support@remapradio.com</u></em></a><em>.</em></p>
		<p><em>Patrick Klepek (he/him) is an editor at Remap. In another life, he worked on horror movie sets, but instead, he also runs&nbsp;<a href="https://crossplay.news/?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Crossplay</em></a>, a newsletter about parenting and video games. You can follow him on&nbsp;<a href="https://www.twitter.com/patrickklepek?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Twitter</em></a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.threads.net/@patrickklepek?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Threads</em></a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://mastodon.social/@patrickklepek?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Mastodon</em></a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/patrickklepek.bsky.social?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Bluesky</em></a>.</em></p>
			</div>
</article>

				</div>
			<div id="notifications">
	<p>You’ve successfully subscribed to Remap</p>
	<p>Welcome back! You’ve successfully signed in.</p>
	<p>Great! You’ve successfully signed up.</p>
	<p>Success! Your email is updated.</p>
	<p>Your link has expired</p>
	<p>Success! Check your email for magic link to sign-in.</p>
</div>
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>