<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - remapradio_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/remapradio_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for remapradio_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 19:08:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Remap Recommends, Volume X]]></title>
            <link>https://remapradio.com/articles/remap-recommends-volume-x/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/remap-recommends-volume-x.1160973/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://remapradio.com/articles/remap-recommends-volume-x/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		<p><em>Remember when you’d walk into a local music, book, or video store and there’d be an adorable section where the employees would recommend what they were interested in that month?&nbsp;</em></p><p><em>Welcome to our little version of it, called Remap Recommends.&nbsp;</em></p><p><em>It's a chance for the staff at Remap to let you know what they've been playing, reading, listening to, or watching.</em></p><hr><h3 id="patrick-recommends-panic-world">Patrick Recommends: Panic World</h3><figure></figure><p>I'm taking a chance here. Ages ago, I recommended a podcast attached to one of my favorite newsletters, <em>Garbage Day</em>, only for the podcast to <em>immediately </em>announce it was winding down. <em>Panic World</em> is another podcast attached to one of my favorite newsletters, <em>Garbage Day</em>, but it's a <em>new</em> podcast, so fingers crossed.</p><p><em>Garbage Day </em>is a newsletter about the internet, specifically untangling the who/what/where/when/why of the discourse of the moment. It features, by my count, vital reporting and commentary and is now essential reading when it hits my inbox. <em>Panic World</em> is an extension of <em>Garbage Day</em>'s mission, but drills down into specific topics that are probably best understood by listing the episode titles:</p><ul><li>My friend's dad is a Holocaust denier now</li><li>Here's who killed the #MeToo movement</li><li>Who turned Gen Z fascist?</li><li>Can you order a hitman online?</li></ul><p>Every episode is funny, interesting, and insightful. I spent a lot of time online, but thankfully, not enough to understand most of it. <em>Garbage Day </em>helps fill the gaps. Most of the conversations are about the ways society is poisoned and dying, but if we're entering a collapse, at least you wanna understand why it's happening, right?</p><hr><h3 id="rob-recommends-permanent-style-magazine">Rob Recommends: <em>Permanent Style</em> Magazine</h3><figure></figure><p>I was trying on some boots at a shoe store in the Village when a man burst in asking, “Hey you have the <em>Permanent Style </em>print thing? Has that arrived yet?” My salesman indicated a stack of large-format magazines on the counter and the visitor started gushing. “Oh wow, you must have the hook up? Do you know him?”</p><p>“Well, yes, but just to email with occasionally. Professional acquaintance level only, I’m afraid. But obviously, huge fan,” the salesman said.</p><p>“Yeah he’s incredible. I’ve been reading since the start of the blog, basically. Thanks!” He paid for the magazine, and raced back out into the street.</p><p>I ended up seeing that magazine at every store I visited, and before I left I made a point to grab a copy. And let me tell you, it’s one of the most gorgeous and aspirational magazines I’ve ever encountered. Like a Condé publication at their peak, but less tacky. It’s the kind of thing that, maybe in my wildest dreams, <em>Remap </em>could put out one day.</p>
		<div>
	<h2>This content is for registered subscribers only</h2>
	<p>Register now to access  "Remap Recommends, Volume X".</p>
	<p><a href="https://remapradio.com/signup/">Sign up now</a>
	<small>Already have an account? <a href="https://remapradio.com/#/portal/signin/">Sign in</a></small>
</p></div>
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>