<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 15:17:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[“Lore should not be a strict set of rules," says Hytale developer in a tribute to player "archaeology"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lore-should-not-be-a-strict-set-of-rules-says-hytale-developer-in-a-tribute-to-player-archaeology</link>
            <guid>1404502</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>It's better thought of as "a set of guardrails"</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-tessa.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-tessa.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-tessa.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-tessa.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-tessa.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-tessa.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-tessa.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-tessa.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-tessa.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Hypixel Studios</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Minecrafty fantasy sandbox <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hytale">Hytale</a> will finally launch into early access today, a few months after being <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/in-a-rare-bit-of-good-news-hytale-lives-on-with-its-original-devs-buying-the-rights-off-of-riot">rescued from cancellation</a> by Hypixel server co-founder Simon Collins-Laflamme. In development for over a decade, it’s <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hytales-devs-hope-to-redefine-the-block-game-genre-with-their-world-generation-and-theyve-now-explained-how-it-works">a bid to “redefine the block-game genre”</a> that features procedurally generated biomes and RPG-style dungeon delving. Unlike the earliest instalments of Minecraft, it will also ship with some pretty fleshed-out lore.</p>
<p>In a post on the official site, the dev’s lore meister “Joe” has shared a few thoughts on the game’s flexible ideas about canon. Naturally, a lot of the chat invites comparison with other games with mighty codices, from The Witcher to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dragon-age">Dragon Age</a>. I’m indifferent to much of Hytale, I confess - I have exhausted my lifetime's supply of enthusiasm for blocks, and in any case, I prefer the drearier tone of <a href="https://www.vintagestory.at/">Vintage Story</a> - but on this count, I’m quite intrigued.</p>
<p>Joe <a href="https://hytale.com/news/2026/1/a-look-at-hytale-s-lore-and-philosophy">begins by noting</a> that Hytale had a lot of concept art, earlier in development, much of which has been dropped over the years in the course of narrative redrafts and other changes of direction, including the discarding of entire factions. However, “since the re-acquisition, many of these changes have been rolled back or re-incorporated in different ways”. This is partly because the developers “have made the conscious decision to return to an earlier draft - one that's far more compatible with the engine we're shipping and the vision we have for the game as a whole.”</p>
<p>In general, the chaos of past year has obliged a hard-headed approach to the narrative convolutions. Certain bits of lore have been shelved, some of them for good, while other materials are being revived. Take various initially “divisive” redesigns for the insectoid, desert-dwelling Scaraks – “with the timeline we're shipping on and the fact that the new designs aren't usable in-game, we can't exactly throw out the old ones anymore,” Joe writes. The devs are working on a method of “bringing both into the lore and making them work”.</p><p>In general, the new draft of the narrative retains “the major aspects of the lore the community has come to love over the years,” Joe goes on. “Characters such as Gaia and Varyn are still very much a part of our canon, and Tessa and Kyros are coming back as well”. The devs also intend “to revisit the concept of Alterverses”, these being parallel planets or dimensions – the main one is Orbis, which looks a lot like Earth.</p>
<p>In general, Hytale’s developers want “to maintain a consistent and coherent narrative while also allowing experimentation. Joe argues that “lore should not be a strict set of rules that everyone on the team is required to follow when designing content”, but “a set of guardrails to ensure we don't get too far off track”.</p>
<p>Hytale has certain fixed “canon foundations”, and the forthcoming Adventure mode will impose more of a narrative. But as regards the initially released Exploration mode, they’re leaving it pretty open. The game will encourage a degree of player “archaeology” that “gives us the flexibility to tell stories from different perspectives, many of which may not share the same understanding of Orbis and its nature”. As you might expect, these clashing perspectives may be faction-based.</p>
<p>As for when Adventure Mode might arrive, Joe cautions that there are currently “no systems in place to support such an endeavour, and there has never been a version of the game that had anything close to a narrative implemented. Even the details of the story itself have never truly been finalized.” So it’ll be up to you dig up the roots, for the moment. There is “a narrative of sorts” in Exploration Mode, tethered to a change in the world generation – Joe ends this section by dropping hints about something called Cursebreaker.</p><p>While a lot of the language here is too fluffy and promotional to get your teeth into, I think Hytale’s evolving lore could be fun to analyse. The early days of Minecraft were a series of improvisations and occasional mishaps <a href="https://archive.org/details/Minecraft_IRC_Logs_2009">discussed on IRC</a>, with minimal suspicion of the massive financial success that would follow – according to Notch, the game’s now globe-straddling Creeper mascot began life as a botched attempt at making a pig.</p>
<p>Nowadays, Minecraft is an absurdly bulky narrative universe, albeit a whimsical one that is rather less supportive of pedantic overreactions than, say, Star Trek. Hytale is sort of trying to follow the same trajectory, surfing the chaos wrought by last year's almost-cancellation, but with the more explicit hope of becoming a behemoth, and I think that puts the backstory writing under interesting stress. What do you reckon?</p>
<p>If you're sold on Hytale, here's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hytale-release-time-and-date">how and when to buy and download it</a>. The game <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hytale-wont-be-on-steam-right-away-as-its-devs-want-to-avoid-overindexing-on-negative-reviews-from-players-who-arent-as-well-informed-yet">won’t release on Steam for the moment</a>, because Hypixel are worried about negative reviews from people unfamiliar with the choppy development history.</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lore-should-not-be-a-strict-set-of-rules-says-hytale-developer-in-a-tribute-to-player-archaeology]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout: London hasn't developed into a Fallout 4-esque hub of new quest and expansion mods so far, and its lead has theories why]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fallout-london-hasnt-developed-into-a-fallout-4-esque-hub-of-its-own-new-quest-and-expansion-mods-and-its-lead-has-theories-why</link>
            <guid>1404418</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"That’s what we’d love to see"</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-london-lead-on-lack-of-quest-expansion-mods-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-london-lead-on-lack-of-quest-expansion-mods-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-london-lead-on-lack-of-quest-expansion-mods-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-london-lead-on-lack-of-quest-expansion-mods-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-london-lead-on-lack-of-quest-expansion-mods-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-london-lead-on-lack-of-quest-expansion-mods-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-london-lead-on-lack-of-quest-expansion-mods-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-london-lead-on-lack-of-quest-expansion-mods-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-london-lead-on-lack-of-quest-expansion-mods-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Team FOLON</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Who mods the mods? A bunch of people, or so was the hope of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/fallout-london">Fallout: London</a> developers Team FOLON when they released their total conversion of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/fallout-4">Fallout 4</a> back in 2024. So far, there've been plenty of tweaks and smaller scale additions to the mod's version of the post-apocalyptic English capital, but no new quests or world expansions of note.</p>
<p>Things playing out that way to this point - despite Team FOLON having <a href="https://www.vg247.com/fallout-london-british-fallout-making-of-interview">been very open in encouraging other modders</a> to have a go at making such creations - is something Fallout: London project lead Dean 'Prilladog' Carter's clearly aware of, and he's offered a few theories as to why it might be the case.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>"There are definitely some cut quests which are not planned in any of the DLCs that could have been implemented, which we have voiced, but that just wasn’t in the scope of what we could do before we moved on as a company," Carter told <a href="https://www.esports.net/news/industry/fallout-london-creator-bethesda-elder-scrolls-vi-fallout-5-gta-london/">Esports.net</a> in a fresh interview. "If a modder wants to get involved in them, they absolutely can. That’s what we’d love to see. We’re modders at the end of the day. We’re never going to say no to other modders wanting to do stuff."</p>
<p>He also acknowledged that, while his team have chatted with "quite a lot of smaller modders", there hasn't been a deluge of folks wanting to flesh out the massive mod with their own extra quests or adventures, as is the case with all of the pro studio-made modern Fallouts. Instead, a glance at <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/games/fallout4london">Fallout: London's Nexus Mods page</a> - which I've kept an eye on regularly to see if these sorts of ambitious or creative works pop up - currently turns up just over 600 mods that generally provide handy tweaks to mechanics or fairly compact additions like player homes. There are <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4london/mods/17">a</a> <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4london/mods/613">few</a> <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4london/mods/461">mods</a> by a creator called WitherAwayyy I've dug up which could fit the expansion bill, but they remain exceptions to the rule.</p><p>"I’ve heard of people who have been looking into it, and we give advice and help if they ask, but I don’t know of any new worlds or spaces coming up," Carter admitted in this chat. That's no huge issue - Fallout: London's plenty good played in its 'vanilla' state, as Carter reckons a lot of potential modders may simply prefer. That said, it's still an intriguing thing to see play out, given I can't think many other mods off the top of my head which have offered such an expansive opportunity for modding on top of modding.</p>
<p>Though, at this juncture Carter reckons that may well have been another of the limiting factors the mod's modding scene has bumped up against. "I think people are also well aware that, given the nature of how large we built an entire game on top of another game, it’s not the easiest to mod, and there are stability issues that come from building a game on top of a game," he said. The modder also reckons Fallout 4's age has played a role. "It’s a modding scene for a decade-old game. I think a lot of people have moved on," he theorised. "Even ourselves, when you go back to that question of would we do more, the answer is probably not in Fallout 4."</p>
<p>While this may be one area in which Fallout: London simply can't mirror the Fallout entry to which some have compared what the sort of detour it offers Fallout players - Obsidian's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/fallout-new-vegas">New Vegas</a> - there are still a couple of bits of free Team FOLON-made DLC yet to arrive for it. Last Orders is the first of these and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fallout-londons-next-dlc-last-orders-will-be-served-up-early-this-year-if-current-pint-pulling-plans-hold">should arrive pretty soon</a>, followed at some point down the line by a Yes Man-esque questline in the Wildcard DLC.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fallout-london-hasnt-developed-into-a-fallout-4-esque-hub-of-its-own-new-quest-and-expansion-mods-and-its-lead-has-theories-why]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>