<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 06:17:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Send kids to the past to save the world from a metallic rain hellscape in the captivating point-and-click Decade]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/send-kids-to-the-past-to-save-the-world-from-a-metallic-rain-hellscape-in-the-captivating-point-and-click-decade</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/send-kids-to-the-past-to-save-the-world-from-a-metallic-rain-hellscape-in-the-captivating-point-and-click-decade.1200036/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/send-kids-to-the-past-to-save-the-world-from-a-metallic-rain-hellscape-in-the-captivating-point-and-click-decade<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Last Piscean</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Earlier this week, one of my industry peers James Bentley (they're over at that other site about PC games, GamerPCs I think it's called) put out a video essay titled "<a href="https://youtu.be/KtqrklovNHI?si=niPEfgfN3OxDxMmF">I Can Guarantee You This Game is Going to be Underrated</a>". Trusting in James as a critic of varied and interesting taste, I clicked through and found that yeah, they're right, it probably will be. However, I also get to write about indie PC games for a living, so I'd like to do my part in telling you about this strange, point-and-click/ <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-10-best-visual-novels-on-pc">visual novel</a> called <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/decade">Decade</a>.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
I don't think Decade is an easy, or perhaps comfortable game to describe, given its heavy themes. The game follows four children, specifically the four last children on the entire planet, the only survivors after metallic rain killing almost everyone else, the rest of them subsequently killing each other. Somehow these kids manage to get a time machine working, with three of them able to travel back 10 years to try and save the world.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Decade - Indie narrative adventure game trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UI7BozEb1xo?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Decade - Indie narrative adventure game trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UI7BozEb1xo?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/UI7BozEb1xo?autoplay=1" title="Decade - Indie narrative adventure game trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UI7BozEb1xo" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
The thing is, time travel or not, aging comes for us all, and these children do in fact grow older across those 10 years. While in the past, they can "investigate documents, technologies, and artefacts to understand history", all the while trying to make decisions that can lead you into several different futures. This, to put it plainly, is a concept that will likely continue to keep me up at night.
</p>
<p>
How much guilt should I feel for leading these children towards a future that might not even be liveable? Will I waste their years away in doing so? Do they get to have a future? These are questions I'm yet to answer myself through playing the game, but I'd like to, and it would be nice if you were interested in trying to do the same.
</p>
<p>
Developer Last Piscean worked on this solo after losing their job, and they still haven't managed to find one, and with the game releasing today (with a discount that makes it the price of two cups of coffee on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3272360/Decade/">Steam</a>), there's no better time to check it out than now.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You should forget about Cities Skyline 2's Bridges & Ports expansions for a while, because it's been delayed again]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/you-should-forget-about-cities-skyline-2s-bridges-ports-expansions-for-a-while-because-its-been-delayed-again</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/you-should-forget-about-cities-skyline-2s-bridges-ports-expansions-for-a-while-because-its-been-delayed-again.1199976/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/you-should-forget-about-cities-skyline-2s-bridges-ports-expansions-for-a-while-because-its-been-delayed-again<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun/Paradox Interactive</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
I think there might be a chance, just ever so slightly, that the development of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/cities-skylines-2">Cities Skylines 2</a> has been a bit difficult. The game launched back in October of 2023 and has suffered from <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cities-skylines-2-wont-get-paid-dlc-until-its-problem-issues-are-sorted-devs-say">performance issues</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cities-skylines-2-devs-apologise-for-rushed-dlc-offer-refunds-promise-conciliatory-fan-summit">rushed DLC</a>, and a delay to its first expansion Bridges and Ports. This expansion was meant to come soon after the Beach Properties DLC, but that obviously didn't happen, catching a delay to sometime in the second quarter of 2025 specifically to continue improving upon the base game. Except the expansion has been delayed once again.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
Over on a <a href="https://forum.paradoxplaza.com/forum/threads/free-patch-and-updated-plans.1760205/">forum post</a>, developer <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/colossalorder">Colossal Order</a> shared an update explaining why the DLC has caught another delay. "After reviewing the content ourselves and sharing it with our early access group, we’ve received consistent feedback: the bridges are super exciting, and the port works well, but there are aspects of the expansion that are not as polished as they could be."
</p>
<p>
This, they say, left them with "a difficult choice: delay the release once again to add more depth, or release it as-is, knowing players may feel it falls short." Colossal also said they think Bridges and Ports is enjoyable as is, but to "bring it to the level you deserve, we need more time." Now, it's expected to launch sometime in the fourth quarter of this year.
</p>
<p>
Ironically, a free update is coming on June 11th that was meant to coincide with the expansion that includes a couple of new bridges, three leisure piers, and three quays. It's something! To be fair to Colossal, delaying it probably is the better decision, I could quite easily see another botched DLC sinking that city builder shaped ship. 
</p>
<p>
I think there was some famous guy who had a plumber for a son that once said something like "a delayed Bridges and Ports expansion is eventually good, but a rushed Bridges and Ports expansion is forever bad." Might be paraphrasing.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>