<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 18:08:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pathologic 3 devs keen to avoid "premature promises" about bringing back the Changeling in Pathologic 4]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pathologic-3-devs-keen-to-avoid-premature-promises-about-bringing-back-the-changeling-in-pathologic-4</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pathologic-3-devs-keen-to-avoid-premature-promises-about-bringing-back-the-changeling-in-pathologic-4.1025508/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pathologic-3-devs-keen-to-avoid-premature-promises-about-bringing-back-the-changeling-in-pathologic-4<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Bachelor-helmed threequel is more about investigation than survival</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_coXI4bf.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Ice-Pick Lodge</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Like a plague doctor delicately administering another handful of leeches, Ice Pick Lodge have shared a bit more about the recently announced Pathologic 3, explaining how their plans for the cult epidemic-battling series have progressed since the release of Pathologic 2.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>As Brendy <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pathologic-3-announced-with-time-travel-mechanic-due-for-release-in-2025">recalled in our announcement post</a>, Pathologic 2 was in fact a remake of the original Pathologic. Like the 2005 game, it was supposed to have three, very different playable characters - the Haruspex, the Bachelor, and the Changeling, each tasked with saving a mucky town of slaughterhouse workers from a vicious infection. 
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Pathologic 3 Announce Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Zb0C2WYUjkI?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Pathologic 3 Announce Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Zb0C2WYUjkI?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Zb0C2WYUjkI?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zb0C2WYUjkI" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
The Haruspex arrived at launch in 2019, and the other two characters were to follow as DLC expansions, but as Ice Pick <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/3199650/view/4468226896061005952">explain in the Steam page</a>, this proved impractical, with development of the Haruspex route taking longer than expected. As such, the Bachelor will form the diseased heart of his own game. Will the same be true of the Changeling, who is capable of healing or killing with a touch? It's still a bit unclear, but that's the hope, yes.
</p><p>
"The game simply grew beyond our concept of DLC," Ice Pick write on Steam. "It will have different gameplay and entirely new features. Instead of one game with three playthroughs using the same gameplay but different storylines (as in the original 2005 release and the Classic HD remaster), we're creating three fully developed games with distinct gameplay and significant differences in narrative.
</p>
<p>
"Now, these are truly three separate protagonists with unique worldviews, perceptions of reality, and distinct tools," they continue. "From a gameplay perspective, this means three different approaches and a complete rethinking of the original scripts."
</p>
<p>
As for the Changeling route, the seeming expectation is that she'll be the heroine of Pathologic 4, but the developers don't want to jump the gun. "We understand that premature promises about the previous Pathologic led to unfulfilled expectations," they write. "We apologize for that and don't want to mislead you in the future. The developer should not be an unreliable narrator - unlike his characters."
</p>
<p>
The post also covers a few of the differences between the Bachelor and the Haruspex, which may be familiar to those who played the 2005 game. "The Haruspex needed to survive, fight, scavenge, rummage through garbage for scraps of bread, and try to save those he held dear along the way," the devs write. "The Bachelor is a man of intellect. Survival is not his primary concern; his goals go beyond what one lifetime could contain. He needs to think, formulate theories, and gather evidence. Ultimately, he must issue commands and observe the results. This distinction will be emphasized through gameplay, mechanics, objectives, soundtrack, and so on."
</p><p>
As you'd hope, people who helped fund Pathologic 2's development according to the original vision of a three-protagonist game will receive keys for Pathologic 3. To be specific, they'll send free keys to "Kickstarter backers and other platforms where support for the game was available during the fundraising stage" together with "Backers from 2014 and 2015". People entitled to two copies will receive two keys.</p>
<p>The game will "likely" be available on all the same platforms as its predecessor, with console launches coming after the PC version. Expect more details closer to release in 2025.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Monster Hunter Wilds beta is live with an early glimpse of the new camping, wound and weather systems]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-monster-hunter-wilds-beta-is-live-with-an-early-glimpse-of-the-new-camping-wound-and-weather-systems</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-monster-hunter-wilds-beta-is-live-with-an-early-glimpse-of-the-new-camping-wound-and-weather-systems.1025430/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-monster-hunter-wilds-beta-is-live-with-an-early-glimpse-of-the-new-camping-wound-and-weather-systems<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>
Stroll on down to Uncle Capcom's garage, girls and boys, because it's time to meddle with a cat's voicebox, ride a combat peacock and meticulously injure a vast, blubbery teddybear. By which I mean, the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> beta is now live on Steam through to 4th November at 2.59am GMT. That's 2.59am sharp. If you're hurrying along at 3am on Monday absolutely desperate to polish the aesthetics of a small enslaved catperson, you can sod off and play <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dragon-age-dreadwolf">Dragon Age: The Veilguard</a> instead.
</p><!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="A Beginner's Guide to Monster Hunter Wilds" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jxSlVspp1cI?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>A Beginner's Guide to Monster Hunter Wilds</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jxSlVspp1cI?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/jxSlVspp1cI?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jxSlVspp1cI" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
To celebrate, Capcom have published <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2246340/view/4438953498491486386?l=english">an introductory guide on Steam</a> that goes into such detail it renders the playing of the open beta absolutely needless, ho ho, I kid, Capcom, please put the greatsword down. To recap, the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-monster-hunter-wilds-pc-beta-launches-this-month-with-a-character-editor-and-co-op-multiplayer">open beta</a> lets you create a character and Palico assistant. It gives you access to a Story Trial, in which you'll get to experiment with 14 different weapons and visit destruction upon a helpless trainer's dummy, together with a Doshaguma Hunt, which takes you out onto the Windward Plains in search of relatively resistant furry mammals to slaughter. While you're out there, you might go Wild with one of the following new Wilds features:
</p>
<p>

- <strong>Focus Mode!</strong> This is a new magic vision ability that lets you see monster wounds. These don't look like wounds, however. They look like glowing weak points, because this is a Capcom game. Imagine if Mortal Kombat did it this way.
</p><p>

- <strong>Ride your Seikret!</strong> This is the aforesaid combat peacock. Not to mix my analogies/metaphors, but it's also a packmule with a pouch for supply items and the opportunity to switch between two loadouts while mounted. What's more, you can sharpen weapons while riding your battlebird, and it even has an auto-drive feature. They could have saved themselves some animation budget and just swapped it for a Toyota Yaris.
</p>
<p>

- <strong>Camping!</strong> You can now have your Palico acquaintance pitch a tent for you to bask inside, cooking or changing your gear or just reclining like a prince. Be warned however that Monsters may come up and sit on it. A herd of sheep did this to me once in darkest North Yorkshire. Ah, what I wouldn't have given for a Toyoto Yaris at the time.
</p>
<p>
- <strong>Slay the Rey Dau!</strong> There are a bunch of monsters in the beta. The rarest of them all is a dragon that lives in a thunderstorm. I saw an Alpha Doshaguma battle one of these back at Summer Game Fest. It did not go well for the Alpha Doshaguma. It turns out that in Mother Nature's great game of roshambo, lightning lizards &gt; furry fartboys.
</p>
<p>
- <strong>Witness the changing weather!</strong> There are several seasons in store, all of which appear to have been named by mildly religious poets. Inclemency is "an ecology-altering event that sweeps in a raging storm" - beware lightning bolts, whether ye be hunterman or monste. Fallow is "a period of scarcity, with hungry predators roaming the land for food", while Plenty is a time of abundant map resources and smaller fauna. I see no option for Wearitude, the British season that somehow combines the heat of summer with the chilliness of winter, and is abundant in wasps that refuse to die or hibernate or whatever it is they do when they're not invading my sandwiches.
</p><p>
- <strong>Possibly turn off the spiders!</strong> I'm not sure if the Wilds beta includes arachnids, but in the full version of the game, you can <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/monster-hunter-wilds-will-have-a-spider-free-mode-for-those-with-arachnophobia">transform them into slimes</a>, though they will still move like spiders, which is possibly worse.</p>
<p>
Speaking of the full version of Monster Hunter Wilds, it's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/monster-hunter-wilds-releases-28th-feb-2025-which-gives-modders-enough-time-to-silence-the-uncanny-talking-palicos">out on 28th February 2025</a>, and your character and Palico from the beta will carry over. So there's no reason not to overcommit. I won't be playing, unfortunately, because my brother is in town and we'll be busy hunting the greatest prey of all: an affordable non-Dominos pizza in London. Give my regards to the Doshaguma.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>