<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 11:55:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ZeniMax staff discuss Microsoft's "inhumane" mass layoffs and how the future looks for the "carcass of workers that remains"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/zenimax-staff-discuss-microsofts-inhumane-mass-layoffs-and-how-the-future-looks-for-the-carcass-of-workers-that-remains</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zenimax-staff-discuss-microsofts-inhumane-mass-layoffs-and-how-the-future-looks-for-the-carcass-of-workers-that-remains.1250799/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"This is an acute traumatic event and it needs to be treated like that"</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>The Initiative</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>A new report delves into the behind-the-scenes chaos caused at <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-online">Elder Scrolls Online</a> studio ZeniMax by Microsoft's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/microsoft-layoffs-are-reportedly-underway-with-zenimax-and-king-employees-losing-their-jobs">mass layoffs</a> earlier this month. Staff say the manner in which the corp let go of around 9k staff was "inhumane" and has left those who remain facing an incredibly tough future.</p>
<p>An unannounced MMO in development at ZeniMax, codenamed Project Blackbird, was one of the games cancelled by Microsoft as part of the corporate bloodletting, with <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rares-mysterious-nature-sim-everwild-has-been-cancelled-as-part-of-xbox-mass-layoffs-according-to-reports">Rare's Everwild</a> and The Initiative's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/perfect-dark">Perfect Dark</a> reboot also <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/microsoft-cancel-perfect-dark-reboot-and-shut-the-developers-down-in-the-name-of-continued-success">being canned</a>. Just <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/zenimax-union-say-theyre-fighting-for-staff-left-in-limbo-by-microsoft-cancelling-mmo-as-part-of-mass-layoffs">last week</a>, the ZeniMax Online Studios United (ZOSU) union said they're still fighting on behalf of workers at the studio left in limbo by Blackbird's cancellation.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>The staff <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/zenimax-staff-lambast-inhumane-xbox-layoffs-it-s-difficult-to-work-when-you-re-looking-at-a-graveyard-">Game Developer</a> spoke to for the report paint a horrifying picture of the day that saw Microsoft jettison all of those people and projects. They claim staff were removed from company communications such as Slack and email before human resources had even made contact to inform them whether they'd been let go. "It was so sad seeing people so distraught and confused and not knowing if they would have a job by the end of the day - or even if the layoffs were done by the end of the day," said current ZeniMax worker and ZeniMax Workers United - CWA union member Page Branson.</p>
<p>"It's not okay. It wasn't normal," added ZeniMax senior QA tester and fellow ZeniMax Workers United member Autumn Mitchell. "I don't care how many times they do it to try and make it seem normal — it's not. The way they do it is inhumane. I don't care how much they say that it's dignified or they want to do it in a respectful way - it's not."</p>
<p>"Making it so that people have to rush to type a goodbye message into Slack to their colleagues that they've been working with on various projects, that have been making your corporation money for 15 years, is disgusting," the QA tester continued.</p>
<p>Both Branson and Mitchell believe the cuts at ZeniMax, which Game Developer report have affected "hundreds" of workers, would have been worse if a significant number of the studio's staff <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/zenimax-qa-workers-have-reached-a-tentative-contract-agreement-with-microsoft-paving-the-way-for-better-wages-and-more">hadn't unionised</a>. As is, they say the layoffs have seen key developers be let go, leaving those who remain facing a bleak future.</p>
<p>"A lot of practical knowledge just disappeared overnight," Branson said. "Everyone left now has to pick up the pieces as best they can. The [dwindling] morale and general confusion of it all has extended into our general workflow. We used to have very, very reliable people working on things and they're no longer there. They were integral. I feel like they were numbers on a sheet that got cut, but the real application of what they were doing was integral to making everything run correctly."</p>
<p>"This carcass of workers that remains is somehow supposed to keep shipping award-winning games," Mitchell added, later likening the situation to having to keep on working while "looking at a graveyard".</p>
<p>We've reached out to Microsoft for comment.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/zenimax-staff-discuss-microsofts-inhumane-mass-layoffs-and-how-the-future-looks-for-the-carcass-of-workers-that-remains]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Splitgate 2 devs 1047 Games lay off more staff as the shooter heads "back to beta", eyeing a 2026 rerelease]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/splitgate-2-devs-1047-games-lay-off-more-staff-as-the-shooter-heads-back-to-beta-eyeing-a-2026-rerelease</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/splitgate-2-devs-1047-games-lay-off-more-staff-as-the-shooter-heads-back-to-beta-eyeing-a-2026-rerelease.1250724/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Servers for the original Splitgate being shut down in a month's time</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>1047 Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/splitgate-2">Splitgate 2</a> is being taken "back to beta" by developers 1047 Games, who say it "launched too early" and are now planning to rerelease it next year. The move has reportedly seen the studio lay off 45 workers, and they've confirmed that the original <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/splitgate">Splitgate</a>'s servers will be shutting down in a month's time.</p>
<p>The news comes following a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/splitgate-2-remains-a-portal-hopping-fps-delight-but-it-really-needs-to-lighten-up">mixed launch reception</a> for the portal-filled <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-fps-games">shooter</a>, which likely wasn't helped by studio CEO Ian Proulx controversially announcing that it was going live while <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/splitgate-2-boss-admits-the-trumpish-hat-he-wore-at-summer-game-fest-was-a-publicity-stunt-after-it-goes-sour">wearing a MAGA-style “Make FPS Great Again” hat</a> on stage at Summer Game Fest. The exec subsequently apologised for that boneheaded publicity stunt.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>In an update posted to the game's <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2918300/view/510712444576860070?l=english">Steam page</a> and <a href="https://x.com/Splitgate/status/1947717804364353641">socials</a> Proulx and fellow 1047 Games co-founder Nicholas Bagamian wrote that they "had ambitious goals with Splitgate 2", but "rushed certain features, made some boneheaded mistakes, and most importantly – we didn't give you the polished, portal-filled mayhem you fell in love with".</p>
<p>So, the game is returning to beta until early 2026, with the studio promising a major overhaul that'll include "reworking progression from the ground up, adding more portals to our maps, simplifying monetisation, refocusing on classic game modes you've been asking for, and more". Though, 1047 say Splitgate 2'll remain playable in the interim, with its Chapter 3 update and some bug fixes still incoming.</p>
<p>The update acknowledged that this decision has been accompanied by layoffs at the studio, but didn't state how many. <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/splitgate-2-will-go-back-to-beta-to-undergo-a-massive-rework-amid-more-layoffs-and-splitgate-1-shutdown?utm_source=threads,twitter">IGN</a> reports that 45 workers have been affected. This is the second round of job cuts at 1047 this year, with <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/following-their-hat-and-pricing-controversies-splitgate-2-studio-1047-games-have-laid-off-an-unspecified-number-of-devs">an unspecified number of devs having been let go</a> in June.</p>
<p>The studio are also planning to shut down the original Splitgate's servers in a month's time. "While we'd love to keep servers online indefinitely, it's cost us hundreds of thousands of dollars over the past couple of years, and we have to prioritize our team," Proulx and Bagamian wrote. "Like us, we know this game means a lot to so many of you, so we are exploring the possibility of supporting offline or peer-to-peer matches."</p>
<p>Hopefully the folks affected by these layoffs can land on their feet.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/splitgate-2-devs-1047-games-lay-off-more-staff-as-the-shooter-heads-back-to-beta-eyeing-a-2026-rerelease]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>