<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 10:49:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A spidery new mech crawls onto the eternal battlefield of The Forever Winter]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-spidery-new-mech-crawls-onto-the-eternal-battlefield-of-the-forever-winter</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-spidery-new-mech-crawls-onto-the-eternal-battlefield-of-the-forever-winter.1254834/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Fun Dog Studios</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Dusty extract-o-shooter <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-forever-winter">The Forever Winter</a> got an update over the weekend that added another mech to the growing list of horrifying war machines that roam its post-apocalyptic world looking for fleshy idiots to squash and eat. "The StiltWalker is a multi-legged destruction machine: equipped with multiple missile and machinegun weapon systems," say the developers in <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2828860/view/547867519580373226">an update post on Steam</a>. Pfft. What's so scary about that? Just shoot some rockets at it.</p>
<p>"It is also equipped with a point defense system that can detonate explosive munitions that are fired at it from a distance."</p>
<p>Ah. Well. Nevertheless.</p>
<!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Forever Winter - July Update: &quot;Lost Angels&quot;" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xevM4VG2SSE?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Forever Winter - July Update: "Lost Angels"</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xevM4VG2SSE?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/xevM4VG2SSE?autoplay=1" title="The Forever Winter - July Update: &quot;Lost Angels&quot;">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xevM4VG2SSE" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>"Its peripheral missile systems are direct-fire," the update continues, "but its core missile systems are ATGM guided munitions that will sail into the sky before raining down on Europa’s foes with deadly homing accuracy." Big talk from someone with skinny little legs. You can see what it looks like in the trailer above. Developers Fun Dog do love recording doomy panning shots of their ashen wastelands peppered with tracer fire and the odd explosion. I suppose when it looks this atmospheric who can blame them?</p>
<p>The update also adds a new region to explore - a rubble-strewn city called "Lost Angels" with its own quests to complete. Although the devs say that this region, like much of the game, is a "work in progress". Alongside all this there are a bunch of performance improvements and other tweaks, like a change to the weight and speed of player characters, and some alterations to weapon reload rates. You can also now spam a button to get up more quickly after being knocked down. Stuff like that.</p>
<p>It's been interesting to track this third-person shooter as it's scavenged its way through the early access wastes. It was in a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-forever-winter-struggles-into-early-access-with-poor-performance-and-a-deadly-thirst-for-your-time">shonky state</a> when it first broke cover, with hostile troops spawning right on top of players and enemy tanks flipping out and flying across the sky. The game's water resource system was divisive too. It was designed so that precious water drained away even while you weren't playing, which could once theoretically result in losing all your gear. </p>
<p>But it looks more and more like many of the early pains have been somewhat soothed. The water system was <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-forever-winters-water-will-no-longer-drain-away-while-youre-offline">completely overhauled</a>, for one thing, and recent monthly updates have seen <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2828860/view/547864982714319391">changes to the way stealth works</a> and a way to <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2828860/view/547862446583317590">hack radar mechs</a> to reveal a better picture of the enigmatic and eternal three-way war that rages around you. As for other buggy war machines, they continue to get fine-tuned in this month's patch: "Tanks now move much more reliably," it says. No more <a href="https://www.youtube.com/shorts/U-ktTg7ACeI">trips to the moon</a>, lieutenant. </p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-spidery-new-mech-crawls-onto-the-eternal-battlefield-of-the-forever-winter]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This week in PC games: Hobbits, gigahorses, internet fixers, ninjas, hellships, junkbots and window cleaners]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-week-in-pc-games-hobbits-gigahorses-internet-fixers-ninjas-hellships-junkbots-and-window-cleaners</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-week-in-pc-games-hobbits-gigahorses-internet-fixers-ninjas-hellships-junkbots-and-window-cleaners.1254816/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>What we're feeding the Maw</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Private Division</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>This week's big news is that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-769">Graham is leaving RPS</a>. Graham, the rock upon which all of our bullshit is built. Graham, the last link to Treehouses gone by. We shall not see his like again. Expect supernatural calamities in keeping with such a terrible loss: rains of frogs, Atari reinventing Pong as a 100 hour gacha RPG, mass hysteria. Still, the wheel of releasing cranks on. Here's what's new in PC games this week.</p><!--more-->
<h2>Monday 28th July </h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/fumes">Fumes</a> is that Mad Maximalist open world vehicular combat game that looks a bit like Micro Machines. Such adorably chubby doof wagons.</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2350270/Primal_Planet/">Primal Planet</a> casts you as a small family of primordial humans fighting dinosaurs, UFOs and rival tribes in side-scrolling metroidvania format.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Tuesday 29th July</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/grounded-2">Grounded 2</a> is here with another helping of very small people building houses out of compost and having turf wars with ants.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/tales-of-the-shire">Tales of the Shire</a> (pictured) is about slightly less small people building houses out of rustic wallpaper patterns and striving to wow their neighbours with soup.</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3008340/Day_of_the_Shell/">Day Of The Shell</a> is a turn-based tactics-me-do set in a shattered, flooded world that reminds me of Bastion, somewhat.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Wednesday 30th July</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2387430/SKY_THE_SCRAPER/">Sky The Scraper</a> is a window-cleaning game with a nonsensical name. And a life sim element, because even window cleaners take days off now and then.</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2637220/Morgan_Metal_Detective/">Morgan: Metal Detective</a> is a metal-detecting game, set on a Cornish island.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/gold-gold-adventure-gold">Gold Gold Adventure Gold</a> is a colony builder in which you help out dungeon-delving heroes or feed them to your pet godbeast. Dungeon Village X Black &amp; White, perhaps.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Thursday 31st July
</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2939600/Tower_Networking_Inc/">Tower Networking Inc</a> is a game about managing internet services for residences and businesses scattered across "an ever-expanding randomly generated tower". Good lord, the sicko factor of this. </li>
<li><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/ninja-gaiden-ragebound">Ninja Gaiden: Ragebound</a> is a flatpacked pixelart take on Team Ninja's venerable shinobi-shanking series.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/mashina">Mashina</a> is a curious junkyard mining fable from Judero developer Jack King-Spooner.</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2513490/Hell_Galaxy/">Hell Galaxy</a> is an open world space shooter with an enticing dollop of body horror. FAO Homeworld Cataclysm enjoyers, maybe.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/heartworm">Heartworm</a> is Silent Evil or Resident Hill, "a reverent evolution of 90's survival horror" that splices fixed cameras with an over-the-shoulder perspective.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/time-flies">Buzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz.</a></li></ul>
<h2>Friday 1st August</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3167280/Ikarus_Parkour/">Ikarus Parkour</a> is a 3D tower-climber with sheeny gameshow environments. Given the title reference, surely the appropriate way to complete this game is to fall and die? It's not clear whether you can craft yourself some waxen wings.</li>
</ul>
<p>What are RPS's assorted scribes, scalliwags and scumbags doing this week? Well, Brendy is practising a mixture of ninjitsu and cleanliness. James aims to bring down a building or two. Mark has his eye on a Sicilian enterprise, assuming code comes in. I've got some interview pieces in the offing that are as interesting as they are tiring.</p>
<p>Finally, what are you doing this week? Aside from making lamentation over Graham's departure.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-week-in-pc-games-hobbits-gigahorses-internet-fixers-ninjas-hellships-junkbots-and-window-cleaners]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>