<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 10:05:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 drops bots from verified mode playlist as EA continues fight against those dastardly XP farmers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-6-drops-bots-from-verified-mode-playlist-as-ea-continues-fight-against-those-dastardly-xp-farmers</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-drops-bots-from-verified-mode-playlist-as-ea-continues-fight-against-those-dastardly-xp-farmers.1333783/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-6-best-guns-hero.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-6-best-guns-hero.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-6-best-guns-hero.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-6-best-guns-hero.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-6-best-guns-hero.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-6-best-guns-hero.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-6-best-guns-hero.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-6-best-guns-hero.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-6-best-guns-hero.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>EA</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-6-weapons-list">Battlefield 6</a>'s battle against the bot farmers continues with a series of backend updates from EA. Amongst other things, the developers have reversed some "unintended" changes to XP progression and balance, and removed bots from "verified" modes available through the Portal editor.
</p><!--more-->
<p>
Last week, the developers <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-6-is-getting-updates-to-speed-up-xp-progression-and-unlocks-as-ea-tackle-plague-of-bot-farmers">announced</a> that they were taking action against players who'd created matches simply to murder computer-controlled soldiers en masse for easy XP. The argument being that Battlefield 6's servers are filling up with XP factories, making it harder for players to find the weird and wonderful mode variations that Portal is supposed to be for. 
</p>
<p>
As ever, the counterargument is that there might be fewer bot-processing joints and more flights of Battle-whimsy in Portal if the game's progression system were less annoying. I didn't find it particularly annoying during my <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-6-review">pre-release time with multiplayer</a>, but then again, I'm not very competitive-minded and was in no hurry to unlock any of those fancy scopes. Too busy lying on my back, enjoying the deep blue sky over Gibraltar (while bleeding out).
</p>
<p>
I neglected to note in the previous story that Battlefield Studios have a more straightforward monetary interest, of course, in stopping people short-circuiting the XP system. Battlefield 6 is a live service game with a forthcoming battle pass and options to pay for XP and tier skips. It's harder to sell those special editions and Double XP boosters if people can accelerate the grind on custom servers.
</p><p>
Here's an update on their attempts to remedy the situation from Battlefield's social accounts. "We have organized a series of changes to emphasize our commitment to highlighting the player community and making this a space where you can celebrate creativity, find unique experiences, play with friends, and build communities.
</p>
<p>
"As part of this effort, we've rolled out several backend updates to support healthier matchmaking and better overall experiences in Portal. This includes resolving unintended systems that affected XP progression and balance across experiences, and for now, removing bots from Verified Experiences to help improve the overall quality of matches."
</p>
<p>
Verified experiences are a more curated and grounded selection of Portal modes that mostly let you twiddle with the settings of Breakthrough, Conquest, and Rush. Unlike other custom modes, these modes award full XP, so you can see why EA would be keen to do away with botfarming in verified experiences.
</p>
<p>
EA have now introduced a change whereby you'll need to disable "bot backfill" if you want full XP gain in a verified mode. Any verified experiences that have bot backfill will need to be unpublished and republished with the change. 
</p>
<p>
"Servers, including persistent ones, may occasionally need to be restarted," the developers add. "These brief interruptions may continue until ongoing improvements are fully implemented."
</p>
<p>
The first season of Battlefield 6's live seasonal seasonings begins on 28th October. It introduces a new map, some extra guns, a new mode, and a paid battle pass for those who partake. 
</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-6-drops-bots-from-verified-mode-playlist-as-ea-continues-fight-against-those-dastardly-xp-farmers]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hades 2 post-launch patch 1 revamps Melinoë's "true ending", and is out now in Steam preview form]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hades-2-post-launch-patch-1-revamps-melinoes-true-ending-and-is-out-now-in-steam-preview-form</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hades-2-post-launch-patch-1-revamps-melino%C3%ABs-true-ending-and-is-out-now-in-steam-preview-form.1333762/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Plus an incantation that'll let you replay story beats and cheaper rugs for the crossroads</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hades-2-post-launch-patch-1-preview-beta-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hades-2-post-launch-patch-1-preview-beta-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hades-2-post-launch-patch-1-preview-beta-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hades-2-post-launch-patch-1-preview-beta-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hades-2-post-launch-patch-1-preview-beta-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hades-2-post-launch-patch-1-preview-beta-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hades-2-post-launch-patch-1-preview-beta-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hades-2-post-launch-patch-1-preview-beta-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hades-2-post-launch-patch-1-preview-beta-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Supergiant Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hades-2">Hades 2</a>'s true ending didn't feel totally slam dunk satisfying to me in its 1.0 release form, and developers Supergiant Games seem to have agreed with those sorts of assessments. Hence, in the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-roguelike-games-pc">roguelike</a>'s first proper post-launch patch they've just put out as a Steam preview, some "true ending enhancements" being rolled out like a boon from a sassy god.</p>
<p>Shameless plug alert, if you want to read my full thoughts on that 1.0 version, you can read <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hades-2-10-review">this here review</a>. The short version is that it's good.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Anyway, enough of that, let's dive into <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1145350/view/505090299391902119?l=english">the notes</a> for this post-launch first patch preview. "The Patch 1 Preview represents a work-in-progress whose contents may evolve, and some text translations are still in progress," Supergiant wrote. "We do not have a release date for the full patch."</p>
<p>In terms of their true ending tweaks, the studio say they've added some extra events with key characters you'll run into both before and after completing Melinoë's task. Bits of the ending scenes before the credits roll have also been "revised", while one change I can't say I'm necessarily a fan of is that the number of times you'll need to clear the underworld run before getting the final ending has gone up. On one hand, it'll ensure you get more chances to see these new scenes, but on the other, I fear it might feel a bit like padding in a game that's already treading a thin line in that regard towards the end.</p><p>Alongside those ending tweaks, Supergiant have added in a cauldron incantation which lets you go back in time and replay previous story beats, which is handy since it means I won't have to start from scratch to take in the revamped finale. "A number of character-related Prophecies, including the one connected to the story epilogue, should unfold faster than before," reads another of the patch's headline changes, while the decor you can buy for the crossroads now costs less spirit kudos points. Phew, no more lofty rug prices.</p>
<p>In terms of the usual bug fixes and balance adjustments, only one of the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/nocturnal">Nocturnal</a> Arms has had an aspect tweaked, that being the Witch's Staff's ability to burn folks when imbued with Hestia's smoulder ring cast boon. The boon and blessing specific tweaks are more numerous and a few bosses have had their hitboxes and effects adjusted.</p>
<p>There's more in the full notes, and if you want to give this preview a go, Supergiant have included instructions on how to opt into its Steam beta after backing up your saves.</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hades-2-post-launch-patch-1-revamps-melinoes-true-ending-and-is-out-now-in-steam-preview-form]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>