<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 14:36:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oh thank Horace, our comments system is up and running again]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oh-thank-horace-our-comments-system-is-up-and-running-again</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/oh-thank-horace-our-comments-system-is-up-and-running-again.1028754/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oh-thank-horace-our-comments-system-is-up-and-running-again<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1200px-Ten_Men_and_Four_Boys_Singing_in_a_Church_MET_DP835947.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Pieter de Jode II / Purchase, Joseph Pulitzer Bequest, 1917 / Metropolitan Museum of Art</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>"Never read the comments," is a truth much-rehearsed by senior games journalists, but I have long since levelled-up past this axiom and entered into a new world of benevolent narcissism. I <em>always</em> read the comments, for all commenters are my children. They exist to glorify and preserve me in my dotage. True, occasionally my children say things like "I think your writing and opinions are appalling, and that you deserve to be repeatedly run over by a herd of deer", but it is the nature of children to rebel.</p>
<p>All of which is to say that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/weve-temporarily-closed-comments-for-maintenance-but-theyll-be-back">the comments downtime during a tech transition</a> this week has been painful for me. I've missed you all! I don't have anything particular to say in this post - I just thought we could do with a place to convene after this long, strange purgatory of articles being published with no accompanying trickle or waterfall of reader insights. What have you all been up to? Any news to share? I hear there's been some kind of election somewhere. I promise you the comments outage is unrelated.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Halo 2's lost E3 2003 demo will finally be playable thanks to modder magic]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/halo-2s-lost-e3-2003-demo-will-finally-be-playable-thanks-to-modder-magic</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/halo-2s-lost-e3-2003-demo-will-finally-be-playable-thanks-to-modder-magic.1028655/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/halo-2s-lost-e3-2003-demo-will-finally-be-playable-thanks-to-modder-magic<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Doing more than grunt work</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/halo2-header.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Xbox Game Studios</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/halo-infinite">Halo Infinite</a> recently received a big update in the form of Delta Arena, a playlist that features recreations of Halo 2's most popular maps and a special third-person mode. The true highlight, though, is yet to come. And that's through an entirely different Halo game: <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/halo-the-master-chief-collection">The Master Chief Collection</a>. Soon enough, you'll be able to play Halo 2's lost E3 demo on it, thanks to some lovely modders.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>So yes, to celebrate Halo 2's 20th anniversary you can boot up Halo Infinite and jump into some Halo 2 maps. There's Ascension, Midship, Lockout and many others that are good and dandy (you can actually play original Halo 2 maps via The Master Chief Collection). I don't remember any of them because I didn't have Xbox Live at the time as I was quite a young lad. I <em>do</em> remember really enjoying the campaign, though, and rinsing it over the course of a day or so. God, I loved dual-wielding and particularly, those Flood-ridden levels.</p>
<p>Now, I also don't remember E3's 2003 demo because I was probably playing tag in the park or something. Either way, it's hailed as an iconic moment for Halo and the Xbox and what was possible back then. In an interview with Halo community director Brian Jarrard for <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2024/11/04/20-years-of-halo-2-new-maps-e3-demo/">Xbox Wire</a>, he explains that it's since remained locked away due to "snags with technology", but thanks to modders and "Digsite data archaeology", the original assets and files were recovered.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Halo 2 - E3 2003 Gameplay Demo Trailer [HD]" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9i-4foLur0g?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Halo 2 - E3 2003 Gameplay Demo Trailer [HD]</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9i-4foLur0g?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9i-4foLur0g?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9i-4foLur0g" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>Still, Jarrard says that because the original E3 demo was then built in a "version of the Halo engine that no longer exists" and with assets incompatible with any other versions of Halo 2, the team still had some more work to do. Halo senior franchise writer Kenneth Peter says that it even needed an "Xbox developer kit to get it to boot", which aren't exactly in abundance in the studio anymore.</p>
<p>Modders like Steven Garcia and Digsite members helped get the demo in shape, though. And Peters says that without them, we'd all have a "rather unceremonious drop of raw assets".</p>
<p>To play the recreated E3 demo, you'll need to own Halo: The Master Chief Collection and download the free mod from the Steam Workshop when it arrives on November 9th.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stop putting hats on your pets, asks Stardew Valley creator]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/stop-putting-hats-on-your-pets-asks-stardew-valley-creator</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/stop-putting-hats-on-your-pets-asks-stardew-valley-creator.1028634/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/stop-putting-hats-on-your-pets-asks-stardew-valley-creator<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/stardew-valley-multiplayer-autumn.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>ConcernedApe</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Back in the misty reaches of time (March) popular farming sim <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/stardew-valley">Stardew Valley</a> got a big update that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/stardew-valleys-huge-update-16-brings-new-items-pets-and-progression-and-more-players-in-co-op">added more pets</a> to the game (it also let you drink mayonaise but let's not get sidetracked). Those new cats, dogs, and turtles had the cute distinction of being able to wear hats, should you choose to kit your wee friends out. Now, following many months of smaller updates to the game, it seems those hats are causing a problem. "[If] you are experiencing performance issues in Stardew Valley 1.6, remove all hats from pets," said creator Eric Barone <a href="https://x.com/ConcernedApe/status/1853889827294650577">in a xeet</a>. When asked the lore-accurate cause of this problem, he blamed: "a strange rash".

<!--more-->
</p><p>"There's rumors of a strange rash affecting pets' ears in Zuzu City," he said in response to a player <a href="https://x.com/ConcernedApe/status/1853890739413082199">jokingly asking for deep Valley lore</a>, "and we just want to make sure those ears can breathe for a few days."

</p><p>This isn't the first time in recent days the big man down on the farm has given lore-appropriate reasons for a bug. A couple of days ago it became clear that chickens were vanishing from some players coops. "Lore: There is a wild coyote on the farm day 1 rn," <a href="https://x.com/ConcernedApe/status/1853521395080368514">explained Barone</a>. This would surely horrify our own <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-am-going-to-become-a-battery-chicken-farmer-in-stardew-valley">battery chicken farmer</a> Alice B (RPS in peace). Thankfully, that bug has since <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/ogg/413150/announcements/detail/4445708897933590776?snr=2___">been fixed</a>, while the too-many-hats-on-animals issue is still being worked on. "We will address the problem as soon as possible," he said.

</p><p>Like all good games, Stardew Valley has had some funny bug fixes over the years, as can be seen in the many patch notes that accompany the regular updates. "Players now close their eyes when they go to bed," reads one note from <a href="https://www.stardewvalley.net/stardew-valley-1-4-update-full-changelog/">update 1.4</a>. "Trees no longer grow on top of placed furniture items," says another in <a href="https://www.stardewvalley.net/stardew-valley-1-5-4-patch-out-now-on-pc/">update 1.5.4</a>. "Spouses will no longer stand around looking at rug-type furniture items," states a change in <a href="https://www.stardewvalley.net/stardew-valley-1-5-1-patch-notes/">update 1.5.1</a>. This last one caused players to get stuck when the love of their life would freeze at the sight of a floor divider and stare at it like they suddenly knew their entire life was a cosy farm simulation for anxious people. 

</p><p>Meanwhile, the developer is still working on the follow-up life sim, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/haunted-chocolatier">Haunted Chocolatier</a>. Although splitting time between both that and Stardew updates is <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/concerned-ape-is-taking-a-break-from-haunted-chocolatier-to-work-on-stardew-valleys-next-update">unsurprisingly difficult</a>.  He's previously <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/stardew-valley-dev-posts-another-look-at-next-game-haunted-chocolatier-sparks-immediate-fan-theories">teased a scene</a> from the upcoming game and has said it will have <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/stardew-valley-devs-next-game-haunted-chocolatier-will-be-more-combat-focused">"a greater focus on combat"</a> than life on the farm.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You can now make video clips using Steam's built-in game recording feature, as an update rolls it out to all users]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/you-can-now-make-video-clips-using-steams-built-in-game-recording-feature-as-an-update-rolls-it-out-to-all-users</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/you-can-now-make-video-clips-using-steams-built-in-game-recording-feature-as-an-update-rolls-it-out-to-all-users.1028631/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/you-can-now-make-video-clips-using-steams-built-in-game-recording-feature-as-an-update-rolls-it-out-to-all-users<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/steam-game-recording-update-video-capture-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun / Critical Reflex</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Steam's built-in game recording feature has been usable in beta since the summer, but it has now been properly launched for every user, following a client update to Steam yesterday. It's basically another method of capturing funny ragdoll glitches and posting them on the "lol-games-are-dumb" channel of your friend's Discord. Or for posting that flukey knife throw in Call Of Duty to Twitter, as if you really meant to kill the man from across the map all along. Or saving a clip for your personal records, like the footage of that time you yeeted an innocent citizen off the 50-foot wall of a castle town in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dragons-dogma-2">Dragon's Dogma 2</a>. We all do that, right? Right?</p>
<!--more-->
<p>The Steam update is accompanied by <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/593110/view/4530150757095178610">a post explaining the ins and outs of the game recording feature</a>. It can run in the background, constantly capturing your games for up to 2 hours (much like similar program OBS, or Nvidia's Shadowplay). You can then clip things out and spread the love of jank with some clicky share buttons. It works on Steam Deck, and you can also set recording limits for each game individually, devoting a longer window of recording time to your run in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hades-2">Hades 2</a>, for instance, but asking it to never record that <em>other</em> game. You know, the one you shouldn't even have installed. What, you thought I wouldn't notice? <em>Disgusting</em>.</p>
<p>Our James <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steams-new-game-recording-beta-lets-you-instant-replay-all-those-elden-ring-deaths">tried out the recording tech during its beta</a> and quite liked Valve's method when compared to other video capture programs. It's easy to find your mp4 files, he says, and you can scrobble back through your footage instantly using the Steam overlay. If a game has special timeline features included, it'll show you icons above certain important moments, like boss fights and deaths.</p>
<p>"I employed this feature to replay my perishing at the hands of some knife-spamming <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-boss-locations">Elden Ring</a> bullshit merchant," said James, "quickly studying his moves in preparation for a more successful rematch. Neat!"</p>
<p>Meanwhile, I will be happy so long as it is less cantankerous than Nvidia's own capture method using GeForce Experience - the video grabber I had been using until it recently decided it doesn't want to record anything if there is even the slightest whiff of Spotify or YouTube running in the background. Awww, is da widdle video capchah softwah afwaid of an iddy bit of copywight infwingement? GROW UP, NVIDIA. Jesus.</p><p>Elsewhere in <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/593110/view/4472730495692571024">the client update post</a>, Valve note that this new client won't work for users still sporting Windows 7 or 8 (plus some old versions of Mac too). Alongside that there are some fixes to Big Picture mode, controller input, and the remote play feature. But that's all very boring. Go yeet a dude and clip it.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>