<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 10:22:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Nightreign's inevitable randomiser mod is here to spice up your runs with extra funky map scrambling]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-nightreigns-inevitable-randomiser-mod-is-here-to-spice-up-your-runs-with-extra-funky-map-scrambling</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-nightreigns-inevitable-randomiser-mod-is-here-to-spice-up-your-runs-with-extra-funky-map-scrambling.1242801/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>The future should bring even more complex randomness shenanigans</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>FromSoftware</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>It's time. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/elden-ring-nightreign">Elden Ring Nightreign</a>'s gotten a randomiser mod, just in case the base game isn't quite maxing out your unexpected chaos-per-run meter at this point, despite its <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-hero-for-our-times-elden-ring-nightreign-boss-becomes-unbeatable-by-refusing-to-show-up">revamped bosses</a>.</p>
<p>While FromSoft's roguelike-ish twist on the established souls formula already <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-nightreign-review">switches things up</a> in a manner that's a bit like a randomiser <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-best-mods">mod</a> makeover of one of the series' traditional entries, modder thefifthmatt has still found ways to tinker with it.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Enter their <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/eldenringnightreign/mods/277?tab=description">Nightreign randomiser and derandomiser</a>, which can be used to scramble map layouts beyond what's possible in the base game, which has a finite range of different map patterns it can chuck at you per Nightlord. It's a first foray into <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-nightreign-tips-tricks">Nightreign</a> randomising that the author says will serve as a "basis for more advanced randomisation" down the line.</p>
<p>"At a base level, the only difference you might notice using the randomizer is that Night Bosses are more varied for a given Nightlord," thefifthmatt wrote. "Under the hood, it's creating map patterns nearly from scratch and has a tremendous amount of freedom in its placements. In the future this can be extended to randomising enemies and bosses within maps and in-depth placement customisation."</p>
<p>The randomiser works by modifying files when you start up the game, and comes with three distinct randomness presets, "similar to base game", "balanced random", "extra random". They all basically do what they say on the tin, with "balanced" looking like the one you'll want to try first, while "extra" ditches some "placement restrictions which are normally helpful for balancing purposes" to make things tougher for uber-hardcore folks.</p>
<p>You can also pick "any custom combination of these options or other options like greatly increasing the frequency of double Night Bosses". Plus, thefifthmatt's chucked in extra options like increasing the chance of shifting earth being a factor or reverting <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-nightreign-already-has-its-first-patch-but-more-importantly-a-trailer-thatll-really-help-you-wake-up">patch 1.01's tweaks</a> to runes and revives so uber-sweaty solo players can wind back the clock to a time of enhanced hardness.</p>
<p>Not every aspect of the maps has been made randomness-eligible yet, but as the modder says, it's a start, and one that's compatible with <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/while-you-wait-for-an-official-update-elden-ring-nightreign-already-has-a-two-player-co-op-mod">Nightreign's Seamless Co-op mod</a> so you can dive in with however many buddies you like. If you fancy giving it a go, you'll need to grab <a href="https://me3.help/en/latest/">Mod Engine 3</a>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-nightreigns-inevitable-randomiser-mod-is-here-to-spice-up-your-runs-with-extra-funky-map-scrambling]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40K: Dawn of War – Definitive Edition gets an August release date, with a chunky discount for Anniversary owners]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/warhammer-40k-dawn-of-war-definitive-edition-gets-an-august-release-date-with-a-chunky-discount-for-anniversary-owners</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40k-dawn-of-war-%E2%80%93-definitive-edition-gets-an-august-release-date-with-a-chunky-discount-for-anniversary-owners.1242780/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Also people are mad about a Space Marine noise or something</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Relic Entertainment</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dawn-of-war-definitive-edition">Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War - Definitive Edition</a> is out August 14th, with a 30% discount off the $30 label price for owners of the Anniversary Edition. That discount applies to both <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3556750/Warhammer_40000_Dawn_of_War__Definitive_Edition/">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/warhammer_40000_dawn_of_war_definitive_edition">GOG</a>, and will be available for the "foreseeable future" (Fateweaver noises). Other currencies aren't listed.</p>
<!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War - Definitive Edition - Enhanced Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pY_JzB0WxSA?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War - Definitive Edition - Enhanced Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pY_JzB0WxSA?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/pY_JzB0WxSA?autoplay=1" title="Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War - Definitive Edition - Enhanced Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pY_JzB0WxSA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>Relic have confirmed that Warhammer 40,000: Dawn Of War: ReDawned: War For All: Come Get Some War Down Ya: One Dawntillion Wardollars Edition will be compatible with "over 20 years of lovingly crafted community mods". Warhammer 40,000: Dawn Of War: This Dawn, Its Warsenal Edition <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/relic-reveal-warhammer-40000-dawn-of-war-definitive-edition-with-full-dlc-and-mod-support">also comes bundled with all four expansions</a>.</p>
<p>All told, the full package contains four campaigns and nine factions, namely Orks, Eldar, Spicy Eldar, Space Marines, Spicy Space Marines, Imperial Guard, Tau, Necrons, and Sisters Of Battle. Tyranids were never released, but you have to remember this was 2004, and the idea of having a swarming species of hive-minded purple bug aliens in a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-strategy-games-on-pc">strategy game</a> was ridiculous.</p>
<p>In terms of multiplayer, Relic <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3556750/Warhammer_40000_Dawn_of_War__Definitive_Edition/">say they've</a> been "fixing some of the most egregious legacy bugs", though balance will remain the same. They also plan to hang around for a bit after launch to fix "high priority issues", and experiment with with changes to things like flying unit behaviour, unit pathing, and "quality-of-life settings such as grid key presets".</p>
<p>As for general improvements, Warhammer 40,000: Dawn Of Phwoar, That's A Lot Of War(hammer) edition features: image-based lighting, unit texture upscaling ("at least four times their original resolution), new world lighting, unit reflections, surface gloss, emissive lighting, and new shadows. There's also an integrated mod manager, an "improved camera", better draw distances, 4K support, and a better HUD for widescreen.</p>
<p>There is apparently a very minor controversy going on over the new trailer (above) replacing a Space Marine's scream. The word 'iconic' has been used. This does not bother me, because everything that has ever come out of a Space Marine's mouth is stupid, and the setting would be vastly improved if you replaced it all with goat noises. Although, as an Ork enjoyer, I realise I'm throwing stones from the glassiest of houses here.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/warhammer-40k-dawn-of-war-definitive-edition-gets-an-august-release-date-with-a-chunky-discount-for-anniversary-owners]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>