<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 08:19:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dune: Awakening hopes to spruce up its endgame in its next major update, coming next week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dune-awakening-hopes-to-spruce-up-its-endgame-in-its-next-major-update-coming-next-week</link>
            <guid>1419151</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dune-awakening">Dune: Awakening</a> has struggled a touch with its endgame pretty much since launch, but with the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-mmos-mmorpgs">MMO's</a> next big update, Chapter 3, is promising to offer a revamp that you (yes, you! The person playing Dune: Awakening right now! Maybe!) have been after. A release date was also offered up for the big update, alongside some specifics on just what this new endgame might look like.
</p>
<p>
Dune: Awakening Chapter 3 is apparently set to arrive as soon as next week, February 3rd, so you've not got all that long to wait. In a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1172710/view/541129246577262618">blog post</a> over on Steam, Funcom explained that the biggest bits of feedback regarding the endgame included the desire for more options, more rewarding ways to play, more things to do, more ways to progress player characters, and other bits, all of which will apparently be addressed in the update.
</p>
<p>
For starters, after you reach Plastanium (Tier 6), there'll be "deeper choices, shared goals, and more ways for players to continue growing." The new Specialization and Augmentation systems should allow for more in-depth progression, and there'll be 10 new locations to explore on the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/overland">Overland</a> Map, "including unique repeatable testing stations that feature challenging boss encounters with scaling difficulty and increasingly valuable loot."
</p>
<p>
Quite amusingly, you will also not have to pay taxes for your bases anymore! All because nobody liked it, which shows you that if we really wanted to, we could all stop paying our actual taxes too (Mr. Government I'm just goofing around, I promise). Those of you that haven't logged in in more than 28 days will also get a return package with some helpful tools too. Whether any of this is enough to bring people back or keep people happy, who knows! We'll find out soon enough in the Switter replies, I'm sure.

</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dune-awakening-hopes-to-spruce-up-its-endgame-in-its-next-major-update-coming-next-week]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>