<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 08:24:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Escape From Tarkov's Steam release comes with a snag for people who already own it]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/escape-from-tarkovs-steam-release-comes-with-a-snag-for-people-who-already-own-it</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/escape-from-tarkovs-steam-release-comes-with-a-snag-for-people-who-already-own-it.1300929/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main-content" data-component="article-header">
  

        <p>Hope you like owning multiple copies of the same game</p>

    </div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
It's that time of the year folks. The weather's getting colder, the days are getting shorter, and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/escape-from-tarkov">Escape From Tarkov</a> is getting Tweeted and Skeeted about again because of a controversial decision. This time, it's because the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/escape-from-tarkov-is-coming-to-steam-now-its-full-release-is-imminent-as-confirmed-by-a-picture-of-a-random-bloke-ironing">game is coming to Steam</a>, which in and of itself is a perfectly fine, perhaps even smart thing to do. The thing that's being called into question however, is the answer to a question on the Steam release's FAQ page about whether or not you'll have to buy it again.
</p>
<p>
"To play Escape from Tarkov through Steam, you must purchase any edition of the game on Steam," the <a href="https://www.escapefromtarkov.com/support/knowledge/542">FAQ page</a> explains. "You can then link your existing Battlestate Games account with an active copy of the game to your Steam profile. If the editions differ, it will automatically use the higher edition of the two when launching the game through Steam."
</p>
<p>
It then provides an example, noting that if you buy the standard edition on Steam, but your Battlestate Games account has the Unheard Edition, that's the one you'll be able to play on Steam. That's… something? I just can't see any particular reason you'd want to buy the game again aside from Steam Deck functionality, except the FAQ also notes that "Battlestate Games [have] no plans to support a version of the game for Steam Deck," so you can throw that reason out of the window. There will be Steam achievements if that's something you care about?
</p>
<p>
All of your character progress will carry over to the Steam version of the game as well, once you've linked your Battlestate Games account, and you'll still be playing on the same servers as people who bought the game on its official website.
</p><p>
I have no idea how easy it would be to guarantee every single person who owns the game a copy on Steam as well, but it still feels like an odd choice in general. In any case, after being in early access for close to a decade, the full version of the game launches in a couple months' time on November 15th.

</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/escape-from-tarkovs-steam-release-comes-with-a-snag-for-people-who-already-own-it]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Solve your own murder and recover your brain in Blanksword, a roguelike RPG with a demo out today]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/solve-your-own-murder-and-recover-your-brain-in-blanksword-a-roguelike-rpg-with-a-demo-out-today</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/solve-your-own-murder-and-recover-your-brain-in-blanksword-a-roguelike-rpg-with-a-demo-out-today.1300890/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>And there's a Kickstarter you can support too</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture data-src-full="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/blanksword.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" src="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/blanksword.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/blanksword.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 690px) and (min-resolution: 2x)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/blanksword.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 690px)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/blanksword.jpg?width=414&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-resolution: 2x)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Quinn K.</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
There are few occasions where a game tells me it's combining two genres that typically don't go together and it convinces me it's worth paying attention to, but <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rockpapershotgun.com/games/blanksword">Blanksword</a>, a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-roguelike-games-pc">roguelike</a> RPG, is quite different. In it, you are Blank, an angel stabbed in the head, brain destroyed, who somehow managed to survive such an ordeal - albeit without any memory of who you were. And now, you are on a quest through a series of islands governed by "Literally God" in order to figure out your mysterious past.
</p>
<p>
Blanksword has been in the works for a little while now, but a <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/283910083/blanksword">Kickstarter for the game just went live today</a>. Taking one look at the game tells you quite quickly that it's "one of those" kinds of indie RPGs. You like, like <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hylics">Hylics</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/felvidek">Felvidek</a>, or the blueprint for many of them, and one that just recently got a rerelease, OFF.
</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Blanksword - Official Demo Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UmOtTNW1mAo?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Blanksword - Official Demo Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UmOtTNW1mAo?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/UmOtTNW1mAo?autoplay=1" title="Blanksword - Official Demo Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UmOtTNW1mAo" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>
In fact OFF is quite an important frame of reference for Blanksword, as one of the game's directors, Quinn K., was the original translator for OFF. Not only that, but OFF creator Mortis Ghost is responsible for the game's lovely key art, and may even design an area of the game if the Kickstarter raises enough funds.
</p><p>
The mechanics sound quite interesting too. Combat, like many RPGs, is turn-based, and you pick up new moves as you go along, all of which vary from run to run. There's apparently "hundreds" of moves to pickup, alongside different bits of equipment and items.
</p>
<p>
And then there's that beautiful thing we call narrative design. With Blank not having a brain and all, you can pick up different Angelic Brain Parts, restoring certain abilities of his. One item might allow Blank to intimidate and heckle his enemies, another will give him the ability to tell if something smells bad. Others might let him understand more complex topics, or grant him the ability to haggle for better prices in certain shops. You keep these brain parts forever, but you can only use a few at a time to keep things balanced.
</p>
<p>
Best of all, alongside the Kickstarter the game has a demo out on Steam for you to try out. Truth be told, while I've had my eye on Blanksword for a good while, I somehow missed that it was a roguelike on top of an RPG. Playing the demo for myself, I soon figured this out, but the roguelike element blended really nicely with the RPG side of it. They aren't genres you often see combined, and in some ways could even be contradictory, but in my short time with it, I think something quite interesting is being brewed up. Here's hoping the full game pans out just as well.
</p>
<p>
Blanksword's "one of those" indie RPG vibes make it feel quite well positioned for a future fanatical following, a thing that's often both a blessing and a curse. That all remains to be seen of course, the game needs to get funded first.
</p>
<p>
A release date hasn't been set just yet, but the team behind it has conservatively estimated a 2027 release window. You can wishlist it, and try the demo out, on Steam <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3484670/Blanksword/">here</a>.

</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/solve-your-own-murder-and-recover-your-brain-in-blanksword-a-roguelike-rpg-with-a-demo-out-today]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>