<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 23:15:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PowerWash Simulator's final update will let you live out your fantasy of giving a London underground train a good scrub]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/powerwash-simulators-final-update-will-let-you-live-out-your-fantasy-of-giving-a-london-underground-train-a-good-scrub</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/powerwash-simulators-final-update-will-let-you-live-out-your-fantasy-of-giving-a-london-underground-train-a-good-scrub.1202103/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/powerwash-simulators-final-update-will-let-you-live-out-your-fantasy-of-giving-a-london-underground-train-a-good-scrub<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Anyone that's ever been on the London underground, no matter their background, can all likely agree on one thing: that place is nasty. I mean, it's all underground, where's the dirt meant to go? And it's not like anyone's putting any money into getting the place cleaned. But, if you've ever fantasized about hosing down a Northern Line train for yourself, one, that's possibly slightly odd, and two, you'll be able to do almost just that in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/powerwash-simulator">PowerWash Simulator's</a> next and last update.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
Developer <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/futurlab">FuturLab</a> shared an <a href="https://www.futurlab.co.uk/news/all-aboard-the-muckingham-files-6-has-arrived-for-powerwash-simulator-s-last-stop">update earlier today</a> saying that "the time has come to reach our final destination for PowerWash Simulator." Four years on since the game launch into early access in 2021, the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-non-violent-video-games">cleaning sim</a> will be getting an update titled The Muckingham Files 6 where you'll be able to clean up a legally safe version of a London underground train, as well as a nice looking park with a big gnome statue, amongst others.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="PowerWash Simulator | The Muckingham Files 6 Release Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ct1awWAUFig?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>PowerWash Simulator | The Muckingham Files 6 Release Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ct1awWAUFig?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ct1awWAUFig?autoplay=1" title="PowerWash Simulator | The Muckingham Files 6 Release Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ct1awWAUFig" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
The update is already available too, and it's completely free, so you'll just need to update your game when you're feeling the need to clean.
</p>
<p>
If you're wondering, "wait, last update? Why?", I would like to say that it's okay when things end sometimes, but also, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/powerwash-simulator-2-devs-tell-us-their-tips-for-real-life-house-cleaning">PowerWash Simulator 2 was announced a couple of months ago</a>, so that'll be why the first one is winding down. The sequel is set to arrive sometime in 2025, as long as all goes to plan, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/powerwash-simulator-2-has-split-screen-co-op-for-twice-the-wash-power">and it'll even have splitscreen co-op</a>. FuturLab are also self-publishing this one, so unfortunately you probably won't be able to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/powerwash-simulators-final-fantasy-vii-crossover-pack-is-out-now">give Cloud's sword a good polish this time around</a>.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reschedule those sailing lessons, as Mount & Blade 2: Bannerlord's War Sails DLC has been delayed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/reschedule-those-sailing-lessons-as-mount-blade-2-bannerlords-war-sails-dlc-has-been-delayed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/reschedule-those-sailing-lessons-as-mount-blade-2-bannerlords-war-sails-dlc-has-been-delayed.1202028/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/reschedule-those-sailing-lessons-as-mount-blade-2-bannerlords-war-sails-dlc-has-been-delayed<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>TaleWorlds Entertainment</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
To be a person that looks forward to video games and DLC for video games is to also be a person that must do so knowing that, at this point in time, they are likely to be delayed. It is what it is! Perhaps the dismantling of our current economic system and rebuilding one that doesn't put profits first would mean developers could take their time, but that'll probably also take a while. As a result, we're in a situation where, earlier today, developer TaleWorlds Entertainment announced that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/mount-blade-ii-bannerlord">Mount &amp; Blade 2: Bannerlord's</a> first bit of DLC, War Sails, has been delayed.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
"After taking a hard look at where things stand, it became clear we won’t be ready by the originally planned release date of June 17th," TaleWorlds explained in a <a href="https://www.taleworlds.com/en/News/574">post</a> on their website. Now, the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-strategy-games-on-pc">strategy</a> game is currently slated for a slightly less specific fall/ autumn release window later this year
</p>
<p>
Further explaining the delay TaleWorlds wrote that they came to this decision because they "need more time to reach the level of quality you rightfully expect. The extra development period will give us more time to apply additional polish, and continue making progress on the improvements to the base game that are already in motion." A new release date should be on the way in "upcoming weeks" at least.
</p>
<p>
War Sails, if you could tell by the name, is all about <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mount-blade-2-bannerlords-first-bit-of-dlc-is-all-about-taking-the-lads-out-on-a-not-so-nice-boat-trip">going out on a lovely little sailing trip</a>. Well, maybe not lovely, it's more about doing trade or fighting enemies, but you get what I mean. You'll be able to board enemy ships while out on the open sea, and a Viking-inspired faction is being introduced with this expansion too. All of it sounds pretty good, you just won't be playing it next month.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>