<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 15:22:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Symphonia might scratch your Silksong itch, even though it's not a metroidvania]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/symphonia-might-scratch-your-silksong-itch-even-though-its-not-a-metroidvania</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/symphonia-might-scratch-your-silksong-itch-even-though-its-not-a-metroidvania.1057725/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/symphonia-might-scratch-your-silksong-itch-even-though-its-not-a-metroidvania<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
  

        <p>A shadowy and sonorous 2D platformer - try the demo, eh</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_J4P7aQC.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Headup / Beep Japan</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
In "non-violent and poetic" 2D platformer Symphonia, you're an extremely fancy violinist exploring a realm of musical machines, where gas lanterns kindle fitfully as you approach, crotchets adorn vast cogwheels, and reams of what I really hope isn't actual catgut feed through titanic pegboxes overhead. Sampling the demo, I was immediately enflamed by the orchestral score and placed in a mood of white-gloved sophistication only slightly spoiled by the familiarity of the underlying platform moveset, and by my repeatedly falling into pits. <!--more-->
</p>
<p>
"Superbesque!" I breathed, watching myself casually tear off a violin solo to magic open a door. "Magnifissimos!" I sang, watching myself artfully bounce my violin bow off the floor and catch it to double-jump. "Bravanche!" I honked, watching myself evaporate against some spikes. While it's not a metroidvania, the cavernous, lamplit, whirring set-dressing puts me strongly in mind of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hollow-knight">Hollow Knight</a> and the eternally-forthcoming <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hollow-knight-silksong-everything-we-know">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a>. Here's a trailer:
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Symphonia | Launch Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/T5JOJiEVnFA?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Symphonia | Launch Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/T5JOJiEVnFA?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/T5JOJiEVnFA?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T5JOJiEVnFA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
And here's some backstory: the aforementioned very fancy violinist is Philemon, who must gather the members of an orchestra and restore vitalising music to a world that has fallen into deathly silence. The levels and backdrops are a phantasmagoric, almost Cubist portrayal of instruments collapsed together into halls and shafts - I am keen to see more of them. Hollow Knight aside, it all reminds me just a little of Amnesia: A Machine For Pigs, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/blasphemous">Blasphemous</a> and Oddworld, which probably aren't the parallels developers Sunny Peak are going for. I mean, I assume there isn't an abbatoir level, but perhaps that's where they get all the catgut. </p>
<p>"Each area in Symphonia has its own distinct feel and characters, and each room is hand-crafted," <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1865960/Symphonia/">the Steam page adds</a>. "Meet prodigious musicians and try to convince them to join the orchestra."
</p>
<p>
And then there's the score, a bespoke piece of classical romance music, written by composer Olivier Esman and his partners Alexandre Bucas-Français and Lou Corroyer. As regards the demo, at least, it's gently synched to your progress, with certain actions triggering the next movement. You'll also perform full-arsed concerts at intervals that are dedicated to a particular section of the orchestra - Strings, Brass and Woodwinds. I deduce from this that the game has a three-act structure.
</p>
<p>
Symphonia is out... now! And feels like a good festive pick if your idea of festive is a soothing melange of velvet, mahogany and candlelight. And spike pits. Here's some of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZJYN1d3f2dc">Disney's Fantasia</a> to wash it all down.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>