<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 19:45:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals unbans Steam Deck and Mac players wrongly caught up in cheater purge]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/marvel-rivals-unbans-steam-deck-and-mac-players-wrongly-caught-up-in-cheater-purge</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-unbans-steam-deck-and-mac-players-wrongly-caught-up-in-cheater-purge.1073442/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/marvel-rivals-unbans-steam-deck-and-mac-players-wrongly-caught-up-in-cheater-purge<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
  

        <p>NetEase "sincerely apologize" for flagging compatibility layers as naughty business</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/marvel-rivals-jeff-the-land-shark.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun/NetEase Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-steam-deck-games">Steam Deck</a>, Mac, and other Linux-based enjoyers of superhero shooter hit <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/marvel-rivals">Marvel Rivals</a> can once again play without fear of being pulped under an unlawfully swung banhammer. Developers NetEase had recently doled out <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/SteamDeck/comments/1hs39mf/can_proton_cause_you_to_get_flagged_for_cheating/">bans of up to 100 years</a> to players they suspected of cheating, but in their eagerness, failed to distinguish between legitimate compatibility layers – the software that non-Windows operating systems, like the Steam Deck’s SteamOS, use to run native Windows games – and actual hacks. Per <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/marvel-rivals-dev-apologizes-for-mistakenly-banning-players-for-using-cheats">IGN</a>, NetEase have now apologised to the affected players, and lifted the bans.</p>
<p>"We sincerely apologize for this situation and want to assure you that we do not and will not ban players who are playing fairly and without cheating," NetEase’s <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1193841000108531764/1201833362399170560/1324661682936746075">Discord</a> statement reads, perhaps not with the kind of wording I’d use if I’d just banned players who are playing fairly and without cheating. It continues: "We have identified the specific reasons behind these false bans and have compiled a list of affected players. We have lifted these bans and want to express our heartfelt apologies for the inconvenience this has caused."</p>
<p>Proof, there, that justice can be served by apologetic executives just as effectively as vigilante supersoldiers and/or sentient trees. I haven’t played Marvel Rivals – <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/marvel-rivals-review">Ed’s review</a> would have put me off even I hadn’t already had my fill of hero shooters – but I do note that Valve have rated it <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2767030/Marvel_Rivals/">Playable for the Steam Deck</a>, so the number of falsely condemned SteamOS players could have been substantial from that alone.</p>
<p>Proton, the specific compatibility layer that SteamOS integrates, does have some past form for triggering certain anti-cheat systems, though in the Deck’s early days this was more down to a simple lack of software compatibility rather than genuine concerns over Proton’s potential dodginess. Still, the prospect of exposing games to the untameable, open-source Linux still spooks some developers. Fortnite has <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fortnite-wont-get-steam-deck-support-epic-ceo-blames-cheaters">never worked on SteamOS</a>, for one, and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/apex-legends">Apex Legends</a> recently <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/respawn-have-killed-apex-legends-steam-deck-support-in-the-name-of-anti-cheat">cut support</a> over potential cheating concerns.</p>
<p>Fair play to NetEase for refraining from such a heavy handed approach, even if you <a href="https://thedirect.com/article/marvel-rivals-winnie-the-pooh-banned">still can't mention Winnie the Pooh</a> in its chat.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>