<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 06:51:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dante's epic poem La Divina Commedia is getting turned into a videogame again]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dantes-epic-poem-la-divina-commedia-is-getting-turned-into-a-videogame-again</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dantes-epic-poem-la-divina-commedia-is-getting-turned-into-a-videogame-again.1275078/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>EA and Visceral aren't involved</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Jyamma Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/enotria-the-last-song">Enotria: The Last Song</a> developers Jyamma Games are making a new action-RPG inspired by and named after Dante Alighieri’s 14th century epic poem La Divina Commedia, aka the Divine Comedy.</p>
<p>Like the poem, it sees you descending through the circles of Hell, each the geological manifestation of a particular Sin. Unlike the poem, it features a set of combat classes, a choice of protagonist genders, a narrative alignment system, procedurally generated extraction dungeons, and customisable weapons and armour. As the poet himself might say: in the middle of the journey of our life I came to myself within a dark wood where I had to grind for crafting materials. </p><!--more-->
<p>The games industry has not been mega gentle with poor old Dante, whose monumental work helped establish the Tuscan language and influenced a brace of English writers, from Blake to Beckett. The best-known video game adaptation is probably still Visceral’s cheeseball 2010 action-adventure Dante’s Inferno, which is often more interested in aping God Of War. A cynical man or snob (hello!) might look at the below, hacky-slashy trailer for Jyamma’s adaptation and consider it to be another act of wanton literary desecration. Terza rima isn’t supposed to be a three-hit combo, you blistering philistines!</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="La Divina Commedia - Reveal Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vTlBUqC2Cto?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>La Divina Commedia - Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vTlBUqC2Cto?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/vTlBUqC2Cto?autoplay=1" title="La Divina Commedia - Reveal Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vTlBUqC2Cto" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>Still, this isn't quite another exercise in crafting boobwalls for the circle of Lust or punching organs out of bodies. Enotria was <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/%E2%80%9Dhttps://www.rockpapershotgun.com/enotria-the-last-song-review%E2%80%9D">pretty metaphysical for a Soulslike</a>, building a universe and combat system around the practice of stagecraft, and Jyamma’s take on the La Divina Commedia is similarly dreamy - it turns Dante’s poem into a kind of overarching mythology.</p><p>“In this new adventure, the studio presents an epic journey set in a world where The Divine Comedy has supplanted the old faith, bringing about a golden age of righteousness among humanity,” explains <a href="https://www.gamespress.com/en-GB/JYAMMA-GAMES-ANNOUNCES-LA-DIVINA-COMMEDIA-AN-EPIC-DARK-FANTASY-ACTION-">a press release</a>. “When dark forces subvert the promises of the poem, order collapses and the world is thrust into chaos. The player will take on the role of a warrior-poet trapped in the infernal depths, called to descend through the circles of Hell, face increasingly powerful demons, and redeem a sinful past.”</p>
<p>Sounds quite involved. Still, I’m not sure where the procgen extraction dungeons fit in, exactly. The idea of mining hell for loot and progression materials is the kind of videogame conceit I’d love to lay before an actual 14th century theologian. I'm sure the humour of the situation would be well worth the inconvenience of being burned at the stake. Anyway, there’s no release date yet for La Divina Commedia. The poem took about 12 years to write – hopefully, Jyamma will turn their version around a little sooner.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Check out our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/events/gamescom-2025">Gamescom 2025</a> event hub for all the PC game announcements and preview coverage from Cologne.</em></p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dantes-epic-poem-la-divina-commedia-is-getting-turned-into-a-videogame-again]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Science reveal Black Myth: Zhong Kui, a new action-RPG that aims to catch Wukong players "off guard"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/game-science-reveal-black-myth-zhong-kui-a-new-action-rpg-that-aims-to-catch-wukong-players-off-guard</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/game-science-reveal-black-myth-zhong-kui-a-new-action-rpg-that-aims-to-catch-wukong-players-off-guard.1275048/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>But is currently "little more than an empty folder"</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun / Game Science</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/black-myth-wukong-walkthrough">Black Myth: Wukong</a> developers Game Science have revealed Black Myth: Zhong Kui, another single-player action-<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> steeped in Chinese mythology. It casts you as a ghost-hunting god who wanders between hell and Earth. Here's a CG short from <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gamescom-opening-night-live-2025-livestream-watch-all-todays-announcements-here">Gamescom's Open Night Live 2025</a>, which shows the fearsomely bearded Zhong Kui himself riding an extravagantly sized tiger. </p><!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Game Science's New Title | Black Myth: Zhong Kui - Teaser Trailer (English Dub)" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NZ7VLcO06Ak?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Game Science's New Title | Black Myth: Zhong Kui - Teaser Trailer (English Dub)</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NZ7VLcO06Ak?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/NZ7VLcO06Ak?autoplay=1" title="Game Science's New Title | Black Myth: Zhong Kui - Teaser Trailer (English Dub)">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NZ7VLcO06Ak" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>In <a href="https://www.gamesci.cn/zhongkui">a Q&amp;A on the official site</a>, the developers call the game a "tentative first step - to build more distinct game experiences, to challenge ourselves with bolder features, and to bring fresh ideas to our world and narrative design". They want Wukong players to feel "right at home" while "catching them off guard in the best way". That said, for now the new game remains "little more than an empty folder", with no release date and little sense in the CG trailer of how Zhong Kui fights, compared to Wukong. I'm guessing that tiger is a useful ally, though.</p>
<p>We quite liked the original Black Myth, with bygone reviews editor Ed Thorn (RPS in peace) <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/black-myth-wukong-is-a-pleasantly-surprising-soulslike-even-if-its-given-me-an-enemy-for-life">calling it</a> "a refreshing adventure after <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-boss-locations">Elden Ring</a>'s knotty DLC". We were less keen on <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/black-myth-wukongs-record-setting-launch-popularity-soured-by-co-publisher-request-to-avoid-feminist-propaganda-in-streams">the mildly draconian PR messages</a> to certain streamers, cautioning them to avoid "feminist propaganda", "politics" and discussion of the Chinese games industry.</p><p>These gamergatory memos followed <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-black-myth-wukong-developers-history-of-sexism-is-complicating-its-journey-to-the-west">a lengthy report from IGN</a> about alleged workplace sexism at Game Science. The devs refused to say anything to Ed about this when he asked at a preview event. If we're invited to preview Zhong Kui, we'll give it another shot.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Check out our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/events/gamescom-2025">Gamescom 2025</a> event hub for all the PC game announcements and preview coverage from Cologne.</em></p>

        </div>
      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/game-science-reveal-black-myth-zhong-kui-a-new-action-rpg-that-aims-to-catch-wukong-players-off-guard]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>