<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 17:21:30 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Come say hello to Mark Warren, RPS's new senior staff writer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/come-say-hello-to-mark-warren-rpss-new-senior-staff-writer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/come-say-hello-to-mark-warren-rpss-new-senior-staff-writer.1209303/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/come-say-hello-to-mark-warren-rpss-new-senior-staff-writer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>The treehouse demands fresh meat</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>RPS</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>You might have seen a new name around the homepage this past week: Mark Warren. It might also be that you recognise the name if you're a reader of RPS sibling site VG247, where Mark has already been plying his trade for several years. Well, we've adopted Mark here at RPS, as one might adopt a puppy if the puppy really liked mods, RPGs and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/helldivers-2">Helldivers 2</a>. Come say hello in the comments.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Mark joined VG247 back in 2023, and since then he's written news, features and reviews that would have all sat comfortably on our own pages. He's <a href="https://www.vg247.com/the-sims-4-25-anniversary-house-build-existential-dread">had a breakdown about his lack of interior design skills in The Sims</a>, braved <a href="https://www.vg247.com/fallout-tv-show-fallout-community-feature">talking to the Fallout community</a>, interviewed developers behind one of <a href="https://www.vg247.com/summer-eternal-studio-ex-disco-elysium-expectations-interview">the half-dozen Disco Elysium spiritual successors</a>, and <a href="https://www.vg247.com/mlb-the-show-24-extra-seinfeld-series-we-never-knew-we-needed">built a baseball team made entirely of George Costanzas</a>. He's also, yeah, written a lot about Helldivers 2, including <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2s-battle-for-super-earth-makes-chinese-news-following-the-successful-and-slightly-review-bomby-defense-of-equality-on-sea">three</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2-follows-up-the-battle-for-super-earth-automaton-fighting-because-bots-waiting-in-big-invasion-queue">posts</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2s-next-gear-drop-includes-judge-dredd-style-armour-just-in-case-you-want-to-be-the-law">for us</a> this week alone, so you know he's not afraid to follow through on his passions.
</p>
<p>It's been an odd year for RPS, with more departures than arrivals. We continue to work to hire a new reviews editor, too. In the meantime, I'm glad that Mark is bringing his expertise to the site. Please give him a warm welcome below.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Does the bird warrior of Elden Ring Nightreign have a human face beneath his beak? I'm glad you asked]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/does-the-bird-warrior-of-elden-ring-nightreign-have-a-human-face-beneath-his-beak-im-glad-you-asked</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/does-the-bird-warrior-of-elden-ring-nightreign-have-a-human-face-beneath-his-beak-im-glad-you-asked.1209276/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/does-the-bird-warrior-of-elden-ring-nightreign-have-a-human-face-beneath-his-beak-im-glad-you-asked<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>FromSoftware</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Does <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/elden-ring-nightreign">Elden Ring Nightreign</a>'s bird-bodied Guardian have a human face hidden somewhere on his feathery body? It's a question people have been thinking about, and by "people" I mean a small subset of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-boss-locations">Elden Ring</a> obsessives who like to watch the game being picked apart 3D model by 3D model.</p>
<p>Thanks to a prolific Souls modder/dataminer, I can provide you with an answer. In their latest video, Zullie The Witch - who's previously <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-727">solved various Souls mysteries</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/people-are-modding-armored-cores-into-elden-ring-and-now-i-want-a-souls-game-where-you-play-a-giant">modded an Armored Core</a> into Elden Ring - has unmasked <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-nightreign-tips-tricks">Nightreign</a>'s crop of nightfarers like they're Scooby-Doo villians. Most of their faces look how you'd expect, but there are a couple of noteworthy cases that I think it's worth you knowing about.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The hidden faces of Nightreign" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aaiC0doOclE?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The hidden faces of Nightreign</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aaiC0doOclE?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/aaiC0doOclE?autoplay=1" title="The hidden faces of Nightreign">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aaiC0doOclE" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>First of all, it's worth noting that due to the switch from custom characters to eight established archetypes, Nightreign's playable characters don't use facedata - by my understanding, this the character creator values that spit out a specfic face - in the same way Elden Ring did, though Zullie does note: "there is technically facedata in Nightreign, but it seems to be just a copy of the existing data from Elden Ring."</p>
<p>With that established, I'm gonna jump to the bit of the video that discusses the Guardian, the game's halberd-wielding Pinionfolk captain. Some folks had been wondering if his birdy visage might have mean FromSoft having to hide a human face somewhere on his model, presumably so he'd conform with the rest of the playable models. Thankfully for all of our dreams, Zullie has checked under the backs of their knees for stray mouths, and says they've not found a weird human face hiding anywhere on the Guardian.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the only nightfarer they couldn't find any kind of proper face for (of the human or birdy variety) was Wylder. Removing the armour from each of his skins has just revealed a featureless "silhoutte", which Zullie notes leaves his appearance a bit of mystery, though folks have inferred that he likely looks similar to the Dutchess. Cue some commenters joking that of course the character they've dubbed <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Nightreign/comments/1l4dhbq/john_nightreign/">John Nightreign</a>, similarly to <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/helldivers-2">Helldivers 2</a> players making a meme out of the name <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Helldivers/comments/1b3pmx5/who_is_john_helldiver/">John Helldiver</a> referring to some legendary everyman figure, is faceless.</p>
<p>One asserted that this confirms that "Wylder is the true John from all Fromsoft games", which is certainly a theory.</p>
<p>If you've not given Nightreign a go yet, make sure to check out <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-nightreign-review">Nic's review of it</a> and the stuff FromSoft <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-nightreign-now-confirmed-to-be-getting-those-duo-expeditions-plus-enhanced-fights-against-its-current-nightlord-crop">recently confirmed</a> is coming to it down the road.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>