<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 17:07:30 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sandfall have no plans for more Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 just yet, but "chances are good" anyway]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sandfall-have-no-plans-for-more-clair-obscur-expedition-33-just-yet-but-chances-are-good-anyway</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sandfall-have-no-plans-for-more-clair-obscur-expedition-33-just-yet-but-chances-are-good-anyway.1180476/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sandfall-have-no-plans-for-more-clair-obscur-expedition-33-just-yet-but-chances-are-good-anyway<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"We're honestly still just trying to process everything that's happening."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Kepler Interactive</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
It seems like <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/clair-obscur-expedition-33">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a> is doing quite alright for itself, 'ey? The <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">J'RPG</a> was awarded Rock Paper Shotgun's coveted Bestest Bests badge by our own Nic in his <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-review">review</a>, and by all accounts it's been received well by most everyone else too. Not that sales matter much in terms of a game's quality, but the fact that it's done well there as well at minimum means the lights are staying on at <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/sandfall-interactive">Sandfall Interactive</a>. In fact it seems things are going better than just keeping the lights on, as it sounds like the developer is considering more of it, whatever that might be.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
Earlier this week, screenshots of a conversation with the game's lead writer Jennifer Svedberg-Yen on Instagram were shared on <a href="https://www.neogaf.com/threads/chances-for-clair-obscure-expedition-33-dlc-are-good.1683512/">NeoGAF</a>, where she was asked if there's plans for any Clair Obscur DLC (cheers, <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/clair-obscur-expedition-33-dlc-has-a-good-chance-of-happening-according-to-games-lead-writer/">Vice</a>). Unsurprisingly, Svedberg-Yen said that as of now, there's "nothing concrete that I can say at the moment, we're honestly still just trying to process everything that's happening. It's been a lot to take in!"
</p>
<p>
The interesting bit followed that though, as Svedberg-Yen continued, "we've always said if there is a strong desire from the players that we would love to do something more, and based on the responses so far, I'd say chances are good." Now, that's obviously not a confirmation of any kind. It's not even the writer saying that there'll be DLC necessarily, just that there's hopes to do more, so it's still probably best to temper your expectations.
</p>
<p>
Still, it's nice to see an underdog do so well, especially in such a busy week for RPGs. Personally I'd love to see some DLC where they pop across the border to Germany, if only to have someone put a JRPG there.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>