<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 15:36:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sharkmob launch public playtest for Exoborne, their open world shoot-O-mecha-looter]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sharkmob-launch-public-playtest-for-exoborne-their-open-world-shoot-o-mecha-looter</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sharkmob-launch-public-playtest-for-exoborne-their-open-world-shoot-o-mecha-looter.1106790/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sharkmob-launch-public-playtest-for-exoborne-their-open-world-shoot-o-mecha-looter<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>It's running till 17th Feb</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ss_df5e39c9d847cd4a8a15066d470071fd072ab575.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Sharkmob AB</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Sharkmob have punched the green light, cracked open the hangar doors and launched a public playtest for their windblown open world extraction shooter <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/exoborne">Exoborne</a>, which I would gingerly summarise as Anthem meets <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/just-cause">Just Cause</a> with a touch of PUBG. From today till 17th February at 1pm GMT, 2pm CET, or 5am PST, you'll be able to get your fill of mech-o-looting via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2705130/Exoborne/">Steam</a>. Here's a trailer's worth of wiggly whooshes, big bangs and exowotsits to celebrate. Mmm, exowotsits. They used to be 25p a bag in the 1990s.
</p><!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Exoborne Playtest | Live Now" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GXp6CC66gVo?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Exoborne Playtest | Live Now</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GXp6CC66gVo?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/GXp6CC66gVo?autoplay=1" title="Exoborne Playtest | Live Now">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GXp6CC66gVo" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>

<p>
If references to antique British crisp brands only leave you confused about what Exoborne actually is, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sharkmob-announce-exoborne-an-open-world-pvpve-shooter-featuring-exo-rigs-and-tornadoes">may I recommend reading my first article about the game from 2023</a>. The narrative premise is that a notional "save the environment" project called Project Rebirth has fucked the world instead, producing a landscape of renegade whirlwinds, broken cities, big sci-fi towers and lashings of loot. 
</p>
<p>
You are a "Reborn" adventurer in an exosuit with high-jumping and grappling capabilities, plus a parachute. Your job is to get in, finish quests and extract with some rad valuables before the match timer runs out, while fighting other players and NPCs. The game is built for groups of three, with a choice of exo-rigs akin to RPG classes, and there's a home hub area where you can shoot the breeze with various story characters. Hah, "shoot the breeze"! I guess that also applies to tangling with inclement weather phenomena as well: some of the game's better items are to be found inside them.
</p>
<p>
I'm not sure about Exoborne so far. The idea of hook-chuting through hurricanes while gunning down robot-shouldered hooligans certainly has its charms. On the other hand, this all feels very "we smooshed a bunch of genres together in the hope of alchemising something new", and the art direction is a bit dreary. There's no release date yet - let us know if you have thoughts about the beta.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring: Nightreign release date knocks back an Estus and takes a swing at May 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-nightreign-release-date-knocks-back-an-estus-and-takes-a-swing-at-may-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-nightreign-release-date-knocks-back-an-estus-and-takes-a-swing-at-may-2025.1106742/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-nightreign-release-date-knocks-back-an-estus-and-takes-a-swing-at-may-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>There's a beta this weekend, but only on disgusting consoles</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/elden-ring-nightreign-mage.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Bandai Namco</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/elden-ring-nightreign">Elden Ring Nightreign</a> will release 30th May 2025 on Steam, developers FromSoftware and publishers Bandai Namco have announced. In a few short months, you and up to two friends will be called upon to rush a few bosses on a large, shrinking map set in the same universe as the 2022 open worlder. Is it the <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-boss-locations">Elden Ring</a> sequel <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-2-isnt-in-development-right-now-but-from-software-do-have-several-other-games-in-the-works">many would like</a>? No. Is it going to kindle similar feelings of frustration, despair and sporadic religious ecstasy? The omens seem good.
</p><!--more-->
<p>

A recap in case you missed <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/from-software-reveal-elden-ring-nightreign-a-three-player-co-op-spin-off">the game's announcement last year</a>: each round of Nightreign challenges you to survive three in-game days, touring the environment in search of randomised elements and events so as to level up and prepare yourself for a boss fight at sunset. Make it to day three and you'll face one of eight Nightlords, whose ranks include characters from previous From Software games. As for player characters, you don't create your own as in vanilla Elden Ring. Instead, you'll pick from upgradeable Nightfarer prefabs such as the omnipurpose Wylder, the tanky Guardian and the agile and devious Duchess.
</p>
<p>
While the game is geared for co-op, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-nightreign-will-support-singleplayer-but-it-might-not-reward-it">you have the option of playing offline with bot pals</a>, and you can queue for matches either alone, in pairs or in trios. So it doesn't quite depend on you having a banger human team of seasoned Tarnished ready to go, though I imagine that'll help. There's a beta test coming this weekend, though it's only on console. It runs from Friday 14th February to Monday 17th February as a series of three hour long sessions, and gives you access to four of eight Nightfarer characters.
</p>
<p>
We may or may not have somebody checking out the console beta. I won't name the individual in question because I do not wish to publicly associate them with one of those awful Eggsbogs or StayPlaytions and Tarnish their career forever. Did you know people don't even play games on Eggsbogs and StayPlaytions while sitting at desks? No, they play them while lolling on the sofa, like disgraceful Golden Retrievers. Fie!
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alan Wake 2 is finally profitable and earning royalties for Remedy]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/alan-wake-2-is-finally-profitable-and-earning-royalties-for-remedy</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/alan-wake-2-is-finally-profitable-and-earning-royalties-for-remedy.1106709/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/alan-wake-2-is-finally-profitable-and-earning-royalties-for-remedy<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>The dark numbers have un-darkened, darkishly</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Alan-Wake-2-alan-writers-room.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun/Epic Games Publishing</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Well, this is nice. Remedy's exceptionally good <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-horror-games">horror</a> game <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/alan-wake-2">Alan Wake 2</a> is finally making royalties for the studio for the first time since its release in late 2023, after shifting over 2 million copies. The jubilant news comes from <a href="https://investors.remedygames.com/">Remedy latest financial report</a>, as spotted <a href="https://www.vg247.com/alan-wake-2-finally-earning-royalties-for-remedy">by VG247</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/alan-wake-2-still-hasnt-quite-made-its-money-back-according-to-remedys-latest-financials">As of September last year</a>, the musical-with-guns had "recouped most of its development and marketing expenses", but still wasn't quite in the green. Since then, they've released both <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/alan-wake-2s-the-lake-house-is-a-dark-brilliant-parable-on-the-devaluation-of-art-and-artists">The Lake House expansion</a> and physical console editions, which appear to have done the trick. "October saw particularly high activity around Alan Wake 2," says the report.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Alan Wake 2 - Gameplay Reveal Trailer | PS5 Games" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/q0vNoRhuV_I?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Alan Wake 2 - Gameplay Reveal Trailer | PS5 Games</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/q0vNoRhuV_I?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/q0vNoRhuV_I?autoplay=1" title="Alan Wake 2 - Gameplay Reveal Trailer | PS5 Games">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=q0vNoRhuV_I" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>While I can't definitely say that my own personal word of mouth campaign has helped matters, I <em>did</em> use my best carving knife to write 'Play Alan Wake 2' into all those mangoes I chucked at people in Cardiff town centre, so who's to say who the <em>real</em> Sam Lake is here?</p>
<p>Elsewhere in the report, Remedy provided updates on their projects in progress, namely <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/fbc-firebreak">FBC: Firebreak</a>, "Action RPG" <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/control-2">Control 2</a>, and their <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/remedy-are-remaking-max-payne-1-2">Max Payne 1 &amp; 2 remasters</a>. In short: yep, still cooking. Firebreak should be out this year, and Control 2 is just gearing up to enter full production. There was <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/annapurna-interactives-entire-staff-resign-following-dispute-with-owner">some walkout chaos</a> at Annapurna Interactive last year, but this doesn't seem to have slowed down the deal made <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/remedy-partner-with-annapurna-to-co-finance-control-2-and-explore-control-and-alan-wake-tv-and-film-adaptations">between them and Remedy</a>.</p>
<p>Max is "making steady progress in full production", too. Love a bit of Max. "It's the best blend of goofy and ridiculous," celebrated Alice Bell (RPS in peace) for the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/happy-birthday-to-the-original-bullet-time-superstar-max-payne">original's 20th birthday</a>. "The writing also contains lines like, "The sun set with practiced bravado", which is absolutely incredible. And you can listen in to the idle bitching of your enemies before you round the corner and they notice you, at which point someone will yell, "IT'S PAYNE!" just before you drop into slow motion and watch bullets drift gently past you."</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>