<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 10:58:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Paradox take "first step" in response to Bloodlines 2's DLC clan backlash with PlayStation refunds, promise more info next week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/paradox-take-first-step-in-response-to-bloodlines-2s-dlc-clan-backlash-with-playstation-refunds-promise-more-info-next-week</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/paradox-take-first-step-in-response-to-bloodlines-2s-dlc-clan-backlash-with-playstation-refunds-promise-more-info-next-week.1291251/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"Making significant changes like this involves many moving parts, and we want to make sure that we get it right"</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Paradox Interactive</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2">Vampire: The Masquerade - Bloodlines 2</a> publisher Paradox have gotten the ball rolling on the "adjustments" they promised in response to the controversy over the game's day-one paid DLC vampire clans.</p>
<p>As we've covered previously, the Toreador and Lasombra clans were <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-sticks-two-bloodsucker-clans-including-the-sexy-one-behind-paid-day-one-dlc">originally revealed</a> to be locked behind a purchase of either Bloodines' £18.69/€21.99/$21.99 Shadows and Silk DLC pack, or the £74.99/€89.99/$89.99 premium edition that said DLC comes bundled with. Cue understandable unhappiness, and Paradox <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/paradox-are-making-adjustments-to-bloodlines-2s-day-one-vampire-clan-dlc-plans-following-backlash">swiftly moving to declare they'd rejig some stuff before launch</a>.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>The first domino's now fallen, and it's refunds for PlayStation pre-orderers. "Anyone who pre-ordered the premium edition through the PlayStation Store will be contacted and refunded starting Monday, September 8th," World of Darkness community developer DebbieElla announced on the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/554580174864384001/1115895131573342279/1413574860512170158">Bloodlines 2 Discord</a>. "You will be able to pre-order your premium edition copy again later, before the release on October 21st."</p>
<p>The good news for us PC folks is that Paradox made clear this is just an "intentional first step" in their planned tweaks following the backlash. "We are working hard on the adjustments that we promised, and we will be able to tell you all the details on September 17th," DebbieElla wrote. "Making significant changes like this involves many moving parts, and we want to make sure that we get it right with this change."</p><p>So, a little longer to wait for info as to whether there'll be changes to the DLC/editions and their pricing on PC. However, pulling existing pre-orders and then requesting folks make them again points towards a premium edition price drop being at least one of the measures Paradox are taking. Any change might make paying extra for the two clans a bit more palatable, but unless the premium edition's brought down to match the price of the base game, dishing the DLC clans out at no extra cost, odds are the sour taste won't come close to being washed away.</p>
<p>Paradox and Bloodlines developers The Chinese Room previously defended charging for Toreador and Lasombra vamps when our James <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-chinese-room-defend-bloodlines-2s-paywalled-vampire-clans-we-have-been-expanding-it-from-where-we-originally-planned-to-land-it">asked them about the decision at Gamescom</a>, citing the game's changing scope.</p>
<p>"We have been expanding it from where we originally planned to land it, I think, constantly, and Paradox have been really good when we go, or when the clients go, or when Paradox go: 'We should add a bit more here. Let's push the date back.' As you know, the date has pushed back, but that has been to fatten it out into something that we feel does land where the players want it," Bloodlines 2 narrative director Ian Thomas said.</p>
<p>We'll keep you in the loop as to what Paradox announce on the 17th, and keep on hoping that Bloodlines 2 will stop all this Sideshow Bob rake-stepping as it tries to position itself as a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bloodlines-2-is-more-spiritual-successor-than-sequel-to-a-a-competently-good-game-by-2004-standards-say-paradox">"spiritual successor" to Bloodlines</a>.</p>

        </div>
      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/paradox-take-first-step-in-response-to-bloodlines-2s-dlc-clan-backlash-with-playstation-refunds-promise-more-info-next-week]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>