<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 14:03:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6's beta been treating you to infinite loading screens? EA are on the case]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-6s-beta-been-treating-you-to-infinite-loading-screens-ea-are-on-the-case</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6s-beta-been-treating-you-to-infinite-loading-screens-ea-are-on-the-case.1265511/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Cairo Conquests look to have been tough to get into for unlucky troops</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>EA</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Waiting's been <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/with-battlefield-6-beta-queues-stretching-around-the-block-a-substantial-increase-in-server-capacity-should-just-have-helped">a bit of theme</a> during the early stages of the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/battlefield-2025">Battlefield 6</a> open beta, which has otherwise been earning a lot of thumbs up from FPS heads. If you've recently run into an never-ending loading screen while trying to jump into a Conquest match, the good news is that the devs have been working to solve those issues.</p>
<p>While EA reckon the problem's specific to that game mode and the Siege of Cairo map, that doesn't look to have stopped plenty of players from running into it over the past 24 hours. Cue a number of <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Battlefield6/comments/1mkcz0j/infinite_loading_screen_glitch_in_beta/">frustrated</a> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Battlefield6/comments/1mko40z/bug_as_of_this_morning_i_cant_get_into_a_game/">Reddit</a> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Battlefield6/comments/1mklzer/need_infinite_loading_screen_fix_asap/">posts</a> that boil down to the word 'stuck' being yelled so loud it could bring down a helicopter.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>"Our team has been investigating reports of an infinite loading screen sometimes occurring when matchmaking into Siege of Cairo while playing Conquest," the official Battlefield Comms account tweeted this morning. "We've identified the cause and are performing server restarts to resolve this. These restarts will not affect players currently in-match. Thank you for your patience."</p>
<p>While waiting for EA to address the issue, folks had been trying stuff like verifying the game's files on Steam or restarting it to solve their problems.</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>Our team has been investigating reports of an infinite loading screen sometimes occurring when matchmaking into Siege of Cairo while playing Conquest.</p><p>We've identified the cause and are performing server restarts to resolve this. These restarts will not affect players currently…</p></div>— Battlefield Comms (@BattlefieldComm) <a href="https://twitter.com/BattlefieldComm/status/1953744806556950777?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 8, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>With those server restarts, hopefully Cairo conquesters'll no longer keep getting stuck staring at some soldiers' shapely posteriors in perma-load, and be back to staring at a soldier's shapely posterior because they've decided to use someone else as cover mid-match. It's a strategy. A crap one, but hey, some of us aren't blessed with Alexander the Great's tactical nous.</p>
<p>For those waiting until this weekend to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-6-open-beta-early-access">jump into the Battlefield beta</a>, first of all congrats on likely missing the longest queues. Second, you'll need <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-6s-open-beta-makes-enabling-secure-boot-on-your-pc-mandatory-because-cheaters">turn on secure boot on your PC</a> if you've not done so already.</p>
<p>Also, EA have posted a <a href="https://x.com/BattlefieldComm/status/1953500544162500657">lengthy list of known issues</a> they'll be updating as they keep firing RPGs at bugs and issues throughout the beta, so maybe give that look too.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-6s-beta-been-treating-you-to-infinite-loading-screens-ea-are-on-the-case]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Classic shooters Heretic and Hexen re-released as an "enhanced" bundle with cross-platform multiplayer and mod support]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/classic-shooters-heretic-and-hexen-re-released-as-an-enhanced-bundle-with-cross-platform-multiplayer-and-mod-support</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/classic-shooters-heretic-and-hexen-re-released-as-an-enhanced-bundle-with-cross-platform-multiplayer-and-mod-support.1265469/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Nightdive and id Software have been hard at work restoring yet more 90s things</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>id Software and Nightdive Studios</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Wake up, it's the 90s again. Ok, so maybe I've lied to you there, but two classic shooters from the decade that I as a child of 1999 definitely remember fondly have been re-released as one handy bundle with some extra features. Heretic + <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hexen-beyond-heretic">Hexen</a> is out now.</p>
<p>The surprise re-release of these virtual spell boxes came as part of QuakeCon, with Nightdive Studios and id Software collborating to revamp more old school shooty things after doing the same with <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/doom">Doom</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/doom-2">Doom 2</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/doom-modders-are-annoyed-at-the-chum-bucket-of-wrongly-credited-mods-in-the-latest-doom-remaster">last year</a>. </p>
<!--more-->
<p>Announced by id’s Marty Stratton and Hugo Martin during last night's <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/videos/2533764889">QuakeCon welcome stream</a>, the <a href="https://slayersclub.bethesda.net/en-US/article/heretic-hexen-release-notes?linkId=100000377011247">Heretic + Hexen bundle</a> gives you Heretic: Shadow of the Serpent Riders, Hexen: Beyond Heretic, and Hexen: Deathkings of the Dark Citadel. Plus, there are two new chapters developed specially for the re-release: Heretic: Faith Renewed and Hexen: Vestiges of Grandier.</p>
<p>If you've already got the old versions of one or more of the games in your library, you'll be offered a free upgrade to the new bundle and retain access to those previous versions, rather than the new thing annoyingly overwriting them.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Heretic + Hexen Official Launch Trailer (4K) | Now Available" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IheADxVkpI4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Heretic + Hexen Official Launch Trailer (4K) | Now Available</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IheADxVkpI4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/IheADxVkpI4?autoplay=1" title="Heretic + Hexen Official Launch Trailer (4K) | Now Available">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IheADxVkpI4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>"There were level designers (including myself) that wanted to work on something new for Heretic and Hexen," developer Matthew Tropiano said of how the new sections came to be in an <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/08/07/heretic-hexen-surprise-release-today/">Xbox Wire interview</a>, "Kaiser (Sam Villareal) took point on the Heretic episode, while I handled the Hexen episode. We both enlisted the help of community member Not Jabba, as well as Heretic + Hexen lead Xaser Acheron for map design, and artist Arthur Biver for additional graphic work." He and Jaemen Moore added the games' original devs have been part of "inspiring some of the areas", with the Heretic chapter specifically drawing on "unused artwork" for some textures and two enemies, the draugr and troll.</p>
<p>Alongside those chapters, the new additions also include the likes of in-game support for community mods, local, online multiplayer support for up to 16 players with crossplay, and a remixed soundtrack by composer Andrew Hulshult. There are also performance tweaks that'll deliver up to 4K resolution and 120 FPS if you're packing the right hardware, and a vault where you can check out the likes of classic concept art.</p>
<p>Heretic + Hexen will set us PC folks back £13.49/$14.99, via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3286930/Heretic__Hexen/">Steam</a> or <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/heretic_hexen">GOG.com</a>, and it's also on Xbox Game Pass. If you've not played the original Hexen, here's our former deputy editor Adam with <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hexen-retrospective">some words on it</a>. If you've not played Heretic then I dunno, maybe imagine it's 1994 and you're enjoying a dark fantasy sibling of Doom. It features a <a href="https://doomwiki.org/wiki/Morph_Ovum">magic egg</a> that can turn enemies into chickens. Life's good. Or at least I assume it was.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/classic-shooters-heretic-and-hexen-re-released-as-an-enhanced-bundle-with-cross-platform-multiplayer-and-mod-support]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>