<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 23:42:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dante's epic poem La Divina Commedia is getting turned into a videogame again]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dantes-epic-poem-la-divina-commedia-is-getting-turned-into-a-videogame-again</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dantes-epic-poem-la-divina-commedia-is-getting-turned-into-a-videogame-again.1275078/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>EA and Visceral aren't involved</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Jyamma Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/enotria-the-last-song">Enotria: The Last Song</a> developers Jyamma Games are making a new action-RPG inspired by and named after Dante Alighieri’s 14th century epic poem La Divina Commedia, aka the Divine Comedy.</p>
<p>Like the poem, it sees you descending through the circles of Hell, each the geological manifestation of a particular Sin. Unlike the poem, it features a set of combat classes, a choice of protagonist genders, a narrative alignment system, procedurally generated extraction dungeons, and customisable weapons and armour. As the poet himself might say: in the middle of the journey of our life I came to myself within a dark wood where I had to grind for crafting materials. </p><!--more-->
<p>The games industry has not been mega gentle with poor old Dante, whose monumental work helped establish the Tuscan language and influenced a brace of English writers, from Blake to Beckett. The best-known video game adaptation is probably still Visceral’s cheeseball 2010 action-adventure Dante’s Inferno, which is often more interested in aping God Of War. A cynical man or snob (hello!) might look at the below, hacky-slashy trailer for Jyamma’s adaptation and consider it to be another act of wanton literary desecration. Terza rima isn’t supposed to be a three-hit combo, you blistering philistines!</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="La Divina Commedia - Reveal Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vTlBUqC2Cto?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>La Divina Commedia - Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vTlBUqC2Cto?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/vTlBUqC2Cto?autoplay=1" title="La Divina Commedia - Reveal Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vTlBUqC2Cto" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>Still, this isn't quite another exercise in crafting boobwalls for the circle of Lust or punching organs out of bodies. Enotria was <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/%E2%80%9Dhttps://www.rockpapershotgun.com/enotria-the-last-song-review%E2%80%9D">pretty metaphysical for a Soulslike</a>, building a universe and combat system around the practice of stagecraft, and Jyamma’s take on the La Divina Commedia is similarly dreamy - it turns Dante’s poem into a kind of overarching mythology.</p><p>“In this new adventure, the studio presents an epic journey set in a world where The Divine Comedy has supplanted the old faith, bringing about a golden age of righteousness among humanity,” explains <a href="https://www.gamespress.com/en-GB/JYAMMA-GAMES-ANNOUNCES-LA-DIVINA-COMMEDIA-AN-EPIC-DARK-FANTASY-ACTION-">a press release</a>. “When dark forces subvert the promises of the poem, order collapses and the world is thrust into chaos. The player will take on the role of a warrior-poet trapped in the infernal depths, called to descend through the circles of Hell, face increasingly powerful demons, and redeem a sinful past.”</p>
<p>Sounds quite involved. Still, I’m not sure where the procgen extraction dungeons fit in, exactly. The idea of mining hell for loot and progression materials is the kind of videogame conceit I’d love to lay before an actual 14th century theologian. I'm sure the humour of the situation would be well worth the inconvenience of being burned at the stake. Anyway, there’s no release date yet for La Divina Commedia. The poem took about 12 years to write – hopefully, Jyamma will turn their version around a little sooner.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Check out our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/events/gamescom-2025">Gamescom 2025</a> event hub for all the PC game announcements and preview coverage from Cologne.</em></p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dantes-epic-poem-la-divina-commedia-is-getting-turned-into-a-videogame-again]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Science reveal Black Myth: Zhong Kui, a new action-RPG that aims to catch Wukong players "off guard"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/game-science-reveal-black-myth-zhong-kui-a-new-action-rpg-that-aims-to-catch-wukong-players-off-guard</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/game-science-reveal-black-myth-zhong-kui-a-new-action-rpg-that-aims-to-catch-wukong-players-off-guard.1275048/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>But is currently "little more than an empty folder"</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun / Game Science</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/black-myth-wukong-walkthrough">Black Myth: Wukong</a> developers Game Science have revealed Black Myth: Zhong Kui, another single-player action-<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> steeped in Chinese mythology. It casts you as a ghost-hunting god who wanders between hell and Earth. Here's a CG short from <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gamescom-opening-night-live-2025-livestream-watch-all-todays-announcements-here">Gamescom's Open Night Live 2025</a>, which shows the fearsomely bearded Zhong Kui himself riding an extravagantly sized tiger. </p><!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Game Science's New Title | Black Myth: Zhong Kui - Teaser Trailer (English Dub)" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NZ7VLcO06Ak?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Game Science's New Title | Black Myth: Zhong Kui - Teaser Trailer (English Dub)</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NZ7VLcO06Ak?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/NZ7VLcO06Ak?autoplay=1" title="Game Science's New Title | Black Myth: Zhong Kui - Teaser Trailer (English Dub)">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NZ7VLcO06Ak" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>In <a href="https://www.gamesci.cn/zhongkui">a Q&amp;A on the official site</a>, the developers call the game a "tentative first step - to build more distinct game experiences, to challenge ourselves with bolder features, and to bring fresh ideas to our world and narrative design". They want Wukong players to feel "right at home" while "catching them off guard in the best way". That said, for now the new game remains "little more than an empty folder", with no release date and little sense in the CG trailer of how Zhong Kui fights, compared to Wukong. I'm guessing that tiger is a useful ally, though.</p>
<p>We quite liked the original Black Myth, with bygone reviews editor Ed Thorn (RPS in peace) <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/black-myth-wukong-is-a-pleasantly-surprising-soulslike-even-if-its-given-me-an-enemy-for-life">calling it</a> "a refreshing adventure after <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-boss-locations">Elden Ring</a>'s knotty DLC". We were less keen on <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/black-myth-wukongs-record-setting-launch-popularity-soured-by-co-publisher-request-to-avoid-feminist-propaganda-in-streams">the mildly draconian PR messages</a> to certain streamers, cautioning them to avoid "feminist propaganda", "politics" and discussion of the Chinese games industry.</p><p>These gamergatory memos followed <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-black-myth-wukong-developers-history-of-sexism-is-complicating-its-journey-to-the-west">a lengthy report from IGN</a> about alleged workplace sexism at Game Science. The devs refused to say anything to Ed about this when he asked at a preview event. If we're invited to preview Zhong Kui, we'll give it another shot.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Check out our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/events/gamescom-2025">Gamescom 2025</a> event hub for all the PC game announcements and preview coverage from Cologne.</em></p>

        </div>
      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/game-science-reveal-black-myth-zhong-kui-a-new-action-rpg-that-aims-to-catch-wukong-players-off-guard]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout season 2 radiates NEW VEGAS with a trailer heavy on stupid sexy House and a December debut date]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fallout-season-2-radiates-new-vegas-with-a-trailer-heavy-on-stupid-sexy-house-and-a-december-debut-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallout-season-2-radiates-new-vegas-with-a-trailer-heavy-on-stupid-sexy-house-and-a-december-debut-date.1274991/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Bethesda / Amazon</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Fire up the geiger counter, the second series of Amazon's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tv-shows/fallout">Fallout TV series</a> just showed off a trailer during <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gamescom-opening-night-live-2025-livestream-watch-all-todays-announcements-here">Gamescom Opening Night Live</a>. It premieres on 17th December.</p>
<p>If it wasn't clear already, this chain of episodes is set to take us to NEW VEGAS. I said NEW VEGAS. That's NEW VEGAS, the setting of obscure 2010 <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/fallout-new-vegas">Fallout: NEW VEGAS</a>. Understand? I don't think you do, so let's all look over here while I point to this sign. It says Lucky 38, which is a casino in NEW VEGAS.</p>
<!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Fallout Season 2 - Official Teaser Trailer | gamescom 2025" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NZY5WiqeyQQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Fallout Season 2 - Official Teaser Trailer | gamescom 2025</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NZY5WiqeyQQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/NZY5WiqeyQQ?autoplay=1" title="Fallout Season 2 - Official Teaser Trailer | gamescom 2025">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NZY5WiqeyQQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>In all seriousness, I doth protest this much because I'm a NEW VEGAS fan who's looking forward to taking in this <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fallout-tv-creators-saved-iconic-elements-for-season-2-so-it-doesnt-feel-like-they-just-skimmed-wikipedia">second series of Fallout</a> when it premieres in December. Ahead of that, this outing of it showed us The Ghoul and Lucy heading to New Vegas in pursuit of a certain someone (I won't say who, to avoid series one spoilers). Between the trailer and little chat actors Ella Purnell, Aaron Moten and the showrunners had with the Geoffman, we look to be getting a lot more of that Purnell/Goggins duo rubbing off on each other in series two, which sounds great to me.</p><p>They'll have to do a lot to pry my attention away from everyone's favourite preservation tube-dwelling Fallout billionaire, though. After popping in briefly in series one, NEW VEGAS' own Robert Edwin House looks to be playing a big role in series two. He and Walton Goggins' Cooper Howard are having plenty of pre-war chats, which see the suave, moustachioed House stare deeply into the Goggler's eyes while talking down to him just like he does to a certain videogame mailperson. Phwoar, Bob Residence. If you weren't a shrivelled prune by the time my character reached you, they'd have stabbed you through some bedsheets after a round or two, rather than that Benny.</p>
<p>Despite all the NEW VEGAS, I'm keen to see whether, with all of of its major characters all now set up and past the early stages of a playthrough when you're still convinced you're not gonna resort to speccing into speech, the series does anything major to take Fallout places it's not been. The likes of new factions or visits to locations the games haven't touched, just to spice up the big screening of things we know and love. Though, I'm aware that's something that I may well be in the minority on, given the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-fallout-tv-show-gave-the-fallout-games-a-huge-player-bump-as-everyone-remembers-they-like-fallout">massive popularity</a> of the first series.</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>Either way, odds are Ella Purnell, Walton Goggins, and co will once again be the faces of a good post-apocalyptic adventure, and one that looks like it's leaning heavily into pre-war flashbacks of NEW VEGAS in all its glory.</p>
<p>That's NEW VEGAS, lest you forget amid your Silver Rush to get on Tops of all the other Gamescom Opening Night live news.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Check out our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/events/gamescom-2025">Gamescom 2025</a> event hub for all the PC game announcements and preview coverage from Cologne.</em></p>

        </div>
      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fallout-season-2-radiates-new-vegas-with-a-trailer-heavy-on-stupid-sexy-house-and-a-december-debut-date]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zero Parades looks to be the new name of ZA/UM's post-Disco Elysium spy cRPG, not that its reveal paraded that around]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/zero-parades-looks-to-be-the-new-name-of-zaums-post-disco-elysium-spy-crpg-not-that-its-reveal-paraded-that-around</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zero-parades-looks-to-be-the-new-name-of-za-ums-post-disco-elysium-spy-crpg-not-that-its-reveal-paraded-that-around.1274943/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Also, maybe not the folks to be mentioning the phrase "fake radicals"</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>ZA/UM</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Remember the spy-themed game ZA/UM have settled into making after all the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/disco-elysium">Disco Elysium</a> drama? Well, unless they've got another espionagey cRPG in the works, Project C4 has gotten a new name in a cameo at <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gamescom-opening-night-live-2025-livestream-watch-all-todays-announcements-here">Gamescom Opening Night Live</a>. It now seemingly goes by Zero Parades.</p>
<p>Yep, amid the waves of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/theres-a-playable-disco-elysium-2-prototype-in-the-wilds-according-to-a-report-on-clashes-between-the-spiritual-successors">spiritual successors</a>, after all the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/disco-elysium-lawsuit-woes-continue-as-fired-devs-double-down-on-claims-of-fraud-at-studio-zaum">controversy around the exits of key team members</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/disco-elysium-expansion-reportedly-cancelled-with-a-quarter-of-staff-at-risk-of-redundancy">cancellations of Discoey things</a>, this is the thing those who remain at the studio have been working on. It looks and sounds very Disco Elysiumy.</p>
<!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Zero Parades - Reveal Trailer | gamescom 2025" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/p-toDEv6n_Q?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Zero Parades - Reveal Trailer | gamescom 2025</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/p-toDEv6n_Q?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/p-toDEv6n_Q?autoplay=1" title="Zero Parades - Reveal Trailer | gamescom 2025">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p-toDEv6n_Q" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>The Keighleybot intrduced Zero Parades trailer as a "first look" at a spy RPG ZA/UM have been working on. Oh, you mean the spy game they <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/despite-it-all-disco-elysiums-original-studio-have-revealed-espionage-filled-new-game-c4">revealed earlier this year</a>, Project C4, I mouthed at the screen. Geoff didn't answer, or even mention the name Project C4. So, unless this is an example of spyish doubling up to confuse a foe, I assume the two must be one in the same.</p><p>Anyway, in Zero Parades, the name for which comes with a host of optional taglines including "Zero Parades for fake radicals", which given all that's happened with folks seen as radical ideasmiths leaving ZA/UM in the Disco aftermath feels maybe a bit cheeky. Anyway, in this game you play as an operant Hershel Wilk, alias CASCADE, who's described as being "brilliant, burnt-out, possibly cursed", as well as "an Anti-Icon". Hershel's also a woman, so modify the mental image of Harry Du Bois that description's inevitably given you a little bit. The <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2863680/ZERO_PARADES/">Steam page</a> continues as follows:</p>
<blockquote>Five years ago you led your team into the abyss and have been haunted by your failures ever since. Now you've been recalled for a mysterious assignment that may give you a chance to prove yourself again. Find yourself thrown into a three-way struggle for cultural and ideological power, played out across an unforgettable new city. In Zero Parades, the world itself is a character with its own secrets, traumas, and miracles for you to discover.</blockquote>
<p>Much like in Project C4's reveal, a big thing's made of the fact you'll be failing a lot, and tha your failure will take you places via improvisation. Places that might not be as ideal, but that be how the dice are sometimes.</p>
<p>Zero Parades, or the artist that looks to be formerly known as Project C4, is currently without a release date. You can wishlist it <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2863680/ZERO_PARADES/">here</a>, if you're so inclined.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Check out our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/events/gamescom-2025">Gamescom 2025</a> event hub for all the PC game announcements and preview coverage from Cologne.</em></p>

        </div>
      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/zero-parades-looks-to-be-the-new-name-of-zaums-post-disco-elysium-spy-crpg-not-that-its-reveal-paraded-that-around]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>