<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 09:42:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arc Raiders takes a turn for the Long Dark with today's Cold Snap update - beware the frostbite]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arc-raiders-takes-a-turn-for-the-long-dark-with-todays-cold-snap-update-beware-the-frostbite</link>
            <guid>1384297</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Don't worry, you won't actually lose your favourite looting fingers</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arcraiderscoldsnap.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arcraiderscoldsnap.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arcraiderscoldsnap.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arcraiderscoldsnap.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arcraiderscoldsnap.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arcraiderscoldsnap.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arcraiderscoldsnap.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arcraiderscoldsnap.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arcraiderscoldsnap.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Embark Studios</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Today sees the release of the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arc-raiders-best-guns-tier-list">Arc Raiders</a> Cold Snap update, which douses the popular sci-fi extraction shooter in glittering snowfall. Ah, how gorgeous the flakes twinkling above the Spaceport gantries. How beautiful the frozen lakes of Dam Battlegrounds. It's definitely a mite nippy all of a sudden, though, isn't it? Best take shelter in that bunker before your fingers and toes turn Uncommon green and Rare blue.</p>
<p>Oh dear, there's another player inside that bunker and she won't let you in. Still, perhaps if you start shouting the patch notes through the door she'll relent out of curiosity? Very good, let's begin.
</p><!--more-->
<p>
<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arc-raiders-is-set-for-a-cold-snap-next-week-and-it-looks-like-forgetting-to-pack-your-mitts-could-be-deadly">As described last week</a>, the Arc Raiders Cold Snap update buries the game's four default maps in the white stuff. "Snowstorms sweep across Speranza as winter conditions take hold of multiple raid locations," explains a press release. "Snowfall reduces visibility, lakes freeze over, and the open surface becomes more dangerous than ever -- turning every raid into a high-stakes survival run."
</p>
<p>
In particular, you will now have to worry about frostbite, or at least, a slow health drain mechanic called frostbite, while rambling outdoors. You won't run the risk of losing any appendages to gangrene, I think. "Raiders must rethink their loadouts, ensuring they can heal themselves or their teammates and plan their extractions with care, finding shelter if needed," comments the press release.
</p><p>
The temperature drop accompanies a modest blizzard of Arc Raiders add-on content. There's the Goalie Raider Deck, the second of the game's Raider Decks, which is yours for free come 26th December, and will be permanently accessible with no time limits. It includes new items and player feats to perform for Raider tokens, cosmetics and such.</p>
<p>Pride of place goes to the hockey-inspired Raider outfit with matching hockey stick raider tool.  I myself used to play (grass) hockey and have, in fact, played hockey in blizzards so thick you could barely see the opposing goal. This was during my grim Yorkshire childhood, when everybody knew that the only way to make kids grow up right was to nearly murder them with bad weather. I've still got my old  stick, propped over the door in humiliating mimicry of a World War heirloom. I'm pretty sure it'll break if I touch it, let alone brain a rival scavenger for a bagful of batteries.
</p>
<p>
Expect two time-limited seasonal events in the course of the Cold Snap. On December 16th, there's the Flickering Flames Event, which boasts 25 levels of new gear, customisation elements and Raider tokens. These are earned by way of Merits, gained from XP in rounds. On December 26th, please gird your loins for the Candleberry Banquet Project, which sees you collecting Candleberries to earn rewards, and is broken into five stages, each with a new banqueting scene. Polish off stages to earn further rewards, including Merits for the aforesaid Flickering Flames event. God, remember when all you had to do in games was gather coins and not die. 
</p>
<p>
Last but not least, this December brings the opportunity to prestige your current character - sorry, I mean, send them on an expedition. This lets you pay a bunch of resources to reset much of your progression, including your player level and inventory. Why would you do this? Because starting over freshens up the experience and makes you feel like Maximilian Gamer, Destroyer Of Worlds. Also, you're awarded a few perks in return to help you begin a fresh character, such as increased XP gain, bonus skill points, and more stash space. Expeditions give you eight weeks to prepare, and the first one "leaves" on 21st December.
 

</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arc-raiders-takes-a-turn-for-the-long-dark-with-todays-cold-snap-update-beware-the-frostbite]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Game About Feeding A Black Hole, out today, is exactly what it proclaims to be, and surprisingly tranquil]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-game-about-feeding-a-black-hole-out-today-is-exactly-what-it-proclaims-to-be-and-surprisingly-tranquil</link>
            <guid>1384072</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/a-game-about-feeding-a-black-hole.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/a-game-about-feeding-a-black-hole.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/a-game-about-feeding-a-black-hole.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/a-game-about-feeding-a-black-hole.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/a-game-about-feeding-a-black-hole.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/a-game-about-feeding-a-black-hole.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/a-game-about-feeding-a-black-hole.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/a-game-about-feeding-a-black-hole.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/a-game-about-feeding-a-black-hole.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Aarimous, Thornityco</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
I do not know if a black hole is something we should feed. Ostensibly they are things (anti-things? I'm not a black holeologist) that I would like to be far away from, given what I've heard. And yet here I am, having tinkered around with the demo for A Game About Feeding A Black Hole, which is a game about feeding a black hole, left with the feeling that this is not only a thing I can do, but find tranquility in.
</p>
<p>
The thing about A Game About Feeding A Black Hole is that it is more or less what it says on the tin. It is also a game about inaction and reaction. You have a tiny circle which every second or so, to start with, does a bit of damage. So, you break down the handful of asteroids you see around you, their remnants being swept up in the nothingness that is the black hole, trying to increase its size as the clock counts down.
</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="A Game About Feeding A Black Hole - Official Demo Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/STyWU0Q58IQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>A Game About Feeding A Black Hole - Official Demo Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/STyWU0Q58IQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/STyWU0Q58IQ?autoplay=1" title="A Game About Feeding A Black Hole - Official Demo Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=STyWU0Q58IQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>
This then gives you money, money which you can spend on a skill tree, a skill tree that can grow your circle, or strengthen it, or increase the length of the timer, or increase the mass of certain asteroids, or make some of them shoot out forks of lightning, or turn some of them radioactive, all of which works in tandem with one another. As your skills increase, so does your ability to destroy asteroids and feed the black hole, growing it in size incrementally. This is one of the reactions, as well as how a lightning bolt might hit another asteroid helping to destroy it, even more effectively on the radioactive rocks.
</p><p>
The inaction is the fact that all you really do is move your mouse around. After a while, in the demo, the game does half of the work for you, but oh that sweet satisfaction of seeing a plethora of numbers and destroyed bits of space boulders flying into deep, dark, nothingness. This is a game to spend perhaps 15 minutes on, the kind of thing you might do on a cigarette break during your shift at the busiest brunch spot in town, a way to get away and calm yourself down.
</p>
<p>
A Game About Feeding A Black Hole is also a game that came out today, December 15th, so for the price of a fancy pastry, you could instead, well… you know. It's available to pick up on Steam right <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3694480/A_Game_About_Feeding_A_Black_Hole/">here</a>.

</p>

        </div>

      </article>




        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-game-about-feeding-a-black-hole-out-today-is-exactly-what-it-proclaims-to-be-and-surprisingly-tranquil]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>