<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 13:36:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No Man's Sky's Voyagers update adds in big custom ships crewed by you and your mates]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/no-mans-skys-voyagers-update-adds-in-big-custom-ships-crewed-by-you-and-your-mates</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/no-mans-skys-voyagers-update-adds-in-big-custom-ships-crewed-by-you-and-your-mates.1281702/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>I give it five parsecs before someone's accidentally flushed out of an airlock</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Hello Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Have you ever wanted to swim out of a spaceship's backside while it sits in orbit, the sound of two dear friends arguing over whether it really needs a fifth teleporter room not seeping with you into the inky blackness? You know, because space is a famously scream-free zone. Well, the latest in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/no-mans-sky">No Man's Sky</a>'s endless string of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/no-mans-skys-latest-big-update-that-is-somehow-also-free-will-let-you-become-a-mayor-of-all-things">free</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/no-mans-sky-has-a-mass-effect-normandy-again-together-with-new-cross-save-functionality">updates</a> has you covered. It's called Voyagers, and adds in custom multi-person ships dubbed corvettes.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>These ships are yours to design and build to your liking, with the addition of some sleeping quarters and a mission radar all you need to get started and welcome a crew of friends aboard to accompany you on your adventures. "These ships have real interiors, med-bays, sleeping quarters, war rooms, radars, teleporters," said Hello Games boss Sean Murray. "It comes with you everywhere, which totally changes how you play. Decorating it with your friends gives you a space that you share together. Whether it's a brightly coloured tiny explorer, or a colossal dark metallic war ship, it allows you to show off your own personality.</p>
<p>Murray adds that corvettes, which you can naturally also tape the likes of extra guns and windows to, are "encountered a little way into the game" and can be unlocked "reasonably swiftly" by spacers who've already sunk plenty of hours into the quest for <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-survival-games-on-pc">spacevival</a>. The Voyagers update relies on tech which Hello say has been developed with an eye to their next game, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/light-no-fire">Light No Fire</a>, which as an open-world thing on an Earth-sized planet with Earth-sized oceans, will feature large boats and crews of its own.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="No Man's Sky Voyagers Trailer (Update 6.0)" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qHZLz1MW0aE?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>No Man's Sky Voyagers Trailer (Update 6.0)</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qHZLz1MW0aE?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/qHZLz1MW0aE?autoplay=1" title="No Man's Sky Voyagers Trailer (Update 6.0)">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qHZLz1MW0aE" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>Naturally, that's no easy feat, with Murray revealing: "Almost every part of the game has had to be reworked to accommodate these relative spaces. Having your multiplayer crew walking around, calmly editing your ship, as it travels at warp speeds towards a planet that is being generated as you approach. It's pretty insane what's going on behind the scenes to make that work."</p><p>Cool, but also, I'm looking at this very being-in-a-ship-centric update and can't help being drawn to an aspect of it that doesn't technically involve being in a ship. You see, if you park multiple corvettes in orbit around a planet, you can spacewalk or skydive between them. In practice, your space-suited little fella's gently spat out of the back entrance to your craft, like... Well, I'll refrain from describing it in the manner I'd typically employ, since the RPS treehouse has a bit more decorum than some of the other places I've hung out. Suffice it to say that mucking about pinging between ships and diving down towards the surface looks like great fun.</p>
<p>No Man's Sky's Voyagers update is out now, and you can check out its <a href="https://www.nomansky.com/voyagers-update">full patch notes</a> here.</p>

        </div>
      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/no-mans-skys-voyagers-update-adds-in-big-custom-ships-crewed-by-you-and-your-mates]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft staff perform sit-in protest in company president's office over Israeli military ties]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/microsoft-staff-perform-sit-in-protest-in-company-presidents-office-over-israeli-military-ties</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-staff-perform-sit-in-protest-in-company-presidents-office-over-israeli-military-ties.1281594/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"There are many things we can't do to change the world," says Microsoft's Brad Smith</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Microsoft</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>A group of current and former Microsoft employees have staged a sit-in protest in the office of company president Brad Smith over the use of Azure and generative AI technologies by the Israeli military during their on-going bombardment of Palestinians in the West Bank and Gaza.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>As reported by <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/766324/microsoft-building-34-lockdown-protesters-brad-smith-office">The Verge</a>, the protestors belonged to the No Azure for Apartheid activist group, which <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/on-the-eve-of-gamescom-microsoft-workers-occupy-the-xbox-companys-campus-in-protest-at-dealings-with-the-israeli-military">continues to petition Microsoft</a> to terminate all of their contracts with the Israeli government and military. Microsoft president Brad Smith claimed in a subsequent press briefing that the group of protestors consisted of seven people, with two being current Microsoft staff, and were removed from the office by Redmond police.</p>
<p>No Azure for Apartheid organizer and former Microsoft employee Abdo Mohamed confirmed to The Verge that Microsoft staffers Riki Fameli and Anna Hattle were part of the protest, alongside former staff Vaniya Agrawal, Hossam Nasr, and Joe Lopez.</p>
<p>Following the protest, Smith staged a press briefing in his office, declaring that Microsoft are "committed to ensuring [their] human rights principles and contractual terms of service are upheld in the Middle East." "When seven folks do as they did today, storm a building, occupy an office, lock other people out of the office, plant listening devices — even in crude form, in the form of telephones, cellphones hidden under couches and behind books — that’s not ok. When they’re asked to leave and they refused, that’s not ok," the exec said. Smith complaining about the planting of listening devices seems rather ironic, given that Microsoft stand accused of collaborating with Israeli military efforts to keep Palestinians under surveillance.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Media Briefing August 26th" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/T6tl7KoIVgA?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Media Briefing August 26th</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/T6tl7KoIVgA?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/T6tl7KoIVgA?autoplay=1" title="Media Briefing August 26th">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T6tl7KoIVgA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>When asked whether the two current Microsoft workers who were part of the sit-in, which was livestreamed on Twitch, will face any internal disciplinary measures for doing so, Smith said the following:</p>
<blockquote>We'll take a look. I think one or two of them may have also been arrested last week. So, if somebody's been arrested twice, that's a situation that is not standard employee conduct I think it's fair to say. I don't think it would be regarded as standard employee conduct by any of the places where you [gestures to media present] work, [or] frankly any of the places where anybody works.</blockquote>
<p>Earlier in the briefing, Smith addressed <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/microsoft-equipped-israels-indiscriminate-palestinian-surveillance-operation-with-azure-cloud-tech-claims-report">The Guardian's recent report</a> about Microsoft's Azure cloud platform being used in the surveillance of Palestinians by Israel, saying that Microsoft are investigating the report's allegations. "We are working every day to get to the bottom of what’s going on, and we will," he said.</p><p>He also touched on Microsoft having contacted the FBI in April this year, with <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-08-26/microsoft-asked-fbi-for-help-with-israel-gaza-protests?embedded-checkout=true">Bloomberg</a> (paywalled) reporting that the company had asked the body to provide information on pro-Palestinian protests that might target Microsoft. The exec said he'd first heard about this last week, and subsequently cited "one of our security folks" as having sent the email to the "local FBI office", claiming that it was a more general inquiry about "disruptions" the FBI could see potentially being planned in the Seattle area.</p>
<p>This latest protest comes as groups like the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bds-calls-for-boycott-of-microsoft-and-xbox-gaming-products-over-alleged-israeli-military-connections">Boycott, Divestment, and Sanctions movement</a> continue to call for people to boycott Microsoft and Xbox products over the company's relationship with the Israeli miliary, with unionised staff at <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dishonored">Dishonored</a> developers Arkane Studios recently having <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/arkane-studios-union-publishes-open-letter-to-microsoft-demanding-a-stop-to-israeli-support">voiced their support</a> for both the BDS boycott and No Azure for Apartheid's efforts.</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/microsoft-staff-perform-sit-in-protest-in-company-presidents-office-over-israeli-military-ties]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>