<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 03:22:24 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Onimusha Way Of The Sword is the Capcom action-RPG's first new instalment in almost 20 years]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/onimusha-way-of-the-sword-is-the-capcom-action-rpgs-first-new-instalment-in-almost-20-years</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/onimusha-way-of-the-sword-is-the-capcom-action-rpgs-first-new-instalment-in-almost-20-years.1060176/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/onimusha-way-of-the-sword-is-the-capcom-action-rpgs-first-new-instalment-in-almost-20-years<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_UccQlcJ.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Capcom / Rock Paper Shotgun</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Well here's one I didn't see coming: a new Onimusha game. It's called Onimusha Way Of The Sword, and is the first new game in Capcom's samurai action-horror series since... well, that upcoming VR entry doesn't count, and nor does the Warlords remaster in 2018. So, 2012? Maybe 2006, if you rule out the Unity browser game? Cor.</p><!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Onimusha Way of the Sword - Reveal Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/16KXGqX59Z8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Onimusha Way of the Sword - Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/16KXGqX59Z8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/16KXGqX59Z8?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=16KXGqX59Z8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>On the off-chance that you've never played an Onimusha game, and possibly weren't alive back in 2006, it's basically <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/resident-evil">Resident Evil</a> but with a samurai and set in Japan. That was true of the first one, anyway. Later instalments took... interesting liberties. Onimusha 3 had Jean Reno in it for some reason. One thing they all share is more of a combat focus than the Resis. You don't need to find ammo for a katana, after all. But they certainly aren't hack-and-slash games.</p>
<p>The Way Of The Sword trailer doesn't reveal much, but it seems to suggest a back-to-basics approach, as you might expect from a series that hasn't had a mainline instalment in almost two decades. It appears to be set in feudal times, and a bunch of demons are causing a ruckus in the woods. There are scenes of swordplay, including a few vicious finishers and some dramatic parrying. If it's cleaving close to formula, there should be RPG elements as well.</p>
<p>It's out in 2026. Any old Onimusha players in the haus? I think I fell off the series around about the time Jean Reno showed up.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>The Geoffening has begun! Catch all the latest Game Awards announcements on our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/events/the-game-awards-2024">Game Awards 2024</a> hub page. You can also get the news hot from our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-game-awards-2024-liveblog">liveblog</a>.</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands 4 looks ready to drop the hottest memes of 2011 in first-look trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/borderlands-4-looks-ready-to-drop-the-hottest-memes-of-2011-in-first-look-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-4-looks-ready-to-drop-the-hottest-memes-of-2011-in-first-look-trailer.1060098/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/borderlands-4-looks-ready-to-drop-the-hottest-memes-of-2011-in-first-look-trailer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Fourderlands was right there</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/borderlands-4-man-with-axe.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Gearbox</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Looter <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-fps-games">FPS</a> <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/borderlands-4">Borderlands 4</a> has gotten its first trailer, courtesy of Medium Geoff’s Happy Hour and..wait. What you mean it’s <em>three hours</em>? I’m going to die tonight, aren’t I? Ah well, at least I’ll die doing what I’m ambivalent about. Here’s the trailer for Fourderlands, which is out sometime next year.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Borderlands 4 - Official First Look" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/26vY2GMfYTw?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Borderlands 4 - Official First Look</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/26vY2GMfYTw?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/26vY2GMfYTw?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=26vY2GMfYTw" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>“Borderlands 4 is a mayhem-fueled looter shooter, jam-packed with billions of weapons, outrageous enemies, and intense co-op action,” says the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1285190/Borderlands_4/">Steam page</a>. “Break free from a dangerous hidden planet as one of four new badass Vault Hunters.” Oh! Nobody told me they were badasses. That changes everything.</p>
<p>You’ll be vault hunting solo or with up to three other players in co-op, and there'll also be skill trees and dynamic movement abilities, touts Steam. You’ll be collecting many, many guns with “death-dealing firepower”, which feels like a superfluous description. I suppose maybe you’d need to say that if there was also non-lethal firepower. There are a lot of guns. I’ll withhold judgement. There’ll also be “free-form combat and exploration, pulse-pounding boss fights, infinitely varied loot drops, and an eclectic cast of unforgettable characters new and old.”</p><p>Great. Great. It’s great. I’m sure it’s great. Steam lists the game as “coming soon”, although the trailer reckons 2025. Who to trust in these uncertain times? Ah well, a little uncertainty makes it exciting. I mean, comparatively speaking anyway.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>The Geoffening has begun! Catch all the latest Game Awards announcements on our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/events/the-game-awards-2024">Game Awards 2024</a> hub page. You can also get the news hot from our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-game-awards-2024-liveblog">liveblog</a>.</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Long Dark 2 announced with co-op multiplayer, new urban areas and sanity system]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-long-dark-2-announced-with-co-op-multiplayer-new-urban-areas-and-sanity-system</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-long-dark-2-announced-with-co-op-multiplayer-new-urban-areas-and-sanity-system.1060092/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-long-dark-2-announced-with-co-op-multiplayer-new-urban-areas-and-sanity-system<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Survival is a dish best served cold</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_kOZKxOh.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Hinterlands</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-long-dark">The Long Dark</a> creators Hinterlands have announced The Long Dark 2, another helping of open-ended wilderness survival. Actually titled Blackfrost: The Long Dark 2 - a travestying of naming conventions that is surely more harrowing than any post-apocalyptic winter - it's out in early access in 2026, and introduces urban environments together with a "Will to Live" sanity system and co-op multiplayer. Here's the trailer.
</p><!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="BLACKFROST -- The Long Dark 2 -- Announcement Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4wlttElgLg4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>BLACKFROST -- The Long Dark 2 -- Announcement Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4wlttElgLg4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/4wlttElgLg4?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4wlttElgLg4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
And here's some backstory, care of <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1586260/BLACKFROST_The_Long_Dark_2/">the just-launched Steam page</a>.
</p>
<blockquote><p>
Experience the Quiet Apocalypse as survivors in the northern industrial city of Harmont and its vast environs. A year has passed since the Aurora first appeared in the sky, rendering all technology inert, with survivors just starting to emerge to face their new reality in its aftermath. Surrounded by a majestic, rugged wilderness, encounter the remnants of an isolated society still coming to terms with how the world has just been forever changed. How will you choose to survive?
</p></blockquote>
<p>
In case the mention of co-op has you screaming, fashioning yourself a wolfskin pelt, and fleeing to the hillside caves, it looks like single-player is still the heart of the game. But you'll potentially have a lot more company, as players must decide whether to join communities of NPC survivors. Co-op players, meanwhile, will "lean on each other and combine your skills and efforts to eke out another day of existence in the hostile environment". I'm not sure whether this means there are unique co-op mechanics. If my co-op partner dies, can I eat them and knit their entrails into a scarf? 
</p><p>
And then there are the new urban areas. "Cities and towns offer new opportunities, and new hazards to your survival, introducing a fresh take on the established survival formula," the Steam page explains. "The wilds are dangerous, but sometimes the city is where the real threats lie." I assume they're not talking about boy racers at the traffic lights.
</p>
<p>
The new Will to Live system complicates the already-steep challenge of keeping yourself fed, watered and uninjured. It "adds elements of psychological survival to the mix, introducing Resilience and its sub-stats to the well-established mechanics," according to the Steam page. "Manage your doubts and fears, and find comfort in the small things if you want to survive."
</p>
<p>
You might be wondering what this "blackfrost" stuff is. It's one of the new hazards, a radioactive substance emitted by a distant reactor complex. It's not clear how exactly it affects you, but you'll want to avoid it. Ditto the "Aurora Storms" and "extreme weather events".
</p>
<p>
There's also a new  Permalife system which sounds like a narrativised respawn feature, in that it  "turns every death into a new adventure". The Steam page phrases it thusly: "Accumulate new risks and fears for your survivor as you move through the world and succumb to various hazards. Face your fears, overcome their downsides, and strengthen your Survivor's story in the world. Make your mark." If you don't like the sound of this, the old Permadeath mode is still an option.
</p><p>
I never played much of The Long Dark. It was for me The Short Dark, in that I struggled to make it past the first hut. Perhaps I'll fare better with the help of a friendly player in the sequel? Or perhaps, I'll just end up padding their stomach?
</p>
<hr>
<p><em>The Geoffening has begun! Catch all the latest Game Awards announcements on our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/events/the-game-awards-2024">Game Awards 2024</a> hub page. You can also get the news hot from our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-game-awards-2024-liveblog">liveblog</a>.</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>