<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 09:21:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Communists attacked the Wild West" for booze in shooter RPG Chambers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/communists-attacked-the-wild-west-for-booze-in-shooter-rpg-chambers</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/communists-attacked-the-wild-west-for-booze-in-shooter-rpg-chambers.1187661/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/communists-attacked-the-wild-west-for-booze-in-shooter-rpg-chambers<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Mr. Pink/JFJ</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Your <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-fps-games">FPS</a> cup likely runneth over this month with <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/doom-the-dark-ages">Doom: The Dark Ages</a> (<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/doom-the-dark-ages-review">unless you've got good taste</a>. Nah, I'm just messing. It's alright) but if you'd like a top up, spare a thought for the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2437570/Chambers/">early access release</a> of "comedic RPG shooter" <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/chambers">Chambers</a>. It's from Mr. Pink and JFJ, the former of which made Golden Light, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-worlds-most-disgusting-fps-golden-light-is-free-for-the-next-hour-only">which Edwin called "the world's most disgusting FPS"</a>. Have you the read the Maw? Do you know how much it takes to disgust Edwin? Here's a little looksee.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Chambers Early Access Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iovhzY955zM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Chambers Early Access Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iovhzY955zM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/iovhzY955zM?autoplay=1" title="Chambers Early Access Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iovhzY955zM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>Not a shield in sight. Just old time, good time, down home rocket communists riding flying machines made of revolver parts, cannibalism, and a "hookshot-hat". Bafflingly, the trailer does not show the hookshot-hat, but I respect the restraint.</p>
<p>The west has been torn apart by the great War For Booze, and your once-idyllic family life has been shattered. So, you hop on your horse and set off to do some gun violence at communists over a series of open sandbox levels. Here are some features:</p>
<p>(Also, here's a grammar question for you, the discerning nitpicker. I always want write to "here's some features" but that's technically not correct because there's multiple features, but "here are some features" just feels so unnecessarily drawn out I want to expire and crumble into dust before I reach the end of the sentence. It's a bloody conundrum, it is! Little insight into the tortuous struggle I experience in the daily process of sausage making, there.)</p>
<blockquote><ul>
<li>Story driven adventure set in open sandbox-like levels.</li>
<li>Dynamic slapstick combat.</li>
<li>Equipment system with upgradeable weapons and clothing.</li>
<li>Trading and cooking systems.</li>
<li>First person rolling, bullet catching, kicking, hookshot-hat, cannibalism, drinking booze and puking.</li>
</ul></blockquote>
<p>The description of "dynamic slapstick combat" puts me in mind of Blendo Games' recent <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/skin-deep">Skin Deep</a>. I read something the other day about how one of the purposes of narrative design is to make the things you do in games seem less weird and stupid, but I'm a supporter of leaning into the opposite. I'm also reading Blood Meridian for the first time at the moment, and feel this would make an incredibly incongruent but just similar enough companion piece to make both experiences much stupider.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 doesn't require reflexes, says player who beat the game without dodges or parries]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-doesnt-require-reflexes-says-player-who-beat-the-game-without-dodges-or-parries</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/clair-obscur-expedition-33-doesnt-require-reflexes-says-player-who-beat-the-game-without-dodges-or-parries.1187631/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-doesnt-require-reflexes-says-player-who-beat-the-game-without-dodges-or-parries<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"Despite the hype, this is not Elden Ring."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Kepler Interactive</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Yes, yes, I'm opting for the scoundrel's gambit and reporting on a Reddit post. Of a self-imposed challenge run, no less! But I <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-review">adored the bejeezus</a> out of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/clair-obscur-expedition-33">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a>, and figured this was worth sharing in case it convinces a couple of you to give it a go. Redditor HunterIV4 has <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/expedition33/comments/1ki94qi/can_you_beat_the_game_without_dodging_yes_part_2/">chronicled their journey</a> to beat the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> without dodging, parrying, or even using the powerful gradient parries, in a bid to show that Sekiro reflexes aren't as crucial to success as they might seem. Thanks, <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/rpg/clair-obscur-player-tanks-their-way-through-the-entire-game-without-dodging-or-parrying-to-prove-a-point-you-can-finish-it-without-gamer-reflexes/">cheery RPS fanzine PC Gamer</a>.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 - Official Launch Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wWGIakhqr5g?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 - Official Launch Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wWGIakhqr5g?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/wWGIakhqr5g?autoplay=1" title="Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 - Official Launch Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wWGIakhqr5g" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>Tackling the game's story mode, HunterIV4 took the approach of bumping up their party's health as much as possible. It sounds like they had a fairly easy time through the game's first act, although they had to focus more heavily on effective builds for the latter portion. Personally, I enjoyed the buildcraft in Clair Obscur so much it's been a little disheartening to see it overshadowed by the Sekiro comparisons and what not. I do think this is partially a quirk of the design, since you can technically make the character building meaningless by just getting very good at button pressing. Still: good to hear that it does have the capacity to play like a more traditional turn-base 'em up.</p>
<p>HunterIV4 ended the second of their two posts with screenshots of both final bosses beaten with zero parries or  dodges. "Don't let concerns about a 'hardcore' experience prevent you from playing this awesome game and experiencing the story first-hand," <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/expedition33/comments/1kfc7mz/no_dodgeparry_an_experiment_and_what_to_do_if_you/">they wrote</a>. "Despite the hype, this is not <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-boss-locations">Elden Ring</a>."</p>
<p>Granted, this doesn't sound like the best way to experience the game - Act I took them much longer that they'd have like, apparently. But, hopefully it's tempted a few more of you to join the cult of Esquie's magnificent ass. The time of the airship is over, now is the age of the dump truck.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>