<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 14:38:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Despite it all, Disco Elysium's original studio have revealed espionage-filled new game, C4]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/despite-it-all-disco-elysiums-original-studio-have-revealed-espionage-filled-new-game-c4</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/despite-it-all-disco-elysiums-original-studio-have-revealed-espionage-filled-new-game-c4.1131000/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/despite-it-all-disco-elysiums-original-studio-have-revealed-espionage-filled-new-game-c4<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"This is not Disco Elysium 2, this is C4."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/c4-key-art.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Studio ZA/UM</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
With several <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/disco-elysium">Disco Elysium</a> spiritual successors in the works from former staff, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/disco-elysium-lawsuit-woes-continue-as-fired-devs-double-down-on-claims-of-fraud-at-studio-zaum">controversy regarding the exits of key team members</a> behind the beloved RPG, and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/disco-elysium-expansion-reportedly-cancelled-with-a-quarter-of-staff-at-risk-of-redundancy">an in-development expansion cancelled</a>, you might have been wondering what <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/zaum">Studio ZA/UM</a> will do next. Well, that answer is here. In a recent presentation held for the press, ZA/UM revealed a first look at their next game. It's called C4 and it's about espionage.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
The presentation was led by Jim Ashilevi, the lead voice over director on Disco Elysium, and Siim "Kosmos" Sinamäe, a producer and writer for the RPG, who are both serving as writers on this new game. Right off the bat, Sinamäe made one thing quite clear: "This is not Disco Elysium 2, this is C4." The writer went on to explain that ZA/UM has "spent the last three years developing this brand new, gripping, completely original world, exploring a theme that each and every member of the ZA/UM collective is inherently obsessed with: espionage."
</p>
<figure>

<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kz9apwrMKi8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
While the presentation didn't offer a look at anything in-game, a short teaser trailer for C4 was shown which mostly consisted of a woman with a London accent talking in a very Disco Elysium-y kind of way, set to some very cool looking art. Story details were pretty slim too, but Ashilevi did explain that "C4 is all about spy games, allegiances, and betrayals. It is not 007, with his hero complex, the Bond girls, the gadgets. It is more like Slow Horses, doing the work you love even if it does not get you any fame or parades. No heroes, only the stench of failure." Failing forward will also apparently be a big part of what sets the game apart, with Ashilevi saying the team is making "failure a joy in itself".
</p>
<p>
This presentation is just part one of two, as ZA/UM is also apparently making an appearance at GDC later this month, where it will presumably talk more about the game.
</p>
<p>
C4 is obviously the first project following <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/disco-elysium-developer-alleges-creative-leads-were-fired-on-false-premises">the departure</a> of Disco Elysium designer Robert Kurvitz, writer Helen Hindpere and artist Aleksander Rostov in 2021. What followed has been a series of messy legal battles, a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JGIGA8taN-M&amp;ab_channel=PeopleMakeGames">documentary</a> that alleged toxicity from Kurvitz and more, and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/former-disco-elysium-devs-are-working-on-a-spiritual-successor-at-new-studio-longdue-though-robert-kurvitz-and-aleksander-rostov-arent-involved">several</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/yet-another-studio-formed-of-disco-elysium-alumni-has-announced-a-cerebral-sci-fi-rpg-just-to-confuse-you">different</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/first-look-at-disco-elysium-spiritual-successor-hopetown-shows-a-painterly-gorgeous-and-utterly-unconvincing-rpg">games</a> claiming to be spiritual successors. I'm looking forward to finding out if the OG ZA/UM can cut through all of that noise.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call Of Duty: Warzone's original Verdansk map is coming back, but a bit later than expected]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-duty-warzones-original-verdansk-map-is-coming-back-but-a-bit-later-than-expected</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-warzones-original-verdansk-map-is-coming-back-but-a-bit-later-than-expected.1130946/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-duty-warzones-original-verdansk-map-is-coming-back-but-a-bit-later-than-expected<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Even Nat King Cole thinks it's an unforgettable map</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/warzone-verdansk.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Activision</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
The passage of time is unfortunately an unstoppable thing, and I seem to have blinked and five years have passed since the release of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/call-of-duty-warzone-20">Call of Duty: Warzone</a>. In the intervening period, a sort-of-sequel was released simply titled Call of Duty: Warzone 2.0 - now just called Call of Duty: Warzone, too - and the single, bountiful map players War upon has changed several times over. Yesterday on March 10th, the day Warzone officially released back in 2020, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/activision">Activision</a> shared a teaser trailer confirming that the game's original map Verdansk will be making a comeback.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
The trailer, which you can check out below, is set to Nat King Cole's classic Unforgettable, all while different characters in a range of military gear lovingly look at dirt, embrace shot-up walls, and cry over the return of Verdansk.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Unforgettable Verdansk Teaser | Call of Duty: Warzone" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OX2LeqDlkBg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Unforgettable Verdansk Teaser | Call of Duty: Warzone</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OX2LeqDlkBg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/OX2LeqDlkBg?autoplay=1" title="Unforgettable Verdansk Teaser | Call of Duty: Warzone">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OX2LeqDlkBg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
To be honest, it feels like a bit of a tone deaf trailer given the general state of the world, but I suppose Call of Duty has never been known for treating these kinds of things sensitively. 
</p>
<p>
It was thought that season 3 of Warzone and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-best-guns">Black Ops 6</a> would be arriving later this month on March 20th, but last week the official Call of Duty X (formerly Twitter) account <a href="https://x.com/CallofDuty/status/1896636715143704641">confirmed that it will instead be coming April 3rd</a>. That's when you'll be able to jump back into Verdansk, too.
</p>
<p>
Call of Duty is obviously following in Fortnite's footsteps here, given that Epic's more popular battle royale did the exact same thing <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fortnite-og-is-here-bringing-back-planes-hamster-balls-tilted-towers-and-more-over-the-next-four-weeks">back in 2023</a> by bringing back a whole bunch of features from the earliest iteration of the game, including its original map. Fortnite found a lot of success with that move, something I'm sure Activision will hope repeats with the return of Verdansk to Warzone.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>