<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 16:05:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Trucker's anniversary update adds wheel and joystick support to the space lorry sim, plus speed cameras]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/star-truckers-anniversary-update-adds-wheel-and-joystick-support-to-the-space-lorry-sim-plus-speed-cameras</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/star-truckers-anniversary-update-adds-wheel-and-joystick-support-to-the-space-lorry-sim-plus-speed-cameras.1288959/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>I'm about to rack up so many fines as I try to drift along the milky highway</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Raw Fury</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/star-trucker">Star Trucker</a>, Raw Fury's answer to what <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/euro-truck-simulator-2%3EEuro%20Truck%20Simulator">Euro Truck Simulator</a> might look like in the year 3000, is now a year old, and has celebrated that fact with an update that finally lets you whip out your wheel and pedals.</p>
<p>Ever since I gave it a go with a controller prior to letting my Game Pass subscription crumble into dust, this is a day I've yearned for. After all, what good are truck sims, be they Euro, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/american-truck-simulator">American</a> or something more <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/snowrunner">Snowrunner</a>y, if you're not operating the controls of your great metal haulage beast by flicking flappy gearbox paddles, or sawing away at a circle clearly designed for something a bit sportier?</p>
<!--more-->
<p>That's what this <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2380050/view/497205194887528952?l=english">anniversary update</a> for the interstellar hauler delivers, with wheels like the Thrustmaster T128 and flight sticks like VKB's Gladiator NXT EVO being early additions to the devs' handy <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/19z_f-lbxQgzQ87M4tpjXOjAFcS3kEX27alN8surU7fM/edit?gid=0#gid=0">tracking sheet</a> of tested peripherals. There's also a <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3560846829&amp;snr=1_5_9_">guide</a> and <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/app/2380050/discussions/0/596285020004455725/?snr=1_5_9_">FAQ rundown</a> from Raw Fury to help folks get their hardware up, running, and fully bound to all the inputs space trucking requires.</p>
<p>Gear recognised by the game should set itself up with default bindings automatically, but I usually find creating my own basic set of essential buttons not that time-consuming, as long as the game wants to acknowledge your wheel exists. Just remember to bind a pause button, and stick the handbrake somewhere your finger can easily hold it when you want to see if your rig can finish a delivery with a 10/10 skid.</p><p>As a counterweight to all the wheel and pedal lorry mischief I planned the minute I clocked this update, it also comes with new speed checks. Yep, cameras, fines, the works. These camera checkpoints along the trails of the galaxy will even show you what speed you're doing as you pass them, though the notes don't mention if you get shown a little smiley face for not blasting through a Jupiter school zone at 120mph. You can also disable these checks via the settings, if the threat of having to attend a speeding course with the crowd from the Mos Eisley cantina is just too much.</p>
<p>Aside from that, there are a couple of updates to trailers, and a couple of optional truck goodies to commemorate the game's first birthday. The latter includes a hologrammatic image of a cake you can display in your cab. Just remember to eat plenty before your next long haul.</p>
<p>If you've not given Star Trucker a go, our Nic dubbed it "a game that's much more about the 'trucker' of it all than the stars, but the trucker of it all really does shine" in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/star-trucker-review">his review</a>, writing:</p>
<blockquote>When you exit the airlock to patch up hull breaches, little white spanner icons mark the offending damage. The symbol that marks the airlock to return to your truck is a home. I noticed it early, and then I kept noticing it. The more I did, the more perfect it felt.</blockquote>
<p>Now, if you'll excuse me, I'm off to oversteer that home into an asteroid belt.</p>

        </div>
      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/star-truckers-anniversary-update-adds-wheel-and-joystick-support-to-the-space-lorry-sim-plus-speed-cameras]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silksong has murdered Steam]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/silksong-has-murdered-steam</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/silksong-has-murdered-steam.1288914/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Valve / Rock Paper Shotgun</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Well, who could have seen this coming: <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hollow-knight-silksong">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a> has taken Steam offline, or at least, laid waste to large swathes of it. Within seconds of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hollow-knight-silksong-is-out-now-on-steam-our-review-is-on-the-way">its release this afternoon</a>, Team Cherry’s <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hollow-knight">Hollow Knight</a> sequel brought Valve's servers to a halt, cue endlessly loading pages when trying to access the checkout, browse the store or do much of anything.
</p><!--more-->
<p>I can’t even sign in. I’m currently staring into the void of an infinite “loading user data” loop. I can’t get the “Most Played” chart to load in a web browser, either, but according to <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1030300/charts/">SteamDB</a>, there are 101,828 people playing already. Smash cut to live footage of Gabe Newell ejected screaming from his exploding yacht, hotly pursued by a cloud of burning hornets. 
</p>
<p>If you’re hoping to play on Steam in the next hour or so, you may encounter the following dread message: "Error Code: 2811-7429. Couldn't connect to the server. The network may be busy, or there may be a problem with the server. Please try again later." There are already thousands of reports of a Steam outage on <a href="https://downdetector.co.uk/status/steam/">Downdetector</a>. Valve have yet to comment. The game is also available on GOG, who have a much smaller audience, but I hear <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/%E2%80%9Dhttps://bsky.app/profile/khonziel.bsky.social/post/3lxzdkzrccs26%E2%80%9D">they’re having similar difficulties</a>. 
</p>
<p>May the good gods save our engineers in this time of Silksinging. May the good gods save them, at least, from wrathful emails. Having to wait an hour or two for demand to die back so you can play Silksong is no great burden. Still, as ever with Steam overloads, you do have to wonder whether Valve as a whole could have prepared better for this. 
</p><p>Silksong has been Steam’s most-wishlisted game since forever. I’m not clear on what Valve do when they know something is going to be mega-popular - I assume it involves buying more servers, but perhaps they just pour energy drinks over the existing ones while uttering the Optimiser’s Prayer. Perhaps they just stick a bike pump in the outer wall of the server farm and have an intern crank the handle for 24 hours.
</p>
<p>If you’re trying to play, best of luck. James claims he’s already got it downloading, but then he’s always trying to be the popular one.
</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/silksong-has-murdered-steam]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>