<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 17:47:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mass Effect 5 devs should "scapegoat" Veilguard and a Dragon Age trilogy remaster was pitched to EA, says ex-BioWare producer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mass-effect-5-devs-should-scapegoat-veilguard-and-a-dragon-age-trilogy-remaster-was-pitched-to-ea-says-ex-bioware-producer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mass-effect-5-devs-should-scapegoat-veilguard-and-a-dragon-age-trilogy-remaster-was-pitched-to-ea-says-ex-bioware-producer.1267287/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"It’s strange for a publicly traded company to basically seem to be against free money"</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>EA / Bioware</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Former <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dragon-age">Dragon Age</a> executive producer Mark Darrah has discussed pitching remasters of the first three games in the series to EA, and made clear in the same interview that he's encourage the developers of the next <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/mass-effect">Mass Effect</a> game to "scapegoat" <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dragon-age-the-veilguard-top-tips-beginners">Dragon Age: The Veilguard</a> "as much as they need to".</p>
<p>Darrah's offered a lot of insight into life at BioWare since departing the studio back in 2022, with the veteran dev having done plenty of that via <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/former-dragon-age-producer-posts-tell-all-video-about-the-messy-birth-of-ea-and-biowares-anthem">his own YouTube channel</a>. This time, though, he was interviewed by YouTuber <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1Pd9OG3HmN0">MrMattyPlays</a>.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Just past the ten minute mark of the chat, Darrah was asked whether he thinks the next Mass Effect game will likely face a "less messy" development cycle than <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-dragon-age-the-veilguard-report-reveals-more-about-turbulent-development-including-forspoken-prompted-shift-from-snark-to-seriousness">the likes of Veilguard have suffered</a>. "To be frank," he responded, "the Mass Effect team is going to be able to point to The Veilguard and say 'We should steer away from some of these things because look what happened.' I would honestly encourage that team to scapegoat Veilguard as much as they need to, to get what they need from the organisation, whether it's true or not."</p>
<p>So, not giving Veilguard's developers - whom Darrah <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/biowares-mark-darrah-thinks-veilguard-is-the-first-dragon-age-where-the-combats-actually-fun">worked with as a consultant</a> and stood up for following the game's release. Instead, just pointing to it in an effort to get dumb execs to stop pushing yet another project in the same problematic directions and learn from some past mistakes.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, slightly further on, Darrah added that he thinks the next step for the Dragon Age series should be remastering the first three games: Origins, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dragon-age-ii">Dragon Age 2</a>, and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dragon-age-inquisition">Inquisition</a>. He also revealed that remastering these games as a "Champions Trilogy" was discussed and soft pitched to EA while he was there, but didn't end up happening for a few reasons.</p>
<p>"EA's historically been and I don't know why, but they've even said this publicly — they're kind of against remasters," Darrah explained, "I don't really know why, and it's strange for a publicly-traded company to seemingly be against free money but they seem to be against it. So that's part of it.</p>
<p>"The other problem is, Dragon Age is harder than Mass Effect to do. To some degree unknowably harder, maybe only a little bit harder, maybe a lot harder. One of the very earliest things for Joplin [the codename for BioWare's earliest version of Dragon Age 4] was let's do Frostbite tools, and then let's find a mod house that seems talented, and just uplift them, and pay them to do a remake of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dragon-age-origins">Dragon Age: Origins</a>."</p>
<p>However, as Darrah went on to outline, that wouldn't fly, because of the "advantages" the series about banging ok has over Dragon Age in terms of being easy to remaster:</p>
<blockquote>One, it's all Unreal instead of two different engines. But actually, just the fact that it's Unreal [engine] means that you can remaster Mass Effect essentially for money. If you're willing to spend money on it, you can go to an external house and they can do most of the work, which is sort of what happened with Legendary Edition. There were a bunch of people at BioWare working on it...I don't know remember how many, but it was not a ton. Whereas, if you're going to do [Dragon Age], you either have to spin up a brand new team that's going to learn this really, really crotchety old tech base, or you've got to do it all in-house.</blockquote>
<p>Sounds like a tough sell to spending-averse execs who Darrah suggests elsewhere in the interview have historically struggled to see the Dragon Age games as potential mainstream hits. Regardless of where it's that or something else, here's hoping Veilguard doesn't end up being the last we ever see of BioWare's lizard era.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mass-effect-5-devs-should-scapegoat-veilguard-and-a-dragon-age-trilogy-remaster-was-pitched-to-ea-says-ex-bioware-producer]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Battlefield 6 beta’s hacking problem shows the difficulty in playing cat and mouse with cheaters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-battlefield-6-betas-hacking-problem-shows-the-difficulty-in-playing-cat-and-mouse-with-cheaters</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-battlefield-6-beta%E2%80%99s-hacking-problem-shows-the-difficulty-in-playing-cat-and-mouse-with-cheaters.1267254/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>A quick defeat for Secure Boot</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>EA</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/battlefield-2025">Battlefield 6</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/with-battlefield-6-beta-queues-stretching-around-the-block-a-substantial-increase-in-server-capacity-should-just-have-helped">open beta</a> is over, and encouraging whispers of its oo-rahhable player count – peaking at over 500,000 on PC alone, so sayeth <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/3081410/charts/">SteamDB</a> – have been tempered with widespread <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/cheaters-already-spotted-in-battlefield-6-open-beta-despite-secure-boot-requirement">reports of invading cheaters</a>. That’s despite BF6’s new and unusual requirement to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-6s-open-beta-makes-enabling-secure-boot-on-your-pc-mandatory-because-cheaters">enable Secure Boot</a>, a BIOS-level security feature in Windows, ostensibly to prevent such do-badding.</p>
<p>In response, a <a href="https://forums.ea.com/discussions/battlefield-6-beta-feedback-en/update-battlefield-6-update-on-secure-boot--cheats/12439803">forum post</a> attributed to EA’s anti-cheat team has played up successes in tracking and catching the beta’s cheaters, whose crimes allegedly range from classic wallhacks, speed hacks, and aimbots to cheats that reduce recoil or display enemy health and weapon info. However, it also concedes that Secure Boot "is not, and was not intended to be a silver bullet" – and in doing so, highlights the immense, perhaps impossible task that developers have of keeping cheater users out of their games.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>I don’t mean to suggest that cheat makers are a breed of impressive technogeniuses. They trade in malevolence for profit, making them almost as big a bunch of loser babies as their customers. But they are persistent, and prideful, so attempts by publishers and developers to big up their latest anti-cheat as being particularly difficult to crack is often seen as a challenge as much as a deterrent. Vanguard, the AC system Riot Games use for their tactical FPS <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/valorant">Valorant</a>, holds a kind of grudgingly respected reputation among players for its relative efficacy, yet cheaters still show up now and then to spoil its shootouts.</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>EA</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>It's true that EA, or BF6 developers DICE, never claimed that requiring Secure Boot would keep hackers out for good. The feature is also just one component of the game’s wider AC protection, named Javelin, which that forum post boasts of having stopped 330,000 cheating and tampering attempts like they were .22 rounds pinging off a tank’s backside. That’s about three successful interventions for every five players, which suggests two things: one, Battlefield 6 faces an absolutely enormous number of malicious actors, and two, if you played the open beta at the weekend, there’s a very good chance that at least one of your games was saved from a cheating attempt.</p>
<p>Some of those numbers were undoubtedly passed around BF6 headquarters as evidence of Javelin’s great success. Except it was also beaten, in a matter of hours, and by a fairly wide variety of different cheats. And anti-cheat systems are a lot like Premier League goalkeepers: you can keep out attempt after attempt, but let just one through and people will think you're rubbish.</p>
<p>I’d argue, then, that the biggest challenge facing multiplayer developers isn’t the pursuit of creating a truly hacker-free game. That, based on current evidence, looks close to impossible. Instead, it’s expectation management: what’s a publicly acceptable proportion of hackers to breach the system, and maybe more importantly, how much can you ask of rule-abiding players before they start getting genuinely pissed off by your AC requirements? What’s a palatable <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blackstone%27s_ratio">Blackstone’s ratio</a> of inconvenienced innocents versus catchable perps?</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>EA</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>So far, there haven’t been any recorded instances of EA – or Riot, whose Vanguard system also goes rooting around in the deepest depths of your PC – using kernel-access anti-cheat for anything untoward. But having to manually enable Secure Boot, especially if you’re not a frequent BIOS spelunker, is enough of a faff that for someone, somewhere, it’s going to chip away at goodwill. There have been recorded instances of user-end problems after the fact, too. The most ironic of which being that Battlefield 6’s anti-cheat can actually <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Battlefield/comments/1mlwcbl/battlefield_6_just_told_me_to_uninstall_valorant/?utm_source=embedv2&amp;utm_medium=post_embed&amp;utm_content=whitespace&amp;embed_host_url=https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-anti-cheat-faces-issues-with-val">clash with Valorant’s</a>, like two hench bouncers trying to fit through the same doorframe. Last year, a more extreme case of 'acceptable loss' calculations saw <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/respawn-have-killed-apex-legends-steam-deck-support-in-the-name-of-anti-cheat">Steam Deck players booted permanently out of Apex Legends</a>, on the grounds that the handheld's Linux-based OS was making it too hard to keep cheaters away.</p>
<p>For now, developers seem to be weighing security more heavily than convenience. Respawn would later, with barely concealed pride, <a href="https://x.com/Respawn/status/1865148176275247312">wheel out an "infection rate" graph</a> as evidence that dropping Linux support was a worthy sacrifice. And as for Battlefield 6... well, their beta just got half a million concurrents. For all the grumbling about Secure Boot, it sure does look like players are happy to go along with it.</p>
<p>Provided, anyway, that it’s in service of an anti-cheat system that broadly works – or at least one that enough people <em>perceive</em> to work. Secure Boot might not be a particularly strong turn-off, but the one thing that gets players quitting faster than being lasered by some prick with X-ray vision is the belief, justified or otherwise, that he or his ilk will show up in the next game too. Battlefield 6 can’t stop every single cheater. But it’ll need to keep quiet the ones that do.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-battlefield-6-betas-hacking-problem-shows-the-difficulty-in-playing-cat-and-mouse-with-cheaters]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>