<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 10:48:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The UN contacted Helldivers 2 studio about giving a talk on "psychological defense against manipulation"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-un-contacted-helldivers-2-studio-about-giving-a-talk-on-psychological-defense-against-manipulation</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-un-contacted-helldivers-2-studio-about-giving-a-talk-on-psychological-defense-against-manipulation.1139823/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-un-contacted-helldivers-2-studio-about-giving-a-talk-on-psychological-defense-against-manipulation<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"We actually try to get people to recognise the science of what is a totalitarian state," says Arrowhead CEO</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/helldivers-2-polar-patriots-warbond.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Arrowhead Game Studios</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Breaking news, folks: <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-co-op-games">co-op</a> bug basher <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/helldivers-2">Helldivers 2</a> is a satire on authoritarian regimes, and apparently such an effective one that the United Nations even contacted Arrowhead to ask if they'd give a talk about psychological manipulation. Speaking at GDC as part of a presentation named 'Helldivers 2: Capturing Lightning in a Bottle,' Chief Easily identifiable satire Officer Johan Pilestedt gave some insight into the game's themes, then bragged about having the UN blowing his DMs constantly (said they got in contact once). Cheers, <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/fps/the-united-nations-asked-helldivers-2-studio-arrowhead-if-itd-give-a-talk-on-psychological-manipulation-could-we-brainwash-an-entire-community-to-fight-for-a-fascist-state-would-we-be-okay-with-that-turns-out-yeah/">Percy Gamer</a>.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Helldivers 2 - Borderline Justice Warbond | PS5 &amp; PC Games" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sr22D9zoRjo?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Helldivers 2 - Borderline Justice Warbond | PS5 &amp; PC Games</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sr22D9zoRjo?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/sr22D9zoRjo?autoplay=1" title="Helldivers 2 - Borderline Justice Warbond | PS5 &amp; PC Games">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sr22D9zoRjo" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>"What is Helldivers 2, fundamentally? It would probably be fun to play a co-op action shooter where you’re put in the shoes of the evil side grunts of pop culture," Pilestedt said. "We asked ourselves, could we brainwash an entire community to fight for a fascist state? Would they? Would we be okay with that? And turns out, yeah, actually."</p>
<p>"We do it all in fun and good spirits, and we actually try to get people to recognise the science of what is a totalitarian state," he said. "If you start wearing the same uniform as everybody else and do salutes constantly, you might be in a totalitarian regime." Pilestedt also told his GDC audience to stop nattering while he was making important points about capes, otherwise he'd get his best mates the UN to come down and sort them out. At least, that's what I imagine happened. "Actually, we got a message from the UN asking if we want to talk, in some form, about psychological defense against manipulation". He didn't elaborate on whether anything actually came of this, however.</p>
<p>Pilestedt went on to say that they pulled aesthetics from the US, the EU, and the UN, alongside "mantras of regimes” like Nazi Germany and North Korea. “It creates pleasing aesthetics,” said Pilestedt, "because there’s something totalitarian regimes are really good at: pleasing aesthetics."</p>
<p>PC Gamer's own use of the words "prevent Helldivers 2 from getting too depressing" in regards to these uniforms is really insightful here, I think - drab deeds in shiny boots being one of fascism's calling cards.</p>
<p>I dislike ending articles with some variation on Howzabout YoU GamErMates ArE You Still Levelling Up For Super Earth?!? (even as these words likely appear above some godforsaken survey that asks you "where you dropping"?) but I'm actually genuinely curious about how the game is these days for people that have been playing since the beginning - I fell off Helldivers 2 for no particular reason months ago and haven't returned since.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Six-armed octopuses and other abyssal horrors from Ark: Survival Evolved's new AI slop trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/six-armed-octopuses-and-other-abyssal-horrors-from-ark-survival-evolveds-new-ai-slop-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/six-armed-octopuses-and-other-abyssal-horrors-from-ark-survival-evolveds-new-ai-slop-trailer.1139814/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/six-armed-octopuses-and-other-abyssal-horrors-from-ark-survival-evolveds-new-ai-slop-trailer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ark-survival-evolved-aquatica-trailer.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Snail Games USA</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>What's the going rate for a flight to attend GDC these days? I ask because I'd have loved to be buzzing my merry way about the convention walls when Snail Games USA unveiled this doozy of an AI-generated trailer for <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/ark-survival-evolved">Ark: Survival Evolved</a>'s Aquatica expansion. I'd give it a solid nine on the "we're not even trying to disguise it any longer" scale. How bad is it? Bad enough that original developers <a href="https://x.com/survivetheark/status/1901846059933942125">Studio Wildcard hastily and firmly distanced themselves</a> from the project, reiterating that their focus was on <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/ark-survival-ascended">ARK: Survival Ascended</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/ark-2">Ark 2</a>.</p>
<p>If I had to sum up the trailer in a single word, I would attempt to write that word out with four-day old regurgitated Alphabetti spaghetti, invariably failing to give voice to my flailing disgust before retiring to the corner to fart at god. This would still take approximately fourteen times more effort than whoever got paid to write "like the ocean, but worse" into their phone to tease out the following results.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="ARK: Aquatica Official Trailer GDC 2025" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/V2eCWWaCzwQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>ARK: Aquatica Official Trailer GDC 2025</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/V2eCWWaCzwQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/V2eCWWaCzwQ?autoplay=1" title="ARK: Aquatica Official Trailer GDC 2025">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V2eCWWaCzwQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>Fans are understandably gobsmacked at the sheer gall of it, as am I, honestly. Nothing builds excitement for a new release like the company behind it proudly declaring they have no respect for the audience's taste or intelligence. It's especially jarring considering Wildcard recently revealed an <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ark-survival-ascendeds-first-expansion-recruits-the-studio-behind-jujutsu-kaisen-for-some-flashy-anime-cutscenes">animated trailer for their Lost Colony expansion by Jujutsu Kaisen studio</a> MAPPA. Now, I'm no art critic, but I do enjoy limbs being shown in correct quantities.</p>
<p>If I can say one positive thing about the trailer, it's that I'm actually nostalgic for the blooming synaptic flora shown at 0:43, because it reminds me of the very early days of GenAI-precursor <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DeepDream">DeepDream</a>, a period where slop could at least have been said to have a distinct aesthetic rather than a distinct odour. I'm also tickled by the shirtless shark riding at 0:56 because, yes, it just looks like the cover of a smut novel about a guy who either fucks sharks or does all his fuckin' on sharkback.</p>
<p>Ah well, there's some comfort to be taken in the immediate and unanimous fan comment backlash at least. Wildcard <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ark-survival-ascended-will-be-sold-without-ark-2-after-backlash-but-will-still-cost-60">haven't been free of controversy themselves</a>, mind, but I suppose we're gradually becoming more wistful and appreciative of honest, artisanal fuck-ups in the face of the alternative. In the meantime, the demoralising assault from all angles on all facets of existence will continue until morale improves.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>