<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:41:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ahead of its early access release this week, Prologue: Go Wayback gets a roadmap filled with big ambitions]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ahead-of-its-early-access-release-this-week-prologue-go-wayback-gets-a-roadmap-filled-with-big-ambitions</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ahead-of-its-early-access-release-this-week-prologue-go-wayback-gets-a-roadmap-filled-with-big-ambitions.1356109/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/prologue-go-wayback-map.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/prologue-go-wayback-map.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/prologue-go-wayback-map.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/prologue-go-wayback-map.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/prologue-go-wayback-map.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/prologue-go-wayback-map.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/prologue-go-wayback-map.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/prologue-go-wayback-map.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/prologue-go-wayback-map.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>PlayerUnknown Productions</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/prologue-go-wayback">Prologue: Go Wayback</a> is due out in early access later this week, and ahead of that developer PlayerUnknown Productions laid out a little roadmap of updates you can expect in the coming… months? They didn't specify, which isn't necessarily a bad thing - I think setting expectations of when certain features may arrive encourages a more demanding audience - but they did give a good overview of what's to come.
</p>
<p>
Starting things off is a list of plans for the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-survival-games-on-pc">survival</a> game's world and environment, which primarily focus on adding "realism, scale, and cohesion to the world." Namely, that includes things like paths and trails that are clearer in how you're meant to navigate them, alongside river systems with "source, tributaries, rapids, and deltas, bringing new movement and life to the world." Eat your heart out, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gcS1HIci4hQ">Any Austin</a>. 
</p>
<p>
And there's also plans for more varied settlements, alongside water that freezes and thaws depending on the weather and season. That one sounds quite neat! I feel like the effects of weather is a thing that many games still don't get quite right yet, hopefully something systems driven like this can have a good crack at it.
</p>
<p>
On the gameplay side of things, there's plans to expand on the game's building system, to add in new ingredients and recipes, make it so that you might need batteries or to repair a power system, and to make it so that clothing can degrade over time, but be fixed too.
</p><p>
More miscellaneously, the <a href="https://playerunknownproductions.net/news/prologue-go-wayback-early-access-roadmap">roadmap</a> also outlines its intention to add in full controller support, Steam Deck support, an in-game camera mode, and for the streamer out there, Twitch integration that allows viewers to mess with spawns and other bits. More ambitiously (and I question whether this will be the game's downfall), the game will also let you build your own worlds, rules, maps, and experiences to share with others. Not everything needs to have user-generated bits, but Prologue: Go Wayback will have them whether it needs them or not.
</p>
<p>
You'll be able to pick up Prologue: Go Wayback when it enters early access November 20th.

</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ahead-of-its-early-access-release-this-week-prologue-go-wayback-gets-a-roadmap-filled-with-big-ambitions]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Where Winds Meet player convinces one of the game's NPCs they're pregnant with his baby]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/where-winds-meet-player-convinces-one-of-the-games-npcs-theyre-pregnant-with-his-baby</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/where-winds-meet-player-convinces-one-of-the-games-npcs-theyre-pregnant-with-his-baby.1355992/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Generative AI, meet videogame players</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Where-Winds-Meet-archer-meeting.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Where-Winds-Meet-archer-meeting.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Where-Winds-Meet-archer-meeting.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Where-Winds-Meet-archer-meeting.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Where-Winds-Meet-archer-meeting.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Where-Winds-Meet-archer-meeting.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Where-Winds-Meet-archer-meeting.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Where-Winds-Meet-archer-meeting.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Where-Winds-Meet-archer-meeting.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun/NetEase Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Sure, you could tease around the edges of generative AI videogame development, spitting out an Anno 117 loading screen here, belching out <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arc-raiders-best-guns-tier-list">Arc Raiders</a> NPC voice barks there, or you could just go the whole hog and hook your characters straight up to an LLM. What could possibly go wrong?</p>
<p>In related news, as reported by <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/rpg/wuxia-mmo-where-winds-meet-is-full-of-ai-chatbot-npcs-and-people-are-doing-all-the-standard-obscene-stuff-to-them-i-made-him-think-that-my-character-was-pregnant-with-his-child/">cheery RPS fanzine PC Gamer</a>, players of Everstone Studios wuxia-themed RPG Where Winds Meet have got NPCs to provide them with <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/WhereWindsMeet/comments/1oy22k0/you_can_chat_with_npcs_and_they_respond_as_an_ai/">cooking advice for potatoes and ketchup</a>, plan a travel itinerary for a trip to Beijing, and they've even <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/WhereWindsMeet/comments/1oxqhuz/anybody_else_mentally_break_the_zhao_dali_ai_just/">convinced one guard that they're pregnant with his baby</a>.</p>
<p>It turns out that when you interact with NPCs in the game, rather than be presented with set options of what to say to the characters, you instead have a chat box in which you're free to type whatever you please. Those lines then are sent off as a prompt to an LLM and then you receive a response somewhat tailored to fit the personality of the character which you're speaking to.</p>
<p>For instance, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/WhereWindsMeet/comments/1oy22k0/you_can_chat_with_npcs_and_they_respond_as_an_ai/">in one interaction shared on Reddit</a>, a player asks "What can I cook at home? I only have ketchup and potatoes". The NPC then replies, "(thinks for a moment, then suggests) You could make fried potatoes and use ketchup as a sauce. It's simple but can be quite tasty." When the player asks if ketchup was available during the Song dynasty, the NPC replies "No, ketchup wasn't available [...]. Tomatoes weren't known in China back then."</p><p>The interactions can lead to tangible outcomes, with <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/WhereWindsMeet/comments/1oyd1gw/been_waiting_for_games_to_use_ai_like_this_lol/">NPCs you anger kicking off fights</a> or increasing your reputation. Though, even then players are finding you don't need to act in good faith, instead simply implying positive actions can be recognised as such. <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/WhereWindsMeet/comments/1oxoe11/comment/noz3ssv/">As one Reddit user points out</a>, if you see a hungry family, telling them "I'll give you food" results in a reputation gain, without needing to actually give them the item.</p>
<p>The players posting to Reddit seem to be happy with the use of AI, with <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/WhereWindsMeet/comments/1oz16tk/comment/npatqla/">one saying</a>, "THIS is how AI should be used in video games. Not to replace artists OR PROGRAMMERS but to have GOOD NPCS." Apparently replacing writers is just fine. As Nic <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/theres-a-future-where-you-and-this-bucket-that-fits-over-your-head-decide-what-a-game-meant-to-say-not-the-useless-idiots-that-made-it">says</a>, "The promised land of never having to experience a game the way it was intended again" is nearly here.</p>
<p>So as not to miss the naffness of this system, while some players are getting roughly in character responses about ketchup and flight plans, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/WhereWindsMeet/comments/1oymfma/teaching_liu_buzhu_some_modern_world_problems/">others are just being presented with rote information about the Godot game engine</a>. This isn't some exciting new frontier for NPC dialogue, it's just the same generic text that pours out of LLMs, it's just appearing in an unusual environment.</p>
<p>Another thing to note is that, unlike Arc Raiders and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/call-of-duty-black-ops">Call of Duty: Black Ops</a> 7, which at least have disclosures on their Steam pages, stating that generative AI was used in the games' development, there is nothing on Where Winds Meet's page revealing this egregious example.</p>
<p>AI tools are clearly not going away and will only become increasingly prevalent, but in Where Winds Meet, we have an example of the immediacy with which generative AI shits the bed when it comes into contact with players.</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/where-winds-meet-player-convinces-one-of-the-games-npcs-theyre-pregnant-with-his-baby]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>