<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 12:19:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Labyrinth Of The Demon King might be the perfect PS1-style horror RPG]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/labyrinth-of-the-demon-king-might-be-the-perfect-ps1-style-horror-rpg</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/labyrinth-of-the-demon-king-might-be-the-perfect-ps1-style-horror-rpg.1191045/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/labyrinth-of-the-demon-king-might-be-the-perfect-ps1-style-horror-rpg<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>King('s Field) of the (Silent) Hill</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Top Hat Studios, Inc</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/labyrinth-of-the-demon-king">Labyrinth Of The Demon King</a> is the concentrated awfulness of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/silent-hill">Silent Hill</a> and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/amnesia-the-dark-descent">Amnesia: The Dark Descent</a> thrown into a toilet bowl with the stamina-based combat of From Software's old King's Field <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPGs</a>. Released this week, it is squalid, lumbering, vicious, desperate and untrustworthy. 
</p>
<p>
The setting is "mythical feudal Japan" - a time of devilry, manual savepoints, and dither filters. The story objective is to track down and slay the yokai boss who led your lord into an ambush. I do not greatly rate my chances. Currently, I am exploring a house full of bloated, whispering fungus and screechy little filthbastards with abbreviated limbs. The filthbastards all want to butcher me but they are no less keen to murder each other. As far as they're concerned, I am just another filthbastard among many. 
</p><!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Labyrinth Of The Demon King - Launch Trailer | PS5 &amp; PS4 Games" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2WXBvuM3efE?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Labyrinth Of The Demon King - Launch Trailer | PS5 &amp; PS4 Games</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2WXBvuM3efE?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/2WXBvuM3efE?autoplay=1" title="Labyrinth Of The Demon King - Launch Trailer | PS5 &amp; PS4 Games">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2WXBvuM3efE" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
My equipment consists of a bottle of sake, some dirty bandages that promise to infect my wounds, and a broken katana that looks like a stick of lichen. My goal right now is to free a self-described blacksmith from the pantry, in the hopes that they will repair my sword. The key is apparently in the possession of a "cat" on the second floor. I do not think the cat will be a nice cat. Usefully, it looks like I can hide in some of the cupboards hereabouts. 
</p>
<p>
There are also crates to smash, some of which harbour cockroaches that must be stamped on before they deduct an infuriating point or two of health. Kicking and stamping are, so far, my favourite activities in Labyrinth Of The Demon King. You can boot enemies to break their guards and avoid being countered, though unhelpfully, this also knocks them out of range of that broken katana. Ah, I really need that blacksmith. I guess there's nothing for it but to investigate the cat. I go looking for the stairs to the second floor and find my way to the basement entrance instead. Haha. I'm not going down there. Fuck no. Nope. No.
</p>
<p>
There are a lot of PS1-style <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-horror-games">horror</a> games on the shop, but so far, Labyrinth Of The Demon King outshines them all, which is to say that there is nothing remotely shiny about it whatsoever. Playing the game is like putting your eye to a plughole. I can't quite dissect what it's doing, but I'm not sure I've played a more convincing encapsulation of the ambience of early Silent Hill. It's in the dithering, of course, but also, the cutscene length and choice of camera angle, the rattling, rolling soundscape, the profusion of locked doors, the presentation of floor maps, and the appallingly sluggish movement.
</p>
<p>
I likes it, in short. There is still a demo on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1804010/Labyrinth_Of_The_Demon_King/">Steam</a>, but be warned that save progress doesn't carry over to the full thing, and you will definitely not appreciate having to retrace your steps.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bungie used an artist's work without permission in Marathon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bungie-used-an-artists-work-without-permission-in-marathon</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bungie-used-an-artists-work-without-permission-in-marathon.1190958/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bungie-used-an-artists-work-without-permission-in-marathon<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>An artist has accused Bungie of plagiarising her designs and using them in upcoming first-person shooter <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/marathon">Marathon</a>. The artist, who creates futuristic posters under the name Antireal (or "4nt1r34l"), posted images of her own work alongside screenshots from Marathon's recent alpha playtest, showing that some designs have been copied. Bungie have confirmed this is the case, but lay the blame on one former artist at the studio.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>"The Marathon alpha released recently and its environments are covered with assets lifted from poster designs i made in 2017," said the artist <a href="https://x.com/4nt1r34l/status/1923067988871147605">on Xitter</a>. "Bungie is of course not obligated to hire me when making a game that draws overwhelmingly from the same design language I have refined for the last decade, but clearly my work was good enough to pillage for ideas and plaster all over their game without pay or attribution."</p>
<figure>

<figcaption>The artist compares her work to the designs present in the game. | <span>Image credit: <cite>Antireal</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The images she shares as proof clearly show elements from her posters reused without alteration on objects in the extraction shooter, like walls, containers, and tarpaulins. Another image she made seems to be the basis for designs used during <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bungie-are-gearing-up-to-reveal-something-about-marathon">Marathon's ARG in April</a> and on the game's official website. You can even make out the artist's handle "Antireal" in one of the offending game assets, as <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/billain.bsky.social/post/3lpafnqfaa22x">pointed out by one of her fans</a>. Several of the artists at Bungie, including art director Joseph Cross, have been following the independent artist on social media while working on the game.</p>
<p>"I don't have the resources nor the energy to spare to pursue this legally," she says, "but I have lost count of the number of times a major company has deemed it easier to pay a designer to imitate or steal my work than to write me an email. </p>
<p>"In 10 years I have never made a consistent income from this work and I am tired of designers from huge companies moodboarding and parasitising my designs while I struggle to make a living."</p>
<p>Bungie have responded to the artist's complaints. They say it's true that her work appeared in the game's alpha, but claim this was an "oversight" and only one former employee from their art team is responsible. </p>
<p>"We immediately investigated a concern regarding unauthorized use of artist decals in Marathon and confirmed that a former Bungie artist included these in a texture sheet that was ultimately used in-game," said the studio in <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/marathonteam.bungie.net/post/3lpb36jqb5c22">a post on social media</a>. "This issue was unknown by our existing art team, and we are still reviewing how this oversight occurred. We take matters like this very seriously. We have reached out to 4nt1r34l to discuss this issue and are committed to do right by the artist.</p>
<p>"As a matter of policy, we do not use the work of artists without their permission."</p>
<p>But policy is one thing and practice is another. This is the 4th time an artist has come forward to complain that Bungie have used their work without permission, as pointed out by <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/fps/artist-accuses-bungie-of-stealing-her-designs-for-marathons-art-i-am-tired-of-designers-from-huge-companies-moodboarding-and-parasitising-my-designs-while-i-struggle-to-make-a-living/">PC Gamer</a>. Last year, they <a href="https://x.com/Destiny2Team/status/1833988238912155813">copied the designs of a Nerf gun</a> in a case that was eventually resolved. In 2023 they <a href="https://x.com/ELEMENTJ21/status/1671281580831297536">copied a design by digital artist Julian Faylona</a> for a <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/destiny-2">Destiny 2</a> cutscene. And in 2021 they used <a href="https://x.com/relay314/status/1441825409562120201">a fan's art</a> in a trailer without asking. Bungie also still face <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/bungie-has-motion-to-dismiss-destiny-2-copyright-lawsuit-denied-over-vaulted-campaign-storyline">a copyright lawsuit by a writer</a> who alleges the game's Red War storyline stole from his ideas (although it should be said this case is not so cut and dry as the above art nabbings).</p>
<p>Bungie say they will take steps to prevent things like this happening again, and that they'll go through the work of the bus-undered employee to make sure there are not other cases of plagiarism. </p>
<p>"To prevent similar issues in the future, we are conducting a thorough review of our in-game assets, specifically those done by the former Bungie artist, and implementing stricter checks to document all artist contributions.</p>
<p>"We value the creativity and dedication of all artists who contribute to our games, and we are committed to doing right by them."</p>
<p>It might be fair to read such promises with a wary eye, given the studio's recent record. If you like Marathon's design style, you might enjoy the original work of Antireal, whose posters are <a href="https://antireal.info/">viewable on her website</a>. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA 6 release won't be delayed again now that it has a "specific date", assures Take-Two boss]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gta-6-release-wont-be-delayed-again-now-that-it-has-a-specific-date-assures-take-two-boss</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gta-6-release-wont-be-delayed-again-now-that-it-has-a-specific-date-assures-take-two-boss.1190955/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gta-6-release-wont-be-delayed-again-now-that-it-has-a-specific-date-assures-take-two-boss<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Also hails second GTA 6 trailer's impact on popular culture</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Take-Two Interactive</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Take-Two Interactive's CEO Strauss Zelnick has served up some dutiful, investor-pleasing sentiments about <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gta-6-everything-we-know">GTA 6</a>'s <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gta-6-has-been-delayed-even-though-take-two-boss-kept-telling-everyone-it-wouldnt-be">delay from 2025 release to a 26th May 2026 launch date</a>. Rockstar, he says, are "seeking perfection", and "consumer anticipation is unprecedented". As such, "affording Rockstar additional time for such a groundbreaking project is a worthy investment".</p>
<p>All that's from a hot mix of Take-Two Interactive's latest quarterly financial results and an interview with our colleagues/primordial mythical adversaries at the Ice Giant Network. Speaking to <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/take-two-ceo-says-delays-pain-me-how-could-they-not-but-insists-gta-6s-new-2026-release-date-was-about-making-sure-rockstar-achieves-its-creative-vision-with-no-limitations">IGN</a>, Zelnick commented that the need for "continued polish became clear" as the game neared completion, and that "there was an opportunity with a small amount of incremental time, we thought, to make sure Rockstar Games achieves its creative vision with no limitations."</p>
<p>Regarding the inevitable question of whether GTA 6 will be delayed again, he added that "historically when we set a specific date, generally speaking, we've been very good about reaching it." Which is possibly more true in console land: <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/grand-theft-auto-v">GTA 5</a> was pushed back once on console from its initial spring window to 17th September 2013, but the PC version didn't arrive till 14th April 2015.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://ir.take2games.com/static-files/1519320d-9555-4bdf-bc7a-44791b7f0dd3">the earnings presentation</a>, Zelnick reiterated that "affording Rockstar additional time for such a groundbreaking project is a worthy investment". He also threw in a bit of trivia. Apparently, GTA 6 "began development in earnest in 2020" after <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/red-dead-redemption-2">Red Dead Redemption 2</a>. The <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grand-theft-auto-6-gets-a-second-trailer-but-theres-still-no-date-for-a-pc-version">recent second GTA 6 trailer</a> is supposedly the "biggest video launch of all time, with over 475 million views in 24 hours". Spotify streams of the song from that trailer, Hot Together by the Pointer Sisters, have "surged by 182,000%, once again proving Rockstar's ability to influence popular culture".</p>
<p>This is probably my 9am brain talking, but I find this last point sort of provocative inasmuch as right now, I'm scratching my head a little about the specifics of GTA's cultural impact. It <em>is</em> an undeniable influence on popular culture, be it in the form of moral panics about kiddies playing crime simulators, or in how its urban sandbox has influenced <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-open-world-games">open world</a> designers, or in the vast extent of the modding community, or - yes - in how it has <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xAgUYyosqVM">popularised certain songs</a>.</p>
<p>That said, and for all the game's stature, GTA today is innately and proudly derivative. It skims the froth of American life, sometimes satirically in the form of, say, <a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/gta-5/Bleeter">Bleeter</a>, and often affectionately in the form of nods to celebrated movies and TV shows - GTA 6's star couple Jason and Lucia are <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-anti-heroes-of-grand-theft-auto-6-look-sexy-and-dull">influencer incarnations of Bonnie and Clyde</a>. One consequence of that is a certain hollowness.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>