<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 12:43:24 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Total War: Warhammer 3 fans reckon they've already guessed which faction is coming next in Tides Of Torment]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/total-war-warhammer-3-fans-reckon-theyve-already-guessed-which-faction-is-coming-next-in-tides-of-torment</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/total-war-warhammer-3-fans-reckon-theyve-already-guessed-which-faction-is-coming-next-in-tides-of-torment.1199268/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/total-war-warhammer-3-fans-reckon-theyve-already-guessed-which-faction-is-coming-next-in-tides-of-torment<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Not penguin beastman, sadly</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Creative Assembly/Rock Paper Shotgun</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Last week's Warhammer Skulls brought announcements for a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-leagues-of-votann-are-coming-to-warhammer-40000-mechanicus-2">new Mechanicus 2 ally faction</a>, a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-strategy-games-on-pc">strategy</a> remaster in the form of the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/relic-reveal-warhammer-40000-dawn-of-war-definitive-edition-with-full-dlc-and-mod-support">first Dawn Of War and all expansions</a>, and a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/warhammer-40000-boltgun-2-is-coming-2026-but-theres-a-typing-of-the-dead-esque-spinoff-you-can-play-for-free-right-now">free Boltgun typing game</a> in which you tap out phrases like 'emperor' and 'thin your paints' to chainsword cultists. Nestled away in the recesses of that skull, like a coiled snake on a tattoo with the name of someone's pug on it, was a teaser for the next <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/total-war-warhammer-iii">Total War: Warhammer 3</a> DLC. Here's that teaser.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Total War: WARHAMMER III - Tides of Torment - Teaser Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zQNKhxbQKuM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Total War: WARHAMMER III - Tides of Torment - Teaser Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zQNKhxbQKuM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/zQNKhxbQKuM?autoplay=1" title="Total War: WARHAMMER III - Tides of Torment - Teaser Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zQNKhxbQKuM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>The hooded zap lad is Sayl the Faithless, a Norscan sorcerer famous for interrupting rituals and turning the attendant spellcasters into chaos spawn. It was fairly slight and esoteric as far as trailers go, but Creative Assembly followed it up with one of those <a href="https://youtu.be/-wN0zM9gp-s">casual sofa talks</a> full of highly curated information and soundbites about how unbeatable their benefits package and workplace satisfaction is.</p>
<p>There was some good stuff in there, in terms of detail. We already knew about Slaanesh's appearance in the DLC, and now it's double-confirmed Norsca will be joining. Sayl's campaign is focused on manipulation, there'll be more monster hunts for Throgg and Seafang raiding from Wulfric, and both are getting new voicelines.</p>
<p>Not mentioned was the DLC's third faction but, as chronicled in a swathe of Reddit posts and <a href="https://youtu.be/BkfUHF2n9jQ">content creator videos</a>, the community seems more or less certain on what that faction is: the high elves, specifically elf naval commander <a href="https://warhammerfantasy.fandom.com/wiki/Aislinn">Aislinn</a>. He likes tides, 'tides' is in the name, the missing High Elf units from the game include naval-themed centerpieces like the Merwyrm and the Skycutter, there's thematic connections there with Slaanesh, people like elves, and so on. Norsca like to raid on boats, Slaanesh likes to lick boats (canon), elves like to ride boats. It all lines up. I also get the impression Creative Assembly like including at least one good guy or neutral faction in these packs too, just for balance. Things get a bit monochrome and grim if it's all chaos, all the time.</p>
<p>There was another notable in that video, too: all the developers interviewed were from CA Sofia, the sister studio previously responsible for games like Pharaoh and Troy, who seem largely to have been moved on to Twarhammer DLC duty since the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sega-sells-company-of-heroes-developer-relic-and-lays-off-more-staff-at-creative-assembly-and-hardlight">big shake ups at CA last year</a> following the cancellation of Hyenas. This could mean that there's multiple expansions in the works, requiring the attention of director Rich Aldridge and the UK team. Or, it could mean that Alridge and his team are already busy on other, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/future-creative-assembly-games-may-require-blood-thematically-which-sure-sounds-like-a-total-war-warhammer-40000-teaser">more power-armoured Games Workshop adaptations</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The WRC games rally behind a new publisher weeks after being dumped by EA]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-wrc-games-rally-behind-a-new-publisher-weeks-after-being-dumped-by-ea</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-wrc-games-rally-behind-a-new-publisher-weeks-after-being-dumped-by-ea.1199256/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-wrc-games-rally-behind-a-new-publisher-weeks-after-being-dumped-by-ea<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Going back to an old flame</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Nacon</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The dirt-speckled WRC <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-racing-games">racing games</a> that were <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ea-arent-making-any-more-rally-games-but-there-are-alternatives">dumped by Electronic Arts</a> a few weeks ago have already found a new partner in Nacon. The French publishers are promising a "complete reboot" of the rally game series, and have exclusive rights on the grubby wheelspinners until at least 2032. This isn't the first time the publisher have had stewardship of the WRC either, so it all kinda makes sense.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>"Nacon is pleased to announce the signing of a new agreement with WRC Promoter for the publishing of games based on the FIA World Rally Championship," they said in <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/05/26/3088220/0/en/PRESS-RELEASE-NACON-ANNOUNCES-AGREEMENT-WITH-WRC-PROMOTER-FOR-THE-PUBLISHING-OF-THE-OFFICIAL-GAMES-OF-THE-FIA-WORLD-RALLY-CHAMPIONSHIP-FROM-2027-TO-2032.html">a press release</a>. "The agreement covers the development and publishing of the official WRC games and eSports competitions, granting Nacon exclusive rights for PC and consoles for six seasons, from 2027 through 2032.</p>
<p>"The games will feature the official rallies, vehicles, teams, drivers, and sponsors among the many anticipated content elements. This project represents a complete reboot of the franchise, based on an entirely fresh vision, and marks an ambitious new chapter in the brand’s development." </p>
<figure>

</figure>
<p>They don't yet say which studio, in-house or otherwise, will actually develop the vroomy vrooms. But Nacon are the owners of Kylotonn, as <a "="" a-month-after-electronic-arts-mashed-the-brakes-wrc-rally-racing-games-are-coming-back-with-a-complete-reboot-under-a-new-publisher="" games="" href-"https:="" racing="" www.pcgamer.com="">PC Gamer point out</a>. Aka, the developers who previously made WRC games for a long time, including WRC 10 in 2021 and WRC Generations in 2022. So the most likely outcome is that the games will be handed back to them. </p>
<p>Meanwhile, the governing body of the rally championship, the FIA (Federation Internationale de l'Automobile), seem happy enough to bounce back to old partners.</p>
<p>"After a comprehensive evaluation, we are delighted to have reached an agreement with Nacon," said a marketing chief. "Their vision for the franchise stands out, and their expertise in delivering great rally games is unquestioned."</p>
<p>Well, it is a <em>little</em> questioned. Their most recent game, Test Drive Unlimited Solar Crown was badly received, with players complaining about dead servers, crashes, grind, and a lack of an offline single player mode. It's sitting at a "mostly negative" average on Steam. Their last rally game, WRC Generations, has a "mixed" review average. Perhaps now is the time to check out all those other cool little indie rally games, like <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/drive-rally-blends-wrc-seriousness-with-arcade-cheer">#Drive Rally</a> or <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/parking-garage-rally-circuit">Parking Garage Rally Circuit</a> or <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/550320/art_of_rally/">Art Of Rally</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>