<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:30:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It's almost Christmas, which means it's time to play Skeal]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/its-almost-christmas-which-means-its-time-to-play-skeal</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/its-almost-christmas-which-means-its-time-to-play-skeal.1058535/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/its-almost-christmas-which-means-its-time-to-play-skeal<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
  

        <p>A daft joke and an annual RPS Christmas tradition</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/skeal-header.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>RPS / Nick Cummings</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Creation is an act of kindness. One person sloughs off a piece of themselves, shapes it, wraps it, and sends it out into the world in the hope that it might mean something to someone else. Other people do this for us all the time and mostly we don't even notice. The work is unseen and unremarked upon even as, through repetition, we come to depend upon it. Until, one day, that light that they shine can't be seen. Maybe you left home, or maybe they did, but now it's your turn to perform such acts of kindness. To carry the tradition forward for others - and for yourself.
</p>
<p>Friends, it's time to play <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/skeal">Skeal</a>.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Playing Skeal at Christmas is an annual RPS tradition, created by Alice O and written about by her in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/skeal-free-skiing-game">2017</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/skeal-comedy-skiing-game">2018</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-is-your-annual-reminder-to-play-skeal-this-christmas">2019</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/merry-christmas-its-time-to-play-skeal">2020</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/its-not-christmas-until-youve-played-skeal">2021</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/skeal-reflects-the-power-pleasure-and-pain-of-all-our-christmasses">2022</a>, and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/here-we-go-ho-ho-its-time-for-your-annual-play-of-skeal">2023</a>. Alice <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/alice0-is-leaving-rps-come-and-celebrate-her-work-and-make-lamentation">departed RPS back in April</a>, so I am continuing it in her stead.
</p>
<p>Skeal is a short, free joke created by Nick Cummings which you can <a href="https://whymog.itch.io/skeal-webgl-version">play in your browser</a>. It'll take you five minutes. Go do it now.
</p>
<p>Ah, that's fun, isn't it. A bit of silly wordplay blown up and out in a way that causes the delight to stack and multiply. Every year I forget the details of it, and every year I smile the first time I miss a gate and the "Pain" counter appears in the top left. 
</p><p>We play Skeal every year and invite you to do the same as a little marker in the closing season. I play every year, but in many ways the tradition begins for me long before I actually head over to Itch to find the game. It begins early in December when I first recall the tradition and start to sing around my kitchen. The mere thought of Skeal has become a prompt for reflection on where I've been and where I am. Briefly put? RPS, you remain my power, my pleasure, my pain.
</p>
<p>The nature of traditions is that we get to choose which we continue and which we don't. Alice O also played <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rock-around-the-christmas-tree-with-dracula-cha-cha-and-christmas-pain-in-christmas-town">Dracula Cha Cha and Christmas Pain in Christmas Town</a> each December - fine traditions! - but I have let them go, for this year at least. 
</p>
<p>Of course, we likewise get to create new traditions of our own, should we want to. Who knows what Nic, Edwin, James and Ed might cook up in the months and years to come? That is for them to decide. For me, for now, I Skeal.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Curiosmos is a galactic playground of planet creation and creature evolution]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/curiosmos-is-a-galactic-playground-of-planet-creation-and-creature-evolution</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/curiosmos-is-a-galactic-playground-of-planet-creation-and-creature-evolution.1058496/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/curiosmos-is-a-galactic-playground-of-planet-creation-and-creature-evolution<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Spore without the boring bits?</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/curiosmos.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Céline &amp; The Silly Stars</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Infamous evolutionary flop <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/spore">Spore</a>, for all its flaws, still had a lot of magic to it. It was fun to design your weird creatures, to watch them try to walk, and - in principle - to turn your humble creations into a spacefaring species.
</p>
<p>Curiosmos is a very different game, but it has a little of the same appeal. It's a galactic playground in which you smash meteors together to make planets, then tinker with the ecosystems of those planets to make life and watch that life evolve. All while a hungry black hole lingers nearby, eager to consume everything you have created. There's an explanatory video below.
</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Day Of the Devs - The Game Awards Edition" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7DszPyueOL4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Day Of the Devs - The Game Awards Edition</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7DszPyueOL4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/7DszPyueOL4?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>The Curiosmos overview begins at 1h 37m in the Day Of The Devs stream above.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7DszPyueOL4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>I drew comparisons with Spore, a game which tried to do everything, so I should stress that it doesn't look like you're directly creating the life that can wander about your planets. Instead, you seem to interact with the physics and elements of the solar system. For example, you can drag a cloud around to spread rainwater across the surface of a planet, perhaps turning it into an ocean world or simply making flowers grow.
</p>
<p>There's a playfulness to every interaction which I really enjoy. Don't like one of those flowers? Pluck it from the ground and toss it into deep space.
</p>
<p>It looks like a delightful playground, but there does seem to be some objectives and story to it. You're guided, somewhat, by a satellite called Curio, who apparently has some plan for dealing with the black hole that wants to devour everything. 
</p>
<p>There's no release date yet - and a lot of the footage used in the Day Of The Devs video comes from trailers released earlier this year - but you can <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2585710/Curiosmos/">follow the game on Steam</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hyper Light Breaker, the co-op, open world 3D prequel, will launch in Early Access in January]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hyper-light-breaker-the-co-op-open-world-3d-prequel-will-launch-in-early-access-in-january</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hyper-light-breaker-the-co-op-open-world-3d-prequel-will-launch-in-early-access-in-january.1058469/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hyper-light-breaker-the-co-op-open-world-3d-prequel-will-launch-in-early-access-in-january<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
  

        <p>All the better to Hyper Light Fixit</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hyper-light-breaker_jw3D8Rn.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Heart Machine</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hyper-light-breaker">Hyper Light Breaker</a> is a prequel to the excellent topdown action-RPG from 2016, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hyper-light-drifter">Hyper Light Drifter</a>. The differences are myriad, given that Breaker is also 3D, open world, co-op and a roguelite. It also now has a release date for its launch into Steam Early Access: January 14th, 2025.
</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Hyper Light Breaker - Official Early Access Release Date Reveal Trailer | Day of the Devs 2024" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yFfWFRl0Vd0?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Hyper Light Breaker - Official Early Access Release Date Reveal Trailer | Day of the Devs 2024</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yFfWFRl0Vd0?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/yFfWFRl0Vd0?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Hyper Light Breaker early access release date trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yFfWFRl0Vd0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>The "Breakers" of the title are an organisation of warriors and explorers attempting to save the world after a war. What those Breakers do, and where its similar to its predecessor, is explore a world full of strange, abandoned buildings, with a plentiful sense of mystery. You'll also scavenge items that you can use to create your character build and change how you approach combat, and that combat is a mixture of ranged and melee with combos and parries.
</p>
<p>I loved Hyper Light Drifter, but it's always a worry when a game makes the leap to a new medium - and 3D, in many ways, is a different medium than 2D. Ed <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/solar-ash">didn't love Heart Machine's last third-person action game Solar Ash</a>, and Edwin was not reassured <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hyper-light-breakers-3d-reworking-of-drifters-combat-is-promising-but-a-little-raw">by his Hyper Light Breaker hands-on</a> from back in March.
</p><p>"In general, I found my character to be unwieldy and a little unresponsive," wrote Edwin. "Equipped with dual knives and a pistol, they're one of several classes you'll be able to choose from in Breaker's final form, so perhaps I simply drew the short straw this time round. However, while the conspicuous recovery times of your attack and damage animations nudges you to memorise the inputs and avoid over-committing, Breaker's delays feel a little too drawn-out versus the overall floridity and fluidity of its presentation."
</p>
<p>I have hope in my heart (machine) all the same. It'll have had nearly another year of development by the time it launches, and it'll still be Early Access even at that. Plus, if Risk Of Rain can successfully leap into the third dimension, anything can.
</p>
<p>You'll find more on Hyper Light Breaker <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1534840/Hyper_Light_Breaker/">on its Steam page</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TankHead offers vehicle combat in a sci-fi world where you scavenge parts from your enemies]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tankhead-offers-vehicle-combat-in-a-sci-fi-world-where-you-scavenge-parts-from-your-enemies</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tankhead-offers-vehicle-combat-in-a-sci-fi-world-where-you-scavenge-parts-from-your-enemies.1058436/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tankhead-offers-vehicle-combat-in-a-sci-fi-world-where-you-scavenge-parts-from-your-enemies<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Surprise release during Day Of The Devs</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/tankhead-1v4nf.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Alpha Channel</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>One of video game's greatest pleasures is being able to shoot bits off an enemy and then append them to yourself. TankHead gets it. It's about steering a tank through a desolate sci-fi landscape, blasting similar tank and mecha enemies to bits, then scavenging them for parts using a drone.
</p>
<p>It's been in quiet development for years, but it got a big reveal during tonight's Day Of The Devs stream. It was also <em>released</em> during tonight's Day Of The Devs stream, so you can buy it from <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/tankhead-2f3b51">the Epic Games Store now</a>.
</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="TankHead - Launch Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fyZo9AC0bsM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>TankHead - Launch Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fyZo9AC0bsM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/fyZo9AC0bsM?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>TankHead trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fyZo9AC0bsM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"As Whitaker your goal is to fight to reach Highpoint, to do that you must traverse the ECA – an area where humans cannot survive. Whitaker must project his mind into a Needle, a robust drone capable of surviving in the harsh conditions of the ECA – and of piloting your Tank," explains the store page. "Use your Needle and Tank to combat the vehicles and creatures of the ECA to reach Highpoint."
</p><p>The tank combat is tactical in the ways you might expect if you've ever shot a tank in a video game before. Some areas of your machine are more armoured than others, so you need to try to keep those angled towards enemies to protect your vulnerable engine. Enemies, likewise, can have their outer shells chipped off, revealing the sweet weak spots within. 
</p>
<p>I'm really a fan of the production design, here. The look of the tanks, the robots, the drones, the larger boss you fight; it's all just a little unexpected, a little odd, in a way that suggests a world worth exploring. That plus <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/captain-forever">Captain Forever</a>-style your-bits-are-my-bits-now action, and I really want to try this.
</p>
<p>TankHead was the recepient of an Epic development grant, which presumably accounts for its Epic Games Store-only release at this stage. With a launch discount, it'll currently cost you £20.74.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>