<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 12:13:51 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The supposed secret best Japanese RPG gets a full remake in September]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-supposed-secret-best-japanese-rpg-gets-a-full-remake-in-september</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-supposed-secret-best-japanese-rpg-gets-a-full-remake-in-september.1182984/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-supposed-secret-best-japanese-rpg-gets-a-full-remake-in-september<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>GungHo Online Entertainment America, Inc</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Sponge away the dross and ephemera of my life and you're left with a series of moments in which I wonder: is <em>now</em> the right time to get into <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/video-game-franchises/the-legend-of-heroes">Legend of Heroes</a>? I've been planning to play Nihon Falcom's 17-part <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> series ever since a respected peer gently suggested that my enthusiasm for Final Fantasy and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dragon-quest">Dragon Quest</a> marked me out as a Basic Bitch, and that if I ever want to experience a <em>real</em> role-playing game, I should give LoH a go.
</p><!--more-->
<p>
I am held back by a number of things: 1) the Legend Of Heroes games are mega-normous, possibly 2) because they're meandering and overstuffed, for all their quality, and 3) nobody I've spoken to can agree on which I should start with. I did have a breakthrough recently, coming to the conclusion that I should get the ball rolling with The Legend Of Heroes: Trails In The Sky, the sixth game from 2004 - it's the one I see most often in GOAT threads, and the first in a distinct subseries. But now Nihon Falcom have ruined everything by plotting to remake it. Titled <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/trails-in-the-sky-1st-chapter">Trails In The Sky 1st Chapter</a>, the remake will launch on 19th September (as revealed in Famitsu, via <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/trails-in-the-sky-1st-chapter-launches-september-19">Gematsu</a>). Here's the most recent trailer.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Trails in the Sky 1st Chapter - Voice Cast Announcement Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nYiKVR3TNp8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Trails in the Sky 1st Chapter - Voice Cast Announcement Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nYiKVR3TNp8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/nYiKVR3TNp8?autoplay=1" title="Trails in the Sky 1st Chapter - Voice Cast Announcement Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nYiKVR3TNp8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
If you're familiar with Trails In The Sky, the key differences here are: new HD visuals, new voiceovers, and "the choice of traditional turn-based combat or all-new, real-time action combat", as per <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3375780/Trails_in_the_Sky_1st_Chapter/">the Steam page</a>. Great: not only do I now have to decide whether to play the original game or the remake first, I also now have to pick between old and new flavours of battling. Why do you vex me, Nihon Falcom.
</p>
<p>
The one thing I consistently hear about the Trails games is that the NPC and world writing are absolutely excellent: generous to the point of exhausting, with every NPC worth returning to. If you've played it, please do not leave a comment expounding upon these or any other virtues. It will only add to my choice paralysis. I've read that anger freezes into depression if left unexpressed. Is there a point where FOMO metamorphs into a full-on midlife crisis?
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA 6's animations have improved, says original GTA programmer: "things are moving much better"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gta-6s-animations-have-improved-says-original-gta-programmer-things-are-moving-much-better</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gta-6s-animations-have-improved-says-original-gta-programmer-things-are-moving-much-better.1182960/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gta-6s-animations-have-improved-says-original-gta-programmer-things-are-moving-much-better<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>OG DMA Design guy comments on second trailer</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Take-Two Interactive</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
One of the programmers behind the very first <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/grand-theft-auto">Grand Theft Auto</a> has praised Rockstar for <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grand-theft-auto-6-gets-a-second-trailer-but-theres-still-no-date-for-a-pc-version">delaying </a><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gta-6-everything-we-know">GTA 6</a>'s initial release to May next year, observing (not in so many words) that the developers could have rushed out an early release consisting of a city's worth of T-posing NPCs and whitebox freeways, and people would still have paid top dollar for the game. 
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
Posting on social media, DMA Design founder (and former Lemmings developer) Mike Dailly also suggested that the Miami-based <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-open-world-games">open world game</a>'s latest trailer is a bump in animation quality over the announcement video from 2023. I know, I know: video game looks better as it gets closer to release - more at eleven. Still, I have a certain amount of nerdy interest in how, exactly, GTA 6's animations may have come along.</p>
<p>Let's rattle through those trailers again. Here's the one from 2023.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Grand Theft Auto VI Trailer 1" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QdBZY2fkU-0?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Grand Theft Auto VI Trailer 1</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QdBZY2fkU-0?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/QdBZY2fkU-0?autoplay=1" title="Grand Theft Auto VI Trailer 1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QdBZY2fkU-0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
Dailly had this to say on <a href="https://x.com/mdf200/status/1731946221030252614">Xitter</a> of the announcement trailer. "Looks pretty, but the animations...bloody hell guys. Can't you animate things properly? No one moves like that!" Ooft, paging the burn ward! Flash forward to this month, and Dailly's open-ended concerns appear to have been addressed by the second trailer, below. 
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Grand Theft Auto VI Trailer 2" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VQRLujxTm3c?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Grand Theft Auto VI Trailer 2</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VQRLujxTm3c?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/VQRLujxTm3c?autoplay=1" title="Grand Theft Auto VI Trailer 2">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VQRLujxTm3c" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
"Now that's more like it," Dailly wrote on <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/mdf200.bsky.social/post/3loj2dmckgs2v">Bluesky</a> yesterday. "That environment is lovely, and things are moving much better... Even if they'd released it broken, it'd still have sold hugely. So it's even more impressive they took the decision to delay it."
</p>
<p>
I am not a computer wizard equipped to conjure sweaty screenfuls of buttock from the sexless insides of a PS5 using the power of maths, but I'll be honest, I don't see an enormous gulf between trailers, beyond the differing presentation and music choice.</p>
<p>Well, I think the bit in the first one where Lucia waves her arms around while standing up in the roofless car looks a bit... impressionistic, like she's trying to conduct an invisible orchestra. But come now, Mike, I don't think it's fair to body-shame an ex-con fresh out of jail because she looks a bit unsteady while sticking her arms out of a moving vehicle. She's trying to blow off some steam, Mike! Besides, perhaps there <em>is</em> an invisible orchestra in the game.</p>
<p>Here are some other arbitrary micro-comparisons: Trailer 1 has flappier bottoms. Trailer 2 has more impetuous playful shoving. Trailer 1 has more heartfelt soul brother handshakes. Trailer 2 has... no crocodiles. Perhaps that crocodile walk cycle can serve as a critical yardstick once GTA 6 releases on console next year (PC release date, as ever, to follow). In the meantime, I welcome your mealy-minded feats of frame analysis.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>