<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 10:54:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dark fantasy bomb-making sim「TERROR」type:【A.L.C.H.E.M.Y.】’s frightful title cannot spoil its crusty 90s vibes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dark-fantasy-bomb-making-simterrortypealchemys-frightful-title-cannot-spoil-its-crusty-90s-vibes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dark-fantasy-bomb-making-sim%E3%80%8Cterror%E3%80%8Dtype-%E3%80%90a-l-c-h-e-m-y-%E3%80%91%E2%80%99s-frightful-title-cannot-spoil-its-crusty-90s-vibes.1357681/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Woke up and chose V.I.O.L.E.N.C.E.</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_tA4yviC.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_tA4yviC.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_tA4yviC.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_tA4yviC.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_tA4yviC.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_tA4yviC.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_tA4yviC.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_tA4yviC.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_tA4yviC.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>The Dark Union</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
The Rock Paper Shotgun CMS groaned like a harpooned whale when I fed the above game title into our database. I was tempted to shave away some punctuation for the benefit of whoever writes about this game next, but then I remembered that I hate everybody here as I do hell, all Montagues, and thee. Anyway, what a title. It's like Type Moon and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/kingdom-hearts">Kingdom Hearts</a> fell into a cyberpunk snakepit.</p>
<p>I don't even know what half the characters are called. They appear malevolently polarised, pushing other letters away from them. They seem... primordial somehow. Our distant ancestors used to hack brackets like those into the walls of caverns, when they wished to add inessential tips about flint storage to paintings of hunters getting tusked by mammoths. 
</p><!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="「TERROR」type:【A.L.C.H.E.M.Y.】trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9iaylbyS2I8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>「TERROR」type:【A.L.C.H.E.M.Y.】trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9iaylbyS2I8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9iaylbyS2I8?autoplay=1" title="「TERROR」type:【A.L.C.H.E.M.Y.】trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9iaylbyS2I8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>
The game beneath is appropriately arcane. Devised by <a href="https://dark-union.org/">The Dark Union</a> - whose official website resounds with monastic chanting and has an About page containing doomy philosophical maxims about bees - it's a third-person "story-driven stealth action immersive sim" in which you play a holy alchemist, Auronika Cortez.</p><p>Her goal is to topple the rulers of a rainy, "medieval-industrial" world of tunnels and ramparts prowled by soldiers brandishing crystal rifles. Your principle weapon is your ability to fashion bits of trash into potions and bombs. The bombs are <em>exceedingly</em> explosive. This is not one of those shooters where you hop back a few paces back after lobbing some C4 at a cave-in. You park your butt behind a nice thick wall. 
</p>
<p>
The demo on Steam leaves me mixed about the cleverness of the immersive simming - I spent a lot of time crouching and running away from guttural guard chatter - but I love the A.E.S.T.H.E.T.I.C. This includes what are probably very strenously observed "technical limitations". The intro cinematic yearns for an era in FMV when developers might luxuriate in the spectacle of individual hair follicles but had yet to animate them. In-game, I was pleased to find that I could back into a corner and poke the camera through my character's skull, to see her pasted-on face from the inside. Kids these days will never understand such delights.
</p>
<p>
Your health gauge is a clump of glaring cybermetal, screwed into the bottom right corner, while item and status notifications clatter down a feed on the left. The setting is a sparsely populated, palpably inhuman undulation of brute grey boxes and pyramids. And then there's the splendid crafting screen. It sees you assembling components inside a wavering ball of energy on a curved wireframe, then drawing a glyph. An aetherial circle plus metal and plastic nets you some bomb components. Add the components to more metal and plastic plus a curvy star glyph, and you'll produce a "basic bomb" capable of dusting a cathedral.
</p>
<p>
It's tentatively slated to release next year. The premise and emphasis on freeform building destruction here remind me of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/red-faction-guerrilla">Red Faction Guerrilla</a>, though being the work of a much smaller team, this isn't nearly as granular in its devastation. I doubt it needs to be that granular, and it's not just a sneaky teardown sim, in any case: the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3503810/TERRORtypeALCHEMY/?curator_clanid=45029635">Steam</a> page promises a "story of resistance, redemption, and the price of freedom as Auronika must navigate between her heavenly mandate and the brutal realities of uprising."
</p>

        </div>

      </article>




        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dark-fantasy-bomb-making-simterrortypealchemys-frightful-title-cannot-spoil-its-crusty-90s-vibes]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["I really get the feeling that Planet Centauri is cursed", says dev of a game that's now been Steamrolled by Valve twice]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-really-get-the-feeling-that-planet-centauri-is-cursed-says-dev-of-a-game-thats-now-been-steamrolled-by-valve-twice</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/i-really-get-the-feeling-that-planet-centauri-is-cursed-says-dev-of-a-game-thats-now-been-steamrolled-by-valve-twice.1357660/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Sci-fi sandbox Planet Centauri keeps being the victim of unfortunate timing on the storefront</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/planet-centauri-steam-machine-deal-unfortunate-timing-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/planet-centauri-steam-machine-deal-unfortunate-timing-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/planet-centauri-steam-machine-deal-unfortunate-timing-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/planet-centauri-steam-machine-deal-unfortunate-timing-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/planet-centauri-steam-machine-deal-unfortunate-timing-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/planet-centauri-steam-machine-deal-unfortunate-timing-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/planet-centauri-steam-machine-deal-unfortunate-timing-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/planet-centauri-steam-machine-deal-unfortunate-timing-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/planet-centauri-steam-machine-deal-unfortunate-timing-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Permadeath</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Sometimes things happen that you can't control. That's now been the case for developers Permadeath and their 2D sandbox <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/385380/Planet_Centauri/">Planet Centauri</a> twice on Steam, with first a wishlist bug and more recently the reveal of Valve's new hardware landing at just the right time to make the devs' task of getting eyeballs on their game more challenging than it would normally be.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>As reported by <a href="https://www.polygon.com/planet-centauri-steam-machine-announcement-valve-daily-deal-sale/">Polygon</a>, Planet Centauri's <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/385380/view/519699831627710608?l=english">1.0 launch</a> in December last year saw it run into what its developers were later informed by Valve to be "a bug that impacted a very small number of game releases (less than 100 since 2015) where wishlist email notifications for the launch of a game were not sent". Oof. Valve, to their credit, did offer Permadeath a make-good in the form of having the game pop up as one of Steam's daily deals, which the steamy storerunners hoped would "help make up for lost visibility" from that launch day bug.</p>
<p>The studio were reportedly <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/gamedev/comments/1nfd2ji/this_is_how_steam_can_ruin_more_than_10_years_of/">initially hesitant</a> to take up the offer, but ended up picking November 12th from a selection of dates Valve offered. That day rolled around and boom: Valve <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valve-announce-a-new-steam-machine-steam-controller-and-the-steam-frame-vr-headset-and-ive-played-them">announced</a> a new Steam Machine, Steam Controller, and the Steam Frame VR headset. Naturally, Valve switched up the Steam storefront to blare that big news front and centre, making it much more difficult than usually might be the case for any deals or sales to stick out and catch folks' attention.</p>
<p>Laurent Lechat, one of Planet Centauri's devs, says they've had to chalk this up to yet another instance of "bad luck". They know they couldn't have expected Valve to offer a heads up by blabbing their big Steam device news to the studio ahead of time. "The day was chosen more or less randomly on our end," Lechat said. There's perhaps an argument that, depending on when it locked in that date for the big reveals, Valve could have blocked out the 12th as a no-go zone for deals, so whichever games might have been in line to be featured during it didn't end up in a battle they'd not expect.</p><p>Though, Permadeath's devs make clear that they did still get some traction out of the daily deal, despite the tough eyeball competition. A little over 5,000 copies shifted on that day, which is less than the studio hoped and apparently less than the bump in coverage when the news of the bug affecting Planet Centauri's 1.0 launch netted them when it broke a couple of months ago.</p>
<p>Despite that, Lechat stressed that these sales will still aid in the studio's efforts to keep on trucking, saying: "what seems like a small amount will be a great help because it's enough for us to survive for at least a year and allow us to finish our second game, which is currently in development." That game's a 2D roguelike which'll be getting a demo when it's ready and won't be following Planet Centauri's early access path.</p>
<p>What the latter's fate in terms of further updates ends up being depends on how well its fresher sibling does. Permadeath aren't against returning to it, even if Lechat understandably has "the feeling that Planet Centauri is cursed" given just how much fun it's run into over the past year and a bit.</p>

        </div>

      </article>




        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-really-get-the-feeling-that-planet-centauri-is-cursed-says-dev-of-a-game-thats-now-been-steamrolled-by-valve-twice]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>