<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 19:50:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GOG shares their thoughts on preservation in the face of payment processor crackdowns]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gog-shares-their-thoughts-on-preservation-in-the-face-of-payment-processor-crackdowns</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gog-shares-their-thoughts-on-preservation-in-the-face-of-payment-processor-crackdowns.1297323/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"Every game that disappears from distribution is potentially lost to game preservation efforts."</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture data-src-full="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gog-payment-processor.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" src="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gog-payment-processor.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gog-payment-processor.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 690px) and (min-resolution: 2x)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gog-payment-processor.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 690px)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gog-payment-processor.jpg?width=414&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-resolution: 2x)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>GOG</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
In general these days it's never a good time to release a video game unless you're Rockstar, but in recent months it's been made even harder due to numerous payment processors cracking down on digital storefronts like Valve and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/itchio-apologise-for-frustration-and-confusion-after-delisting-thousands-of-nsfw-projects">Itch.io</a>. There's a host of reasons this is problematic, but one less spoken about how this is also an issue of preservation. GOG, another digital storefront, this one owned by The Witcher developer CD Projekt, is known for their preservation efforts, and in a recent interview they shared a bit of their thoughts in relation to these recent issues regarding payment processors.
</p>
<p>
When asked about GOG's stance on what's been happening with payment processors in recent months in an interview with <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/interviews/earning-the-trust-of-major-japanese-developers-like-capcom-is-not-an-easy-task-but-gog-is-getting-there-one-classic-at-a-time-we-ask-gog-about-preservation-and-censorship/">Automaton</a>, senior PR rep Piotr Gnyp had this to say: "At GOG, as a platform devoted to Good Old Games and video game preservation, we see it as a game preservation issue. Every year, many games are disappearing, for various reasons. Every game that disappears from distribution is potentially lost to game preservation efforts. It is particularly worrying when games are potentially vanishing due to external pressure."
</p>
<p>
While possibly not quite as strong or confident an answer as I might like - after all, GOG has plenty of reasons to be wary of pissing off these same payment processors - there is something worth honing in on. 
</p>
<p>
Steam and Itch.io are obviously not some kind of beautiful digital landscapes where games become hits after hits, both are much too saturated for that to happen. Plus, a majority of games on Steam are not DRM-free, meaning they require a connection to the storefront in question in order to be played. Most games on Itch and GOG are DRM-free, however.
</p><p>
The issue comes from the fact that, unfortunately, developers are forced into relying on third-party platforms to sell their games. It is incredibly hard to tell someone to come to your dedicated website to buy your game, and that only works insofar that you've found a payment processor to use that allows something like an adult game.
</p>
<p>
So what happens to these games when they have no place to call a home? How do we ensure that they continue to be available, when they might be hosted on the developer's personal website, which in some cases few people might be aware of? It's a difficult question to answer.
</p>
<p>
In this same interview, Gnyp notes that GOG is a "curated storefront," continuing on to explain that this means "not every game submitted to us is accepted - we select titles based on quality, relevance, and alignment with our values and audience." Again, that line about values feels like it could be a bit of a cop out, but the idea of curation is one worth exploring. It's not a perfect solution, though it could be one way to at least keep some aspect of these unfairly shunned works alive. The question becomes how to do this, and right now, I'm still figuring it out, for myself at least.

</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gog-shares-their-thoughts-on-preservation-in-the-face-of-payment-processor-crackdowns]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Still getting dunked on in Dota 2? Don't worry, even Gabe Newell gets called a noob once a week, apparently]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/still-getting-dunked-on-in-dota-2-dont-worry-even-gabe-newell-gets-called-a-noob-once-a-week-apparently</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/still-getting-dunked-on-in-dota-2-dont-worry-even-gabe-newell-gets-called-a-noob-once-a-week-apparently.1297272/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"I still play Dota every day."</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture data-src-full="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gabe-newell-dota-2.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" src="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gabe-newell-dota-2.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gabe-newell-dota-2.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 690px) and (min-resolution: 2x)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gabe-newell-dota-2.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 690px)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gabe-newell-dota-2.jpg?width=414&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-resolution: 2x)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Valve</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
I don't play online games particularly often, mostly the only ones that I do enjoy are the kind of games I can play with just my friends. People are mean, you see, and I have a sensitive soul, and also I often find them deeply boring conceptually and in practice. Take of that what you will in relation to this story about <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dota-2">Dota 2</a>! Moving on swiftly to a topic that I promise connects to this intro, Gabe Newell! He is a co-founder of Valve, and a noted Dota 2 lover. He also, apparently, is someone who is often subjected to ridicule while playing the very same game his company makes.
</p>
<p>
The man himself made a pre-recorded experience at this year's Dota 2 International, opening exactly how you'd expect him to: "Hi, I'm Gabe Newell." After clearing that up, he waxes not quite poetically about how he fell in love with the MOBA quite deeply thanks to the first International. But, he says says, "It's not just the game I love, but the community.
</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="[EN] Day 1 - The International 2025" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/g_uN-k7BjGw?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>[EN] Day 1 - The International 2025</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/g_uN-k7BjGw?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/g_uN-k7BjGw?autoplay=1" title="[EN] Day 1 - The International 2025">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g_uN-k7BjGw" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>
"Sure, people talk s**t at me in chat, and about once a week people say, hey noob, uninstall the game and [censor blip]. But that's really about their enthusiasm, and the energy that they bring, and that's why, after all these years, I still play Dota every day."
</p><p>
Now, I do feel I have to say that this is a pretty subtly horrendous way to endorse quite toxic behaviours that many people are often subjected to in online games. I don't care if you're enthusiastic! We're all here to have fun, right? Try a friendly word of advice before you make your way to the arcade's basketball machine for some easy dunks.
</p>
<p>
On the other hand, I find it quite an amusing, if brief, anecdote about the ways in which we don't know who we're playing with online. I fully believe that Newell regularly gets lambasted by strangers online, and it tickles me to imagine how they might change their behaviour if they had the relevant context.
</p>
<p>
Not to say that it's good many of them would likely be kinder with said context, I just think there's a lesson to be had here in how we encourage certain kinds of communication in game spaces. One that Valve, even now, still should probably learn how to do better.

</p>

        </div>
      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/still-getting-dunked-on-in-dota-2-dont-worry-even-gabe-newell-gets-called-a-noob-once-a-week-apparently]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dying Light: The Beast gets a release date bump so short you'll wonder why they bothered]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dying-light-the-beast-gets-a-release-date-bump-so-short-youll-wonder-why-they-bothered</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dying-light-the-beast-gets-a-release-date-bump-so-short-youll-wonder-why-they-bothered.1297239/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture data-src-full="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dying-light-the-beast_NCuy3oO.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" src="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dying-light-the-beast_NCuy3oO.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dying-light-the-beast_NCuy3oO.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 690px) and (min-resolution: 2x)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dying-light-the-beast_NCuy3oO.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 690px)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dying-light-the-beast_NCuy3oO.jpg?width=414&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-resolution: 2x)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Techland</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Whenever there is word of a video game's release date being changed, it's hardly ever surprising because nine times out of ten, it's because it has been delayed. That's just the way things are these days, no one can have the luxury of Team Cherry, who took so long making <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hollow-knight-silksong-walkthrough">Silksong</a> just because they were having fun. However, in this case, the release date shifting news is actually a positive one, as <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dying-light-the-beast">Dying Light: The Beast</a> will be launching just that little bit earlier.
</p>
<p>
By little bit, I truly do mean only a tiny amount. The game was originally slated for release on September 19th, and now it's coming out… September 18th! I do genuinely wonder how such a miniscule change will make any difference to Techland's bottom line, but I'm no accountant, or, I don't know, money line go up predictor, whatever that particular job might be called.
</p>
<p>
In a press release, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dying-light">Dying Light</a> franchise director Tymon Smektała said that because they know the game is ready, they wanted to "do something special for our players," so they pushed themselves to "make the impossible possible," which translates to one day less that everyone has to wait for it. Feels like a slightly hyperbolic way to present such a tiny release date bump, but I suppose it is always nice to see this as opposed to yet another delay.
</p>
<p>
Also, as another form of thanks to those who have or will pre-order the game, some kind of "exclusive new reward" will be in store for them. Can't tell you what that is, not because it's a secret, but because proper details will be coming during launch week, i.e. next week.
</p>
<p>
Our own Edwin <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dying-light-the-beast-wants-to-make-you-afraid-of-the-dark-again">got to have a little jaunt</a> through the upcoming <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-open-world-games">open world game</a> earlier this year which he described as "on the whole, quite jolly."

</p>

        </div>
      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dying-light-the-beast-gets-a-release-date-bump-so-short-youll-wonder-why-they-bothered]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>