<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 16:22:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2077's update 2.3 is delayed, and definitely not just because CD Projekt can't stop adding things]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cyberpunk-2077s-update-23-is-delayed-and-definitely-not-just-because-cd-projekt-cant-stop-adding-things</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cyberpunk-2077s-update-2-3-is-delayed-and-definitely-not-just-because-cd-projekt-cant-stop-adding-things.1225866/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>They're addicted to the shindig</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>CD Projekt</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Sorry, we're not done yet, CD Projekt has said about a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/cyberpunk-2077">Cyberpunk 2077</a> update that also represents that same phrase, it being about the third patch to be labelled the final one the game'll be getting. Update 2.3 was originally set to be dropping on this week, but now it's been delayed so the devs can make it about the same size as its predecessor.</p>
<p>Yeah, they're probably adding more stuff to the pile of new things we never thought Cyberpunk'd still be getting at this stage. We're multiple encores deep in the Samurai gig at this point, but hey, the crowd's still having a great time.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>"We initially hoped to put Update 2.3 in your hands on June 26th," the studio wrote in a post addressed to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5SX5CJ2hN_c">choom nation</a>, "However, we'll need some more time to make sure we're happy with it — we're aiming for a scope similar to Update 2.2. We'll update you further as soon as we can!"</p>
<p>So, no new details about what to expect in this next patch, which <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oh-it-turns-out-cyberpunk-2077-is-getting-one-more-update-after-all-and-its-not-too-far-away">was announced</a> alongside Cyberpunk making its debut on a certain new console made by a company often associated with the profession you enlist if your loo's clogged. Well, aside from the fact it's apparently going to about as beefy as its predecessor, the previous holder of the 'last Cyberpunk patch, for realsies' title.</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>Hey chooms,</p><p>We initially hoped to put Update 2.3 in your hands on June 26. However, we'll need some more time to make sure we're happy with it — we're aiming for a scope similar to Update 2.2. We'll update you further as soon as we can!</p><p>We appreciate your patience! <a href="https://t.co/Hx5fEF8wj7">pic.twitter.com/Hx5fEF8wj7</a></p></div>— Cyberpunk 2077 (@CyberpunkGame) <a href="https://twitter.com/CyberpunkGame/status/1937135894978253112?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 23, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>In case you were busy in December 2024, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oh-it-turns-out-cyberpunk-2077-is-getting-one-more-update-after-all-and-its-not-too-far-away">update 2.2</a> added a bunch of extra customisation options for your car and character, as well as the ability for Keanny Reevhand to sometimes spawn into your passenger seat during free roam. You know, so you can show him your sickest handbrake turns without attempting a drift while something important's happening.</p>
<p>Who knows what CD Projekt has in store for this <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cyberpunk-2077s-surprisingly-substantial-update-21-is-out-now">final</a>, final, final patch. They've added in a whole metro system previously, so maybe we're getting futuristic <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/bus-simulator">Bus Simulator</a>. Or a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/euro-truck-simulator-2">Euro Cybertruck Simulator</a> that's about flying MAN and DAF lorries with <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cyberpunk-2077s-flying-car-modder-has-removed-the-games-max-speed-limit-and-i-may-soon-be-involved-in-a-1222mph-mid-air-fender-bender">heavy duty thrusters</a> and mantis windscreen wiper blades.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cyberpunk-2077s-update-23-is-delayed-and-definitely-not-just-because-cd-projekt-cant-stop-adding-things]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>