<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 16:23:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RoadCraft sibling Docked's Steam Next Fest demo is aimed at folks who're deeply moved by container movement]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/roadcraft-sibling-dockeds-steam-next-fest-demo-is-aimed-at-folks-whore-deeply-moved-by-container-movement</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/roadcraft-sibling-dockeds-steam-next-fest-demo-is-aimed-at-folks-whore-deeply-moved-by-container-movement.1323700/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Seriously though, you better get ready to move some containers</p>

    </div>


  <p>


  <figure>
        <picture data-src-full="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/docked-steam-next-fest-demo-01.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" src="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/docked-steam-next-fest-demo-01.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/docked-steam-next-fest-demo-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/docked-steam-next-fest-demo-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/docked-steam-next-fest-demo-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/docked-steam-next-fest-demo-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/docked-steam-next-fest-demo-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/docked-steam-next-fest-demo-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/docked-steam-next-fest-demo-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/docked-steam-next-fest-demo-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/docked-steam-next-fest-demo-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Saber Interactive</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>There's a container. It needs to be moved. Get in this big crane thing and move it. That's the short and sweet summary of the Steam Next Fest demo for Docked, Saber Interactive's latest addition to their ever-expanding roster of simulations based around jobs which require high-vis gear.</p>
<!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Docked - Steam Next Fest Demo Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YXcTF7ekSiA?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Docked - Steam Next Fest Demo Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YXcTF7ekSiA?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/YXcTF7ekSiA?autoplay=1" title="Docked - Steam Next Fest Demo Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YXcTF7ekSiA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>Docked's laser-sharp focus on simulating the workings of a port means that, at least as far as its Next Fest demo is concerned, there's very little of the driving that characterises siblings <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/roadcraft">RoadCraft</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/snowrunner">SnowRunner</a>. You're not commuting, because all of your jobs are in and around Port Wake. Instead, Saber look to be aiming at the demographic of folks who've lived for the bits of their previous works which saw you given a crane and told to load some cargo onto your lorry, usually with a crane.</p>
<p>I'll be honest, this has never been where much of the appeal lies to me. Though, that might be because of my tendency to rush and end up having a bunch of logs escape to freedom. That said, if you're in it for the chance to get behind the complex controls of some heavy machinery, Docked's got you covered. The demo consists for four little jobs, with the first charging you to scale a colossal ship-to-shore crane, running around on foot as you fire it up. Once you're in, the act of moving containers off a damaged ship wasn't too far from what I've experienced in other Saber sims, but I did appreciate the change in pace that a bit of first-person climbing represented.</p><p>To be honest, that's where the demo peaks. The other jobs also revolve around moving containers, but this time with smaller vehicles. The straddle carrier you get to use last was my favourite of these, as it's a giraffe-esque contraption that drives astride containers to pick them up, which is wonderfully satisfying compared to the more mundane craneing of its cousin the reach stacker.</p>
<p>The menus suggest there'll be plenty of more in-depth port management in the full thing, but none of it's available just yet. That's a bit of a bummer, as I think for Docked to really catch on, it'll be the aspect of the game which has to do the most heavy lifting. Saber themselves have already put out plenty of games in which you can lift a thing using a big machine, but I can't think of too many games which put you in charge of a full port. It remains to be seen just how much there is to the upgrades and changes you'll be able to make to Port Wake, but since it seems likely to be the game's calling card, I'd hope the answer's plenty.</p>
<p>There's still no concrete release date to wait for right now, but you can both find Docked's Next Fest demo and wishlist it via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2487300/Docked/">Steam page</a>.</p>

        </div>
      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/roadcraft-sibling-dockeds-steam-next-fest-demo-is-aimed-at-folks-whore-deeply-moved-by-container-movement]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No, commuters of Bus Bound's Steam Next Fest demo, I will not stop publicly transporting you to the scene of accidents]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/no-commuters-of-bus-bounds-steam-next-fest-demo-i-will-not-stop-publicly-transporting-you-to-the-scene-of-accidents</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/no-commuters-of-bus-bounds-steam-next-fest-demo-i-will-not-stop-publicly-transporting-you-to-the-scene-of-accidents.1323595/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>And yes, we must catch air off of every speed bump</p>

    </div>


  <p>


  <figure>
        <picture data-src-full="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/busbound-steam-next-fest-demo-out-01.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" src="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/busbound-steam-next-fest-demo-out-01.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/busbound-steam-next-fest-demo-out-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/busbound-steam-next-fest-demo-out-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/busbound-steam-next-fest-demo-out-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/busbound-steam-next-fest-demo-out-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/busbound-steam-next-fest-demo-out-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/busbound-steam-next-fest-demo-out-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/busbound-steam-next-fest-demo-out-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/busbound-steam-next-fest-demo-out-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/busbound-steam-next-fest-demo-out-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Saber Interactive</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The bumper sticker plastered to the rear of the pickup in front of me reads 'please let me merge before I start crying'. Behind me, an angry mob are starting to sharpen their pitchforks and light their torches. The next stop beckons, and I'm not going to make it on time. There's nothing I can do. For I am Bus Bound in this Steam Next Fest demo, and that bus is too large to slice through gridlock like a hooligan.</p>
<!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Bus Bound - Steam Next Fest Demo Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2DKnyjacdtQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Bus Bound - Steam Next Fest Demo Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2DKnyjacdtQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/2DKnyjacdtQ?autoplay=1" title="Bus Bound - Steam Next Fest Demo Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2DKnyjacdtQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>Up until this point, the few thumbs down I've earned from stillalive studios' latest bout of bus simulation have been due to my own carelessness. I've mounted the occasional curb, forgotten to stop at stop signs, and occasionally engaged in a bit of touring car-esque paint trading with my fellow road users. This time, I don't think it's my fault. There are cars strewn across the junction, blocking any ability myself and the distressed merger before me might have to obey the green light being pointed our way.</p>
<p>I sound the horn. Come on, its pathetic call tells everyone else stuck in the gridlock, I've got a timetable to keep. No one moves. I look at the list of stops left on the route I've drawn up by connecting various stops around the suburban American city of Emberville. Next up is 99th Street. Get us there, urge the disgruntled passengers. I'd tell them to eff off because there's nothing I can do. I'd tell them to eff off because they haven't paid. I can't though, because in order to circumvent simulating the art of giving someone a dirty look when they try to pay for a £3 bus fare with a £20 note, the method by which my bussing success is measured is likes and dislikes.</p><p>The myriad whims of public opinion are the be-all-and-end-all in this cashless corner of the world's most openly capitalism-loving nation. It's a utopia in which local councils actually get funding and dedicate it to getting strong public transport links up and running. It's an uber-utopia in which that investment's followed up by renovation of city neighbourhoods once you've bussed through them regularly enough and earned the approval of their citizens. The works to improve these areas aren't farmed out to a third-party contractor corporation who respond to getting lucrative government contracts because they've agreed to appoint a cabinet minister to their board by taking a millenium to do the work.</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Saber Interactive</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>It's beautiful, and far too good to be true. It also dilutes the sim's appeal a bit in my mind. In opting to specifically simulate bus driving, you're putting all of your eggs in that basket. Were Bus Bound more of a generalist sim, or even a bus-centric add-on to an existing one as with the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/12-years-after-teasing-buses-were-coming-to-euro-truck-simulator-2-they-finally-arrive">coaches SCS Software are working on adding to their truck sims</a>, I'd be more forgiving of it not getting as into the nitty gritty of commuting capital. As it is, Bus Bound's more of a straightforward city driving sim whose routes happen to run between bus stops. That does make it a lot easier to get the hang of, and there is plenty of challenge in resisting the urge to drive like an idiot, disregarding the rules of the road like they're nothing.</p>
<p>Generally speaking, the AI traffic do a convincing job of simulating the real thing, even down to being receptive of your indicators. It's hard to have an accident that isn't your fault, usually because you didn't check after stopping at a junction or forgot the buses don't have the same stopping distance as your average circuit racer. The city's a vibrant enough backdrop that repeated runs through the same streets didn't get too stale, at least through  the end of the demo hour. The few real-world buses on offer for Next Fest have a decent amount of paint customisation on offer. I'll have to wait until the full thing's out to be allowed behind the wheel of a double decker, but that's fair.</p><p>Having tried the demo, which you can find on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2095420/Bus_Bound/">Bus Bound's Steam page</a>, I've enjoyed its laid back vibes. On the other hand, I'm not sure at this point whether it'll have the sim depth to keep folks around in the long run and carve out a place among the genre's leaders, especially if they're offering coach trips with a bit of real world tourism mixed in. We'll have to see when its 2026 release rolls around.</p>

        </div>
      </article>




        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/no-commuters-of-bus-bounds-steam-next-fest-demo-i-will-not-stop-publicly-transporting-you-to-the-scene-of-accidents]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>