<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 11:19:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alien: Rogue Incursion gets a non-VR "Evolved" edition this year, with prettier, deadlier xenomorphs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/alien-rogue-incursion-gets-a-non-vr-evolved-edition-this-year-with-prettier-deadlier-xenomorphs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/alien-rogue-incursion-gets-a-non-vr-evolved-edition-this-year-with-prettier-deadlier-xenomorphs.1185072/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/alien-rogue-incursion-gets-a-non-vr-evolved-edition-this-year-with-prettier-deadlier-xenomorphs<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>How many drops is this for you, lieutenant?</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Survios</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/alien-rogue-incursion">Alien: Rogue Incursion</a> will get a non-VR release on PC later this year, allowing would-be Colonial Marines access to its Weyland-Yutani black site without first requiring you to force your head inside a pair of microscopic televisions. Subtitled "Evolved Edition" - which feels like a real elbow in the kidneys for VR evangelists - it will sport "even deadlier Xenomorphs and enhanced visuals". Hopefully, that'll be enough to juice the VR version's current <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1850050/Alien_Rogue_Incursion_VR/">Mixed</a> user review consensus on Steam. </p><!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Alien: Rogue Incursion Evolved Edition | PS5 &amp; PC Announce Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0Ho3DAL11eA?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Alien: Rogue Incursion Evolved Edition | PS5 &amp; PC Announce Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0Ho3DAL11eA?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/0Ho3DAL11eA?autoplay=1" title="Alien: Rogue Incursion Evolved Edition | PS5 &amp; PC Announce Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0Ho3DAL11eA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>As you may guess from the above, I'm not a VR evangelist, partly because I can't afford a modern VR headset and don't have the living space to play VR games without injuring myself, my loved ones or my precious (scavenged) bedroom furniture. I only own an original PSVR, which is curled up in the corner of my cupboard like a dead servo-skull. It was last used to play <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/star-wars-squadrons">Star Wars: Squadrons</a> and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/paper-beast">Paper Beast</a>, which are the two VR games I consider worth the discomfort, if not the expense, of VR.</p>
<p>I hear that the latest Zucker Buckets and Gaben Goggles are more comfortable to wear, but I still don't trust myself to put them on without becoming a public health hazard. I have terrible, humiliating memories of previewing some Marvel VR game at an event. Surrounded by the minions of Thanos, I swung Thor's hammer with all of my strength and clanged the PR person over the head. This happened in a converted warehouse about 300 metres wide. Now, imagine if I'd been surrounded by digital xenomorphs. That PR person would be dead.</p>
<p>So yes, I'm delighted that Rogue Incursion has decided to trade in its fancy eyestrain helmet for reassuringly non-engulfing 2D displays. Here's some story blurb about Rogue Incursion. It's the first of a two-act story, with the second act promising "new challenges and deadlier enemies".</p>
<blockquote><p>An all-new action-horror entry into the classic franchise, Alien: Rogue Incursion transforms you into Zula Hendricks-the ex-Colonial Marine hellbent on exposing Weyland-Yutani's black-site experiments-on an extremely dangerous mission to the uncharted planet Purdan. With her synth companion Davis 01 for guidance, Zula must infiltrate the infested Gemini Exoplanet Solutions research facility and survive the ever-present threat of the most cunning Xenomorphs ever encountered, with both skilled stealth and serious firepower at her disposal. And when the threat she discovers has extinction-level consequences, Zula suddenly finds herself with humanity's fate on her shoulders.</p></blockquote>
<p>The Evolved Edition launches on 30th September. Read more on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3655390/Alien_Rogue_Incursion_Evolved_Edition/">Steam</a>. Did you play the VR one? Let us know how you got on with it. While we're talking Alien, I'll conclude by shoving you towards <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/duskers-is-getting-a-ship-building-sequel-years-after-the-sci-fi-roguelike-scared-us-to-bits">the next game from the people behind Duskers</a>, one of the finest unofficial Alien games yet made.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chrono Trigger writer is "starting to contemplate" a remake after all]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/chrono-trigger-writer-is-starting-to-contemplate-a-remake-after-all</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/chrono-trigger-writer-is-starting-to-contemplate-a-remake-after-all.1185033/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/chrono-trigger-writer-is-starting-to-contemplate-a-remake-after-all<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Time is a flat circle, and a small one apparently</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Square Enix</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Rumours of a <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/chrono-trigger">Chrono Trigger</a> remake briefly bubbled up before being <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/no-sorry-put-the-party-poppers-away-chrono-trigger-isnt-getting-a-remake-as-far-as-anyone-knows-anyway">swiftly pin-popped last week</a>, following a mistranslation of the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-11-best-jrpgs-on-pc-in-2024">JRPG</a>'s writer, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dragon-quest">Dragon Quest</a> creator Yuji Horii at a panel. The potion-swilling public were understandably chuffed (you still can't Google Horii's name without being served videos of pog-faced excite-os screaming "Chrono Trigger Remake Confirmed!!!"), but it soon turned out that no such remake was actually planned.</p>
<p>Based on a recent interview with <a href="https://www.gamereactor.eu/exclusive-yuji-horii-contemplating-a-chrono-trigger-remake-1540193/">Gamereactor</a> at the same event, it sounds like Horii has been considering doing something with Chrono Trigger after all, which isn't too surprising after Square Enix said they <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/square-enix-celebrating-chrono-trigger-anniversary-with-new-projects-sparking-re-release-hopes">planned to celebrate</a> the game's 30th anniversary with "various projects" back in March. From Gamereactor:</p>
<!--more-->
<blockquote><p>"Yes, it is. It has been a long time. Yes, I want to do something", Horii-san tells Gamereactor when asked about the celebrations for the Chrono Trigger 30th Anniversary. "Currently, Dragon Quest has seen III, I-II [HD-2D] Remakes. I get a lot of requests for the remake of Chrono Trigger as well, and so I am starting to contemplate on it",</p></blockquote>
<p>Which is nice, although not all that exciting to me personally for a couple of reasons. Firstly, Chrono Trigger is still extremely playable, and secondly, I've never actually understood what all the fuss was about. I guess I view Chrono Trigger like I view The Beatles: sure, I can accept they pushed the medium forward, but I don't actually care to listen to them for fun except about a third of Sergeant Pepper's. Also, I'm still salty that Frog turned out to be a human named pissing Glenn. Glenn! Just let your talking frog knight be a talking frog knight, game.</p>
<p>That said, the fairground trial scene blew my mind when I first played it, so I can only imagine how wild it was in 1995 to have a JRPG call you a stinking thief for eating a man's lunch after you'd been conditioned to treat layabout items as a purely ludic contrivance. Still, give me a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wild_Arms_(video_game)">Wild Arms</a> remake over this any day. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/airships-dinosaurs-and-robots-meet-in-spiritual-successor-to-chrono-trigger-rpg-threads-of-time">Threads Of Time looks nice though</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tamagotchi and Quake both join World Video Game Hall Of Fame]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tamagotchi-and-quake-both-join-world-video-game-hall-of-fame</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tamagotchi-and-quake-both-join-world-video-game-hall-of-fame.1185027/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tamagotchi-and-quake-both-join-world-video-game-hall-of-fame<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>It's 'videogame', actually</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Id Software</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>New York's Strong National Museum of Play has welcomed four new entries into its Video Game Hall Of Fame: <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/quake">Quake</a>, Goldeneye, 1981's arcade side-scroller Defender, and the virtual pet Tamagotchi. It's that last one that's by far the most interesting of the four picks, and I must admit, I'd never actually thought about Tamagotchi in these exact terms before.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Quake History" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/azd68Z8H8Oc?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Quake History</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/azd68Z8H8Oc?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/azd68Z8H8Oc?autoplay=1" title="Quake History">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=azd68Z8H8Oc" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>Here's The Strong on Tamagotchi's inclusion:</p>
<blockquote><p>"Beyond cultivating nostalgia, Tamagotchi offered a distinct form of play apart from the prevailing popularity of video game electronics at the time. In the book Millennial Monsters: Japanese Toys and the Global Imagination (2006), scholar Anne Allison argued that Tamagotchi provided young users with feelings of connection, intimacy, and personalization, a respite from competition and fighting games."</p></blockquote>
<p>This is purely speculative on my part - I'd love for someone to give me a little more context or insight - but the first Tamagotchi was released in 1996, the same year as SNES farming game and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/stardew-valley">Stardew Valley</a> influence Harvest Moon and the original Pokémon. Taken together, that's an incredibly influential year for contemporary <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-non-violent-video-games">non violent</a> or "cosy" titles, and I do wonder if these three games (or two games and Tamagotchi, depending on your view) themselves share common influences.</p>
<p>When I say I'd never thought of Tamagotchi as a videogame, I don't mean it in "not a real game sense", either. Just that it hadn't actually occurred to me to think about in what we might broadly call videogame canon or history. But I came around the idea pretty quickly, honestly. Now I think about, Tamagotchi might actually have been my first exposure to permadeath. I once lost one for months, eventually finding it under my bed to behold my beloved pet dying in a mountain of its own shit. Brutal stuff.</p>
<p>As for Quake's inclusion, The Strong focuses on its use of 3D space, as well as the popularity of its competitive multiplayer "central to the creation of esports as an industry". It was also, <a href="https://www.museumofplay.org/games/quake/">they point out</a>, "the first shooter to get widespread mod support", spawning the likes of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/team-fortress-2">Team Fortress 2</a>.</p>
<p>These four additions bring the hall of fame's total up to 49 games. The earliest entry is <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/spacewar">Spacewar!</a>, and the most recent is The Last Of Us. We like to complain about irritating uses of punctuation in game names here at RPS but I suppose they've been with us since the beginning. I'm now wishing they'd named The Last Of Us something like Panic! At The Abandoned Supermarket just for the sake of symmetry.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Europa Universalis 5 won't launch with a subscription - but it might get one later]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/europa-universalis-5-wont-launch-with-a-subscription-but-it-might-get-one-later</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/europa-universalis-5-wont-launch-with-a-subscription-but-it-might-get-one-later.1185024/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/europa-universalis-5-wont-launch-with-a-subscription-but-it-might-get-one-later<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun / Paradox Interactive</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Grand strategy country crusher <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/europa-universalis-v">Europa Universalis 5</a> was <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-next-grand-strategy-game-from-paradox-is-europa-universalis-5">announced yesterday</a>, revealing a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/everything-we-know-about-europa-universalis-5">complex century-spanning historical sim</a>. But one thing we still don't know is the price or how it'll be sold. If you want to buy the previous game in the series, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/europa-universalis-iv">Europa Universalis 4</a>, you'll find a slew of subscription models and a big library of DLC alongside <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/236850/Europa_Universalis_IV/">the base game</a>. Which might cause some fans to worry that the sequel will launch with some sort of similar subscription model. But this won't be the case, say developers Paradox Tinto. They're going to sell it normally. At least for now.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>"Obviously, when we have enough DLCs there will be subscription models, because subscription models are great," said game director Johan Andersson in an interview with RPS. But when asked if the publisher was planning to have a subscription model straight out of the gate, he said no.</p>
<p>"No, unless we have DLC. I mean, of course, I would love to have a subscription model where people paid me five euros a month, or ten euros, whatever. But unless we actually have any content, I'm not sure people want [to be told]: 'Hey! Pay ten euros now for January, February, March... and in April you'll get DLC!' No."</p>
<p>Paradox started experimenting with subscriptions to their biggest and most expandofied games like EU4 <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/paradox-are-experimenting-with-a-subscription-service-to-play-europa-universalis-iv-and-its-dlc">back in 2020</a>, and later offered <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/stellaris-launches-expansion-subscription-offering-access-to-all-dlc-for-850-per-month">a subscription to all Stellaris's space stuff</a> in 2024. It costs £8.50 a month and you don't get to keep anything when you unsubscribe. You can still buy each of these games normally, of course. The sub is just an option - one I don't really recommend. It certainly wouldn't make a lot of sense for the publisher's latest grand strategy sequel at launch, and the devs agree. </p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun / Paradox Interactive</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>But there is another familiar problem for Paradox. <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/europa-universalis">Europa Universalis</a> 5 will be sized up next to its predecessor. How can the new strategy game compete with a decade of DLCs and extras? Will there be enough in the base game of Europa Universalis 5 to entice veterans to hop over to the new game? Andersson thinks so. </p>
<p>"Almost all of the EU4 features that are in its DLCs right now are part of the base game in EU5," he told us. This means EU5 will inherit all of the systems that EU4 has built up over years of expansions and updates. Which theoretically gives it as much value as the entire catalogue of EU4 expansions. Of course, players will be able to verify that promise once EU5 is fully released.</p>
<p>As for DLC plans, Paradox Tinto are not worrying about that just yet, says Andersson. </p>
<p>"We have visions," says Andersson, "but I think it's a bad idea to write ideas and work on things... before you have wrapped up and shipped the game. That's my experience. Of course, salespeople want [to say]: 'we need to have 12 DLCs ready ASAP!' But, yeah... I don't want to do it because it takes away from the base game."</p>
<p>That's quite refreshing and reassuring to hear. Paradox are sometimes accused of milking it when it comes to their many cosmetic packs and expandobits. They have even been accused of "fixing" games with paid DLC - something the company's CEO refuted by comparing their process of making games to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/paradox-respond-to-the-accusation-that-they-fix-games-with-paid-dlc-we-try-to-find-a-middle-ground">painting a piece of art</a>. "When is a painting done?" he mused. "When you stop painting it, I guess."</p>
<p>My own view is that Paradox DLC is always, by its nature, going to be hit or miss. And you can easily dodge the duff stuff by reading up on reviews. It's the best way to tell what's a thin soup of hats and what is a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/im-sorry-for-all-the-dead-bodies-i-left-behind-while-walking-from-ireland-to-china-in-crusader-kings-3s-brilliant-new-dlc">rich stew of adventure</a>. You don't need a subscription model when you've got Rock Paper Shotgun, is what I'm saying, friend. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Eric Barone, the guy who can't stop updating Stardew Valley, says the words "I might eventually make a Stardew Valley 2"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/eric-barone-the-guy-who-cant-stop-updating-stardew-valley-says-the-words-i-might-eventually-make-a-stardew-valley-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/eric-barone-the-guy-who-cant-stop-updating-stardew-valley-says-the-words-i-might-eventually-make-a-stardew-valley-2.1184838/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/eric-barone-the-guy-who-cant-stop-updating-stardew-valley-says-the-words-i-might-eventually-make-a-stardew-valley-2<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>ConcernedApe</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Did you know that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/stardew-valley">Stardew Valley</a> is the 21st best-selling game of all time? It's sold more than <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim">Skyrim</a>! At least by the numbers we currently have, anyway. I don't care all that much about sales figures, but if creator Eric Barone cared more about money, I can only imagine that a sequel would be all but guaranteed. As it turns out though, the developer could actually see himself making a sequel to the beloved <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games-like-stardew-valley-the-best-farming-games-on-pc">farming sim</a>.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
Barone recently appeared on the podcast Tiger Belly (thanks, GamesRadar), where host Bobby Lee asked why he doesn't just make a Stardew Valley 2 when he's constantly releasing new updates. "It's just so much easier to just add more stuff to Stardew Valley than to make a whole new game from scratch," Barone explains. "Because Stardew Valley, all the systems, the major systems, are already all done. That's the stuff that's not fun to do. When I make an update, it's like, throw in this, throw in that, let's add green rain. These random ideas I have. Whimsical ideas."
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Bobby's Dream Guest, Stardew Valley Creator Eric Barone (ConcernedApe) | Bonus TigerBelly" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/83DYlsJoaFk?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Bobby's Dream Guest, Stardew Valley Creator Eric Barone (ConcernedApe) | Bonus TigerBelly</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/83DYlsJoaFk?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/83DYlsJoaFk?autoplay=1" title="Bobby's Dream Guest, Stardew Valley Creator Eric Barone (ConcernedApe) | Bonus TigerBelly">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=83DYlsJoaFk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
He noted that a lot of these ideas come about from playing the game himself and thinking, "'Oh, wouldn't it be cool if there was this or that?' And then I can just do it, and that's a new update. It's really just fun and creative and spontaneous to do it that way than to make a whole new game."
</p>
<p>
And then came the comment that struck fear into my heart: "I might eventually make a Stardew Valley 2, to be honest." I say fear, because Barone struggles to not update the original game, so much so he's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/who-knows-if-stardew-valley-is-finally-done-but-the-dev-behind-it-is-committed-to-not-working-on-it-until-haunted-chocolatier-is-done">somewhat forcing himself to stop working on it so he can actually finish Haunted Chocolatier</a>. However, Barone did also say that while he won't deny the possibility of a Stardew Valley 2, he doesn't "want to just be the Stardew Valley guy, that's why I'm making <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/haunted-chocolatier">Haunted Chocolatier</a>."
</p>
<p>
So, really we've got a Schrodinger's Stardew Valley sequel here. Fingers crossed Barone doesn't get carried away and do it, I'd like to play Haunted Chocolatier before I retire.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>