<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:30:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayerUnknown's Battlegrounds creator wants to build a "metaverse" but says it might take 15 years and can't explain what it will look like yet]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/playerunknowns-battlegrounds-creator-wants-to-build-a-metaverse-but-says-it-might-take-15-years-and-cant-explain-what-it-will-look-like-yet</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playerunknowns-battlegrounds-creator-wants-to-build-a-metaverse-but-says-it-might-take-15-years-and-cant-explain-what-it-will-look-like-yet.1072647/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/playerunknowns-battlegrounds-creator-wants-to-build-a-metaverse-but-says-it-might-take-15-years-and-cant-explain-what-it-will-look-like-yet<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
  

        <p>I've never metaverse I fully understood</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/brendan-greene-playerunknowns-battlegrounds-profile-picture-2.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Playerunknown Productions</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Brendan Greene, the modder-turned-millionaire who designed battle royale game <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/playerunknowns-battlegrounds">PUBG: Battlegrounds</a>, wants to make his studio's next game a "metaverse", although he says he's wary of using the term. The project is called "Artemis" (at least for now) and you won't be seeing it any time soon. That's because the studio is still working on the tech behind it all, and plans to release two other games before it. Meaning it'll be 10-15 years before it actually comes out. </p>
<p>Greene describes Artemis as an internet-like platform where users create and share things, but doesn't say specifically what those things might be. He doesn't know how his user-led "multiverse of worlds" will be moderated, or how it will prevent copyright infringement, or what makes this idea distinct from, say, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/roblox">Roblox</a>. He is nonetheless "full of confidence".</p>
<!--more-->
<p>"[Yes], it's a big vision," he told <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-creator-of-playerunknowns-battlegrounds-wants-to-build-a-true-metaverse">IGN in a recent interview</a>, "but I've got a good team of industry professionals and they don't think it's that crazy.</p>
<p>"I hesitate to talk about this, because it's just such a dirty word, but I want to build a metaverse because I don't think anyone else is. I think everyone's building IP bubbles that might talk to each other at some stage in the future, maybe if we're lucky, but it's not the metaverse. See, the Metaverse is a 3D internet. You should be able to create your own worlds and just have them all operating on the same protocol, like HTTP. So a world is a page, and that's what I'm trying to do with Artemis.”</p><p>What Artemis will actually look like, and what players (users?) will actually do within that realm isn't talked about in concrete terms, except to say it might be a bit like <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/star-trek">Star Trek</a>'s Holodeck or Minecraft's survival mode. He also says his studio, PlayerUnknown Productions, may build it with the world-generation technology they're creating for their upcoming survival game <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/prologue">Prologue: Go Wayback</a>, which so far seems an aesthetically realistic orienteer 'em up with hunger, thirst, and all the usual survival game go-tos. Artemis itself, however, is years away from release, according to Greene. And even when it does come out, it's possible it'll take time to gain traction. </p>
<p>“The internet was empty when it first started, and it was just the way of sharing data, and I look at this the same. This is probably going to be empty for the first few years, but then eventually you'll start to see the possibility of what you can do with this kind of world generator that it's like a multiverse of worlds.”</p>
<p>Greene expands on his thoughts in the interview but the gist is this: Artemis is still a lot of big, cloudy ideas. My gut reaction to millionaires chasing the metaverse is rabid, frothing-at-the-mouth skepticism. The two mentioned inspirations (the Holodeck and Minecraft) have something of a chasm between them in technical terms. And the player-led creativity Greene describes already exists in other games such as Roblox, which <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/roblox-is-limiting-access-to-social-hangouts-and-unrated-games-for-children-aged-under-13">struggles just to keep its audience of children protected from harm</a>. </p>
<p>In the meantime, Fortnite has given players tools to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fortnite-creative-20s-beta-is-out-allowing-for-some-wild-custom-content">make their own creations with the Unreal Editor For Fortnite</a> and other studios are building similar games-as-a-platform, such as <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/everywhere">Everywhere</a>, an upcoming <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/everywhere-from-a-former-gta-producer-looks-like-a-retro-throwback-to-2022s-metaverse-craze">make-your-own-minigame machine</a> by Build A Rocket Boy, itself described in somewhat grandiose terms for what looks to be essentially Dreams for the PlayStation with more multiplayer options. It might be exactly these types of games that Greene thinks of as "IP bubbles", but it's not clear what will make PlayerUnknown's Metagrounds different from these.</p><p>Artemis is also - let's face it - unlikely to be as revolutionary as the internet, the thing Greene repeatedly compares it to. I'm wary of calling the metaverse the holy grail of the tech world, mainly because many head honchos in games and technology seem to hear the words "holy grail" and think: "cool thing we can definitely achieve if we pump enough money into it!" Which is not quite the original meaning of the phrase. But also calling the metaverse a "holy grail" implies it is a universally desirable thing in the first place. And I'm not sure that's true. Many people just want to play a video game.</p>
<p>Greene does talk more about all the possibilities for Artemis in the interview, so it's worth reading if you want to understand his reasoning and get a sense for some of the other questions that arise from his ponderings. When asked how such a world-of-worlds would be moderated, he says: "we're going to have to figure it out" and acknowledges it is "important to get right".  When asked if Artemis will use NFTs, he says it won't, despite <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/artemis-pubg-creators-next-game-will-have-nfts-and-the-metaverse">a previous report</a> claiming this would be the case. </p>
<p>For now, Artemis remains a non-extant dream of unproven value. Whatever it turns out to be might be fun. It might even get the hundreds of thousands of players of Plunkbat. But will it get the millions Greene is fantasising about? Will it be a second 3D internet? I'm not so sure. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ancient Chinese RPG The Bustling World is, in fact, all of the genres, from city builder to life sim]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ancient-chinese-rpg-the-bustling-world-is-in-fact-all-of-the-genres-from-city-builder-to-life-sim</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ancient-chinese-rpg-the-bustling-world-is-in-fact-all-of-the-genres-from-city-builder-to-life-sim.1072587/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ancient-chinese-rpg-the-bustling-world-is-in-fact-all-of-the-genres-from-city-builder-to-life-sim<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Too ambitious for its own good?</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/PV2-screenshot-(5).jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Lightning Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
It's frightfully early in the year to be bustling, but I can't get enough of the crowded streets of ancient "Chinese-style" <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-bustling-world">The Bustling World</a>. The latest trailer is a series of sweeping yet intimate, colourful urban cross-sections, showing dozens of NPCs selling fish, shaking hands on balconies, shouldering barrels, dancing with fans, honing their feng shui, and various other pursuits that allegedly form part of full NPC life simulations. It's like scrutinising a Hitman level from above, except that all of these people have evolving relationships and sleeping patterns and they might hunt you down if you murder any of their relatives. Me, I just want to play Where's Wally. 
</p><!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Bustling World - Feature Trailer | A Beautiful Blend of Art and Freedom in a Chinese-Style World" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vPeSbLdIZe0?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Bustling World - Feature Trailer | A Beautiful Blend of Art and Freedom in a Chinese-Style World</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vPeSbLdIZe0?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/vPeSbLdIZe0?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vPeSbLdIZe0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
That's a slice from the game's minutiae. At its most expansive, The Bustling World threatens to become a 4X <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-strategy-games-on-pc">strategy</a> game: you can take charge of factions, lead armies, design houses, build cities of your own, and organise production chains into - my goodness, it sounds like they're trying to make it a factory sim as well? "Bustling" is certainly the word. "Bursting" might be more appropriate. "Breaking" seems like a possibility. This is a cross-genre pudding of fearful, perhaps ill-advised scale. The trailer proudly advertises itself as real-time and in-engine, but I can't quite believe they're going to pull it all off.
</p>
<p>
The Bustling World - <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2724650/The_Bustling_World/">Steam page here</a> - is the work of Chinese developers FireWo Games, with Lightning Games publishing. It doesn't appear to have a core storyline. Instead, you play a nameless everyperson who can either carry on being a nameless everyperson or evolve into a proper MC with globe-straddling aspirations. 
</p><p>
"In this ancient world, limitless possibilities await," comments the press release. "You can choose to lead a tranquil life--work, engage in trade, and build a family. Alternatively, satisfy your insatiable desires for wealth, status, and military might. Embark on daring journeys, exploring, adventuring, solving mysteries, combating bandits, and recruiting heroes. Or, aim for the peak of power through establishing influence, city planning, policy formulation, diplomatic endeavors, and territorial expansion."
</p>
<p>
The game promises "dozens of diverse maps, ranging from peaceful villages to strategic border fortresses" and a few special locations that blend "historical landmarks and mythology - like Xiaoxitian and the Underworld". There's a building system with "over 2,000 authentic components, enabling players to design and decorate with ancient Chinese furniture, tools, and artwork", plus a farming element with "over 60 varieties of typical plants from ancient times", each of which requires a certain soil type and temperature. 
</p>
<p>
You might also form bonds with "more than 30 creatures", training them up as mounts and selectively breeding them. But perhaps you'd rather set up a metallurgy business, hiring workers, opening branches, and doing promotion while sabotaging rival businesses at night. Or perhaps you'd rather be a diplomat. Or a black market dealer with a grappling hook. Or a wandering martial artist. Or a general with their own chariot and a retinue of catapults. Or a ravenous amalgamation of all these things.
</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/PV2-screenshot-(7).jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Lightning Games</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
I am deeply suspicious that all of this will work quite as promised, especially "in a world where every choice ripples through the tapestry of the game" and NPCs, "driven by their unique character traits and familial ties, dynamically shape the cityscape based on players' interactions" - they're apparently capable of building their own houses and running their own businesses, and they'll undertake more personal behaviours like fleeing warzones and avenging slain loved ones. That's a lot of cause-and-effect to thread together.
</p><p>
The Bustling World does not have a release date yet. I'm not sure how long it's been in development, but this feels like it needs to be a "ready when it's ready" gig of the sort Hooded Horse <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-manor-lords-publisher-thinks-we-should-all-reject-the-opportunistic-and-predatory-quest-for-a-viral-hit">like to fund</a>, perhaps even a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/caves-of-qud-one-of-the-most-exciting-development-projects-in-pc-gaming-hit-10-this-week">Caves of Qud</a>-style decade+ marathon. It's not being advertised as an early access game, and I haven't been able to discover how large FireWo Games are. I hope they've got resources and people to spare.
</p>
<p>
In trailer form, at least, The Bustling World is a treat for the eyes and synapses, a lavish historical ant farm in which every NPC looks like they'd be worth shadowing. My favourites from the video are the kids - will they eventually grow into adults? It seems consistent with the premise - all of whom bounce along with the same carefree gait, whether they're attending a lion dance or trampling fish guts on the dock. Ah, my sweet summer children. You will have troubles aplenty when I found my empire of textile sweatshops. 
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Doom on a CAPTCHA is the most frustrating though admittedly raddest way to prove your humanity to an algorithm]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/doom-on-a-captcha-is-the-most-frustrating-though-admittedly-raddest-way-to-prove-your-humanity-to-an-algorithm</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/doom-on-a-captcha-is-the-most-frustrating-though-admittedly-raddest-way-to-prove-your-humanity-to-an-algorithm.1072575/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/doom-on-a-captcha-is-the-most-frustrating-though-admittedly-raddest-way-to-prove-your-humanity-to-an-algorithm<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>What difficulty are you on, <a href="https://doom-captcha.vercel.app/">Doom CAPTCHA</a>? I want to know because I need to know how bad to feel about myself. Six times I’ve tried to pass your <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-fps-games">FPS</a> test by killing three monsters to prove I’m human. Six times I’ve failed. For thousands of years, people have asked what it means to be human. It turns out it was never a philosophical issue after all. It was, I’m gutted to report, a skill issue all along.</p>

<p>It’s a fun concept, nonetheless, although it doesn’t really have the same effect removed from the context of an actual website. If I’d encountered it after trying to log on to do taxes, for example, it’d really stand apart from the usual fare asking you to identify all the buses you’d most like to lick or whatever. Sadly, you’re unlikely to see this one in the wild, as it’s really just an elaborate advertisement for frontend-as-a-service product <a href="https://x.com/vercel">Vercel</a> (thanks for the spot, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2025/01/01/people-are-playing-a-new-doom-themed-captcha/">TechCrunch</a>). It’s also one that’s been done before, albeit <a href="https://vivirenremoto.github.io/doomcaptcha/">in a different form</a> that I actually found far more playable.</p>
<p>As is customary whenever Doom On A Thing occurs, I must now list all previous instances of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/topics/can-it-run-doom">Doom On A Thing</a> RPS have covered in the past. Partly to uphold tradition, but mostly to spur on venomous comment discourse over what really counts as ‘running’ Doom. Ahem:</p><p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/balatro-can-run-doom-or-can-it">Balatro</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fortnite-can-run-doom-now-making-it-officially-as-useful-as-gut-bacteria-and-rat-neurons">Fortnite</a>, an <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/before-you-brush-your-teeth-tonight-remember-to-install-doom-on-your-electric-toothbrush">electric toothbrush</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-next-weird-device-to-run-doom-your-lawnmower">your lawnmower</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/now-you-can-play-doom-over-teletext">Teletext</a>, a<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/doom-can-now-run-on-a-jailbroken-tractor"> jailbroken tractor</a>,  a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/doom-on-game-and-watch">Nintendo Game &amp; Watch</a>, a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/yup-a-pregnancy-test-is-the-weirdest-device-ive-seen-running-doom">pregnancy test</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/you-can-play-doom-using-gut-bacteria-but-the-framerate-is-atrocious">gut bacteria</a>, and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/theres-a-new-weirdest-way-to-play-doom-using-rat-neurons-grown-in-a-jar">rat neurons in a jar</a>. The first person to write a narratively cohesive short story using all these objects gets a nice biscuit. The biscuit cannot run Doom. Yet.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delightful dark fantasy fable Ghost Of A Tale, aka Ico meets Redwall, is getting an Unreal Engine sequel]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/delightful-dark-fantasy-fable-ghost-of-a-tale-aka-ico-meets-redwall-is-getting-an-unreal-engine-sequel</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/delightful-dark-fantasy-fable-ghost-of-a-tale-aka-ico-meets-redwall-is-getting-an-unreal-engine-sequel.1072530/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/delightful-dark-fantasy-fable-ghost-of-a-tale-aka-ico-meets-redwall-is-getting-an-unreal-engine-sequel<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Developers break their silence after a year and a half of "lost" development</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_RG7o8Kx.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>SeithCG</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Happy new year all! And what better way to kick off another undignified 12 month crawl toward the next Xmas holiday than with the news that one of my favourite dark fantasy storybook extravaganzas, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/ghost-of-a-tale">Ghost Of A Tale</a>, is getting a sequel.</p>
<p>The newness of this news is in question, admittedly. Developer Lionel "Seith" Gallat and his team have been working on another helping of haunted mouseketeering since 2022. But this is the first time they've properly blogged about it, sharing details of a gruelling switchover to Unreal Engine 5 and a couple of new screens. They still haven't updated the title to make the obvious pun, but perhaps a title as pungent with whimsy as "Ghost Of A Tail" is beyond the trumpeted capabilities of Unreal Engine 5.

</p><!--more-->
<p>
If you've not had the pleasure, Ghost Of A Tale is sort of a whole game set inside the Undead Parish of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dark-souls">Dark Souls</a>, except that it's also sort of set in Redwall. You are an incarcerated mouse minstrel, Tilo, who must escape a monstrous clifftop fortress full of gangly rat guards. Along the way, you'll plunder spider nests, strike deals with reclusive alchemists, practice songs with preening rat lords, don some fetching disguises, and unravel some surprisingly well-imagined species prejudice, rooted in a mythological battle against an apocalyptic Green Flame. 
</p>
<p>
There's a sparkling cast of anthropomorphic animals with jovial character portraits, some absurdly handsome, tumbledown environments, and a fair bit of fun writing. The stealth kind of sucks, mind, but it's nothing you won't forgive when you're handed a quest to identify mushrooms in a sun-dappled courtyard using a parchment fungipedia. Redwall and Dark Souls aside, the game's other inspirations include The Secret of NIMH, Ico (probably the more natural comparison than From Software's output, here), The Dark Crystal, and Zelda. The words "love" and "lovely" appear no less than eight times in John Walker's (RPS in peace) <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ghost-of-a-tale-is-a-stealthy-rpg-with-bright-whiskers">review</a> from 2018. 
</p><p>
The original game ran in Unity, and that's the engine they were using for the sequel, to begin with. Seith - a former DreamWorks animator - and his collaborators have also developed a new in-house tool for quests and dialogue - the "previous off-the-shelf tool was little more than a glorified text editor", apparently.
</p>
<p>
The game had been in development for a "couple of years" before the team found that Unity wasn't cutting the mustard. "We were spending more time fighting the engine rather than actually creating gameplay systems and assets," Seith <a href="https://www.ghostofatale.com/were-back/">writes in the blog post</a>. So he decided to switch to Unreal Engine 5, despite "not having liked at all the earlier 4.x iterations", after talking it out with designer Paul Gardner and programmer Cyrille Paulhiac.
</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/2_tHsyFBf.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>SeithCG</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
Changing to a different game engine mid-production "almost never happens in the industry because the consequences are too dire to contemplate," Seith notes in the blog post. "Normally you would have to go through a storm of unpleasant meetings, convince the heads of the studio, look producers and investors in the eye and say 'we need to scrap those last couple of years of development and start again from scratch'. Unthinkable!
</p><p>
"Thankfully in our case it turned out Paul and Cyrille were willing to trust me and bite the bullet," he goes on. "Still, Cyrille was doing a lot of the back-end pipeline like data management, saving/loading system and authoring tools and it meant for him to ditch everything he knew and had accomplished in C# and move on to C++. Not an easy prospect by any stretch of the imagination."
</p>
<p>
Gardner, meanwhile, had "to revert to early stages of testing and participate again [in] the initial development of a new system of dialogs and quests, intricately interwoven with game design" but thankfully, investing in their own tools for dialogue and quests "meant that the nature of Paul's writing work wouldn't be affected too much by the game engine change." 
</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/3_hsfvOu4.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>SeithCG</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
The reset has also given Seith and his collaborators a chance "to refocus on the game's strengths and essence, which we might not have done had we kept on plowing ahead as initially planned". 
</p>
<p>
Changing to Unreal Engine 5 has involved a "lost" year and a half of development time, Seith concludes, "but I'm very glad to say today that it was all well worth the time, pain and money. We're now at a stage we would never have reached with the previous engine." You can assess the results yourself by means of the screenshots, creatively dotted around this article like mice peeking over parapets.
</p>
<p>
I've given Ghost Of A <strike>Tail</strike> Tale much love over the years, though as with many games I cherish, I'm not sure I've ever written anything that measures up to my enthusiasm. It's the first and only game my life partner has ever watched me play from intro to credits. What I want from the sequel is: make the stealth a more organic part of exploration and questing, and less of an irksome capital-S system (with grating encounter music) you have to appease along the way to the Good Stuff. Do clevererer things with disguises, too. And give me an even more elaborate mushroom-picking quest. I wouldn't object if the entire experience were about foraging.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>