<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 11:40:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mewgenics, the cat breeding roguelike from The Binding Of Isaac creator, has been delayed to avoid fighting other big moggies]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mewgenics-the-cat-breeding-roguelike-from-the-binding-of-isaac-creator-has-been-delayed-to-avoid-fighting-other-big-moggies</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mewgenics-the-cat-breeding-roguelike-from-the-binding-of-isaac-creator-has-been-delayed-to-avoid-fighting-other-big-moggies.1213074/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mewgenics-the-cat-breeding-roguelike-from-the-binding-of-isaac-creator-has-been-delayed-to-avoid-fighting-other-big-moggies<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Edmund McMillen and Tyler Glaiel</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/mewgenics">Mewgenics</a>, the long-in-development endless cat breeding game from devs Edmund McMillen and Tyler Glaiel, has just had its release pencilled in for February 10th, 2026, by a fresh trailer. Yes, it’s still looking very weird and nigh impossible to explain to a mate in less than two minutes.</p>
<p>Following on from the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-first-trailer-for-the-binding-of-isaac-devs-next-game-mewgenics-answers-none-of-the-many-questions-i-have"> trailer it got in April</a>, this latest one roped in the most fitting collab <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-binding-of-isaac">Binding of Isaac</a> developer McMillen and co could have landed, in the form of sinewy surrealism expert and YouTuber MeatCanyon. We’ve also gotten a nice overview of where the devs are at in assembling their weird feline with two heads.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Mewgenics Release date trailer! ( By Meat Canyon )" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FhxmMH8VohA?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Mewgenics Release date trailer! ( By Meat Canyon )</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FhxmMH8VohA?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/FhxmMH8VohA?autoplay=1" title="Mewgenics Release date trailer! ( By Meat Canyon )">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FhxmMH8VohA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>As you can watch above, the release date trailer featured a cartoon bloke explaining a bit about his cat to a real bloke who I’m sure is a real vet. Among other things, the kitty’s got a gambling addiction, a conjoined twin, and has been probed by aliens in addition to having made a deal with the devil. So, just your average cat with average cat quirks.</p>
<p>In an accompanying <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/686060/view/529848673510623712?l=english">Steam dev blog</a>, McMillen explained the decision to push back releasing the “turn based legacy roguelike draft sim” into the wild until next year, rather than chucking it out of the cat flap before the end of 2025.</p>
<p>“Dude, listen. Launching in Nov–Dec is hard,” he wrote, “We want this game to get the attention it deserves and don’t want to compete with holidays and holiday AAA releases. And honestly, adding a few more months to dev means launching with an even more heavily tested and polished experience!”</p>
<p>In addition to more general polishing and playtesting, the sorts of things the team says they’ll be focusing on in this extra time include the addition of custom events, more cutscenes, and making sure they can launch the game in a few different languages.</p>
<p>McMillen added that Mewgenics’ mysterious final boss - which I’ve got no doubt will be <strong>something</strong> - is on track to be finished by the end of this month. The game’s “big secret late-game system” is already ready to go, and it’ll start getting some “alt/shiny furniture” next week. Sit back down on your gleaming throne, I know you’re excited about that last part, but patience is key here.</p>
<p>Why does a turn-based RPG/roguelike thing about cats shagging needs sparkling sofas, you might wonder. Don't look at me, I've got no idea whatsoever, but Mewgenics has definitely captured my curiosity, even if it's just because it has cats in it.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alien city explorer Bernband reemerges from a sci-fi alleyway]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/alien-city-explorer-bernband-reemerges-from-a-sci-fi-alleyway</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/alien-city-explorer-bernband-reemerges-from-a-sci-fi-alleyway.1213047/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/alien-city-explorer-bernband-reemerges-from-a-sci-fi-alleyway<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>More xeno jazz on the way</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Tom van den Boogaart / Sokpop Collective</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The appearance of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/bernband">Bernband</a> during last night's PC Gaming Show had a few of us at RPS clicking our fingers and pointing at our monitors yelling: "Bernband! Bernband!" This remake of the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-being-pleasantly-lost-bernband">best sci-fi walking sim of 2014</a> has been in the works for a while. Creator Tom van den Boogaart has dipped in and out of working on the alien wanderer, often switching focus to other projects such as <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/grunn">Grunn</a>. But now it looks like we are once again getting a trickle of sweet extraterrestrial wanderlust. Here's a trailer.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Bernband - Announcement Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yxSl96druSQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Bernband - Announcement Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yxSl96druSQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/yxSl96druSQ?autoplay=1" title="Bernband - Announcement Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yxSl96druSQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>"Bernband is a sci-fi exploration sim set in a bustling alien metropolis," says <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2789170/Bernband/">the Steam page</a>. "Wander the streets at your leisure. See the sights, from dodgy dive bars to sprawling mega-marts. Discover secret areas, or hang out with the locals! There are no missions or timers; your only goal is to take a stroll."</p>
<p>That lack of goals and objectives puts it once again firmly into walking simulator turf, but if it shares even a bit of the atmospheric richness of the original walkabout, that is absolutely grand. When Bernband <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/explore-alien-city-bernband">first appeared</a>, it offered a crowded little world of alien barflies, night clubs, high walkways, creepy alleys, xeno churches, school classrooms, and plenty of elevators connecting it all together. </p>
<p>It was a wonderful city to get lost in, and a reminder that simply dandering around a strange place can be exciting without having to collect anything, or even speak to anyone. As Alice O put it at the time, it's "about the freedom of being alone in a crowd, the joy of noise washing over you and filling you, and the pleasure of wandering with no purpose beyond wanting to have time to yourself and see some interesting things."</p>
<p>The original game's maker, Van den Boogaart, has <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bernband-gifs">periodically shared some of his ongoing work</a> on the remake. But it would often submerge again for some time as he worked on other things. After all, the creator is a member of the busiest gang of Dutch game tinkerers in the world, the Sokpop Collective (who are also credited as helping on this remake). Sokpop are a a kind of romantic ideal of the games industry - a crowd-funded independant gang of mates who have <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sokpop-collective-are-releasing-their-100th-game-and-aiming-for-100-more">made over 100 games</a> after announcing their plan to release <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sokpop-collective-are-popping-out-a-new-game-every-2-weeks">a new plaything every two weeks</a>. Their many many works include village building card game <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/stacklands-is-a-gentle-village-building-game-played-with-cards">Stacklands</a>, and tiny controller-friendly RTS <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/king-pins-is-sokpops-teeny-tiny-take-on-age-of-empires">King Pins</a>.  </p>
<p>No release date for Nu-Bernband yet, but we will stay ever vigilant. Bernband. Bernband!</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>