<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 12:14:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Team Cherry working on "quality issues" with Hollow Knight: Silksong's Simplified Chinese translation, following mixed Steam reviews]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/team-cherry-working-on-quality-issues-with-hollow-knight-silksongs-simplified-chinese-translation-following-mixed-steam-reviews</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/team-cherry-working-on-quality-issues-with-hollow-knight-silksongs-simplified-chinese-translation-following-mixed-steam-reviews.1289679/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Improvements will be in the works "over the coming weeks"</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Team Cherry</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hollow-knight-silksong">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a> developers Team Cherry are "working to improve" the game's Simplified Chinese translation, following "quality issues" which have seen its Steam user reviews from those speaking the language drop to "mixed".</p>
<p>As you can easily see thanks to Steam's recent introduction of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-now-has-language-specific-review-scores-which-might-make-identifying-certain-review-bombs-easier">language-specific review splits</a>, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1030300/Hollow_Knight_Silksong/#app_reviews_hash">the mixed reviews</a> are unique to the 6,382 people who've left verdicts in Simplified Chinese so far. For every other language, including Traditional Chinese, the impressions being left are either mostly or overwhelmingly positive, though it's worth noting that a sizeable number are more shows of support for Team Cherry than proper reviews, being based on less than an hour's playtime.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Team Cherry have clearly spotted this, with the studio's marketing and publishing director Matthew 'Leth' Griffin having <a href="https://x.com/griffinmatta/status/1963798473700168146">posted a message</a> to Chinese-speaking Skongers. "We appreciate you letting us know about quality issues with the current Simplified Chinese translation of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hollow-knight-silksong-walkthrough">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a>," he tweeted. "We'll be working to improve the translation over the coming weeks. Thanks for your feedback and support."</p>
<p>Issues with this translation of metroidvania were <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/app/1030300/discussions/0/595157852293939174/">flagged online</a> as early as its recent Gamescom demo in late August, with one user describing it as "terrible" and adding "if there are no changes in the official version, I am afraid there is a risk of bad reviews".</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Another user in that thread added: "If the demo’s text reflects what we’ll see in the final release, I must say the translation style in the demo differs greatly from the first game. Many lines feel unnatural, and some are even quite awkward or confusing in Chinese."</p><p>According to our Guides Writer Jeremy, who's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wuchang-fallen-feathers-bosses-made-unkillable">half-Chinese and categorises his knowledge of the language as moderate with speaking fluency</a>, the unnaturalness of the translation appears to stem from the use of classical grammar, a bit like an English translation which uses words like 'thee' and 'thou'. Shakespearean Skong. Sounds like it could be a fun time, were you not just trying to lose yourself in a game you've waited ages for.</p>
<p>Wherefore art thou, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/watch-out-hollow-knight-silksongs-hiding-a-sneaky-stardew-valley-creatorman-cameo">Eric Barone cameo</a>?</p>
<p>Here's hoping Team Cherry's planned translantion tweaks do let Chinese players enjoy jumping about as Hornet as much as many other Steam reviewers appear to be, without being subjected to bardly prose.</p>

        </div>
      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/team-cherry-working-on-quality-issues-with-hollow-knight-silksongs-simplified-chinese-translation-following-mixed-steam-reviews]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In rare show of hacking for joy, Blue Archive player fills the world with clones of their favourite character]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/in-rare-show-of-hacking-for-joy-blue-archive-player-fills-the-world-with-clones-of-their-favourite-character</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/in-rare-show-of-hacking-for-joy-blue-archive-player-fills-the-world-with-clones-of-their-favourite-character.1289652/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Begun, the "Koyukification" has</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Jambo971 / Nexon / Rock Paper Shotgun</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Late last month, players of Nexon's tactical schoolgirl gacha fest <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/blue-archive">Blue Archive</a> were horrified to discover that their universe had undergone Koyukification. For context, Kurosaki Koyuki is one of Blue Archive's recruitable characters, a twin-tailed pinkhead known for her immense natural code-breaking skills, her passion for gambling, and her mischievous persona. 
</p>
<p>
On August 31st, Blue Archivists logged onto discover that Koyuki had <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/wesleypires.bsky.social/post/3ly2cxqdos22w">multiplied like a virus</a>. Cafes and arcades teemed with duplicates of the character. Her snaggle-toothed rictus filled the game's recruitment banners. The very information page - once a source of guidance and solace to so many - had been edited to read "nihahaha", in mimicry of the character's giggle. 
</p>
<p>
It was kind of like<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c2fVfIejbfM"> this scene from Being John Malkovich</a>, if John Malkovich had been a freakazoid 15-year-old piker armed with a light machinegun. And also, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EBmH1M4DSSU">the closing scenes from Matrix Revolutions</a> (Koyuki's in-game nickname is "White Rabbit"), if Neo and Agent Smith had decided to lay off the kung fu and sample the local parfait.
</p>
<p>
How to explain these nightmarish events? It was a hack, obviously. As reported by <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/blue-archive-got-hacked-but-the-hacker-just-spawned-the-same-character-everywhere-without-touching-valuable-data-nexon-confirms/">Automaton West</a>, publishers Nexon took Blue Archive offline for a few hours that Sunday to expunge the excess Koyukis and carry out an investigation. Seemingly, this was the good kind of hack, carried out for the glee of it rather than to filch anybody's credit card details. Or at least, that's what they're saying publicly.
</p><p>
<a href="https://forum.nexon.com/bluearchive-en/board_view?board=3028&amp;thread=3123126">According to Nexon</a>'s subsequent notice to players, somebody managed to break into the game's content delivery network and mess with the environment settings, which are managed separately from the game itself, redirecting them to an IP address in the Netherlands.</p>
<p>The hacker's changes only "affected the client-side content display", it seems. Nexon say that "players' accounts, game data, and payment information were not affected, as they are operated in a separate database and always revalidated by the game server."
</p>
<p>
You may find the idea of your online gameworld being suddenly suffused by goblin cryptanalysts amusing. Rest assured that Nexon do not. Aside from introducing new restrictions and countermeasures, they've reported the whole ordeal to the Korea Internet &amp; Security Agency. They've also prepared a player compensation package of in-game McGuffins to say sorry for the emergency maintenance period. Thoughts and prayers, etc.

</p>
<p>Is Blue Archive worth playing post-Koyukification? I can tell you nothing save that <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YHy8JmWX3kw&amp;t=62s">this trailer</a> thoroughly weirded me out with its bright and breezy scenes of school life in which everybody present is packing enough firepower to clear out a Terminid nest.</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/in-rare-show-of-hacking-for-joy-blue-archive-player-fills-the-world-with-clones-of-their-favourite-character]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch out, Hollow Knight: Silksong's hiding a sneaky Stardew Valley creatorman cameo]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/watch-out-hollow-knight-silksongs-hiding-a-sneaky-stardew-valley-creatorman-cameo</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/watch-out-hollow-knight-silksongs-hiding-a-sneaky-stardew-valley-creatorman-cameo.1289616/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Well, I say hiding, he's literally in the credits</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Team Cherry</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>In case you missed it, a plucky little game no one had heard anything about whatsoever <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hollow-knight-silksong-is-out-now-on-steam-our-review-is-on-the-way">arrived yesterday</a>. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hollow-knight-silksong">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a>. Yeah, I know, it's news to me too. Anyway, what's also news is that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/stardew-valley">Stardew Valley</a> creator Eric Barone has a voice acting cameo in Skong. Though, he's being all coy about revealing when and where you can hear his dulcet tones.</p>
<p>This came to light because of some valiant folks who've already made it to Silksong's end credits, presumably having pulled mammoth sessions last night, as our own Ollie did to provide you lot with <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hollow-knight-silksong-walkthrough">some helpful early game walkthroughs</a>. Or, you know, they've gone to the extras bit of the main menu and pressed the button that rolls the credits.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Barone's name is just chilling there in a section dedicated to additional characters voices, which also features Team Cherry marketing and publishing fellow Matthew Griffin. Naturally, the question is where do folks have to go to find Barone's cameo?</p>
<p>According to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/771772/hollow-knight-silksong-stardew-valley-eric-barone-concernedape">The Verge</a>, who reached out to ConcernedApe LLC's head of operations Cole Medeiros, neither he nor Barone would just come out and say where the cameo is, despite confirming it is indeed <em>that</em> Eric Barone. Medeiros told the site that the Stardew and and also <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/haunted-chocolatier">Haunted Chocolatier</a> dev would "rather not say which character(s) so as not to spoil any surprises for anyone".</p>
<p>I've not had a chance to join the RPS Skong hive currently reviewing/guiding/Edwining their way through Silksong yet, so I'm gonna take a big old stab in the dark as to which character Barone's voiced.</p>
<p>It's this one:</p>
<blockquote data-bluesky-cid="bafyreifwcukkxtexsdoejobekbbwpwimbsad6bzwyxikpvskcklgexuyba" data-bluesky-embed-color-mode="system" data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:ka7tco6wduc3ycrknd4l52yl/app.bsky.feed.post/3lxyqvsokec2l">— Kelsey (<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:ka7tco6wduc3ycrknd4l52yl?ref_src=embed">@badkirbys.bsky.social</a>) <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:ka7tco6wduc3ycrknd4l52yl/post/3lxyqvsokec2l?ref_src=embed">4 September 2025 at 09:43</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><p>I stress, that's a total guess based on zero knowledge or information, just vibes. If it's correct, everyone who reads this owes me a pound of human flesh to feed Horace. If it's wrong, I'll pretend it didn't happen and probably go dark on the socials for a bit, as is the custom when you've callously said something wrong and are a bit embarrassed about it.</p><p>Outside of the Barone cameo coming to light, Silksong's arrival also <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/silksong-has-murdered-steam">briefly murdered Steam</a>. The storefront has since been revived by a crack team of medics exhibiting the sort of CPR enthusiasm reserved for those who know their ability to play <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/i-am-jesus-christ">I Am Jesus Christ</a>'s demo is at stake.</p>

        </div>
      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/watch-out-hollow-knight-silksongs-hiding-a-sneaky-stardew-valley-creatorman-cameo]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ConcernedApe assures that Stardew Valley update 1.7 won't delay Haunted Chocolatier much - it might even release first]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/concernedape-assures-that-stardew-valley-update-17-wont-delay-haunted-chocolatier-much-it-might-even-release-first</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/concernedape-assures-that-stardew-valley-update-1-7-wont-delay-haunted-chocolatier-much-it-might-even-release-first.1289595/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Barone is taking more of a "creative director" role on the new update</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>ConcernedApe</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Fear not, fans of spirit candy! <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-cats-out-of-the-bag-stardew-valley-update-17-revealed-bagged-cat-content-tbc">The recent announcement of Stardew Valley 1.7 update</a> is not evidence that Eric "ConcernedApe" Barone's next game <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/haunted-chocolatier">Haunted Chocolatier</a> has been banished to the realm of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/our-favourite-videogame-vapourware-no-silksong-allowed-edition">vapourware</a> - or so sayeth Barone himself, at least. In a brief and caveat-strewn Q&amp;A, the life sim creator has gone into more depth about development on Stardew, revealing that he's not as heavily involved with it as with previous updates. As such, he's still focussing "the vast majority" of his attention on Haunted Chocolatier.</p>
<p>It's even possible that the latter will release before <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/stardew-valley">Stardew Valley</a>'s next update, but let's not count our Cocoa Loco Little Choc Chicks (£6.99 minus delivery costs) before they've hatched.
</p><!--more-->
<p>

"Recently, I announced that there will be another major content update for Stardew Valley -- the 1.7 update," <a href="https://www.hauntedchocolatier.net/2025/09/02/on-the-recent-stardew-valley-1-7-update-announcement/">writes Barone on his blog</a>. "You might be wondering: If ConcernedApe is working on Stardew Valley 1.7, will that cause Haunted Chocolatier to take longer? The answer: Maybe a little, but not as much as you might think."
</p>
<p>

Barone goes onto explain that he's been working with a small team on Stardew Valley additions and fixes since update 1.3 - he's still "completely solo" on Haunted Chocolatier "for the time being". 
</p>
<p>
While he was "fully, personally locked-in on content development" for previous Stardew updates, Barone says that with update 1.7, "I have been trying to take more of a "creative director" role in the team, so that (at least for now) I can focus the vast majority of my attention on Haunted Chocolatier." 
</p><p>
"So far, it's been pretty good... we are working at a relaxed pace, we have a ton of ideas, and everything has been high quality," Barone continues. "Eventually, I will have to spend a little more time focused on Stardew Valley, because in order for me to maintain a full connection to the game, I need my hand to touch every piece of new content. And there are some aspects of content development which I insist on doing myself, like the music. 
</p>
<p>
"But with our "no release date" approach to the 1.7 update, it's not certain when that time will come. It might even be after Haunted Chocolatier comes out. (no guarantees though)".
</p>
<p>
Barone adds that "the reality of my life is that I have a very popular 1st game that I still want to take care of, which means that my 2nd game might take a little longer". Stardew Valley's audience is "still growing", he notes, and "it's hard to just stop improving it when there are still things that can be improved. But I hope the approach I am taking for Stardew Valley 1.7 will help keep Haunted Chocolatier on track."
</p>
<p>
Stardewman remains tight-lipped as to what update 1.7 might involve. We don't know a whole caboodle about Haunted Chocolatier, either, other than that it's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/haunted-chocolatier-is-the-stardew-valleys-developers-next-rpg">more of an action-RPG than Stardew Valley</a>, and sees you staffing a chocolate shop with ghosts.</p><p>Let me laboriously do some Audience Engagement and ask: what kind of chocolate would you be <em>least</em> surprised to discover is made by ghosts? I've always found hazelnut truffles a bit sinister. I find that they mysteriously make me fatter - clear indications of paranormal activity.
</p>
</div>
      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/concernedape-assures-that-stardew-valley-update-17-wont-delay-haunted-chocolatier-much-it-might-even-release-first]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>