<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 18:52:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grounded 2 brings big bug survival to Game Preview this July]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grounded-2-brings-big-bug-survival-to-game-preview-this-july</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grounded-2-brings-big-bug-survival-to-game-preview-this-july.1212240/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grounded-2-brings-big-bug-survival-to-game-preview-this-july<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/grounded-2">Grounded 2</a>, the sequel to Obsidian's Honey I Shrunk The <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/kids">Kids</a> 'em up, has been announced for a July 29th release into Xbox's Game Preview program - effectively early access. It's looking very similar to the previous game so far - a creative <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-survival-games-on-pc">survival</a> game where regular garden features like spiders and plants becoming terrifying foes and imposing megastructures. Trailer below. It's got some early Offspring in it! God. Smash is 21 years old. Shrink me into a pile of dust.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Grounded 2 - Official Announce Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/q0HQNOtg1WI?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Grounded 2 - Official Announce Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/q0HQNOtg1WI?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/q0HQNOtg1WI?autoplay=1" title="Grounded 2 - Official Announce Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=q0HQNOtg1WI" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>Here's Xbox on the game:</p>
<blockquote><p>Shrunk again, but the world is much larger. In this open-world, single-player or cooperative survival adventure, craft weapons and armor, build your base, and traverse the playground on your buggy. But something else is out there—and it hasn’t forgotten you.</p></blockquote>
<p>As seen in the trailer, you can fight bugs, pet bugs, ride bugs, build a base out of parts presumably at least in part gathered from the corpses of bugs, and do this all with mates. Maybe one of your mates is a bug. Maybe you're all bugs. It's fine. This is the garden. It's a great place to be a bug. Or an awful place I suppose if you're a smaller, prey-like bug. My heart goes out to those guys, consumed as they may be by the time it reaches them.</p>
<p>"An incredibly rewarding survival experience that constantly pushes you into new areas of its reactive world," was Hayden's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grounded-review">take</a> (RPS in peace) on the first <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/grounded">Grounded</a> "filled with insect inhabitants that are some of the best baddies in gaming".</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones And The Great Circle's first DLC arrives September]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circles-first-dlc-arrives-september</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circles-first-dlc-arrives-september.1212234/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circles-first-dlc-arrives-september<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Explore Rome, learn about those big fellas</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Machine Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Indiana Jones And The Great Circle contained at least one big lad, that I remember. Now it's expansion is sending you to the land of the big lads. At this evening's Xbox Game Showcase, Machine Games announced the first DLC for their first-person archaeol-'em-up, titled The Order of Giants. The trailer below doesn't show much, but there's a release date: September 4th.
</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Indiana Jones and the Great Circle: The Order of Giants - Official DLC Reveal | Xbox Games Showcase" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/A2RuOBSGy8o?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle: The Order of Giants - Official DLC Reveal | Xbox Games Showcase</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/A2RuOBSGy8o?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/A2RuOBSGy8o?autoplay=1" title="Indiana Jones and the Great Circle: The Order of Giants - Official DLC Reveal | Xbox Games Showcase">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>The Order Of Giants DLC trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A2RuOBSGy8o" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>This is one of those trailers where it spends a lot of its running time recapping and celebrating the base game. Fair enough, honestly. I might not have completed The Great Circle yet, but I loved the 25 hours I did play of it. It's no mean feat to bring a beloved icon of cinema to life in a video game and make it feel both authentic and original at the same time. Take the victory lap, in other words.
</p>
<p>This also means I'm keen on DLC even without having finished my plate of the first one. There are <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/06/08/indiana-jones-great-circle-dlc-order-giants-xbox-games-showcase/">more details over on Xbox Wire</a>, for those who found the trailer lacking:
</p>
<blockquote>The Indiana Jones and the Great Circle: The Order of Giants DLC kicks off when Indy meets Father Ricci, a young priest in desperate need of assistance tracking down a mysterious artifact. What starts as a typical treasure hunt soon becomes a perilous expedition as Indiana uncovers the history of the Nephilim order.</blockquote>
<p>Your journey will take you into Rome, beyond the boundariies of Vatican City so thoroughly explored in the Great Circle. I hope we don't spend all of our time in sewers, though. We'll find out come September.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dontnod are working with the European Space Agency to make sci-fi adventure game Aphelion]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dontnod-are-working-with-the-european-space-agency-to-make-sci-fi-adventure-game-aphelion</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dontnod-are-working-with-the-european-space-agency-to-make-sci-fi-adventure-game-aphelion.1212231/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dontnod-are-working-with-the-european-space-agency-to-make-sci-fi-adventure-game-aphelion<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Xbox / Microsoft</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Of all the space exploration agencies to consult while making a videogame, perhaps the European Space Agency is the best bet. Dontnod, the makers of Life Is Strange, have teamed up with the organisation of euronauts to create a third-person action adventure about an astronaut struggling to survive after crash landing on an alien planet. It's called <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/aphelion">Aphelion</a>, and it'll be out sometime in 2026. Here's a trailer from the Xbox Games Showcase.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Aphelion | Reveal Trailer | Xbox Games Showcase 2025" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RZs_IthEb2s?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Aphelion | Reveal Trailer | Xbox Games Showcase 2025</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RZs_IthEb2s?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/RZs_IthEb2s?autoplay=1" title="Aphelion | Reveal Trailer | Xbox Games Showcase 2025">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RZs_IthEb2s" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>That's a lot of classic Uncharted-style hill-sliding and panic-leaping. For the less scientifically inclined, the "aphelion" is the point in a planet's orbit at which it's furthest from their star. It sounds dangerous. Travelling to other planets is an absolute peril, and I keep telling everyone to stop doing it. Look, there's even the growls of some off-screen alien creature at the trailer's end. Aliens love to stay off-screen, it's like their hobby.</p>
<p>I make fun, but Dontnod actually have good form at climbing and clambering, with Alice B calling their mountaineering game <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/jusant">Jusant</a> a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/jusant-review">"show don't tell masterpiece"</a>. So there's a chance this space adventure will turn out deec. We'll see.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>