<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 15:31:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oh thank Horace, our comments system is up and running again]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oh-thank-horace-our-comments-system-is-up-and-running-again</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/oh-thank-horace-our-comments-system-is-up-and-running-again.1028754/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oh-thank-horace-our-comments-system-is-up-and-running-again<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1200px-Ten_Men_and_Four_Boys_Singing_in_a_Church_MET_DP835947.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Pieter de Jode II / Purchase, Joseph Pulitzer Bequest, 1917 / Metropolitan Museum of Art</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>"Never read the comments," is a truth much-rehearsed by senior games journalists, but I have long since levelled-up past this axiom and entered into a new world of benevolent narcissism. I <em>always</em> read the comments, for all commenters are my children. They exist to glorify and preserve me in my dotage. True, occasionally my children say things like "I think your writing and opinions are appalling, and that you deserve to be repeatedly run over by a herd of deer", but it is the nature of children to rebel.</p>
<p>All of which is to say that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/weve-temporarily-closed-comments-for-maintenance-but-theyll-be-back">the comments downtime during a tech transition</a> this week has been painful for me. I've missed you all! I don't have anything particular to say in this post - I just thought we could do with a place to convene after this long, strange purgatory of articles being published with no accompanying trickle or waterfall of reader insights. What have you all been up to? Any news to share? I hear there's been some kind of election somewhere. I promise you the comments outage is unrelated.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>