<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 13:10:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The sequel to Robocop: Rogue City sounds more like Dredd]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sequel-to-robocop-rogue-city-sounds-more-like-dredd</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-sequel-to-robocop-rogue-city-sounds-more-like-dredd.1127946/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sequel-to-robocop-rogue-city-sounds-more-like-dredd<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article">
        <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/robocop-rogue-city-unfinished-business-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Nacon</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>RoboCop will be climbing an apartment tower full of slimebags in a standalone follow-up to his trudging but faithful 2023 shooter. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/robocop-rogue-city-unfinished-business">Robocop: Rogue City - Unfinished Business</a> is so over-named it looks like DLC, but is actually an independent sequel from the same developers, and directly follows the events of the recent criminal justice 'em up. It'll see metal man Murphy going floor to floor as he and other Detroit city policefolk ascend a residential tower after "a group of highly trained mercenaries armed with cutting-edge weapons takes control of the building and turns it into their deadly fortress." Wait... doesn't this sound like another cyberpunk dystopia?</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="RoboCop: Rogue City - Unfinished Business | Reveal Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HZxqWFQI7GY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>RoboCop: Rogue City - Unfinished Business | Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HZxqWFQI7GY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/HZxqWFQI7GY?autoplay=1" title="RoboCop: Rogue City - Unfinished Business | Reveal Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HZxqWFQI7GY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>"Prepare to take on a new breed of enemies: OmniTower is packed with high-tech threats," says the game's blurb <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3527760/RoboCop_Rogue_City__Unfinished_Business/">on Steam</a>. "From flying drones to exploding bots and anti-personnel turrets, every floor is riddled with deadly traps, and heavily armed elite troops. Expect to face minigun-toting armoured squads, special forces equipped with jet packs or even katana-wielding foes who look more machine than man."</p>
<p>If you have seen 2012's <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G-eI5oLlIeY">Dredd</a> starring Karl Urban, you may have raised an eyebrow (if you have seen <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=m6Q7KnXpNOg">The Raid</a>, you have raised both). Yes, this sounds like the same premise. But maybe that's no big deal. Developers Teyon seem to be doing their due diligence by adding all the requisite RoboCop-flavoured elements. You will play through FPS flashbacks with Murphy as a pre-cyberized meatcop, for example, and get some new abilities and weapons, such as a freezey cryo cannon and "devastating finishing moves" where you can slam crime-doer faces into nearby walls and vending machines.</p>
<p>The additional hands-on bone-crunching checks out. One of the more enjoyable parts of Robo's recent wreckabout was being able to lift any perp and yeet them ragdollifically across the city streets and prison corridors that you stomped through. Other than that I wasn't too fond of the shooter in my <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/robocop-rogue-city-review">RoboCop: Rogue City review</a> but I did acknowledge that it would likely be pleasing to long time fans of Paul Verhoeven's ultra-violent satire. </p>
<p>The sequel-follow-up-not-DLC-we-promise is due out sometime in "Q3 2025" which is business speak for "I dunno, autumn, I guess". </p></div>

        </article>

  
    </div><div data-component="article-footer">
    <div>
      <p><span><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/authors/brendan-caldwell">Brendan Caldwell</a></span>: Brendan likes all types of games. To him there is wisdom in Crusader Kings 2, valour in Dark Souls, and tragicomedy in Nidhogg.
      </p>
    </div>




  



  <section>
    <p>In this article</p>

    

  </section>

  <section>
    <p>Related topics</p>

    
  </section>

  <div data-mode="signup" data-component="smart slot">
      <p>
        Rock Paper Shotgun is better when you sign in
      </p>

      <p>
        Sign in and join us on our journey to discover strange and compelling PC games.
      </p>

      
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Forever Winter's water will no longer drain away while you're offline]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-forever-winters-water-will-no-longer-drain-away-while-youre-offline</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-forever-winters-water-will-no-longer-drain-away-while-youre-offline.1127901/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-forever-winters-water-will-no-longer-drain-away-while-youre-offline<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-forever-winter-water-update-3.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Fun Dog Studios</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Mechy and messy extraction shooter <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-forever-winter">The Forever Winter</a> sees a big update today that addresses the biggest player complaint the game had on launch - the precious water that drained away in real-time, even while you weren't playing the game. The patch to the early access shooter reworks water so it becomes a currency that you use to infiltrate the game's brutal maps at different entry points, instead of dripping away and threatening to leave you thirsty and destitute. And this isn't the only promising news - enemy spawning changes, reworked gunplay, and a new map also appear. </p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Forever Winter - March Update: “The Descent to Averno is Easy”" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/agY8OeKcur0?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Forever Winter - March Update: “The Descent to Averno is Easy”</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/agY8OeKcur0?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/agY8OeKcur0?autoplay=1" title="The Forever Winter - March Update: “The Descent to Averno is Easy”">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=agY8OeKcur0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>If you missed the water fury the first time around, let me explain. The Forever Winter's brutal warzones would often hide barrels of water you could strap to your back. Escape the map and you would add these litres to a big water tank in your home base (a hub of bullet merchants where you stash all the good gear you've scavenged). But that water supply would slowly drain - the cost of keeping your hub running. If it hit zero, your hub would "die" and all your stashed goodies would vanish. This water supply would deplete even while offline, the idea being that this adds more stress to the process of surviving in an apocalyptic hellscape. </p>
<p>Now the game's creators are ditching that idea entirely. "Water is no longer a resource that drains [in] real-time," say developers Fun Dog Studios in the update's <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2828860/view/496063443495814171">patch notes on Steam</a>. "It is now a currency that is used to access region entry points. Region entry points have specific water costs that are in an RNG range."</p>
<p>This basically means the game's maps now have a default entry point, and you'll need to use water as payment to enter the hellish battleyards from other starting points (you may also need to have a good reputation with certain factions for this). Water can now also be traded from player to player, and the frequency of scavengable water barrels appearing in maps has been rebalanced, say the devs. </p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-forever-winter-water-update-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Fun Dog Studios</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Unsurprisingly, many players disliked the original water premise. It became one of the biggest gripes in an early access launch marred by performance issues and unpredictable enemy behaviour. The developers promised changes, but didn't want to remove water as a stressy driving force completely. </p>
<p>One early patch saw <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-forever-winter-devs-answer-complaints-about-water-scarcity-by-adding-thieves-who-invade-your-hq-and-steal-your-water">thieves creep into your subterranean home to steal your last drops</a>. Defeating these scoundrels offered a last chance to save your stash from a water shortage. Later, the developers added a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2828860/view/547848028756640978">"thief-proof vault"</a> - a limited space for goodies that would never be lost, even in a critical water crisis. They also introduced water bots that would let players collect water automatically. (The meme-faced water thieves will still appear following this latest update, we're told. Although the consequences for not dealing with them won't be so high anymore.) </p>
<p>The water system, for all the ire it attracted, was the least significant of my complaints when I played The Forever Winter for <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-forever-winter-struggles-into-early-access-with-poor-performance-and-a-deadly-thirst-for-your-time">our early access review</a>. Enemy spawning was wacky, their combat behaviour was difficult to understand, levels were cluttered and visually noisy, bugs were commonplace, and even the simple act of picking up items from the ground was a chore. I loved the core idea (little scav caught in the middle of an eternal robo-war) and the art direction is precisely my weathered cloth bag. But it was hard to stomach the rough state of the launch.</p>
<p>This update addresses several of those problems too, though. Enemy spawning has been adjusted to "hopefully completely remove" the problem of "seeing enemies spawn right in front of you out of thin air" or "having enemies spawn right on top of you or out of view." Guns have seen a big rework, and a new map featuring a fiery stone staircase has been added. We're also told "rendering improvements have been made to increase FPS" and "enemy detection icons show up more reliably with the correct information", meaning that you should theoretically be able to understand when and where a foe spots you or a teammate.</p>
<p>This is all good news, and I want to return to the game to see if it plays a little smoother now. I'm in favour of the water rework too. I understand that game designers often aim to elicit strong emotions in players, and here Fun Dog's designers desired a feeling of unease and insecurity, all the better to fit their game's permawar theme. But I prefer when those feelings are confined to the time when I'm actually playing the game, rather than spreading like a nervous tendril into my real life. I imagine many others feel the same about "FOMO" designs like this. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Goblin stealth gaming returns in Styx: Blades Of Greed, out in 2025 - here's the first trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/goblin-stealth-gaming-returns-in-styx-blades-of-greed-out-in-2025-heres-the-first-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/goblin-stealth-gaming-returns-in-styx-blades-of-greed-out-in-2025-heres-the-first-trailer.1127874/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/goblin-stealth-gaming-returns-in-styx-blades-of-greed-out-in-2025-heres-the-first-trailer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Cyanide and Nacon have announced <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/styx-blades-of-greed">Styx: Blades Of Greed</a>, the third in a trilogy of goblin <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-stealth-games">stealth</a> games known for puke-based mechanics and many a snarky note-to-self. I never completed the previous <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/styx-master-of-shadows">Styx: Master Of Shadows</a> or <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/styx-shards-of-darkness">Styx: Shards Of Darkness</a>, and if I'm honest, I fear Cyanide's impish infiltrator is doomed to forever butt his smirking, warty head against the 6/10 glass ceiling, with Thief's Garrett flashing V-signs on the other side.</p>
<p>Still, I have a certain respect for the series. There aren't many third-person sneakers like this any more, still fewer that have successfully gotten away with a protagonist who sounds like a chaddy Sam Fisher and looks like he should be cleaning toilets in Moria. So a quiet hip-hooray, then, for Blades Of Greed, which is out later in 2025. Here's a trailer.
</p><!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Styx: Blades of Greed - Official Cinematic Reveal Trailer | Nacon Connect 2025" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wxS7-6uT2Bo?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Styx: Blades of Greed - Official Cinematic Reveal Trailer | Nacon Connect 2025</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wxS7-6uT2Bo?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/wxS7-6uT2Bo?autoplay=1" title="Styx: Blades of Greed - Official Cinematic Reveal Trailer | Nacon Connect 2025">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wxS7-6uT2Bo" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
What's the Green Plague up to in this one, then? The usual, from the looks of it: clambering up massive citadels, shivving or bamboozling their guards, cracking the bad kind of bad joke, making away with the treasure. You can still sick up a clone of yourself and turn invisible using Amber, but you also get powers derived from a new energy source, Quartz - these include mind control and time manipulation. 
</p>
<p>
The story is about stealing Quartz from the human Inquisition, and takes you via airship to three large environments - "The Wall, which marks the boundary of the human world; the lush orc village of Turquoise Dawn; and the Ruins of the elven capital, Akenash". New areas become available within those sandboxes via "Metroidvania-style" tool-gating. You'll also get to craft weapons and potions before undertaking each heist.
</p>
<p>
The setting has always been Styx's big draw for me. All that cobbled-together, piled-up masonry, buttressed by some respectable grimdark lore. I share Alec Meer's (RPS in peace) distaste for the character's internal monologue, however. "Clearly, a lot of money and skill has gone into making Shards Of Darkness, which only makes the fact that you have to battle past this woeful characterisation to get to the strong stealth meat below all the more tragic," he <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/styx-shards-of-darkness-review">wrote of the most recent Styx outing</a>.</p>
<p>Re-reading that review, I'm struck by the mention of rampant fourth-wall-breaking, which I don't remember being quite so abundant in Master Of Shadows. Hopefully they've eased off on it in Blades Of Greed. <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3290690/Styx_Blades_of_Greed/">Find out more on Steam</a>.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First look at Disco Elysium "spiritual successor" Hopetown shows a painterly, gorgeous, and utterly unconvincing RPG]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/first-look-at-disco-elysium-spiritual-successor-hopetown-shows-a-painterly-gorgeous-and-utterly-unconvincing-rpg</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/first-look-at-disco-elysium-spiritual-successor-hopetown-shows-a-painterly-gorgeous-and-utterly-unconvincing-rpg.1127847/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/first-look-at-disco-elysium-spiritual-successor-hopetown-shows-a-painterly-gorgeous-and-utterly-unconvincing-rpg<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Longdue Games have shared the first gameplay image from <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hopetown">Hopetown</a>, their <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> "spiritual successor" to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/disco-elysium">Disco Elysium</a>, coming soon to <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/longduegames/hopetown/">Kickstarter</a>.</p>
<p>First namelessly <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/former-disco-elysium-devs-are-working-on-a-spiritual-successor-at-new-studio-longdue-though-robert-kurvitz-and-aleksander-rostov-arent-involved">teased last October</a> as part of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sure-why-not-third-group-of-former-disco-elysium-devs-announce-revolutionary-new-rpg-studio">The Great Disco Thrupening</a>, then <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-psychogeography-est-of-disco-elysiums-spiritual-successors-is-a-gonzo-journalism-rpg-named-hopetown">revealed last month</a>, Hopetown was described as "merging the raw emotional depth and psychological intricacy of Disco Elysium with the philosophical richness and narrative complexity of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/planescape-torment">Planescape: Torment</a>."</p>
<!--more-->
<p>At the time, I hoped this tone and tenor of trying too hard<em> </em>was just press release guff. No such luck, if the writing shown off below is any indication.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Hopetown-gameplay-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Longdue</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>But let's first back up a moment, because it does <em>look</em> great. So great I'm having some difficulty believing this is what the game looks like, rather than just being concept art. It's stunning. The purple and yellow palette. The painterly style, soft but sharp with detail.</p>
<p>Then you start reading. "Let me introduce myself," says your character to a sweet old lady feeding pigeons. "I don't shit in my own drinking water - though I see that's not a deal-breaker".</p>
<p>In Disco Elysium, your character could find a leather jacket with "Fuck The World" written on the back. If you tried hard enough, you could even convince your partner Kim to wear a complimentary jacket that read "Pissf****t". Someone at Longdue evidently thought those jackets were a good baseline for character development.</p>
<p>Admittedly, I'm viewing this dialogue through eyes pre-exhausted by Longdue's description of your character as "a chaotic, self-destructive provocateur who sees humanity as inherently selfish and cruel" and "unapologetically cynical and dangerously unhinged". Disco Elysium was frequently self-satisfied, show-offish, and overly slick. But it wasn't ever, you know, <a href="https://youtu.be/rr56tvKSe28">Nathan Barley on the bus</a>.</p>
<p>The pigeon lady offers your character a loaf of bread. You've got three responses to that, one of which is categorised "Noblesse N'oblige". I like that name. The dialogue itself is "I'd rather lick the bin [knock the bread from her hands]" - a jejune and obliviously mean-spirited interpretation of why the chaotic cringe comedy options in Disco were so much fun.</p>
<p>Your "Gonzo" option is: "Yeah, feed the masses! So let it be done. EAT UP, SKY RATS! (Take the bread)". You ever see a sentence that reads like someone wrote the exclamation points first and worked backwards from there? The attempts at understated philosophy feel just as unconvincing: "They give the filth on the ground a fighting chance to touch the sky. That's admirable".</p>
<p>I don't expect or even especially want a carbon copy of Disco Elysium from Hopetown, but if you're going to piggyback off the imagination of people that<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/disco-elysium-studio-bosses-humiliated-the-cancelled-expansions-lead-writer-for-speaking-to-journalists-claims-report"> have allegedly had their work stolen from them</a>, apparently justified by the sole contribution of a lone systems designer from an outsourced studio (who I'm sure is excellent at their job and likely had no say in the "spiritual successor" marketing angle), I think you should probably make a more convincing attempt to better understand the spirit you're succeeding.</p>
<p>Still, bloody gorgeous art. And, look, I'm obviously cherrypicking lines out of context from a single screenshot. I'd be very happy to be eat crow for doubting pigeons here. If not, there's always two <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/yet-another-studio-formed-of-disco-elysium-alumni-has-announced-a-cerebral-sci-fi-rpg-just-to-confuse-you">others</a> anyway.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>