<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 12:15:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Subnautica 2 studio will get their bonus, says Krafton, but it's not the $250 million promised]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/subnautica-2-studio-will-get-their-bonus-says-krafton-but-its-not-the-250-million-promised</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/subnautica-2-studio-will-get-their-bonus-says-krafton-but-its-not-the-250-million-promised.1244844/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Unknown Worlds</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Publishers Krafton have told workers at <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/subnautica-2">Subnautica 2</a> studio Unknown Worlds they would still get a promised bonus if they ship enough of the game by the end of 2026. In other words, they've been given an extension to hit their targets. The bonus money was in question after <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/krafton-suddenly-replace-three-subnautica-2-leads-with-one-of-the-execs-behind-callisto-protocol">the surprise firing of senior staff</a> a couple of weeks ago, and the enforced delay of the survival game by Krafton. After worker concerns and fan outrage, now the corp says "don't worry, we'll pay!" Although it's not the huge $250 million they were originally supposed to.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>A report by <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-07-15/krafton-extends-subnautica-2-bonus-period-is-sued-by-founders?">Bloomberg</a> says the sweetener would include a $25 million payout to be shared (unequally) among roughly 40 specific developers at the studio. All other workers would meanwhile get a bonus paid this year, an advance on the "projected 2026 profit-sharing bonus pool". Although the amounts involved for those employees isn't specified.</p>
<p>It's a big wad of cash. It is also just one-tenth of the $250 million Krafton were due to pay out to the studio if it achieved certain sales figures by the end of 2025. So a relative bargain for the South Korean corporation. The reasons for all this are muddy. So let's go mudlarking.</p>
<p>In 2021 the studio were bought by Krafton for $500 million, with a further $250 million "earnout" promised if the studio hit a certain level of revenue by the end of 2025. The bulk of that earnout would be claimed by the leadership at the studio, who've since said they <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/subnautica/comments/1lwsxco/lawsuit_a_community_update_from_charlie/">planned to share some of that money</a> with other employees. Meanwhile $25 million of the earnout was ringfenced for the 40 employees mentioned above, with each getting a different sum, "most in the six or seven figures" according to paperwork seen by Bloomberg.</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Krafton</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>With all that cash at stake, things went wrong. Subnautica 2 was due to come out this year. Studio co-founder Charlie Cleveland <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/subnautica-2-is-ready-for-early-access-says-co-founder-ousted-from-studio-but-the-publishers-seem-to-disagree">believed the game was "ready for early access"</a>. Krafton disagreed. They wanted more work done on it. Naturally, whoever lost this argument would potentially lose quite a bit of dough. Presumably at an impasse, Krafton pulled out an axe and decapitated the studio heads Charlie Cleveland, Ted Gill, and Max MacGuire, and now <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/subnautica-2-publishers-krafton-accuse-ousted-bosses-of-abandoning-duties-and-now-those-ex-leads-are-suing">claim that they abandoned their duties</a>. The publisher installed Steve Papoutsis, a producer from Striking Distance (another Krafton studio) as new CEO, then publically delayed the game until 2026.</p>
<p>This left remaining workers concerned they too wouldn't see their promised bonuses. But Krafton have now extended their deadline by a year, until the end of 2026, says Bloomberg. Seems promising for those who'll benefit, although we haven't seen what Krafton consider as "ready" for release, nor know if it's achievable in that year.</p>
<p>Basically, it looks like Krafton understand that they have created a legal and financial headache for themselves - the three ousted devs are now suing the publisher, for one thing. They now look to be throwing some money at the problem. If one were inclined to think like a spreadsheet-brained corporate entity, one would surmise that as long as said throwin' money soothes current staff and does not exceed the $250 million they have been avoiding so far, it will all work out in the green. </p>
<p>It's a dirty mess soaked in cash, and it will likely get dirtier in court. Earlier this week, a document was "leaked" on Reddit that purpotedly showed how <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/subnautica-2-leak-is-authentic-say-publishers-who-benefit-the-most-from-that-leak">Subnautica 2's scope was reduced in the last two years</a>. Krafton still haven't responded to our question asking if they themselves were the source of this leak.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/subnautica-2-studio-will-get-their-bonus-says-krafton-but-its-not-the-250-million-promised]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valve change Steam's rules to let banks and credit card firms prohibit "certain kinds of adult only content"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valve-change-steams-rules-to-let-banks-and-credit-card-firms-prohibit-certain-kinds-of-adult-only-content</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valve-change-steams-rules-to-let-banks-and-credit-card-firms-prohibit-certain-kinds-of-adult-only-content.1244802/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>According to their own "rules and standards"</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Valve</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Valve have updated Steam's rules and regulations to prohibit games that "may violate the rules and standards set forth by Steam's payment processors and related card networks and banks, or internet network providers". And in particular, "certain kinds of adult only content". In other words, they are giving banks, ISPs and credit card companies some degree of control over Steam's definition of acceptable "adult only content". All of which potentially has rather dramatic ramifications, given that banks and payment companies have a track record for pressuring platform holders to nuke what they deem to be NSFW material.</p><!--more-->
<p>The new rule appears on Steam's <a href="https://partner.steamgames.com/doc/gettingstarted/onboarding?language=english#5">onboarding page for developers</a>. I've verified that it was recently added using the ole <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20250217163251/https://partner.steamgames.com/doc/gettingstarted/onboarding?language=english#5">Internet Wayback Machine</a>.</p>
<p>Valve's policy towards "adult content" and what separates this from pornography has always been rather foggy, partly because humans in general struggle to agree on what "adult" and "pornography" really mean. For a time, the platform holders tried to enforce a no-porno approach. This came to a head - probably not the best choice of words, so let's swiftly and humorously add "of steam" - in 2018, when Valve <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valve-threatening-removal-of-visual-novels-with-adult-content-some-authorised-years-ago-say-mangagamer">issued a bunch of rather arbitrary warnings</a> to various developers and publishers, demanding that they edit "pornographic content" out of games that ranged from horror sex comedies to puzzlers that are arguably far less raunchy than, say, the wham-bam scenes in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-witcher-3-wild-hunt">The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt</a>.</p>
<p>Following an outcry, Valve <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/games/593110/announcements/detail/1666776116200553082">announced</a> that they were stepping back from the enforcement of definitions around porn and adult content, and would instead focus on equipping players with tools and systems for labelling and filtering anything they'd rather not see. The current Steam rules require adult content to be "appropriately labeled and age-gated". Still, Valve continue to intervene to remove "adult" games that, for example, <a href="https://www.vg247.com/the-steam-rape-day-controversy-how-it-became-a-scandal-and-why-its-further-testing-valves-policies">glorify rape</a>, in line with Steam's other prohibitions against hate speech, games that simulate the exploitation of children, nude or sexually explicit images of real people, and any content "that is patently offensive or intended to shock or disgust viewers".</p>
<p>Handing over authority to banks, ISPs and other payment providers may result in further arbitrary rejections of games, given that companies such as Stripe, Mastercard and Paypal are in <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/patreon-suspension-of-adult-content-creators/">the</a> <a href="https://thenextweb.com/news/patreon-continues-to-crack-down-on-nsfw-content-creators">habit</a> of nudging sites like Patreon to crack down on "NSFW" or "adult" material.</p>
<p>In particular, this could lead to a stifling of games that are in any way non-conforming, particularly given the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/ending-radical-indoctrination-in-k-12-schooling/">current climate of repression</a> in Valve's home country, the USA. I know about the rule change thanks to Youtuber and self-described former game developer NoahFuel Gaming, who has <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/noahfuelgaming.bsky.social/post/3lu2ngnm3hc26">posted on Bluesky</a> about the potential fallout for projects the banks and financial corporations consider "adult" because they deviate from reactionary framings of sex and gender. As the Youtuber writes: "Queer content gets flagged as 'explicit' even when it's PG. A trans dev making a personal story? 'Too controversial.' A surreal queer VN? 'Sexualized.' Financial deplatforming in action."</p>
<p>I'll ask Valve if they'd like to comment on all this.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valve-change-steams-rules-to-let-banks-and-credit-card-firms-prohibit-certain-kinds-of-adult-only-content]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Killing Floor 3’s next stress test launches today, and won’t share the last one’s five-year NDA]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/killing-floor-3s-next-stress-test-launches-today-and-wont-share-the-last-ones-five-year-nda</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/killing-floor-3%E2%80%99s-next-stress-test-launches-today-and-won%E2%80%99t-share-the-last-one%E2%80%99s-five-year-nda.1244772/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Yes, it’s still meant to be out next week</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Tripwire Interactive</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>What happens when an unenforceable force meets an un-shut-uppable object? Cooperative monsterman shooter <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/killing-floor-3">Killing Floor 3</a> found out this past Sunday, as players of its closed online stress test were asked to agree to a nondisclosure agreement (<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/killingfloor/comments/1lyxr4w/a_5_year_nda_for_2_hours/">shared on Reddit</a>) that would stay in effect for <em>five years</em>. Or four years, three hundred and fifty-four days after KF3 is supposed to launch, on July 24th.</p>
<p>Naturally, this was broken almost immediately, including by Twitch streamers clicking through the agreement <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/videos/2511631428">live on air</a>. In a <a href="https://forums.tripwireinteractive.com/index.php?threads/killing-floor-3-wednesday-stress-test-details.2341991/">forum post</a>, developers Tripwire Interactive have since declared that they stopped bothering to enforce within the test’s first hour, and apologised for making such a mad demand in the first place. The post also confirms that another stress test – which PC players can still apply to join – is happening later today, Wednesday 16th, and won’t insist on any legal gagging at all.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>NDAs are commonly wheeled out when developers run limited pre-release play sessions like these, though the half-decade duration is plainly nonsense in KF3’s case. Tripwire’s statement attributes it to essentially misused paperwork, claiming "5 years is our standard boilerplate language for internal tests and was too heavy handed for this context," adding that "It was never our intention to enforce a 5-year ban on discussing the game." The same post infers that at least some time <em>was</em> spent clamping down on agreement breakers, but then that wouldn’t have been weird at all were they only told to keep schtum for a few days. Not, y’know, the same time it took to build the Hoover Dam.</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Tripwire Interactive</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>It's not like gamers have a particularly proud history of nondisclosure compliance, either. Take the Fortnite tester who <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/epic-games-sue-tester-for-spoiling-chapter-2">let slip its Season 2 details</a>, or the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-streamer-played-an-hour-of-marathon-early-before-bungie-cut-him-off">rogue Marathon streamer</a> who managed to beam an hour of the upcoming FPS like that doomed Rebel Alliance soldier passing the Death Star plans out of Darth Vader’s murder hallway. Or my personal favourite case, YouTuber and arch <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/team-fortress-2">Team Fortress 2</a> Engie main Uncle Dane <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/tf2/comments/1cxveqf/uncule_dane_leaks_the_deadlock/">leaking Deadlock</a> so hard that Valve abandoned their secrecy altogether.</p>
<p>Anyway, this new, unbound stress test begins today at 2pm BST / 9am EST, and will run for 12 hours, making it a much meatier opportunity to test drive Killing Floor 3 than Sunday’s two-hour sesh. You can request access <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1430190/Killing_Floor_3/">via Steam</a> if you’d like to see what all the fuss is about.</p>
<p>Fuss has certainly been in no short supply for KF3; it was previously delayed from a planned March 2025 release after a disastrous open beta that produced widespread complaints on the game’s performance, gunfeel, and switch from having freely mix-matchable characters and perk classes – as in Killing Floors 1 and 2 – to a more hero shooterish Specialist system. By many accounts from the Sunday stress test, encouraging improvements have been made, though Tripwire say that unjoining characters and perks won’t take place until after release.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/killing-floor-3s-next-stress-test-launches-today-and-wont-share-the-last-ones-five-year-nda]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avowed's summer update revamps fighter and ranger skills so those pesky wizards aren't having all the fun]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/avoweds-summer-update-revamps-fighter-and-ranger-skills-so-those-pesky-wizards-arent-having-all-the-fun</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/avoweds-summer-update-revamps-fighter-and-ranger-skills-so-those-pesky-wizards-arent-having-all-the-fun.1244721/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Plus, more unique weapons and the game's now Steam Deck verified</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Obsidian</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>I liked <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/avowed">Avowed</a>, and having read through the notes for its summer update, patch 1.5, I reckon I'll like it even more whenever I next decide to don <a href="https://www.vg247.com/becoming-avoweds-most-toxic-360-no-scoper">the persona of a trickshotting Envoy</a>.</p>
<p>This patch is the <a href="https://x.com/AvowedtheGame/status/1945182871930511524">second of three seasonal updates</a> Obsidian outlined that the game'd be getting <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/avoweds-latest-update-comes-with-community-requested-features-lots-of-tweaks-and-a-promise-of-a-roadmap">over the course of this year</a>. It's brought a substantial rework of fighter and ranger skills, some extra unique weapons for you to get your mitts on, Steam Deck verification, plus a bunch of other tweaks and fixes.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>The changes to abilities on offer to non-magical scrappers form the meat of <a href="https://forums.obsidian.net/topic/134877-patch-15-notes/">the patch's notes</a>, and Obsidian say they've been made "to round out the classes compared to the Wizard tree". Those damn wizards, always getting the fancy tricks.
</p>
<p>The new abilities added in include the likes of a Shadow Step skill for sneaky stealthers that'll let you casually "step into the Beyond, reappearing behind your enemy", with upgrades offering the chance to do stuff like ensure these killer backstabs reset the ability's cooldown.</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>Update 1.5 is now live for Avowed! Please update your game when you see that this update is available to receive the following features, fixes, and changes: <a href="https://t.co/XKApoZIa0r">https://t.co/XKApoZIa0r</a></p><p>• Explore new weapons, abilities, and armor<br>• Korean and Japanese language support<br>• ✔️ Steam… <a href="https://t.co/6VEIccb1Ir">pic.twitter.com/6VEIccb1Ir</a></p></div>— Avowed (@AvowedtheGame) <a href="https://twitter.com/AvowedtheGame/status/1945181691800076625?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 15, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>Melee Maurices, on the other hand, get skills like reviving allies "from a great distance", a Barbaric Smash that lets you absorb an enemy's built up stun reserves if your "massive blow" kills them, and the ability to take a deep breath that immediately recovers all of their stamina. That last one's something I need in real life.</p>
<p>Alongside that, Obsidian have aimed to address folks "not able to play specific builds that they wanted to early on in the game" by littering a bunch of extra unique weapons throughout Dawnshore, Emerald Stair, Shatterscarp, and Galawain’s Tusks. The former two have gotten the most, with six and five items respectively, mirroring the goal to frontload some more fun.
</p>
<p>Meanwhile, enemies have been given some player abilities "such as Returning Storm, Ring of Tire, Taunt, Clear Out, Blizzard, and Tanglefoot" as well as new physical and magical barriers to block attack. So they should be equipped to try and hold off your newfound skillage.</p>
<p>Add in the Steam Deck verification, some changes to the cooking and crafting interface, and a bunch of bug fixes. The result's a patch that looks to me like a decent excuse to dust off <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/avowed-beginners-guide">your facial shrooms</a> if you fancy a fresh playthrough, even if it's unlikely to turn your view on Avowed around if <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/avowed-review">the release version</a> wasn't up your alley.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/avoweds-summer-update-revamps-fighter-and-ranger-skills-so-those-pesky-wizards-arent-having-all-the-fun]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>