<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 16:39:51 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vaults are open, flames are thrown and ghouls are sick, as Doom mod Fallout: Bakersfield shows off more shootering]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/vaults-are-open-flames-are-thrown-and-ghouls-are-sick-as-doom-mod-fallout-bakersfield-shows-off-more-shootering</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/vaults-are-open-flames-are-thrown-and-ghouls-are-sick-as-doom-mod-fallout-bakersfield-shows-off-more-shootering.1282017/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Also, the recent trailer's 90s visuals have been delivered in 4K</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Alexander 'Red888guns' Berezin</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>We're back again, gang. Bang bang. The Doom modder behind Fallout: Bakersfield, which recreates the city of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/necropolis">Necropolis</a> from the original Fallout as the backdrop to irradiated boomer shooting, has followed up their first trailer in ages with some more footage of the mod in action.</p>
<p>Alexander 'Red888guns' Berezin, the modder in question, caught most of us off guard last month, when he whipped out <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-surprise-update-for-fallout-bakersfield-the-doom-mod-that-rebuilds-the-rpgs-necropolis-as-a-shooter-level">that trailer</a> for a GZDoom WAD plenty had assumed wouldn't ever see the light of day. After all, Berezin had <a href="https://x.com/NewBlood/status/1537228975906627585">plenty of other stuff</a> on his plate. He's definitely working hard to show it off now, though.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Two new videos have hit the modder's YouTube channel in the past day. One's a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VzZdCmv8AsY">4K version of the previous trailer</a>, because clearly experiencing Doomy visuals in crisp 144p isn't the more authentic way to go, and the other's an extended gameplay montage of Fallout: Bakersfield.</p>
<p>While a good potion of this montage is made up of longer sections you've seen clipped up as part of the trailer, there are some bits that didn't feature there. There's an extended sequence with the Vault Doomweller approaching the entrance to Vault 12, giving us a glimpse through the gear-shaped doorless void at what exploring the massive underground shelter that Necropolis' ghoulish residents emerged from will be like. Plenty of dim, grey chambers to paint with blood, I'd imagine.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Fallout: Bakersfield Extended Gameplay Footage" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/L0Wv6kkloCU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Fallout: Bakersfield Extended Gameplay Footage</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/L0Wv6kkloCU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/L0Wv6kkloCU?autoplay=1" title="Fallout: Bakersfield Extended Gameplay Footage">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=L0Wv6kkloCU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>Other bits I liked include the moment a bunch of ghouls are set on fire by a trusty flamer and do a bit of a monster mash with their smouldering arms aloft, before being shotgunned. And also, the moment when one just throws up. I take that back, he doesn't just throw up, he actually pukes, then immediately goes to puke again, at which point Berezin pulls up the mod's main menu as if he's decided that's enough ghoul vom for one day.</p><p>By far the best thing about this raw footage, however, is that without the music and quick cuts of the trailer, you really get a chance to take in the mod's eerie and sinister ambience. Thunder crackles regularly, drowning out footsteps that're often the only thing cutting through the tense silence. Weapons prime for firing with satisfying metallic clunks, ghouls moan and murmur, mysterious figures ominously hum as you approach. So gritty a symphony you'd never find if you had a grunge band with sand instruments play on a freshly-salted winter road.</p>
<p>Fallout: Bakersfield's sadly still release dateless as of now, but it's cool to be getting regular reminders that it exists, now Berezin's busy blasting through the bits of it that need work.</p>

        </div>
      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/vaults-are-open-flames-are-thrown-and-ghouls-are-sick-as-doom-mod-fallout-bakersfield-shows-off-more-shootering]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Konami blame Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater crash bugs on cranky crocs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/konami-blame-metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-crash-bugs-on-cranky-crocs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/konami-blame-metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-crash-bugs-on-cranky-crocs.1281948/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Do not wear them, do not eat in their presence</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Konami</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater">Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</a> is out now, and while it's a lot prettier or at least, more Unreal than the original <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/metal-gear-solid">Metal Gear Solid</a> 3, it's got its fair share of technical problems. Curiously, two of the major crashing issues involve crocodiles. If you want a smooth opening bout of Snake Eater, I would avoid either pretending to be a crocodile or having lunch in the presence of a hungry one. Did a crocodile work on this game? There seems to be some underlying reptilian resentment at work, which I guess is to be expected from a game called Snake Eater.
</p><!--more-->
<p>Konami, of course, are well aware of these issues, and are working on a patch. They'll roll the fixes out in stages, with exact release timing to follow. Here's their shortlist of the known issues, plucked from <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2417610/METAL_GEAR_SOLID_D_SNAKE_EATER/">the Steam page</a>.
</p>
<blockquote><ul>
<li>Performing an additional survival knife attack after completing a series of consecutive attacks to secure food may cause the game to crash under certain conditions.</li>
<li>Removing the Crocodile Cap from the Survival Viewer while it is equipped may cause the game to crash under certain conditions.</li>
<li>Collecting food when a hungry crocodile is nearby may cause the game to crash under certain conditions.</li>
<li>Transitioning from a roll into a crawl may result in the character model floating in mid-air under certain conditions.</li>
<li>In areas where the camera switches to Intrusion View, character movement may become restricted under certain conditions.</li>
<li>Opening the Radio Window under certain conditions may cause the game to crash.</li>
</ul></blockquote>
<p>Who amongst us has not rolled into a crawl and ended up drifting across the scenery? I think it's got something to do with eating parsnips after their sell-by-date. Konami are mum as to what might happen if you roll into a crawl while wearing a crocodile hat. Presumably, your keyboard will grow teeth and clamp shut around your hands.</p>
<p>Sulky swamp lizards aside, Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater is notable for having <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/theres-a-new-platinum-game-hidden-in-the-metal-gear-solid-3-remake-thats-actually-a-remake-of-a-rework-of-a-zone-of-the-enders-3-prototype">a whole Platinum game inside it that is secretly a cancelled Zone Of The Enders 3 prototype</a>. </p>

        </div>
      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/konami-blame-metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-crash-bugs-on-cranky-crocs]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>