<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 10:58:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The current developers of Vampire: The Masquerade - Bloodlines 2 are going "fully" indie again]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-current-developers-of-vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-are-going-fully-indie-again</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-current-developers-of-vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-are-going-fully-indie-again.1248622/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Still Wakes The Deep creators The Chinese Room secure management buyout</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Secret Mode</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>A few of the UK's fanciest former indie developers are going indie again... with help from venture capital. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/still-wakes-the-deep">Still Wakes The Deep</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dear-esther">Dear Esther</a> creators The Chinese Room have slipped the surly bonds of former parent company Sumo Digital in the course of a management buyout, with "facilitation" from Hiro Capital. Now "fully independent", they're focussing on the creation of original games, with two unannounced projects in the offing once they've finished developing <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2">Vampire: The Masquerade - Bloodlines 2</a>.</p><!--more-->
<p>Founded in 2007 by a group of academically minded <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/half-life-2">Half-Life 2</a> modders, The Chinese Room made waves initially with Dear Esther, an introspective first-person exploration game that emphasised environmental storytelling over mechanics, aggressively and affectionately described as a "walking sim".</p>
<p>They later worked with Frictional on Amnesia: A Machine For Pigs - sequel to The Dark Descent and perhaps the best-written Amnesia game - and Sony's Santa Monica Studio on <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/everybodys-gone-to-the-rapture">Everybody's Gone To The Rapture</a>, in which you chase golden phantoms around a sorrowful English village. I once <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2020/dec/08/a-video-game-garden-the-delights-of-virtual-botany">took a botanist on a walking tour of Rapture</a> and we both thought the flowers were excellent. I also love the soundtrack, which makes me want to wander off into the hills of Shropshire and die tragically of, nudge-wink, "Spanish flu".</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Mourning Tree" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cREJyD1eN00?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Mourning Tree</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cREJyD1eN00?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/cREJyD1eN00?autoplay=1" title="The Mourning Tree">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cREJyD1eN00" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>The Chinese Room were acquired by Sumo Digital in 2018, who were themselves later acquired by Tencent. The developers' most recent project is Still Wake The Deep, a creature feature set aboard a Scottish oil rig: in his <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/still-wakes-the-deep-review">review</a>, Brendy concluded that it "doesn't push the boat out but still excels within its genre". Sadly, there has been some belt-tightening of late. Sumo <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/layoffs-at-vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-studio-as-paradox-promise-rpg-will-still-release-in-october">confirmed layoffs at The Chinese Room and elsewhere in their operations this June</a>, as part of plans to move away from original game creation and "focus exclusively on development services for partners".</p>
<p>According to a PR email this week, Sumo put The Chinese Room up for sale earlier this year, with the expectation that it would be sold to private equity or an overseas buyer. The management buyout ensures that the studio will remain UK-owned, according to the email, though it's not clear how exactly Hiro Capital (who are based in London and Luxembourg) have "faciliated" the deal, and what they'll expect in return. Compare and contrast how <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/endless-legends-how-amplitude-bought-their-independence-back-from-sega">Amplitude bought their independence back from Sega</a>.</p>
<p>According to studio director Ed Daly, "this management buyout allows us to scratch the creative itch of continuing to work on new, original intellectual property, but also to partner with other studios on other projects when they fit in with our vision." Best of luck with it all, peeps. Please make another game about a subterranean hellfactory.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-current-developers-of-vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-are-going-fully-indie-again]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scrapped Evolve sequel revealed by concept art, including an asteroid mining station straight of Dead Space]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/scrapped-evolve-sequel-revealed-by-concept-art-including-an-asteroid-mining-station-straight-of-dead-space</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/scrapped-evolve-sequel-revealed-by-concept-art-including-an-asteroid-mining-station-straight-of-dead-space.1248612/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article">
        <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Alas, it never escaped pre-production</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>2K Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Turtle Rock's Evolve was, for me, an almost-brilliant asymmetrical shooter straining to extract itself from the jaws of a live service kaiju maddened by <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/evolve-wot-i-think-in-progress-conclusion">a sludgy diet of unlocks and micro-transactions</a>. It was a huge round of hide-and-seek featuring one, very large and fast, upgradeable alien monster and four hunters equipped with jet packs, trackers, forcefield nets and assorted demolition gear. I had a grand old time at launch as the Wraith, a godawful sneaklizard with warping capabilities, like a xenomorph moonlighting as Corvo Attano. But such thrills were sabotaged by the grindiness of the early game and by an infuriating deluge of paid DLC. Publishers 2K Games <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/evolve-shutting-down-dedicated-servers-and-f2p-version">delisted it in 2018</a>, after attempting to reboot Evolve as a free-to-play game. The beast clings onto a little life care of <a href="https://discord.com/invite/evolvereunited">a community Discord for existing owners</a>.</p>
<p>Even given the reaction to Evolve's nickel-and-diming, it seems unlikely a sequel would have stripped out the live service progression elements and reverted to something like the menu-light horror movie sandbox approach of the developer's previous <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/left-4-dead">Left 4 Dead</a>. After all, Turtle Rock went onto make <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/back-4-blood">Back 4 Blood</a>, a zombie blaster marinated in grindogubbins. Still, I'd have liked to see them try it. And look, they almost did.</p> <!--more-->
<p>A <a href="https://www.tj-frame.com/evolve">concept artist portfolio</a> flushed out by <a href="https://mp1st.com/news/report-evolve-2-was-once-in-development-concept-art-reveals-scrapped-sequel">MP1st</a> describes plans for a cancelled Evolve 2. These included ideas for what sound like more linear missions (boo!), and a level consisting of a massive spacerock-digesting facility that puts me in mind of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dead-space">Dead Space</a>'s USG Ishimura (yes please). "After Evolve released, the studio began work on a sequel," writes TJ Frame, who was senior concept artist at Turtle Rock between 2011 and 2017. "Sadly that project was canceled after several months of pre-production.</p>
<p>"At one point the game design included locations such as a huge asteroid mining station, tentatively named The Akhenaten, as well as more sequentially oriented missions back on Shear," the post continues. "It would have been fun to really flesh out new locations and architectural styles within the world of Evolve, but the studio moved onto other projects and pitches."</p>
<p>TJ Frame's portoflio includes a bunch of art for the abandoned Evolve 2, which I will hold off recirculating here because I don't have the developer's blessing. Some of the images are labelled "Evolve II", though one "Scraptown" or "Slagtown" area appears to be an outline for some Evolve DLC. The concepts for the aforesaid Akhenaten map are definitely the highlights, in terms of inherent munsterliness. The subliminal theme TJ Frame and their colleagues appear to have been working with is "nasty insect biting/liquefying paralysed and helpless prey". Now picture yourself standing on that insect's abdomen, attempting to harpoon Godzilla.</p>
<p>Alas and alack, such antics will probably never come to pass. Turtle Rock were acquired by Tencent in 2021 - their current project is <a href="https://www.turtlerockstudios.com/games">TBA</a>. If you too mourn the extinction of Evolve, you might be interested to hear that one of its spiritual progenitors, Aliens Vs Predator, is enjoying <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ancient-aliens-vs-predator-game-briefly-resurrected-by-steam-player-thirst-for-six-packs">a new lease of existence care of a sporadically reanimating community server</a>.</p></div>

        </article>

  
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/scrapped-evolve-sequel-revealed-by-concept-art-including-an-asteroid-mining-station-straight-of-dead-space]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>