<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 12:00:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Splitgate 2 boss admits the Trumpish hat he wore at Summer Game Fest was a publicity stunt after it goes sour]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/splitgate-2-boss-admits-the-trumpish-hat-he-wore-at-summer-game-fest-was-a-publicity-stunt-after-it-goes-sour</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/splitgate-2-boss-admits-the-trumpish-hat-he-wore-at-summer-game-fest-was-a-publicity-stunt-after-it-goes-sour.1215324/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/splitgate-2-boss-admits-the-trumpish-hat-he-wore-at-summer-game-fest-was-a-publicity-stunt-after-it-goes-sour<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"We really saw this as a meme that was kind of stating our truth"</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Summer Game Fest</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Ian Proulx, the CEO of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/splitgate-2">Splitgate 2</a> developers 1047 Games, has apologised for wearing a 'Make FPS Great Again' cap while talking about the game's battle royale mode on stage at Summer Game Fest. As you might have guessed, the hat drew unfavourable comparisons to US president Donald Trump's MAGA hats.</p>
<p>It'd have been a pretty dumb, controversy-baiting stunt for a games company CEO to pull at any point in recent history, but especially hasn't gone over well given the timing. As the SGF show happened, a large number of anti-ICE protests also began in response to violent immigration raids, and later that weekend Trump <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/cj93d3r0zz0o">deployed the National Guard onto the streets</a>."</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Up until yesterday, Proulx had opted not to apologise for the hat, which he wore while <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3hqhyCGp2uU">taking some shots</a> at the state of the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-fps-games">shooter genre</a> right now, specifically going at the Call of Duty series for repetitive annual releases and wishing for a <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/titanfall">Titanfall</a> 3. "I’m not here to apologize but I am here to clarify. This is not a political statement, it is quite literally what it says, so take it at face value," he wrote in a tweet on June 7.</p>
<p>"I don't regret what I said to be candid. I think that I stand by it and my intent is I'm speaking my truth and my intent is to make a great game for everybody," he said of that tweet in an interview with <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/splitgate-2-director-refuses-to-apologize-for-make-fps-great-again-hat-then-apologizes-anyway">IGN</a> published yesterday, doubling down on decling to apologise.</p>
<p>Just a few hours prior to that article's publication, however, Proulx u-turned and <a href="https://x.com/Splitgate/status/1932502832281694366">posted a video apology</a> Splitgate 2's official Twitter account, admitting that the hat was a publicity stunt.</p>
<p>"It is really freaking hard as an independent studio to break through the noise...at our biggest stage, coming out of beta, we needed something to grab attention, and the honest truth is we tried to think of something, and this is what we came up with," the exec said in the video.</p>
<p>"We did not intend for this to be taken in any political way whatsoever and I’m not an idiot, obviously I knew there would be some level of controversy," Proulx continued, "But we really saw this as a meme that was kind of stating our truth, which is we do want to improve this genre and we are disappointed with the state of the genre.</p>
<p>"You don't have to believe me, but the truth is I am sorry, and the reason I’m sorry is because of what this has done to the community...I hate seeing division, and that's what I'm seeing right now on both sides. There’s division in the community, and for that I am truly sorry."</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mad Metal is a wonderfully janky Mad Max-like with a big robot eye that says you need some milk]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mad-metal-is-a-wonderfully-janky-mad-max-like-with-a-big-robot-eye-that-says-you-need-some-milk</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mad-metal-is-a-wonderfully-janky-mad-max-like-with-a-big-robot-eye-that-says-you-need-some-milk.1215258/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mad-metal-is-a-wonderfully-janky-mad-max-like-with-a-big-robot-eye-that-says-you-need-some-milk<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Also, it makes you follow a damn train</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Mad Mechs</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>One minute you’re flicking through Steam’s Next Fest demos, and finding one that looks to be included despite having <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/3068230/view/498320947205375622?l=english">come out in May</a>. The next, you’re desperately firing missiles into the rear end of giant monster truck, a sole red light glaring out from its metallic behind, as though it’s mega-pissed that it seems to have gotten stuck in a cluster of trees. Given that, it should be easy prey for the ordnance strapped to the bonnet of my very <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/mad-max">Mad Max</a>-ish muscle car coated in enough sheets of metal to fence off several allotments.</p>
<p>This is <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3068230/Mad_Metal/">Mad Metal</a>, though, an indie game whose murderous enemy cars have minds of their own and move more like automotive animals than simple machines.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>The car combat was the thing that drew me to try the demo of solo developer Hakim Elayday’s work-in-progress metal twister, which fittingly looks to have grown from<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/IndieDev/comments/1gxca8h/made_a_vehicle_combat_game_because_i_was_sad/"> its creator’s sadness</a> at <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-reportedly-cancels-twisted-metal-live-service-game-as-part-of-mass-layoffs">last year’s reports</a> Sony had canceled an unannounced live-service Twisted Metal game.</p>
<p>I’m a simple man, I see the opportunity to slam the pedal to the metal and fire a machine gun while doing some skids, and I take it. As you can imagine, then I was in my element when pretty much right out of the gate, Mad Metal tasked me with chasing down and stopping a train covered in rusty spikes.</p>
<p>Yelling <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cF3GK_sfPVM">the line</a> from GTA San Andreas as I went, I splattered the engine pulling it with lead until it looked like a chrome colander, and was rewarded with some new car parts. This is the general loop of Mad Metal from what I’ve played of it so far. You drive around an Unreal Engine map that’s mostly hills littered with light shrubbery and patches of woodland, running into groups of two or three hostile vehicles from various gangs at a time.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Announce Trailer - Mad Metal" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ri7hRfaHdMc?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Announce Trailer - Mad Metal</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ri7hRfaHdMc?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Ri7hRfaHdMc?autoplay=1" title="Announce Trailer - Mad Metal">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ri7hRfaHdMc" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>Then, the great driving dance of death begins. You and your foes that in some instances seem to lurch around more like hostile creatures than cars orbit each other, firing your ordnance and occasionally smashing together, until one of you explodes. It’s an absolute blast most of the time, with the loveable jankiness with which it all happens just adding to the blast you can have with it.</p>
<p>There was one point when I was fighting two “Monster Driller ATVs” - bright yellow armoured 4x4s with three spinning drill bits menacingly protruding from their bumpers - and ended up wearing one as a hat. Its raised suspension meant that my slam into it had wedged me underneath, so I merrily drove around for a bit with my camera clipped into the invisible void of a nonexistent interior, watching as its circular teeth continued to spin away despite their host being out for the count.</p>
<p>There’s a slow time button, which really helps you appreciate fun little touches like the game’s bushes hastily flattening like frightened possums in response to you launching a flurry of bullets at a camper van. There’s also a giant metal eye right out of something like 2001: A Space Odyssey or Portal hovering over you the whole time, providing guidance and dropping memey computer sass like “he needs some milk” when you get exploded.</p>
<p>Overall, at this point Mad Metal’s a bit of a car crash, in both good ways and bad. The core of it’s pretty fun, even if getting a kick out of the more ridiculous jank has definitely played a role in that for me. It’s not got a release date right now, but the demo’s definitely something.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>