<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 16:01:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin's Creed 4: Black Flag Steam update sparks more remake speculation, but hold fire, sailor]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/assassins-creed-4-black-flag-steam-update-sparks-more-remake-speculation-but-hold-fire-sailor</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassins-creed-4-black-flag-steam-update-sparks-more-remake-speculation-but-hold-fire-sailor.1239324/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Unity, Syndicate, and even Odyssey have all received updates too</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Ubisoft</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/assassins-creed-iv-black-flag">Assassin’s Creed Black Flag</a> Remake chatter has started <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-cant-be-bought-on-steam-due-to-a-technical-issue-not-an-incoming-remake-ubisoft-insists">reverberating around the decks of the internet again</a> recently, like a mighty sea shanty that Ubisoft won't say much about.</p>
<p>With folks keener for new info than they are booty, an update to the original Black Flag's Steam backend is the latest thing to fan the Remake speculation flames, but before you get excited about it, it's worth bearing in mind that a bunch of other Assassin's Creed games got similar tweaks yesterday.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>This update to <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/242050/history/">Black Flag's Steam listing</a> was deployed exactly four seconds before 10AM UK time, and enabled a bunch of new store categories for it. They're for functions/features like "Adjustable Difficulty" and "Custom Volume Controls", with a "Mouse Only Option" and the ability to manually save at any time also mentioned.</p>
<p>Cue some speculation from fans and <a href="https://www.kitguru.net/gaming/matthew-wilson/ubisoft-preparing-for-assassins-creed-black-flag-remake-announcement/">headlines</a> wondering what the addition of features that aren't in the original Black Flag might mean for the remake project that's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ubisoft-might-be-remaking-their-swashbuckling-pirateventure-assassins-creed-iv-black-flag">reportedly in the works</a> at Ubisoft.</p>
<p>Hold your mainsails, though. Assassin's Creed YouTuber The Hidden One, whose post about the Steam update looks to have gotten this speculation shanty going, has <a href="https://x.com/TheHiddenOneAC/status/1942620544442179807">seemingly acknowledged</a> after sending that tweet that the Steam listings for <em>every</em> Assassin's Creed game released since 2014 got updates like that Black Flag one yesterday.
</p>
<p>Before you accuse me of wasting your time just to drop a 'womp, womp' worthy revelation like that, I've done a bit of extra work looking into these Steam updates, just in case they do turn out to mean something worth noting. While some of the updates to other AC games, such as the one for <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/368500/history/">Syndicate</a>, are carbon copies of the Black Flag one, there are some differences: no more <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/289650/history/">"family sharing"</a> for AC Unity, a <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/812140/history/">"keyboard only option"</a> for Odyssey, and <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/3035570/history/">"camera comfort"</a> for Mirage.</p>
<p>We've also asked Ubisoft for comment. I personally want to know how you make a video game's cameras so comfortable it's worth noting in a store listing, and why you can seemingly no longer share some Parissassinating with your great uncle Bert. The people deserve to be informed.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/assassins-creed-4-black-flag-steam-update-sparks-more-remake-speculation-but-hold-fire-sailor]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I Don't Want To Be A Good Woman is a "museum of resilience" that explores sexism and repression in Iran]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-dont-want-to-be-a-good-woman-is-a-museum-of-resilience-that-explores-sexism-and-repression-in-iran</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/i-dont-want-to-be-a-good-woman-is-a-museum-of-resilience-that-explores-sexism-and-repression-in-iran.1239300/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Based on stories the developers have "heard, gathered, or lived ourselves"</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun / We Remember</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>I Don't Want To Be A Good Woman is an abstract walking simulator that depicts the experience of being a young girl in Iran - a country that, <a href="https://news.un.org/en/story/2024/09/1154306">as characterised by UN human rights investigators in September 2024</a>, operates "a system, both in law and in practice, that fundamentally discriminates on the grounds of gender". It takes the form of a molten grey landscape strewn with faceless figures, floating symbols and text.</p> <!--more-->
<p>Play consists of wandering around, witnessing frozen scenes and reading text based on stories the developers We Remember have "heard, gathered, or lived ourselves". The devs have omitted names and their own identities, which I am naturally a bit uneasy about, but the anonymity is to be expected given the Iranian state's <a href="https://iran-shutdown.amnesty.org/">track record for brutal censorship</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3779700/I_Dont_Want_To_Be_A_Good_Woman/">Find it on Steam</a>. Needless to say, I wouldn't play this one lightly. Here is how the developers describe the subject matter:</p>
<blockquote><p>This experience explores real-life challenges faced by women in Iran under Islamic law, including gender-based discrimination, restricted bodily autonomy, and limitations on freedom of expression. Themes such as forced hijab, lack of reproductive rights, and state violence are presented through a narrative lens. While the game contains no explicit imagery, it does involve mature social and political themes.</p>
<p>The game depicts discriminatory behavior toward women by state and religious systems from the perspective of a victim. These portrayals are not meant to promote hate or disparagement, but to raise awareness of real-world issues through an empathetic and objective narrative.</p> </blockquote>
<p>We've covered a few projects that address Iran's society and politics and its recent history. Back in 2013, Adam Smith (RPS in peace) <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tales-of-tehran-1979-revolution-black-friday">wrote about 1979 Revolution: Black Friday</a>, an adventure game created by Iranian developers based inside and outside the country, which casts you as a photojournalist during the overthrow of the (originally CIA and MI6-backed) Pahlavi dynasty.</p>
<p>You might also want to check out this <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/game-platforms/iran-video-games-timeline-from-1970-to-2019">abbreviated history of Iranian video game development</a> for Game Developer, written by Iranian journalist and designer Arash Hackimi in 2020. It spans the creation or importing of new hardware, from the Magnavox Odyssey-esque Video Master through bootlegged Atari 2600s to modern mobile phones; the arrival of Iranian video game magazines, such as Bazi Rayane; the origins of the first Iranian video game developer, Honafa; and the founding of video game festivals, like the Digital Media Festival in 2007.</p>
<p>Hackimi also details a few individual games, including the perpetual motion drawing tool <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/415170/Engare/">Engare</a>, the fantasy action-adventure <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/353990/Parvaneh_Legacy_of_the_Lights_Guardians/">Parvaneh</a> and <a href="http://farsh.golabistudio.com/">Farsh</a>, a puzzle game about unrolling carpets. All of which might surprise you if, like me, your understanding of Iran in video games begins and mostly ends with the likes of Prince of Persia.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-dont-want-to-be-a-good-woman-is-a-museum-of-resilience-that-explores-sexism-and-repression-in-iran]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>