<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 09:44:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It's a UK bank holiday, please talk amongst yourselves]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/its-a-uk-bank-holiday-please-talk-amongst-yourselves</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/its-a-uk-bank-holiday-please-talk-amongst-yourselves.1279536/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>And/or play this rock, paper, scissors strategy game</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>snow-kiss / Rock Paper Shotgun</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>It's <a href="https://beep8.org/b8/beep8.html?b8rom=d1e5030bea0f2f80d55b32857c00f656.b8&amp;">a free and simple territory control game</a> from hobbyist dev snow-kiss, in which you switch your tiles between rock, paper or scissors to claim those of opponents. I'm not sure the idea has serious legs, but I like how it thickens when you have more than two participants and a more elaborate board setup.</p>
<p>I wonder if it could be the basis for a top-down open world exploration game in which you move a blob of tiles around by absorbing/being absorbed by surrounding tiles. You'd have to worry about the coherence of the blob, as the roshambo mechanics tend to result in stray colonies of tiles peeling away from the starting mass. Perhaps the view could centre on the largest clump of tiles.</p>
<p>Anyway just a few Thoughts. Assuming you're also in England, Northern Ireland or Wales - apologies to Scottish readers for initially calling this a UK-wide bank holiday - what are you up to today? Here is some possibly mood-appropriate <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gdTOozVPqqM">mid-campaign music</a>.</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/its-a-uk-bank-holiday-please-talk-amongst-yourselves]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>