<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - www.rockpapershotgun.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for www.rockpapershotgun.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 21:08:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Total War: Warhammer 3 is getting some absolutely murderous cats]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/total-war-warhammer-3-is-getting-some-absolutely-murderous-cats</link>
            <guid>1437541</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Blood for the blood god, cats for Grand Cathay</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bashiva.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bashiva.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bashiva.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bashiva.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bashiva.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bashiva.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bashiva.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bashiva.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bashiva.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Sega</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Creative Assembly have just detailed <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/total-war-warhammer-iii">Total War: Warhammer 3</a>’s first character pack, these being “smaller, focused content drops built around a single character with their own unique feature, supported by a handful of exciting new units”, priced (in this case) at £3.99, $4.99 or €4.99 apiece. 
</p>
<p>
Yes, it’s Creative Assembly once again nosing at the shards of your smashed piggy bank, but the developers have, in theory, pre-empted any rancour over DLC nickel-and-diming by making the character pack cat-themed. Everybody loves cats! Even when they cost as much as a medium oatmilk latte. Especially cats like Bhashiva – an entirely new Warhammer character - and her company of Tiger Warriors. Look at her ickle grumpy face! Look at her ickle flaming twin katara! ARGH get it off me get it off me get it off me, etcetera.
</p>
<p>
Bhashiva and her feline gangsters will form part of the Grand Cathay faction, though sadly not, it seems, because some Creative Assembly designer spotted an obvious pun and was immediately assigned £100,000. The pack’s paid contents are one Legendary Lord, one Lord, three regular units, and a “Unique Campaign Feature, Final Battle, Quest Battle etc”.
</p>
<p>
What manner of combatant is Bhashiva, then? She’s a stealthy wrecking ball, equipped with incendiary weapons and a Heaven’s Gate blink-style ability. “Each strike not only scorches her victims but weakens their resistance to flame, letting her plough through fights the moment she commits,” enthuses <a href="https://community.creative-assembly.com/total-war/total-war-warhammer/blogs/94">a blog post on CA’s site</a>. “Her agility is at the core of her playstyle; she darts between threats, repositions effortlessly, and uses her mastery of stealth to pick the perfect moment to appear.” 
</p>
<p>
Battle designer Josh King adds that “she’s the quiet dread in the back of your mind”. How very unlike my family’s own moggy, best summarised as “the quiet shitter in the back of the bedroom cupboard”.
</p>
<p>
As for the Tiger Warriors, they’re a gang of nippy ambushers and so, relatively exotic among the boxy formations of regular Grand Cathay. Their Clawspeaker spellcasters are vanguard units equipped with a mix of healing, beast and shadow lore, making them an “incredibly versatile force multiplier.” 
</p><p>
 If you don’t already own the Grand Cathay DLC, buying the Tiger Warrior character pack includes access to “the core Grand Cathay roster to ensure you get a complete experience”. We can expect more details down the line. Also down the line: the release of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/total-war-warhammer">Total War: Warhammer</a> 3’s Lords of the End Times expansion, which is chock full of necromancers. And sometime after that, the release of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/total-war-warhammer-40000">Total War: Warhammer 40,000</a> - one of Julian's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/julians-most-anticipated-games-for-2026">most anticipated games of 2026</a>. And sometime after that, a long time probably, the release of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/creative-assembly-reveal-total-war-medieval-3-while-teasing-a-huge-game-reveal-to-follow">Total War: Medieval 3</a>.
</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/total-war-warhammer-3-is-getting-some-absolutely-murderous-cats]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[If Mewgenics is too appalling, you might prefer the turn-based charms of Dobbel Dungeon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/if-mewgenics-is-too-appalling-you-might-prefer-the-turn-based-charms-of-dobbel-dungeon</link>
            <guid>1437475</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Sweet and well-made and very unthreatening</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dobbeldungeon.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dobbeldungeon.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dobbeldungeon.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dobbeldungeon.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dobbeldungeon.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dobbeldungeon.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dobbeldungeon.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dobbeldungeon.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dobbeldungeon.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Gamepie</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The first thing I noticed about turn-based tactics game <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dobbel-dungeon">Dobbel Dungeon</a> is that you can see fingerprints on the playdough character models. Even hard metallic objects such as swords are decked with faint, glimmering whorls. I’d have liked the game to let me leave my own prints on those playdough characters, care of the biometrics functionality I assume is secretly built into my work laptop. Perhaps they could have made this part of a proper degradation system, with high level characters looking all greasy and smooshed.</p>
<p>Alas, Dobbel Dungeon has no time for such <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/crysis">Crysis</a>-grade simulation elements. Going by the demo, it is simply a cheerful and well-made, tabletop-style game of leisurely flanking and special ability usage with a gentle twist. The twist is that every time a character takes a turn, they fling a bunch of dice. These dice are then slotted into ability boxes to perform them. Some abilities deal effects proportionate to the dice score – stick a dice roll of 5 into a fireball and you’ll inflict 5 points of damage. The three starting characters also have the ability to reroll one die per turn. </p><!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Dobbel Dungeon - Release Date Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/P4pxElPuI2Y?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Dobbel Dungeon - Release Date Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/P4pxElPuI2Y?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/P4pxElPuI2Y?autoplay=1" title="Dobbel Dungeon - Release Date Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P4pxElPuI2Y" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>I’m not sure it’ll get too fiendish, going by the laidback presentation, but I can imagine scenarios where you’re umming and erring over whether to spend a 3 on a healing spell, or reroll in the hopes of that 6 you need to one-shot a boss boggo. </p><p>The Dobbel Dungeon feature rundown hints that “if you find yourself disagreeing with your dice, there are ways to ‘gently nudge’ them in the right direction via various manipulative actions gained through items and skills”. Hey, they’re trying to make us cheat! No <em>thank</em> you, Gamepie. You won’t find me trying to get one over Lady Luck. You won’t find me strolling down the Trickster's Highway. In the shorter term, the maps are pleasant to gaze down upon, the music is catchy in a Viva Pinata sort of way, and the controls and interface feel like second nature.</p>
<p>The story here is that a witch’s cottage has blown up and transformed local wildlife into slightly angrier, humanoid-looking wildlife. It's definitely not in the same bracket of atrocity as <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mewgenics-review-a-roguelite-where-sacrificial-arse-maggots-and-frightful-defecation-are-the-keys-to-success">Mewgenics</a>.</p>
<p>You get a hub town with surrounding jetties that ship you out to islands full of individual mission-battles. You’ll also encounter merchants where you can buy gear for your clayfaced critter clubbers, and yes, there are the expected skill trees. All very genre-standard, but executed with enough bouyancy that I can see myself plugging on for another few hours.</p>
<p>Dobbel Dungeon is <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2622820/Dobbel_Dungeon/">out today on Steam</a>. There’s still a demo as of writing, but demos tend to vaporise fast, once the game is on sale. For a considerably less saccharine take on the ‘what if your characters were made of physical arts and crafts materials’ racket, try <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mashina-is-a-chill-stop-motion-adventure-with-friendly-robots-from-the-judero-team">Mashina</a>, which we really should have reviewed. Curse the limitations of my non-playdough body.</p>

        </div>

      </article>




        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/if-mewgenics-is-too-appalling-you-might-prefer-the-turn-based-charms-of-dobbel-dungeon]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>