<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 14:07:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[InZOI's system specs make me want to see this handsome Sims killer running on a pocket calculator]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/inzois-system-specs-make-me-want-to-see-this-handsome-sims-killer-running-on-a-pocket-calculator</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/inzois-system-specs-make-me-want-to-see-this-handsome-sims-killer-running-on-a-pocket-calculator.1133292/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/inzois-system-specs-make-me-want-to-see-this-handsome-sims-killer-running-on-a-pocket-calculator<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Devs trying to support punier PCs "without compromising overall quality"</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/screencap-of-system-specs.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Krafton / Rock Paper Shotgun</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            
<p>
<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/video-game-franchises/the-sims">The Sims</a> players among us have been gazing cautiously at <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/inzoi">inZOI</a>, a new neighbourhood and life management game from Krafton. I am cautious for essentially two reasons. One is that the game makes use of live generative AI: you can stuff its jaws with text, images and video to create items such as outfits and animate your pet humans, here known as Zois. Your Zoi's "actions and thoughts" are also based on "small machine learning" tech, which as the name implies is a teenier species of generative AI that commonly runs live on the user's own hardware. Going by <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2456740/inZOI/">the Steam page </a>disclosure, the actual base game assets weren't AI generated, but then again, Steam AI disclosures can be <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-dutys-generative-ai-disclosure-reveals-a-glaring-issue-with-steams-policies">rather unrevealing</a>.
</p>
<p>
We've published a fair bit about <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/topics/electric-nightmares">the risks and potential abuses of generative AI tools in video game development</a>, so we'll be looking at that in more depth when the game hits early access on 28th March. In the meantime, here's the second reason I'm cautious: inZOI's key selling point over its obvious (and massively updated) rival <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-sims-4">The Sims 4</a> is that it has photorealistic visuals, and frankly, they creep the hell out of me.</p> <!--more-->
<p>So does the fact that all the Zois in the marketing screenshots appear to be fashion models. I feel like I'm stuck in a window display with a bunch of possessed marionettes, screaming at shoppers to bust me out before they harvest my bone marrow. Accordingly, the first thing I thought when Krafton released the system specs - see image below - was "please let there be a potato mode that makes everybody look like an honest, god-fearing PS1 NPC".
</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/inzoi-pc-specs.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Krafton</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
The system specs accompany <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2456740/view/518581441632667234?l=english">a blog post</a> that lays out how to achieve optimal settings, including choice of storage and resolution and which kind of ray tracing to implement. We'll let hardware editor James be the judge of all that, thanks. 
</p>
<p>
The devs are naturally well aware that their gleaming Unreal beastie innately requires more juice than other life sims, and are keen to ensure that as many people get to play as possible. "As mentioned earlier, inZOI delivers high-quality graphics and realistic city-level simulations, which require higher system specifications," they write. "While these requirements ensure the best possible gameplay experience, we remain committed to making inZOI accessible to more players. We plan to implement a feature that automatically adjusts game settings to provide the best possible experience. Additionally, we will continue working on optimizations to improve performance while finding ways to lower system requirements without compromising overall quality."
</p>
<p>
To accompany the post, they've knocked together one of those comparison videos in which builds running at different settings are steadily erased by a merciless horizontal screen wipe, as though whole dimensions were being repeatedly deleted by some kind of spacetime eruption. The vid also shows off some close-ups of NPCs who, in fairness, pretty much look like regular people rather than varnished catwalk vampires.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="inZOI: Graphics Comparison by System Specs" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JFzk45yOjkY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>inZOI: Graphics Comparison by System Specs</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JFzk45yOjkY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/JFzk45yOjkY?autoplay=1" title="inZOI: Graphics Comparison by System Specs">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JFzk45yOjkY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
Still, there's no "true" potato mode here from the looks of the video. That's a shame, because I think running games on absurdly low specs often reveals fascinating things about their art direction. Given a dev team who are really committed to low-end play, you sometimes get what feels like a distinct game. For example, I find <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hardspace-shipbreaker">Hardspace: Shipbreaker</a> rather lovely when you boil back the resolution and detail. Sometimes it's more intriguing when the min spec implementation is crude. There's another game I can't quite recall which becomes a mesh of free-floating pipes and chimneys when you oblige it to run in Abacus Mode. Any recommendations, dear reader?
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I'm already smitten by upcoming action RPG Town of Zoz thanks to how much it understands food]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/im-already-smitten-by-upcoming-action-rpg-town-of-zoz-thanks-to-how-much-it-understands-food</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/im-already-smitten-by-upcoming-action-rpg-town-of-zoz-thanks-to-how-much-it-understands-food.1133190/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/im-already-smitten-by-upcoming-action-rpg-town-of-zoz-thanks-to-how-much-it-understands-food<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/town-of-zoz.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Studio Pixanoh/ Humble Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
I love a game that features some kind of cooking element, so I was quite pleased yesterday when <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/humble-games">Humble Games</a> revealed they're publishing Town Of Zoz, a new action RPG that's all about fighting off rats from eating your crops, taking down baddies to gather up ingredients, and using said ingredients and crops to make some tasty meals. It's got wonderfully vibrant art and animation. The announcement trailer quickly won me over with the choppy, almost stop-motion-like quality of certain character models.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
Town Of Zoz is the debut title from Studio Pixanoh, following Ito, a "young shaman chef adventurer" who has to come home to help run his family's farm and restaurant. There's the usual RPG questiness - dark secrets amongst the locals that you have to uncover, you know the drill - but what really sells me is its Breath Of The Wildy cooking format. Kill an enemy and out comes something like an avocado or chicken legs. Once you've got enough ingredients, you head to the kitchen, where it looks like you'll have to fend off more enemies while your food cooks.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Town of Zoz | Announcement Trailer | Humble Games" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/keA0jqnl-Rw?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Town of Zoz | Announcement Trailer | Humble Games</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/keA0jqnl-Rw?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/keA0jqnl-Rw?autoplay=1" title="Town of Zoz | Announcement Trailer | Humble Games">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=keA0jqnl-Rw" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
It looks like a fun, satisfying loop, and the cherry on top is what you do with the food afterwards. As you get to know people around town, you might learn their favourite meal. Making it for them will bring you closer together, and let you learn more about them. Obviously this is just a trailer, but so far Town of Zoz really seems to understand that food is best when it's a communal activity, something to share and bond over. As someone whose family used to run a restaurant themselves, this one's really speaking to me.
</p>
<p>
And if I wasn't sold enough by this game already, some of the score is coming from 2 Mello. His <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/jet-set-radio">Jet Set Radio</a> inspired album Memoirs Of Tokyo-To is a banger, and he's done excellent work for games like If Found, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/bomb-rush-cyberfunk">Bomb Rush Cyberfunk</a>, and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/later-alligator">Later Alligator</a> too. I'll take that release date now please! You can, like I already have, wishlist it <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1748110/Town_of_Zoz/">right here</a>.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>