<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 18:57:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40,000: Dark Heresy is the next tactical and bloody CRPG from the devs behind Rogue Trader]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/warhammer-40000-dark-heresy-is-the-next-tactical-and-bloody-crpg-from-the-devs-behind-rogue-trader</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40-000-dark-heresy-is-the-next-tactical-and-bloody-crpg-from-the-devs-behind-rogue-trader.1196808/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/warhammer-40000-dark-heresy-is-the-next-tactical-and-bloody-crpg-from-the-devs-behind-rogue-trader<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Owlcat Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
The Warhammer Skulls Showcase was full to the brim with, unsurprisingly, lots of Warhammer 40,000 game news, including a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/warhammer-40000-boltgun-2-is-coming-2026-but-theres-a-typing-of-the-dead-esque-spinoff-you-can-play-for-free-right-now">sequel to Boltgun</a> and a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/relic-reveal-warhammer-40000-dawn-of-war-definitive-edition-with-full-dlc-and-mod-support">definitive edition of Dawn of War</a>. CRPG heads were also treated to a reveal of Warhammer 40,000: Dark Heresy, a new party-based title from <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/owlcatgames">Owlcat Games</a>, the devs behind another Warhammer game <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/warhammer-40000-rogue-trader">Rogue Trader</a>. The reveal came in the form of a nicely partially 2D-animated trailer alongside some brief looks at gameplay, all of which is looking quite good.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
Much like Rogue Trader, Dark Heresy will feature turn-based combat, with this game "set against the backdrop of the Noctis Aeterna and the mystery of the Tyrant Star." You'll have "intricate investigations" to complete outside of combat, with both those and combat potentially leading to some "grave consequences." Specifically, you'll be an acolyte of the Inquisition, and it'll be up to you to search out for heresy and ultimately decide what happens to the Calixis Sector.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Warhammer 40,000: Dark Heresy - Announcement Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KVqOfHFJQFA?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Warhammer 40,000: Dark Heresy - Announcement Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KVqOfHFJQFA?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/KVqOfHFJQFA?autoplay=1" title="Warhammer 40,000: Dark Heresy - Announcement Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KVqOfHFJQFA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
As of now, a release date hasn't been set in stone, not even a release year, so you'll have to hold out for now. I imagine it'll be a while away too, as Owlcat Games are actually still working on Rogue Trader right now. The <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG's</a> next expansion, Lex Imperialis, also received a release date reveal of June 24th during the presentation. A second season pass was announced too, revealing two more expansions due out between January and March, and July and September respectively next year.
</p>
<p>
The <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2186680/Warhammer_40000_Rogue_Trader/">base game is half-off right now too</a>, if you fancy giving it a punt. Our very own Edwin <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/warhammer-40000-rogue-trader-review">reviewed it last year</a>, coming away from it with lots of nice things to say about, as well as a few not so nice things that probably would have been easier to deal with in smaller doses.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Relic reveal Warhammer 40,000: Dawn Of War Definitive Edition with all original expansions and mod support]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/relic-reveal-warhammer-40000-dawn-of-war-definitive-edition-with-full-dlc-and-mod-support</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/relic-reveal-warhammer-40-000-dawn-of-war-definitive-edition-with-all-original-expansions-and-mod-support.1196685/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/relic-reveal-warhammer-40000-dawn-of-war-definitive-edition-with-full-dlc-and-mod-support<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>4K graphics, new lighting, widescreen HUD</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Relic Entertainment</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Relic Entertainment have announced Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War - Definitive Edition, an upgraded, 64-bit version of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/these-are-your-50-favourite-strategy-games-of-all-time">your 29th favourite strategy game of all time</a>, which includes all of the original expansions and will be compatible with "over 20 years of lovingly crafted community mods".</p>
<p>The developers assert that "this is the iconic Dawn of War as players remember it, but optimized for modern hardware." Nonsense, Relic! In order for this to be Dawn Of War as <em>I</em> remember it, I would need to play it while subsisting entirely on cans of 20p Tesco tomato soup. Nowadays Tesco tomato soup costs 65p a can. It turns out that in the grim darkness of the far future, there is only rampant inflation. And 4K graphics. Here's the announcement trailer.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War - Definitive Edition Announcement Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9CLDiE8OQ1M?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War - Definitive Edition Announcement Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9CLDiE8OQ1M?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9CLDiE8OQ1M?autoplay=1" title="Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War - Definitive Edition Announcement Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9CLDiE8OQ1M" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>The Definitive Edition features four Dawn of War campaigns, encompassing nine armies and over 200 maps. You can expect upscaled textures and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Image-based_lighting">image-based lighting</a>, together with an optimised HUD layout for widescreen displays and an "improved" camera. "World lighting, unit reflections, and shadows have all been improved, and new unit gloss and emissive lighting will faithfully enhance the moment-to-moment action," gushes the press release.</p>
<p>Back in February, a few months after Sega sold them to UK investment firm Emona Capital LLP, Relic unveiled plans for a fiendishly diversified mix of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/company-of-heroes-devs-relic-bounce-back-with-plans-for-big-rts-sequels-smaller-experiments-and-spiritual-revivals">big RTS sequels, smaller experiments and spiritual revivals</a>. Happy as I am that they're still in the Spice Maureen business, this does feel like a quick cash-in while they work on something brand-new. If you don't care for those Definitive technical flourishes, you can already find a Dawn Of War compendium on Steam in the shape of the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/4570/Warhammer_40000_Dawn_of_War__Anniversary_Edition/">Anniversary Edition</a>, which also features all the old expansions and is currently 80% off till 29th May.</p>
<p>All this confirms <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/warhammer-skulls-returns-amidst-dawn-of-war-4-rumours">Nic's report</a> from earlier this week that "something Dawn Of War shaped" would turf up at this year's Warhammer Skulls event. Nic is our premier Games Workshop astropath and archivist. He knows his Great Knarlocs like I know yearly increases in the price of canned goods. Let us gather trustingly around his arcane relay in the hopes that he absently murmurs the words "<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/warhammer-40000-chaos-gate-daemonhunters">Warhammer 40,000: Chaos Gate - Daemonhunters</a> sequel".</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40,000: Boltgun 2 is coming 2026, but there's a Typing of the Dead-esque spinoff you can play for free right now]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/warhammer-40000-boltgun-2-is-coming-2026-but-theres-a-typing-of-the-dead-esque-spinoff-you-can-play-for-free-right-now</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40-000-boltgun-2-is-coming-2026-but-theres-a-typing-of-the-dead-esque-spinoff-you-can-play-for-free-right-now.1196682/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/warhammer-40000-boltgun-2-is-coming-2026-but-theres-a-typing-of-the-dead-esque-spinoff-you-can-play-for-free-right-now<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>You'll be gunning to play this one</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Auroch Digital</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Ever find yourself thinking, "man, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/warhammer-40000-boltgun">Warhammer 40,000: Boltgun</a> was a good video game, it sure would be swell if they made another one of those"? If so, the headline already spoiled this for you, but I'm going to pretend like it hasn't: a sequel was just revealed at the Warhammer Skulls Showcase! The reveal trailer mostly shows off what looks like more of the first game, but with boomer <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-free-pc-games">shooters</a> that look this good, I think that's just fine.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
Right now, the game is currently slated for a 2026 release, with no more specific a window than that. I'm sure it'll be nowhere near GTA 6, just like literally every other game next year. A press release explains that enemies like Nurglings and Chaos Cultists will be making a comeback alongside the introduction of new enemies like Bloodletters and Juggernauts. I'm sure this'll all mean a lot more to Warhammer 40K lore heads than it does to me, honestly there could be an enemy called Hellsuckers and I'd believe you.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Warhammer 40,000: Boltgun 2 Reveal Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rG19wrCGR5g?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Warhammer 40,000: Boltgun 2 Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rG19wrCGR5g?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/rG19wrCGR5g?autoplay=1" title="Warhammer 40,000: Boltgun 2 Reveal Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rG19wrCGR5g" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
On top of all that there'll be new weapons to pick up, locations to explore, and a storyline with different branches to head down, each with their own unique levels.
</p>
<p>
Oh, and there's actually another new Warhammer 40,000: Boltgun game you can play right now too, Words of Vengeance. This one's a "first person typer", so think games like The Typing of the Dead, but with a Warhammer 40,000 paintjob. Words of Vengeance looks silly as hell, and it's even completely free! Love that.
</p>
<p>
There's also a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/bundle/36406/Warhammer_40000_Space_Marine_Anniversary__Boltgun__Graia_Collection/">Steam bundle</a> with the original Boltgun, alongside the first Space Marine, that's 47% off at the moment if you've not played either of them before. You can also wishlist Boltgun 2 on Steam <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3115160/Warhammer_40000_Boltgun_2/">right here</a>, and pickup Words of Vengeance on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3533730/Warhammer_40000_Boltgun__Words_of_Vengeance/">here</a>.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>