<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:58:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Earth Must Die publishers say an "alien orgy depicted as a gyrating lump on the floor" left the game's Steam launch "unclear"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/earth-must-die-publishers-say-an-alien-orgy-depicted-as-a-gyrating-lump-on-the-floor-left-the-games-steam-launch-unclear</link>
            <guid>1418446</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Valve's bouncers reportedly requested a video so they could double check the context of the gyrating lump orgy</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valve-steam-reviewed-earth-must-sue-alien-orgy-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valve-steam-reviewed-earth-must-sue-alien-orgy-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valve-steam-reviewed-earth-must-sue-alien-orgy-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valve-steam-reviewed-earth-must-sue-alien-orgy-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valve-steam-reviewed-earth-must-sue-alien-orgy-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valve-steam-reviewed-earth-must-sue-alien-orgy-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valve-steam-reviewed-earth-must-sue-alien-orgy-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valve-steam-reviewed-earth-must-sue-alien-orgy-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valve-steam-reviewed-earth-must-sue-alien-orgy-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>No More Robots</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>What Steam operators Valve are and aren't prepared to allow onto their storefront has been a major talking point for the past year or so, especially when it comes to mature or sexually-themed content. Our Edwin's done some <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-payment-networks-control-the-definition-of-acceptable-sex-in-videogames">fine reporting on the topic</a> and how it relates to payment processors, as well as delving into individual cases like <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/saturnalia-creators-santa-ragione-will-wind-down-operations-after-valve-ban-horror-game-horses-from-steam">Santa Ragione's Horses</a>.</p>
<p>Now, the developers of point-and-click comedy <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/point-and-click-adventure-game-filled-with-ah-yeah-them-british-actors-earth-must-die-is-out-later-this-month">Earth Must Die</a> say things looked "unclear" for a bit in terms of whether they'd be able to launch on Steam, with the platform then offering a thumbs up after reviewing footage of an "alien orgy".</p>
<!--more-->
<p>"Up until a few days ago, it was unclear if we were actually going to be allowed to launch Earth Must Die on Steam, as Valve had told us that they were 'unable to verify' the context of the alien orgy," publishers No More Robots told <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/adventure/valve-needed-to-verify-footage-of-the-alien-orgy-in-earth-must-die-before-it-was-allowed-to-launch-on-steam/#viafoura-comments">Painting Collection Gamer</a>. "We were required to record and send footage of said orgy for their verification."</p>
<p>Thankfully, once that footage was sent over, approval was forthcoming. That said, whether on Valve's orders or by No More Robots' own volition, Earth Must Die's Steam page bears a mature content warning specifying that "there is a puzzle that takes place in an alien adult bookshop, and an alien orgy depicted as a gyrating lump on the floor".</p><p>As much as it's funny to imagine a Valve staffer examining footage of cartoon extraterrestrials going at it, No More Robots' retelling of the events paints what's turned into an amusing anecdote as something that could potentially have thrown a major spanner in the works. If games that dabble in jokey depictions of shagging face that sort of gaze into the void, right up until they're sure Valve are 100% satisfied, one can only imagine the uncertainty more serious explorations of mature themes might encounter.</p>
<p>On one hand, Valve have a right to apply the rules they decide to enforce on their storefront, even if said storefront's domination of the PC space makes such calls far weightier than they might otherwise be. On the other, as Edwin's reported, the matter of credit card companies and payment processors influencing what those rules - and the rules of other storefronts - are when it comes specifically to adult content complicates the matter significantly.</p>
<p>At least in this case, the alien orgy made it through whatever contextual hoops it needed, so that No More Robots' game about British actors and comics quipping their way through a tale about a martian ruler doing quirky stuff could drop as planned this week.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/earth-must-die-publishers-say-an-alien-orgy-depicted-as-a-gyrating-lump-on-the-floor-left-the-games-steam-launch-unclear]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arc Raiders update rips out one of the game's most maddening puzzles]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arc-raiders-update-rips-out-one-of-the-games-most-maddening-puzzles</link>
            <guid>1418341</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Guitars now sold at Shani's</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arcraidersguitar.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arcraidersguitar.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arcraidersguitar.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arcraidersguitar.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arcraidersguitar.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arcraidersguitar.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arcraidersguitar.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arcraidersguitar.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arcraidersguitar.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Screenrant / Nexon</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arc-raiders-best-guns-tier-list">Arc Raiders</a> has a new Headwinds game update that, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arc-raiders-headwinds-update-asks-whether-extra-xp-is-enough-to-go-solo-in-a-group-lobby">amongst many other things</a>, removes an extravagantly drawn-out puzzle from the game’s Buried City map. Introduced in December, the puzzle in question saw people tracking down and pushing 15 buttons in a certain order to unlock a secret chamber containing an actual, strummable guitar. As of this updating, you’ll now be able to buy that guitar at Shani’s, like a millionaire tourist paying to be flown to the top of Mount Everest. </p>
<p>I regard this as a dilution of the game, on paper, but I am not one of the players who’ve driven themselves crackers trying to get hold of the instrument (or paying real money for the battle pass to unlock it). Arc Raiders is a multiplayer game, of course, so even if you survive being shot at while stampeding between buttons, it’s possible another, distant player might innocently press one and reset your progress.</p><!--more-->
<p>I really like multiplayer puzzles, in general, especially when the game isn’t really designed for this kind of trickery. It’s hard enough lugging loot back to the elevator in Arc without getting a bellyful of bullets. One can only imagine the feats of cunning required to track down a bunch of buttons in parallel. One can only imagine the elation of bringing home the prize.</p>
<p>Still, reactions to the tweak on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ArcRaiders/comments/1pp7gdr/how_to_get_guitar_buried_city_music_puzzle_and/">Reddit</a> are mostly a mixture of contempt and relief. As one user points out, even if you unearth the guitar, there’s no guarantee you’ll have enough time to extract. Perhaps turning the guitar into a purchaseable item was all part of Embark's plan, after milking community desperation for a few weeks? It <em>is</em> a very nice guitar. You can play up to seven tunes with it. The difficulty of obtaining the thing may explain why so many wasteland buskers are getting shot in the head.</p><p>Read more about this and other Raider business in <a href="https://arcraiders.com/news/patch-notes-1-13-0">the full changelog</a>. The devs have “fixed the Seedvault extraction glitch on Stella Montis that allowed players to remain in the extraction point after it had closed”. They’re also in the process of implementing a three strikes progressive ban system for cheaters, with bans progressing “from 30 days, to 60 and finally a permaban for repeat offenders”.</p>
<p>Any successful examples of puzzles in multiplayer shooters to share? I guess the obvious ones to beat are still Destiny’s Raids, hashtag Vault Of Glass. There’s probably some good stuff in certain editions of Fortnite, but I forget.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arc-raiders-update-rips-out-one-of-the-games-most-maddening-puzzles]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>