<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 18:03:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Creative Assembly reveal Total War: Medieval 3, while teasing a huge game reveal to follow]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/creative-assembly-reveal-total-war-medieval-3-while-teasing-a-huge-game-reveal-to-follow</link>
            <guid>1373266</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>It's in "early pre-production"</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Med-III_BeforeBattle_Concept-Art.webp?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Med-III_BeforeBattle_Concept-Art.webp?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Med-III_BeforeBattle_Concept-Art.webp?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Med-III_BeforeBattle_Concept-Art.webp?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Med-III_BeforeBattle_Concept-Art.webp?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Med-III_BeforeBattle_Concept-Art.webp?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Med-III_BeforeBattle_Concept-Art.webp?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Med-III_BeforeBattle_Concept-Art.webp?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Med-III_BeforeBattle_Concept-Art.webp?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Sega</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/total-war-medieval-3">Total War: Medieval 3</a> is in early pre-production, Creative Assembly have revealed during Total War's 25th anniversary showcase, with release still years away. It's to be the "rebirth of historical Total War", and CA are unveiling it earlier than they've ever announced a Total War game before, so that you crafty peasants can offer more feedback throughout development.</p>
<p>Time to hang up your Reikland Runefang and start boning up on the fall of the Byzantines - though there's precious little news about how the new Twar will differ in practice from Medieval 2, which launched way back in 2006. Here's a live action trailer full of moody-looking regents, some of whom are badly in need of a sticking plaster.
</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Total War: MEDIEVAL III - Announce Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qFKhUJTnC-E?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Total War: MEDIEVAL III - Announce Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qFKhUJTnC-E?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/qFKhUJTnC-E?autoplay=1" title="Total War: MEDIEVAL III - Announce Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qFKhUJTnC-E" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>
During the showcase stream, there was much loose historical background and talk of reinventing the wheel (which may have happened several times during the medieval era - enlighten me, historians?) but few concrete specifics. They don't even have a fixed start date for the period, though it sounds like it'll be approximately 12th to 15th century.</p><p>If I'm reading the entrails correctly, the game's world will range from the Holy Roman Empire through the Kingdom of England to the Italian Free States, the Mongols and the Ottomans. It will feature such celebs as Saladin, Eleanor of Aquitaine, and Richard the Lionheart.
</p>
<p>
The devs characterised the medieval period as one of experimentation, personal ambition, and the formation of nations. There was an aside on "lines of succession", which suggests you might be switching between rulers and their heirs, but colour that speculation. There was also a bit of detail on recruitment and historical armies, with a senior game designer commenting that rather than having a standing army, you might call on oaths of fealty to rally the banners of your vassals. 
</p>
<p>As divulged on <a href="https://www.totalwar.com/news/welcome-to-total-war-medieval-iii">the official website</a>, Medieval 3 will run on Warcore, Creative Assembly's new engine tech. It's billed as "unlike anything we’ve worked with before, offering a bespoke set of new and improved tools across our animation system, to the renderer and campaign building blocks - all designed to bring the medieval era to life in ways we’ve previously never been able to achieve." Given how long Creative Assembly have been working on <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/total-war-warhammer">Total War: Warhammer</a>, it's nice to hear that there's a more comprehensive technological overhaul in the offing. </p>
<p>
I'll be honest, Medieval is one of the Twars I skipped. I am Shogun and Three Kingdoms to the bone. Still, I'm delighted for you fans of knights and castles. If you're baying for more, please direct your baying at <a href="https://www.totalwar.com/news/our-vision-for-total-war-medieval-iii">this announcement post</a> from Medieval 3 creative director Leif Walter. It contains a lot of blue sky thinking, but there are some possibly indicative remarks about letting players deviate from the textbooks and your realm being "really almost like the main character in an RPG game".
</p><p>
That's not all Creative Assembly announced in their showcase. Not all they teased, rather. They've got another game reveal next week, during the Geoff Awards. Apparently, "this title will be Total War's next major release and represents one of the most ambitious projects in the franchise's history, marking the beginning of an exciting new era." Are the words "for the Emperor" stomping with zealous indignation towards this sentence, CA?
</p>
<p>
If all of this has you classique Warhammer advocates boarding your griffins and fleeing to the mountains, come back. There's more Total War: Warhammer 3 DLC on the way - Lords of the End Times, which introduces uber-necromancer Nagash and three other legendary lords. We'll try to write about that when we can. I have to go read up on Eleanor of Aquitaine.
</p>
</div>

      </article>




        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/creative-assembly-reveal-total-war-medieval-3-while-teasing-a-huge-game-reveal-to-follow]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wreckreation studio put entire staff on notice of redundancy, but still believe in their latest Burnout revival]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wreckreation-studio-put-entire-staff-on-notice-of-redundancy-but-still-believe-in-their-latest-burnout-revival</link>
            <guid>1373224</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"My hope is that by showing this work publicly, someone out there might also see that potential"</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/wreckreation-three-fields-entertainment-notice-of-rendundancy-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/wreckreation-three-fields-entertainment-notice-of-rendundancy-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/wreckreation-three-fields-entertainment-notice-of-rendundancy-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/wreckreation-three-fields-entertainment-notice-of-rendundancy-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/wreckreation-three-fields-entertainment-notice-of-rendundancy-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/wreckreation-three-fields-entertainment-notice-of-rendundancy-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/wreckreation-three-fields-entertainment-notice-of-rendundancy-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/wreckreation-three-fields-entertainment-notice-of-rendundancy-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/wreckreation-three-fields-entertainment-notice-of-rendundancy-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Three Fields Entertainment</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Three Fields Entertainment, developers of Burnout with sky roads racer <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/wreckreation">Wreckreation</a>, have announced that their entire team have been put on notice of redundancy. According to the announcement from CEO and former Criterion studio director Fiona Sperry, this comes as Three Fields find themselves without backing from Wreckreation publishers THQNordic, having "had to self-fund most of this year".</p>
<!--more-->
<p>"Without the enthusiasm or financial support from our publisher to continue development, we simply cannot sustain the studio in its current form. Making this decision has been unbelievably painful," Sperry wrote in a message shared via the game's Twitter account.</p>
<p>"This is a heartbreaking moment for all of us," she continued. "What makes it even harder is that we have so many things in the pipeline — multiple features, updates, and creative ideas that we were excited to bring to the game, many of which are showcased in the video we’re sharing today."</p>
<p>Said video, which you can watch via the tweet above, shows off a number of feature additions which I'll be keen to give a go if they do make it into Wreckreation. One's an "accident black spots" mode mirroring classic Burnout's brilliant crash mode, in which you're given a junction and tasked with causing as costly a pileup as possible. There's also a "tightrope mode" all about driving along very narrow airborne obstacle courses, the ability to add buildings to the map while in the game's live mix building mode, and a bunch of construction vehicles and trucks you can drive around.</p><div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>Today I am having to share one of the hardest messages of my career. After twelve years of building and nurturing Three Fields Entertainment, I am forced into the situation of today placing our entire team on notice of redundancy.</p><p>Since the launch of *Wreckreation*, our small… <a href="https://t.co/4lq7irQrNF">pic.twitter.com/4lq7irQrNF</a></p></div>— Wreckreation Game (@ArcadeDriving) <a href="https://twitter.com/ArcadeDriving/status/1996584475682115871?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 4, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>Of all those, the crash mode's something I could genuinely see giving Wreckreation some bounce-back potential, assuming the likes of BeamNG.Drive haven't filled that void in many players' minds. The ability to essentially build your own towns could also go a long way to helping put a plaster on one of the game's biggest problems - its boringly barren worldspace outside of player-built sky spaghetti.</p>
<p>"My hope is that by showing this work publicly, someone out there might also see that potential and perhaps an opportunity could still emerge," Sperry wrote. "But even if that hope does not materialise, we want this to stand as a testament to our vision and to the strength, passion, and skill of our tiny team." As of writing, Three Fields still plan to deliver an update adding crossplay to Wreckreation before Christmas.</p>
<p>All the news we report about game developers losing their jobs or being at risk of that sees us send our best to the folks affected, but I'm particularly sad to see Three Fields in this tough situation. That's largely because I really enjoyed the work Sperry, Alex Ward and co did on Burnout and Need For Speed while at Criterion, with both those series either dormant or <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/need-for-speed-will-return-ea-pledges-but-team-all-in-on-battlefield-for-now">currently on hold</a>.</p>
<p>Both Wreckreation and 2019's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dangerous-driving">Dangerous Driving</a> had a chance to be Three Fields' big 'Burnout's back, baby' moments, conclusively proving to the suits at EA that locking the series in the attic of dormant entities was a hugely short-sighted move. Neither quite managed to stick the landing, though. In <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wreckreation-melds-burnouts-anarchy-with-gta-onlines-airborne-marble-runs-but-it-needs-a-lot-more-polish">my hours playing both</a>, I've never felt like that faliure was down to them being cynical nostalgia-fests, attempts to cash in on the anarchic old arcade racers myself and others fell in love with. Instead, and perhaps this is because I've gone in each time hoping I'll be blown away, the two games felt like the vision was solid, but the small studio just hadn't been able to nail the nuances of execution.</p><p>They weren't a million miles off reigniting the magic of classic Burnout, with EA and Criterion's substantial resources behind it. They're still yet to get there, though. Here's hoping that another publisher who're willing to back Three Fields swoop in and as always, solidarity to the studio's staff as they face an uncertain future.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wreckreation-studio-put-entire-staff-on-notice-of-redundancy-but-still-believe-in-their-latest-burnout-revival]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>