<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 19:14:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Surprise! Nuclear Throne has a new update that's mostly for people that insist on only playing games that can do 60fps]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/surprise-nuclear-throne-has-a-new-update-thats-mostly-for-people-that-insist-on-only-playing-games-that-can-do-60fps</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/surprise-nuclear-throne-has-a-new-update-thats-mostly-for-people-that-insist-on-only-playing-games-that-can-do-60fps.1229289/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Plus some other useful improvements</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Vlambeer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
I think <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/nuclear-throne">Nuclear Throne</a> is one of those games that will always be at least just a little bit relevant, in some shape or form. There are other indie games I'd rather play more than it from its era, but it kind of feels like the best representation of that period in indie games too. Throwback pixel art, a unique spin on both bullet hells and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-roguelike-games-pc">roguelike</a>, a bangin' soundtrack, it's got the right mix of things to help it stand the test of time. And here we are now, the game approaching its 10th anniversary, arriving with a new update.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
To be specific, it's a new beta build, so it's only there if you want to try it out, but it is available right now. Don't go expecting massive features or additions or anything though, this is a quality of life update. To that end, here's what it includes! For starters there's now 60 or 120fps support, for those of you that care about that sort of thing (look, most games just don't need 60fps, alright). 
</p>
<blockquote data-bluesky-cid="bafyreigkdha3xq7ur53flrqxyevbjwlqotz5ckcb6dva3u42jn45vddaue" data-bluesky-embed-color-mode="system" data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:efqtjl4pdgshwti6enxa57uf/app.bsky.feed.post/3lshervnxtc23"><div lang="en"><p>Good news for (future) Nuclear Throne fans: there's an updated beta build on Steam with many quality of life improvements like 120fps support, different aspect ratios, and a new controls menu! Oh, and a new melting loading screen tip. 😎 store.steampowered.com/app/242680/N...</p><p><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:efqtjl4pdgshwti6enxa57uf/post/3lshervnxtc23?ref_src=embed">[image or embed]</a></p></div>— Vlambeer (<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:efqtjl4pdgshwti6enxa57uf?ref_src=embed">@vlambeer.com</a>) <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:efqtjl4pdgshwti6enxa57uf/post/3lshervnxtc23?ref_src=embed">June 25, 2025 at 8:45 PM</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><p>
There's also new aspect ratios, and a new controls menu too, but to find out the exact changes there you'll have to take a look for yourself. "Oh, and a new Melting loading screen tip", the post rounds off, alongside a very cool emoji wearing sunglasses.
</p>
<p>
If you want access to this update, your steps are pretty simple: right click on Nuclear Throne in your Steam library, click properties, then betas, then select "openbeta_win64", and Bob's your uncle, the update is ready and waiting for you.
</p>
<p>
Vlambeer explain in the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/242680/view/528724684296945991?l=english">Steam post</a> announcing the update that they plan to add all these improvements into the main game too, as well as more than what's mentioned above, so don't feel like you have to rush for it.

</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/surprise-nuclear-throne-has-a-new-update-thats-mostly-for-people-that-insist-on-only-playing-games-that-can-do-60fps]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[There shall be no Sifu 2, says Rematch dev, because "chasing safe bets is a death sentence"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/there-shall-be-no-sifu-2-says-rematch-dev-because-chasing-safe-bets-is-a-death-sentence</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/there-shall-be-no-sifu-2-says-rematch-dev-because-chasing-safe-bets-is-a-death-sentence.1229286/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>OK, but please do a martial art now and then, Sloclap</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Sloclap</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Sloclap’s <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/latest-foot-to-ball-visualisation">foot-to-ball</a> game Rematch is <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rematch-review">very good</a>, and has been doing very well, with over three million sales to date, but some of us yet grieve for a time when kicks were reserved for torsos and limbs. Which is to say, some of us have been hoping that Sloclap might return to the martial arts realm in which it has hitherto made waves.</p> <!--more-->
<p>If it happens, it will not happen in the form of a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/sifu">Sifu</a> 2 or even a sequel to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/absolver">Absolver</a>, Sloclap’s chain-punching debut. For you see, creative director Pierre Tarno is of the opinion that “chasing safe bets is a death sentence” and that "gamers are on the lookout for new, original experiences." He’s got better things to do than develop sequels, and I’m sure no video game publishers brandishing huge sacks of rubies will persuade him otherwise.</p>
<p>That’s from a new Edge interview sliced into sandwich-sized slablets by <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/sports/as-rematch-fires-past-3-million-players-devs-say-they-werent-planning-to-follow-up-their-cult-kung-fu-game-sifu-chasing-safe-bets-is-a-death-sentence/">Gamesradar</a>. According to Tarno, he pitched Rematch after Sloclap finished Absolver, but the studio were too small at the time to handle more than one project, and Sifu won the coin toss. Still, Sloclap were already prototyping the football game almost a year before Sifu’s release.</p>
<p>Again, Rematch has done very well. Extraordinarily well, for a game braving a sports genre dominated by essentially one series, the artist formerly known as FIFA. I’ve enjoyed what I’ve played of it – you can feel the dev’s past games in the tuned-up leather-walloping SFX, which make EA Sports FC seem anodyne. I also enjoy that, for all the souped-up holographic stadiums, each match is basically a neighbourhood kickabout with loosened rules and no referee.</p>
<p>Still, I wouldn’t mind playing another Absolver, or some other, very stylish experience in which feet are a means of speedy jaw removal rather than being used to abuse innocent, air-filled orbs. Hmm, what other things can you kick? I do kick this computer now and then when I'm doing my tax returns, but I'm not sure you could get a whole game out of that.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/there-shall-be-no-sifu-2-says-rematch-dev-because-chasing-safe-bets-is-a-death-sentence]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cool train strategy game Railgrade gets a free campaign about escaping a rival corporation's planet]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cool-train-strategy-game-railgrade-gets-a-free-campaign-about-escaping-a-rival-corporations-planet</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cool-train-strategy-game-railgrade-gets-a-free-campaign-about-escaping-a-rival-corporations-planet.1229223/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Crafted by the pick of the map-making community</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Minakata Dynamics / Gamirror Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>This article on a free update for train factory <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-strategy-games-on-pc">strategy game</a> Railgrade is the absolute height of presumption, for we have never actually covered <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/railgrade">Railgrade</a> before, even though it came out ONE MILLION YEARS AGO in October 2023.</p>
<p>I cannot hear your cries of outrage and scorn, however, for my ears are filled with the otherworldly whistle of speeding locomotives. The locos wail to me of a brand new campaign encompassing 11 missions and nine hours of playtime. Did you play Railgrade? Do you wish there were more of it? Well, stop carping about our spotty coverage and get this patch down your trousers, then.</p><!--more-->
<p>The campaign in question is Rapid Repo Rescue. As <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1355090/view/803443087671039134?l=english">detailed on Steam</a>, it takes you to a brand new colony planet except that, oops, it turns out the colony ship accidentally landed on a planet owned by a rival corporation. As such, you'll now need to rush-develop a factory network in order to recharge your space launcher before the legal goons arrive and suitcase the entire site from orbit.</p>
<p>The new campaign is the work of a Railgrade player, Mortiz, who is currently studying at university. Railgrade devs Minakata Dynamics commissioned him - in the form of cash, scandalously enough, rather than the standard creative industry currency of exposure - in light of his past work for the mapmaking community. A few Discord group members have pitched in with playtesting, seemingly for free. I frown upon devs who enlist their players as unpaid testers, but in fairness, this appears to have been a more informal community production.</p>
<p>If you own Railgrade, you'll find Rapid Repo Rescue on the bonus campaign menu. "We gave Mortiz access to every yet-unused asset in the game," lead programmer Daniel Dressler notes. "This meant new trains, new industry, and new resources." The latter bits include "a Natural Gas &amp; Hydrogen set of energy production chains", a new Gas Powerplant, and Offshore Gas Wells.</p>
<p>If you never played Railgrade, because you think trains are the work of the Devil, you may be more interested in the developer's forthcoming <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2489330/Whiskerwood/">Whiskerwood</a>. It's about building factory-colonies of mice and sending shipments of goods to villainous cats overseas - a pleasantly concussed reimagining of European colonialism, plus jolly pirate ships. We'll try to write about that one when it actually comes out.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cool-train-strategy-game-railgrade-gets-a-free-campaign-about-escaping-a-rival-corporations-planet]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>