<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 14:10:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Possible GTA 6 parody websites hint at in-game activities, including buying tackle from Hookers Galore and posting creepy corndogs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/possible-gta-6-parody-websites-hint-at-in-game-activities-including-buying-tackle-from-hookers-galore-and-posting-creepy-corndogs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/possible-gta-6-parody-websites-hint-at-in-game-activities-including-buying-tackle-from-hookers-galore-and-posting-creepy-corndogs.1292430/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Tackle as in cod, not codpiece. Corndog as in dick.</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture data-src-full="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Jason_Duval_06_ZrqWgst.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" src="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Jason_Duval_06_ZrqWgst.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Jason_Duval_06_ZrqWgst.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 690px) and (min-resolution: 2x)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Jason_Duval_06_ZrqWgst.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 690px)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Jason_Duval_06_ZrqWgst.jpg?width=414&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-resolution: 2x)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Rockstar Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gta-6-everything-we-know">GTA 6</a> will feature a bunch of in-game websites with real-world URLs, going by various domain registrations spotted by an active and efficient dataminer. The site URLs offer potential clues about the businesses and organisations you might patronise, during your time in Vice City. They include what sound like parody versions of ride-sharing app Uber and communication network WhatsApp, together with a government website for Leonida, the fictional US state and parody of Florida in which Rockstar's new <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/grand-theft-auto">Grand Theft Auto</a> takes place. </p>
<p>One of the other rumoured GTA 6 websites appears to feature "hookers galore". I give odds of 6-4 that this will prove to be an in-game fishing supplier, ho ho. And then there's "myboyhasacreepycorndog.com". I give odds of 3-2 that "corndog" means "penis", har har. It's GTA, isn't it. There's absolutely a dick joke in there somewhere.</p><!--more-->
<p>It's not impossible that these websites - <a href="https://uk.godaddy.com/whois/results.aspx?itc=dlp_domain_whois&amp;domainName=leonidagov.org">registered in May this year</a>, and spotted by Tez2 on the <a href="https://gtaforums.com/topic/1002286-gta-vi-general-speculation-discussion-vice-city-baby/page/51/#comment-1072587065">GTAforums</a> - are either a false flag or a massive wind-up. Perhaps there genuinely <em>is</em> a real-world business called wipeoutcornskin.com, presumably some kind of reality gameshow with, again, a discreet phallic component. If they exist, they'll be getting a lot of hysterical calls about map size right now.</p>
<p>A few things support the case for these sites being actual GTA 6 tie-ins, however. Firstly, they were originally registered to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Name_server">nameservers</a> such as ns03.vandalay-industries.net and dns2.p05.nsone.net that, as <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/grand-theft-auto/take-two-tries-to-hide-gta-6-websites-behind-its-back-after-fans-uncover-them-achieving-nothing-but-fuelling-the-fire/">PCG report</a>, are also tied to sites like rockstargames.com. In what could be a hasty attempt at hiding the tracks, they've since been unhitched from those nameservers and are now registered under <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markmonitor">Markmonitor</a>, a trademark protection business whose clients include Rockstar parent company Take-Two Interactive.</p><p>Secondly, one of the rumoured GTA 6 websites, what-up.app, also appears in materials from <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-gta-6-leaks-benefit-precisely-no-one">the great GTA 6 leak of 2022</a>. Thirdly, and most sketchily, GTA 6 deuteragonist Jason is wearing a cap with "Brian" on it in the image at the top of this article. Here's the complete list of domain registrations passed along by Tez2:</p>
<ul>
<li>what-up.app</li>
<li>rydeme.app </li>
<li>buckme.app </li>
<li>leonidagov.org </li>
<li>brianandbradley.com </li>
<li>hookers-galore.com </li>
<li>wipeoutcornskin.com </li>
<li>myboyhasacreepycorndog.com </li>
</ul>
<p>GTA 6 having a bunch of parody websites is in keeping with marketing campaigns and world-building for GTA 4 and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/grand-theft-auto-v">GTA 5</a>. None of the addresses above lead to actual websites at the time of publication; come release day, they will likely redirect to the official GTA 6 portal. </p>
<p>In other news, Devolver's co-founder recently branded GTA 6 <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/devolver-boss-calls-gta-6-an-aaaaa-game-in-latest-attack-on-human-dignity">the first AAAAA game</a>. Sadly, it is too late for Take-Two to register AAAAA.com - that URL already redirects to a Korean holding page seemingly registered by somebody from Arizona. Are there... are there creepy corndogs in Arizona? I'm not sure I wish to know the answer.</p>
<p><em>This article has been updated with additional details about the original nameservers tied to the possible GTA 6 parody sites.</em>
<span data-fixed="true" data-hashid="dk1r7n" data-init="false" data-poll-position="1"></span>

        </p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/possible-gta-6-parody-websites-hint-at-in-game-activities-including-buying-tackle-from-hookers-galore-and-posting-creepy-corndogs]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>