<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 17:40:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Patapon spiritual successor Ratatan musically marches towards an early access release next month]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/patapon-spiritual-successor-ratatan-musically-marches-towards-an-early-access-release-next-month</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/patapon-spiritual-successor-ratatan-musically-marches-towards-an-early-access-release-next-month.1211202/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/patapon-spiritual-successor-ratatan-musically-marches-towards-an-early-access-release-next-month<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Ratata Arts</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
If we're being honest with ourselves, the original PSP was a sort of Proto-Switch too, no? As in it was home to a lot of odd, smaller-scope games that not many other platforms might have featured outside of Nintendo's earlier handhelds. <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/patapon">Patapon</a> was one such tiny oddity, one of the most charming games on the platform, if not to ever outright exist. It did go on to get a couple of sequels, but the series (outside of an upcoming remaster of the first two) is sort of dead. Luckily, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/ratatan">Ratatan</a>, a spiritual successor from Patapon's creator is here to satisfy your tiny-guy-chanting-to-music needs with a newly revealed release date!
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
Featured during yesterday's Day of the Devs presentation, it was revealed that the rhythm <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-roguelike-games-pc">roguelike</a> action game (take a shot for every genre it mixes) will be coming to <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2949320/Ratatan/">Steam in early access</a> next month on July 25th. I'm quite excited by this one personally, those little chants in the original Patapon are burnt into my ear canals, I'm looking forward to getting something fresh in there that I can also repeat to myself ad infinitum. Yes that sounds like someone's personal hell, I just love a good chant.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Ratatan Early Access Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/h_UngFO7E40?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Ratatan Early Access Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/h_UngFO7E40?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/h_UngFO7E40?autoplay=1" title="Ratatan Early Access Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h_UngFO7E40" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
Luckily, none of us actually have to wait to check it out either. There's a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3449820/Ratatan_Demo/">demo</a> you can give a punt right now, something I'll be trying to fit in amongst the 1000 showcases taking place this week. The one thing I'm uncertain of is the roguelike element - outside of that it just looks like an incredibly lush and colourful, modern take on an old classic. Whether that roguelike quality will rob itself of tightly designed levels is something I'll have to find out for myself.
</p>
<p>
Ratatan also differs slightly in that you can freely move the little guys around, adding an extra tactical layer to it all. I will cry if even one of the Ratatans die, so, I'll be working hard to make the right choices.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arc Raiders prepares to stake its claim in making extraction shooters popular with an October release date]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arc-raiders-prepares-to-stake-its-claim-in-making-extraction-shooters-popular-with-an-october-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arc-raiders-prepares-to-stake-its-claim-in-making-extraction-shooters-popular-with-an-october-release-date.1211115/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arc-raiders-prepares-to-stake-its-claim-in-making-extraction-shooters-popular-with-an-october-release-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Embark Studios</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/arc-raiders">Arc Raiders</a>! It's an extraction <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-fps-games">shooter</a>! A fact that will leave many with the question, "is this the one that'll push the genre to the mainstream?" Personally I haven't the foggiest, and I don't have a horse in that race either. That kind of nonsense matters more to shareholders than it does to little old me. Still, we've not got a huge amount of time to wait to find out if Arc Raiders is the one to make extraction shooters big, as during <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pondering-geoffs-orbs">Geoff's Livestream of Questionable Quality and Orbs</a>, it got a release date.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
That date is October 30th, a little over four months away. Just in time for Halloween, too, which isn't at all thematically appropriate or relevant, but, it's a holiday? Sort of? Yeah, let's go with that. The shooter held a technical test last month to see if the thing actually works, and according to a press release, executive producer Aleksander Grøndal said it was the "best rehearsal we could get."
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="ARC Raiders | Release Date Reveal Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sfufcWOh2LE?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>ARC Raiders | Release Date Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sfufcWOh2LE?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/sfufcWOh2LE?autoplay=1" title="ARC Raiders | Release Date Reveal Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sfufcWOh2LE" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
Grøndal explained that there are the usual things developer <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/embark-studios">Embark Studios</a> have to do ahead of launch like bugs, polish, and performance improvements. But there's also more gameplay oriented things like balance and the player economy to work on. Notably, he also said that they're working on "an even better onboarding experience for players who come in new to this genre." Quite clearly, Embark understand that they have some work to do to get people to stick with their extraction shooter.
</p>
<p>
For those not yet on the uptake with Arc Raiders, you'll be playing as one of those titular raiders in an alternate future of earth overrun by evil robots (the titular Arc). You'll need to scavenge what's left of the surface world to build up your home underground, either working with others, or facing off against them, depending on how co-operative you're feeling. Good looking vibes so far, but the proof will be in the pud.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>