<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 18:37:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GeoGuessr is making its way to Steam next month after almost 12 years of sticking it out as a browser game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/geoguessr-is-making-its-way-to-steam-next-month-after-almost-12-years-of-sticking-it-out-as-a-browser-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/geoguessr-is-making-its-way-to-steam-next-month-after-almost-12-years-of-sticking-it-out-as-a-browser-game.1144467/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/geoguessr-is-making-its-way-to-steam-next-month-after-almost-12-years-of-sticking-it-out-as-a-browser-game<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>You'll have to guess its exact release date, though</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/geoguessr_1FzTfyi.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>GeoGuessr</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
I'm absolutely naff when it comes to geography, whether it be the version in school which is actually more about rocks and rivers than places, or said places themselves and where they are. I just don't know where things are! And that's fine. Even still, like many others I partook in a good few games of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/geoguessr">GeoGuessr</a> during the height of the COVID-19 pandemic and found it to be good fun, particularly with some friends. And now, five years on since that whole thing happened, the geography guessing game is coming to Steam.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3478870/GeoGuessr_Steam_Edition/?curator_clanid=3693985">GeoGuessr Steam Edition</a>, as it's appropriately called, is actually apparently going to be an early access title. The explanation for this given on the game's Steam page is the usual kind of thing, refining gameplay, adding features, getting direct feedback. It also notes that the dev's goal is to create the "ultimate competitive and casual geography game", which is a funny goal to have in mind given that it is generally the first game you immediately think of within that incredibly niche genre.
</p>
<p>
There's no exact release date just yet but the Steam page says that it's actually coming next month, which is literally a week away, so you've not got long to wait. The thing that isn't particularly clear right now is how it will be priced. Right now the web version of the game, which has been around for 12 years I might add, requires a subscription to play more than three rounds a day, something that <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/geoguessr/comments/19aipld/pro_subscription_will_be_needed_to_continue/">wasn't all that well received</a> when the change was announced last year.
</p>
<p>
The game's Steam page does note that the price won't change during its early access period, and is unlikely to change afterwards, so this version might be a one-off payment. Fingers crossed! Bloody sick of subscription fees.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pacific Drive's next update makes driving around endlessly sound pretty good, actually]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pacific-drives-next-update-makes-driving-around-endlessly-sound-pretty-good-actually</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pacific-drives-next-update-makes-driving-around-endlessly-sound-pretty-good-actually.1144389/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pacific-drives-next-update-makes-driving-around-endlessly-sound-pretty-good-actually<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>And there's a few quality of life improvements coming too</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/pacific-drive_abCc5qy.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Ironwood Studios</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
You would think that with a game that is pretty much all about driving like <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/pacific-drive">Pacific Drive</a>, the prospect of an update that promises "endless" driving wouldn't be all that exciting or interesting. In this case you'd be wrong, though, as the game's upcoming Endless Expeditions patch sounds like a pretty solid one. Developer <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/ironwood-studios">Ironwood Studios</a> revealed the update with a new trailer yesterday, showing off all the changes and additions coming to the game, the most notable one being expeditions, described as "new continuous drives" that are a bit more dangerous than you might be used to.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
Outside of offering "unique rewards", Ironwood kept quiet on what this new mode will be like, but that makes the mystery of it all the more intriguing, no? On top of that there's also a few quality of life improvements coming. There's a new feature called cluster spawning, though I couldn't tell you what that is right now. The thermal vacuum and plasma scrapper are seeing some improvements too. As well as all that, a new zone trader, Ida's Exchange, can be discovered too.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Pacific Drive | Endless Expeditions Spring 2025 Update" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZrUC6K2tMcM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Pacific Drive | Endless Expeditions Spring 2025 Update</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZrUC6K2tMcM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ZrUC6K2tMcM?autoplay=1" title="Pacific Drive | Endless Expeditions Spring 2025 Update">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZrUC6K2tMcM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
A suspend run feature is being added in too, meaning if you need to quit out of the game because you realised you forgot to file your taxes or something, you can save mid-trip and go do that without sacrificing progress.
</p>
<p>
Oh, and there's more cosmetics you can unlock for your garage, more than an hours worth of new music to listen to on the radio while you're on the aforementioned endless expeditions (and anywhere else), and more lore too - Ironwood described this one as their "biggest" update yet, unsurprisingly.
</p>
<p>
You've not got long to wait for the update either, as it's due out in a little over a week's time on April 3rd.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>