<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 17:09:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Witcher 3 dev kept mum about a secret Blood and Wine quest epilogue for nearly a decade, until someone dug up some cut parents]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-witcher-3-dev-kept-mum-about-a-secret-blood-and-wine-quest-epilogue-for-nearly-a-decade-until-someone-dug-up-some-cut-parents</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-witcher-3-dev-kept-mum-about-a-secret-blood-and-wine-quest-epilogue-for-nearly-a-decade-until-someone-dug-up-some-cut-parents.1227117/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"It felt like an appropriate time!"</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>CD Projekt</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>There's no way I'm learning this for the first time after ten or so years of people exploring every nook and cranny of this game. That's the thought that went through my head when I spotted a tweet from <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-witcher-3-wild-hunt">Witcher 3</a> quest designer Philipp Weber earlier this month, revealing that one of the Blood and Wine DLC's quests had a secret cut epilogue.</p>
<p>I've played quite frankly far too much of the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> over the years, and I'd never heard of it. Of course, I'm just one bloke, and hardly an endless encyclopedia containing every single bit of trivia about a decade old game. That's when I raked through the internet, and couldn't find any mentions of the cut epilogue. Surely Weber hadn't kept this under his hat for about a decade, not even mentioning it when folks found what he'd called a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NZZ9p1HbeHs">"last secret"</a> by investigating the exact same quest. Er, yes, he had.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>First, I'll give you the context. The tweet from Weber that started off my wild goose chase came in response to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/witcher/comments/1l7uk19/fun_fact_vivienne_from_blood_and_wine_has_a_mom/">a Redditor</a> discovering cut models for Vivienne De Tabris' parents while digging around in TW3's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-witcher-3s-redkit-mod-tools-launch-may-21st-enabling-a-new-era-of-ambitious-overhauls">REDkit modding tools</a>. For a refresher, De Tabris is the cursed lady-in-waiting from the quest 'The Warble of a Smitten Knight'. It's the one where Gerry takes part in the knightly tournament and you're about to read some spoilers for it.</p>
<p>Cue Weber posting that "originally the Warble of a Smitten Knight used to have a flashback scene where we would see Vivienne's parents at the pond, being watched by a nymph who was envious of their love. She was the one who cursed their unborn baby, setting the whole story into motion.</p>
<p>"We used to have a secret quest epilogue in which you could find this nymph, but had to cut it due to scope," he continued, "However, we were able to reuse the nymph's model for the Lady of the Lake and add her to the quest for Aerondight. Originally, she was not even supposed to be seen."</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><p dir="ltr" lang="en">This post shows a nice example of how cut content can sometimes also be a good thing. We lost Vivienne's parents, but gained a Lady of the Lake. <br>Blood and Wine for the Witcher 3 was a huge expansion, but to make it we still had to cut some scope.<br>(1/3)<a href="https://t.co/XJz4bIFOr9">https://t.co/XJz4bIFOr9</a> <a href="https://t.co/28vfghTDpy">pic.twitter.com/28vfghTDpy</a></p>— Philipp Weber (@PhiWeber) <a href="https://twitter.com/PhiWeber/status/1932419237714526465?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 10, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>Very cool, but not just that. An answer to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vdKNtepEt0o">the debates</a> some Witcher fans have been having for years about <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/witcher/comments/1ekqcv0/witcher_3_the_identity_of_the_creature_who_cursed/">the identity of the nymph</a> that cursed Vivienne, with some having speculated that Hearts of Stone baddie Gaunter O'Dimm or one of Velen's crones could be behind it.</p>
<p>And not something that, as far as Weber knows, was public knowledge prior to him tweeting about it on a Tuesday more than nine years on from Blood and Wine's release in May 2016. "I never revealed the secret," the current Witcher 4 narrative director told me yesterday in response to my reaching out to him the day the tweet appeared in our lives, "but after the 10th anniversary and since people found the models already, it felt like an appropriate time!"</p>
<p>It goes to show you, TW3 really is a gift that just keeps on giving. I look forward to learning for the first time once ten more years have passed that Geralt's <a href="https://www.vg247.com/witcher-3-mod-geralt-centaur-horse-man">secretly a horse man</a> while he's saving the world from the Wild Hunt.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-witcher-3-dev-kept-mum-about-a-secret-blood-and-wine-quest-epilogue-for-nearly-a-decade-until-someone-dug-up-some-cut-parents]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[War Thunder player once again leaks classified military documents to win an argument]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/war-thunder-player-once-again-leaks-classified-military-documents-to-win-an-argument</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/war-thunder-player-once-again-leaks-classified-military-documents-to-win-an-argument.1227063/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Nerds. Nerds never change</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Hunter / Gaijin Entertainment</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>I know <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/war-thunder">War Thunder</a> only as 1) the vehicular combat sim Emily Gera somehow penned <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/british-invasion-war-thunder-adding-tanks-from-blighty">erotic poetry</a> about - "O succulent tank porn and its lusty armour"... Emily! What r u doing. STAHP - and 2) an unofficial information arm for the world's militaries, fuelled by the power of pedantry.</p>
<p>Back in July 2021, an actual tank commander <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/war-thunder-player-posts-classified-document-to-prove-tank-is-inaccurate">posted classified documents</a> for the Challenger 2 tank on the game's forums in order to prove that the game's representation of said tank is inaccurate. Now, somebody's done likewise for the pride of the United States Air Force: the British-made Harrier Jump Jet.</p><!--more-->
<p>In this latest blowout, a user uploaded a section from a US Naval Air Training and Operating Procedures Standardization manual for the AV-8B and TAV-8B Harrier airplanes. Said manual is not approved for public release and restricted to authorised US government bods and their contractors. Gaijin Entertainment's community manager has confirmed that the document breaches the forum's rules on such things, and has handed the user in question a temporary ban.</p>
<p>This and the previous leak of strictly need-to-know ballistic smut were spotted by the <a href="https://ukdefencejournal.org.uk/classified-data-once-again-leaked-on-war-thunder-forums/">UK Defence Journal</a>, an unaffiliated group of hardcore wonks, including former service members. The latter org say that War Thunder has been a source of leakage at least nine times in total, with previous victims including France's Leclerc, China's ZTZ-99, the Eurocopter Tiger, the Eurofighter Typhoon and the US F-16, F-15E and F-117 jets. In each case, they say, the leak happened because some nerd wanted to win an argument. This is how the world ends, isn't it.</p>
<p>The UK Defence Journal also cite an anonymous former RAF engineer who sizes up the latest breach as follows:</p>
<p>"This probably isn't the biggest leak ever, not at all. These kinds of manuals float around online, especially older ones. But that doesn't change the fact that if it's marked as controlled or restricted, platforms like War Thunder have no choice but to take action."</p>
<p>War Thunder isn't just in the military realism business. The developers are partial to the occasional Gatling gun burst of whimsy, such as <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/flying-saucers-take-over-war-thunder-for-april-fools-week">this weeklong flying saucer takeover</a>. No erotic tank designs for the moment, alas, though I guess there's always the modding scene. I am not going to look up the modding scene. I don't want to upset myself.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/war-thunder-player-once-again-leaks-classified-military-documents-to-win-an-argument]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SteamWorld Dig is free on Steam for the next couple of days? Ah, go on then]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steamworld-dig-is-free-on-steam-for-the-next-couple-of-days-ah-go-on-then</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steamworld-dig-is-free-on-steam-for-the-next-couple-of-days-ah-go-on-then.1227060/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>A couple other titles from the series are on sale too</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Image &amp; Form</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Chances are if you like the SteamWorld series that this won't matter very much to you, but for those of you (like me) who've never touched a single game, here's something neat: <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/steamworld-dig">SteamWorld Dig</a> is <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/252410/SteamWorld_Dig/">completely free on Steam right now</a>. That's free to keep forever, to be clear, not one of those free weekend types of deals. It's not free for that long, mind, only from now until June 26th, and I can't give you a specific time on that day, so if you're remotely interested you might as well just add it to your library.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
There doesn't seem to be a particular reason as to why it's going free, though there is also a sale on a couple other games in the series right now. Its sequel, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/steamworld-dig-2">SteamWorld Dig 2</a>, is <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/571310/SteamWorld_Dig_2/">currently 94% off</a>, which is as good as free, and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/steamworld-build">SteamWorld Build</a> is <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2134770/SteamWorld_Build/">currently 80% off</a>, with its Mechanized DLC and soundtrack also 35% off. You've got options essentially!
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="SteamWorld Dig - HD Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Fe-9OPMUz4w?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>SteamWorld Dig - HD Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Fe-9OPMUz4w?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Fe-9OPMUz4w?autoplay=1" title="SteamWorld Dig - HD Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fe-9OPMUz4w" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
Starting life on the Nintendo 3DS, SteamWorld Dig is a steampunky, western-themed <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-metroidvania-games">metroidvania</a> where you play as a robot called Rusty. There's a bit of a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/spelunky">Spelunky</a> element to it in that you can destroy blocks as you dig further and further, but there's a much bigger focus on exploration and resource gathering as opposed to the repeatable gameplay of the roguelike.
</p>
<p>
Whether we'll see much more of SteamWorld is the next big question though. Last year, Thunderful, the owner of the series, had <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/steamworld-creator-thunderful-announces-80-100-more-layoffs-as-part-of-second-round-of-restructuring">two sets</a> of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/thunderful-group-to-implement-restructuring-programme-affecting-around-20-percent-of-staff">layoffs</a>, putting the next entry in the series <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-next-steamworld-is-a-third-person-co-op-action-game">SteamWorld Headhunter</a> on hold for the time being. Doesn't exactly scream confidence.

</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steamworld-dig-is-free-on-steam-for-the-next-couple-of-days-ah-go-on-then]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft are reportedly laying off staff yet again, with "substantial cuts" at Xbox]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/microsoft-are-reportedly-set-to-lay-off-staff-yet-again-with-substantial-cuts-expected-at-xbox</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-are-reportedly-laying-off-staff-yet-again-with-substantial-cuts-at-xbox.1227012/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>It isn't clear yet how many people will be affected</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Microsoft</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Microsoft are reportedly gearing up to lay off more staff next week, in what would be the fourth round of major job cuts at Xbox in 18 months.</p>
<p>This is according to a report from <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-06-24/microsoft-plans-major-job-cuts-at-xbox-gaming-division">Bloomberg</a>, which says that Xbox managerial staff are "expecting substantial cuts" across Microsoft's gaming arm.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>"Not yet clear how many people, but it's expected to be big," reporter Jason Schreier wrote in a <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:2mkgbhbhqvappkkorf2bzyrp/post/3lseaakusns2s">Bluesky post</a> about the report. Bloomberg had <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-06-18/microsoft-planning-thousands-more-job-cuts-aimed-at-salespeople">previously reported</a> that Microsoft was set to cut thousands of jobs next week, with its salespeople being the main folks affected.</p>
<p>The site notes that Microsoft declined to comment on this latest report.</p>
<p>Microsoft has been laying off staff en masse on a depressingly regular basis over the past couple of years, with 10,000 workers being let go in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/microsofts-mass-layoffs-will-affect-starfield-halo-infinite-and-gears-of-war-developers">January 2023</a>, 1,900 in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/microsoft-have-aligned-on-the-best-opportunities-for-growth-by-firing-nearly-two-thousand-people">January 2024</a>, and 650 in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/microsoft-have-aligned-on-the-best-opportunities-for-growth-by-firing-nearly-two-thousand-people">September 2024</a>. They also let go of around 6,000 people across the company <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/microsoft-is-laying-off-even-more-of-its-staff-with-potentially-almost-7000-workers-at-risk">just last month</a>.</p>
<p>It's a frankly horrifying rate of contribution to the ever-deepening sea of layoffs that the games industry's been drowning in for the <a href="https://publish.obsidian.md/vg-layoffs/Archive/2025">past few years</a>. A lot of it has come following Microsoft <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/uk-regulator-provisionally-approves-microsofts-activision-blizzard-buyout-following-ubisoft-deal">acquiring Activision Blizzard</a> – it’s the usual cost-cutting after a massive investment. That said, Microsoft aren’t exactly struggling on the money-making front. They <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/04/30/microsoft-msft-q3-earnings-report-2025.html">reported net income</a> of $25.8 billion for their most recent financial quarter.</p>
<p>Bloomberg notes that this latest round of Microsoft layoffs would come just before the company rolls into a new financial year after June 30. Is it cool to chuck human beings out of their livelihoods just to make a spreadsheet look a bit tidier?? No, but sadly it keeps happening.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/microsoft-are-reportedly-set-to-lay-off-staff-yet-again-with-substantial-cuts-expected-at-xbox]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>