<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 15:44:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Finishing Skyblivion is a new dev diary series about the last leg of the Oblivion remake mod's run to release]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/finishing-skyblivion-is-a-new-dev-diary-series-about-the-last-leg-of-the-oblivion-remake-mods-run-to-release</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/finishing-skyblivion-is-a-new-dev-diary-series-about-the-last-leg-of-the-oblivion-remake-mods-run-to-release.1259703/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>By Talos, it's Patrick Stewart's bodyless head</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>The Skyblivion team.</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>With unofficial Oblivion remake <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/skyblivion">Skyblivion</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elder-scrolls-oblivion-in-skyrim-mod-still-on-track-for-a-2025-release">aiming to arrive this year</a>, one of its developers has kicked off a new dev diary series documenting the work they've been doing to get the massive <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-skyrim-mods">Skyrim mod</a> ready to emerge through the release gates.</p>
<p>While the folks behind Skyblivion certainly <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oblivion-in-skyrim-mod-skyblivion-still-looks-stunning-in-latest-development-update">haven't been shy</a> when it comes to regularly showing off their progress, it's always cool to see more of the blood, sweat, and tears that's going into finally getting such a gargantuan undertaking into players' hands. Then again, maybe I'm just partial to trippy glimpses at Uriel Septim's detached head floating in the development void.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Finishing Skyblivion is the name YouTuber and Skyblivion implementation lead Heavy Burns has given to this series they've just released the first episode of, and it certainly delivers on said trippy glimpses right off the bat. You see, among the various bits and bobs documented in the video is putting the final touches on exported NPC head models the mod's artists have developed, to ensure they look as detailed as the mod's character creator will allow.</p>
<p>Cue shots of severed heads with glowing purple eye holes sitting in the great grey unknown, ready to have their brows, beards, and trims retextured so they look a bit more presentable. Among the characters getting makeovers here are the likes of the Dark Brotherhood's Lucien Lachance and emperor Uriel Septim himself. The fact that the devs have made the latter look exactly like his bald acting man Patrick Stewart definitely adds to the weirdness of the floaty bodylessness.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Last Leg of Release | Finishing Skyblivion™ #1" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0-Egq51mJSA?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Last Leg of Release | Finishing Skyblivion™ #1</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0-Egq51mJSA?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/0-Egq51mJSA?autoplay=1" title="The Last Leg of Release | Finishing Skyblivion™ #1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0-Egq51mJSA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>There are also a couple of bits that'll likely be of interest to youm regardless of whether you get as much of a giggle from the bizarre visuals afforded by <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/skyblivion-devs-used-their-bethesda-visit-to-fight-the-good-fight-asking-todd-and-co-to-bring-back-skyrim-style-official-modding-tutorials">WIP mods</a> or games as I do. There are some nice looks at how Anvil and the Imperial City are shaping up, with Heavy Burns revealing that the latter's "the final part of the overworld that is yet to be finished" ahead of release.</p>
<p>There's also some statue installation in the realm of Oblivion you'll travel to as part of Boethiah's Daedric quest, and while it's still quite lava-filled, it's got plenty of nice touches to set it apart from Mehrunes Dagon's chambers of evil. Kerb-tweaking and sign-making are also covered, if you're interested in learning the ins-and-outs of some modding for yourself.</p>
<p>The YouTuber finishes up by teasing that Skyblivion's next full developer diary isn't too far away, with the project still looking for <a href="https://skyblivion.com/volunteer/">any volunteers</a> with the skills to help get it over the line. If you want an idea of what the mod's full release might look like, check out <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/skyblivion-project-lead-and-gog-chat-about-partnering-up-to-release-the-massive-elder-scrolls-mod-following-fallout-londons-troubled-success">our interview with project lead Kyle 'Rebelzize' Rebel from June</a>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/finishing-skyblivion-is-a-new-dev-diary-series-about-the-last-leg-of-the-oblivion-remake-mods-run-to-release]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Major payment firm behind Itch adult game cull say they themselves face "restrictions" from another banking firm]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/major-payment-firm-behind-itch-adult-game-cull-say-they-themselves-face-restrictions-from-another-banking-firm</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/major-payment-firm-behind-itch-adult-game-cull-say-they-themselves-face-restrictions-from-another-banking-firm.1259700/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Itch re-index free NSFW games, still looking for new partner</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Emma Kidwell / Rock Paper Shotgun</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
It's time for another bulletin from the exciting world of desexindexification. Itch.io have re-listed a bunch of free adult-themed games that were taken down as part of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/itchio-apologise-for-frustration-and-confusion-after-delisting-thousands-of-nsfw-projects">a recent massive cull of supposedly licentious materials</a> under pressure from payment processors. Itch are still, however, working out whether and how to restore paid NSFW projects that were removed from public channels as part of their efforts to stop the payment companies suspending store purchases in general. 
</p>
<p>
In a further mild twist, one of the firms behind Itch.io's delistings, Stripe, have now informed the site that they themselves are acting under pressure from one of their own banking partners, without naming names. They'd like "to support adult content in the future". Nonetheless, Itch are still looking for new payment partners who are <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/itchio-are-seeking-out-new-payment-processors-who-are-more-comfortable-with-adult-material">happier to process this kind of material</a>.
</p><!--more-->
<p>
Itch.io's owner, Leaf Corcoran, announced the return of free NSFW projects to search results, browse pages and recommendations in <a href="https://itch.io/t/5149036/reindexing-adult-nsfw-content">a blog post today</a>.
</p>
<p>
To be eligible for re-indexing, your game must have the "no payments" option checked under the "pricing" section of your project's editing page on your dashboard. Leaf cautions that any "individually priced files" on that game will become free in the process, as Itch doesn't currently support the ability to have "owners only" stuff on a page configured to be fully free. The site's management are looking at adding new developer dashboard options to address this.
</p>
<p>
As for the paid games, Leaf writes that "we are still in ongoing discussions with payment processors and will be re-introducing paid content slowly to ensure we can confidently support the widest range of creators in the long term."
</p>
<p>
According to Leaf, Itch have had some relatively positive conversations lately with Stripe, a $91 billion corporation and one of the world's largest privately owned financial tech companies. The bad news is that Stripe have told Itch.io that they can no longer support payments for any "content designed for sexual gratification", perhaps the baggiest of recent efforts to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/itch-post-new-list-of-banned-nsfw-content-that-would-rule-out-certain-kojima-games-plus-goty-2024-mouthwashing">pin down the kind of adult content the payment processors object to</a>. They have also, however, passed along the below message to Itch.io's users:
</p>
<blockquote><p>
Stripe is currently unable to support sexually explicit content due to restrictions placed on them by their banking partners, despite card networks generally supporting adult content (with the appropriate registrations). Stripe has indicated that they hope to be able to support adult content in the future.
</p></blockquote>
<p>
Itch are still looking for other partners to handle payments for "adult NSFW content". Leaf defines the latter as follows: </p>
<blockquote><p>pages that have both the "Contains sensitive material" option checked and a tag suggesting adult content (e.g., "porn," "mature," "lewd," "erotic," "hentai," "fetish"). 
</p></blockquote>
<p>
Regarding the recent paid game takedowns, Leaf says that "now that we have a more specific definition of what Stripe won't process, we may review that initial list for potential re-introduction", but that the long-term plan remains "to implement one or more new processors to avoid putting the platform at risk".
</p>
<p>Itch.io are not, of course, the only PC storefront to have taken an axe to their catalogue recently. Valve have also <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valve-change-steams-rules-to-let-banks-and-credit-card-firms-prohibit-certain-kinds-of-adult-only-content">changed their policies</a> to give payment processors, banks and internet service providers more say over what constitutes unacceptable adult material on Steam. They've <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valve-are-now-removing-a-bunch-of-sex-games-from-steam-to-keep-banks-and-card-companies-happy">delisted or removed some games as a consequence</a>, though nowhere near as many as Itch. You can read more about that and the pressure group who've claimed overall responsibility for the cull <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/anti-porn-group-who-tried-to-ban-gta-5-claim-credit-for-steams-sex-game-crackdown">here</a>.</p>
<p>I'm currently talking to some economists to build up more of a picture of the financial machinations that undergird this moral panic. I'll hopefully have more for you on that front next week. In the meantime, why not learn how to put on a condom in Emma Kidwell's <a href="https://emmkid.itch.io/well-this-is-awkward">Well This Is Awkward</a>, pictured above.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/major-payment-firm-behind-itch-adult-game-cull-say-they-themselves-face-restrictions-from-another-banking-firm]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>