<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:06:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grimy 90s GTA homage Vivat Slovakia leaves early access in April]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grimy-90s-gta-homage-vivat-slovakia-leaves-early-access-in-april</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grimy-90s-gta-homage-vivat-slovakia-leaves-early-access-in-april.1131384/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grimy-90s-gta-homage-vivat-slovakia-leaves-early-access-in-april<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
I confess, I'm writing up the 1.0 release date for grubby open world game Vivat Slovakia less because I'm tantalised by the carboot sale <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gta-6-everything-we-know">GTA 6</a> aesthetic, than because the latest trailer ends with main character Trotter squatting weirdly on a coffee table. He perches there with track-suited elbows akimbo, smiling faintly. Mockingly. 
</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Vivat Slovakia - Official Release Date Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1GjDyjsZ78g?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Vivat Slovakia - Official Release Date Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1GjDyjsZ78g?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/1GjDyjsZ78g?autoplay=1" title="Vivat Slovakia - Official Release Date Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1GjDyjsZ78g" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
Trotter aside, the table sustains various piles of money and a bottle of what could be Jack Daniels. The room containing Trotter and the table also contains two high-collared chairs, an expansive, dimpled sofa, and some well-fitted bookcases. There is a dog in one of the chairs, while the sofa is being used to prop up some guns. Sunlight streams through the conservatory windows behind, lending the whole scene the quality of an angelic visitation.
</p>
<p>
What to make of this? Why is Trotter squatting on a table? His amused rictus contains no answer. Nor is there any catharsis to be found on the Steam page, which characterises him as an undercover cop and taxi driver, making his way through a 10 km² city map based on post-Communist 1990s Slovakia. I feel the need to workshop this bizarre spectacle before I can say anything further about the game. There's nothing for it - I'm going to have to write a quick listicle.
</p>
<h3>Seven reasons Trotter is squatting on that coffee table</h3>
<p>
1. Trotter is squatting on the table simply to free up a chair for his dog. He is doing this because he loves his dog like a child, and considers it a crime against Very Good Boys to ask the beast to sleep on the floor. Still, that doesn't explain the other, apparently vacant chair and the sofa.
</p>
<p>
2. The dog is Trotter's landlord, who has cruelly forbidden Trotter from sitting on people furniture. What more dastardly an archnemesis for "a city that reflects the tumult of an era caught between communism and capitalism"? You can't quite see it in the video, but the dog is definitely smoking a cigar.
</p>
<p>
3. Trotter has just been standing on the coffee table to change a light bulb. We catch him at the precise moment of his triumph, settling back on his haunches in the blissful knowledge that he and his dog will be able to comfortably read all the books they please, when the sun goes down. Not for them the terrifying oblivion of Night.
</p>
<p>
4. Trotter fears you are plotting to take his money. Like a mother hen, he has flown screeching to the table and planted himself defensively atop his riches, ready to claw and peck your eyes out. In a few seconds he is going to seal the deal by urinating explosively.  
</p>
<p>
5. Trotter thinks the floor is lava.</p>
<p>
6. Tables are in danger of growing stale, and Trotter is taking them to strange new places. We are witnessing the birth of <em>tablepunk</em>. 
</p>
<p>
7. Due to a fluke mixture of deprivation and bad luck, this is literally the first time Trotter has ever encountered a coffee table, and the sheer audacity of the concept has scrambled his brain. He's absolutely tripping balls over here. His entire cognitive framework is rebooting before our eyes. His soul is molting like caterpillar.
</p>
<p>
It's been a long day, in case you couldn't tell, and I'm too exhausted by these intrigues to say anything further about Vivat Slovakia, which launches out of early access on 17th April. Nic <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-no-longer-care-about-grand-theft-auto-6-for-i-have-the-open-world-of-vivat-slovakia">did a write-up last year</a> and was ambivalent, though he liked the radio stations. You can read more on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2132690/Vivat_Slovakia/">Steam</a>.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Celeste composer shares a snippet of Earthblade's soundtrack, and now I'm even more gutted it was cancelled]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/celeste-composer-shares-a-snippet-of-earthblades-soundtrack-and-now-im-even-more-gutted-it-was-cancelled</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/celeste-composer-shares-a-snippet-of-earthblades-soundtrack-and-now-im-even-more-gutted-it-was-cancelled.1131246/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/celeste-composer-shares-a-snippet-of-earthblades-soundtrack-and-now-im-even-more-gutted-it-was-cancelled<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/earthblade_jWzDDpB.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Extremely OK Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
I'm not all that big on ranking games, truth be told - why would I want to catalogue a piece of art that way? But seeing as you have me at gunpoint (just pretend for me), I'll admit I'd probably put <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/celeste">Celeste</a> in my top five. The platforming is tighter than any Mario entry, the art and soundtrack are stellar, and the story really hits home for me too.</p>
<p>You can imagine how excited I was when <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/earthblade">Earthblade</a>, the follow-up from developer Extremely OK Games, was <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/celeste-devs-announce-gorgeous-new-platformer-earthblade">announced</a>, and how upset I was when it was <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/celeste-devs-cancel-lush-platformer-earthblade-to-focus-on-smaller-scale-projects">cancelled a couple months back</a>. Still, we've been treated to a small taste of what the game might have been like in the form of a <a href="https://radicaldreamland.bandcamp.com/album/earthblade-across-the-bounds-of-fate">mini-album with a select set of tracks from composer Lena Raine</a>.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
Right off the bat you'll hear Raine's signature, synthy sound. Some tracks from the album are reminiscent of Celeste's score, while others feel completely fresh and unique. It definitely feels like it's going for a fantasy role-playing vibe - I’d love to know how this would have paired with the cancelled game’s action-platforming.
</p>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><p>
Raine explains over on the album's Bandcamp page that Earthblade "Across the Bounds of Fate" is more concept album than soundtrack. "The music I wrote for the game is highly dynamic, in the tradition of what I wrote for Celeste," she wrote. "I took it many steps beyond, in ways that temporally-constrained pieces of music can’t really do justice. But I did my best to arrange them into the emotional arc of their progression, much like I would for any soundtrack release."
</p>
<p>
Apparently Raine took a lot of inspiration from older animation and film, like the "huge Yamaha synths" of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/blade-runner">Blade Runner</a> composer Vangelis, as well as the "weird textures and combination of old synths &amp; live strings of Joe Hisaishi’s score for Nausicaä of the Valley of the Wind," and the "haunting saxophone and percussive textures of Yoko Kanno’s work on Cowboy Bebop &amp; Ghost in the Shell Stand Alone Complex." I think that Kanno influence can really be heard in particular on the sixth track, Poison in the Roots.
</p>
<p>
It's always quite gutting when a game gets cancelled, but I'm thankful to be able to hear a little bit of Earthblade's soundscape, especially given that 50% of the album's sales will be donated to <a href="https://translifeline.org/about/">Trans Lifeline</a>. Get on it!

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>