<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 18:48:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hit city-builder Manor Lords has been updated with two new maps and a heap of changes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hit-city-builder-manor-lords-has-been-updated-with-two-new-maps-and-a-heap-of-changes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hit-city-builder-manor-lords-has-been-updated-with-two-new-maps-and-a-heap-of-changes.1079235/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hit-city-builder-manor-lords-has-been-updated-with-two-new-maps-and-a-heap-of-changes<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/3_nvpccwv.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Hooded Horse</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Slavic Magic and Hooded Horse have released a new <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/manor-lords-tips-and-tricks">Manor Lords</a> update, adding a couple of maps, the ability to construct bridges, and a bevy of smaller features to an <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/manor-lords-early-access-review">already quite robust</a> medieval city builder. 
</p><!--more-->
<p>
The update rolls together two beta patches into one, gargantuan changelog. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/manor-lords-is-getting-new-maps-building-upgrades-and-reworks-for-the-marketplace-and-ale-distribution">Teased last November</a>, the new maps are High Peaks and Winding River. The latter is obviously where the bridge-building mechanic - an extension of the existing road tool - gets its chance to shine. 
</p>
<p>
Bridge-building is, I imagine, also helped along by some tweaks to the game's cliff geography. <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1363080/view/534338967351329253?l=english">Posting on Steam</a>, lead developer Greg Styczeń writes that it should be clearer which areas are buildable or traversable, thanks to a zigzag pattern that appears during build mode. He's also tweaked the pathfinding around cliffs, and got rid of a problem where gaps would appear between landscape components and cliffs when you zoom out.
</p>
<p>
Other major changes include worker restrictions for stalls. As of this patching, only storage building workers can set up marketplace stalls, because "there was too much confusion about who owned what and works where, and it was very difficult for players to understand, for instance, that a gravedigger could have a food stall," the developer goes on. Sorry gravediggers, but you'll have to flog your homegrown produce by other means. The number of goods a marketplace can supply is also now capped by the number of stalls (and therefore, assigned storage buildings), with capacity indicated on the market panel.
</p>
<p>
Styczeń has also introduced a stone well upgrade for wells, along with level two taverns, while changing how ale and water are distributed from wells and taverns. 
</p>
<p>
This is but the tip of the update's acrid compost heap. By all means click that Steam link and fill your horrified eyes with bulletpoints. Sometimes when I read an overly long changelog, I can feel myself... <em>changelogging in turn</em>. My brain starts to feel like a village marketplace, crowded with boisterous oxen and sorrowful gravediggers, hopelessly offering handfuls of turnips to anybody who will take them.
</p><p>
<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/manor-lords">Manor Lords</a> launched in April last year, and was due to remain in early access for approximately one year. Using such braincells as I have left that aren't now wholly given over to talk of bowyers, burgage plots and butchery, I deduce from this that it might leave early access in April 2025. If you'd like to learn more about how publishers Hooded Horse manage their early access projects, check out our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-manor-lords-publisher-thinks-we-should-all-reject-the-opportunistic-and-predatory-quest-for-a-viral-hit">interview with one of the company's founders</a>.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Era One is an enveloping space RTS from Homeworld modders that lets you clip together your own Mothership]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/era-one-is-an-enveloping-space-rts-from-homeworld-modders-that-lets-you-clip-together-your-own-mothership</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/era-one-is-an-enveloping-space-rts-from-homeworld-modders-that-lets-you-clip-together-your-own-mothership.1079184/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/era-one-is-an-enveloping-space-rts-from-homeworld-modders-that-lets-you-clip-together-your-own-mothership<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Also has space cities and mutants</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_DiN0x00.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Team Complex</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>If it seems like only last week that I was complaining there were too many gigantic space games, that's because <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/spacecraft-is-aiming-for-the-gap-between-starfield-satisfactory-and-eve-online">it was only last week</a>. Since then, I have written about <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/kerbal-space-program-2">Kerbal Space Program 2</a> and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/space-engineers">Space Engineers</a> 2, because I am nothing if not a creature of contradictions. Now, here I am writing about Era One. In my defence, it's all your fault. Specifically, it's TheGreatOneSea's fault. They left a comment about Era One on our list of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/our-50-most-anticipated-pc-games-of-2025">most-anticipated 2025 games</a>, and reader, I Googled.</p> <!--more-->
<p>It turns out that Era One is Homeworld, but you can clip together your own fleets like LEGO models. "It's Homeworld, but" is a formulation that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/nebulous-fleet-command">unfailingly gets my hyperdrive humming</a>, and in this case, the developers are the modding team behind celebrated <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/homeworld-2">Homeworld 2</a> mod the Complex. They also helped Gearbox with Homeworld Remastered. Yes, I still have space in my life for this space sim. But it's the last one, you hear? None of you better recommend anything else in the comments. I'm serious. I will cry.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Era One - First Look" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aT7Rdabpa-s?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Era One - First Look</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aT7Rdabpa-s?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/aT7Rdabpa-s?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aT7Rdabpa-s" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>What excites me about Era One is actually the sound design. There's a particular grade of radio chatter I associate with Homeworld, a special blend of tinniness and white noise that makes even the most routine NPC dialogue sound a little sinister, a little inhuman. Era One very much has that. It also has, oh, so many ship modules. Here's some blurb to wash down that trailer.</p>
<blockquote><p>"Era One is an innovative space-themed game that empowers players to build their own fleet from scratch. Starting with a primary core ship or base, you'll have the freedom to construct a diverse range of capital ships, stations, floating bases, and even cities. This is made possible through the assembly of modules (referred to as cubes or bricks) that, when combined in a 3D space, give shape and function to your ship or base. </p>
<p>"Various types of modules will be available, each serving a specific purpose. For instance, basic modules will focus on structural integrity and customization, offering numerous variants that may expand in the future. Dedicated modules will handle resource loading, unloading, storage, and energy production. Hangar modules will enable the creation of fighters, cruisers, battleships, while other modules will manage your population, offensive and defensive weaponry, and subsystems." </p></blockquote>
<p>The developers classify Era One as "a spaceship builder and survival game set in an RTS environment". If you're fretting that it all sounds too sandboxy, there's a story component as well, though it's not clear from <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2509200/ERA_ONE/">the Steam page</a> how elaborate the campaign options will be. </p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Era One - Development Update 5" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/x5wvsx79bVQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Era One - Development Update 5</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/x5wvsx79bVQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/x5wvsx79bVQ?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x5wvsx79bVQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>"From the ashes of a shattered universe, a young woman's quest for salvation sparks a journey of intrigue, danger, and discovery," explains the blurb. The short version is that Earth's resources have been depleted, and humans are now scattered across the solar system, warring over scraps. Genetic modification is rife, political upheaval abounds, and many people now live in space cities called "Navi Mondo". Somebody called Alya De Shars has stolen a power source and is embarked on a secret mission to find "a fresh beginning beyond the solar system". Honestly, I find the worldbuilding a bit of an undecided stew, but the premise of a fateful voyage is very Homeworldy.</p>
<p>Era One launches on 20th February. If you'd rather not build your own ships, and you like hiding behind planets, you might prefer to keep an eye on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1280190/Falling_Frontier/">Falling Frontier</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>