<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:56:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam Replay says 2025 releases accounted for 14% of the time we've collectively spent Steamilygamening this year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-replay-says-2025-releases-accounted-for-14-of-the-time-weve-collectively-spent-steamilygamening-this-year</link>
            <guid>1386004</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Also, I regret to inform you that I've failed to amass a daily playing streak of exactly 69 (nice) days two years running</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/team-fortress-2-summer-update-and-valve-open-letter-matchmaking-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/team-fortress-2-summer-update-and-valve-open-letter-matchmaking-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/team-fortress-2-summer-update-and-valve-open-letter-matchmaking-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/team-fortress-2-summer-update-and-valve-open-letter-matchmaking-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/team-fortress-2-summer-update-and-valve-open-letter-matchmaking-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/team-fortress-2-summer-update-and-valve-open-letter-matchmaking-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/team-fortress-2-summer-update-and-valve-open-letter-matchmaking-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/team-fortress-2-summer-update-and-valve-open-letter-matchmaking-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/team-fortress-2-summer-update-and-valve-open-letter-matchmaking-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Valve</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Steam Replay, Valve's yearly roundup of where all of the hours spent playing games in the Steamy place have gone, has emerged from its hidey-hole yet again. 2025's edition is out now - you've likely already seen it if you've hopped into Steam since yesterday afternoon. Amid all the bits telling you that you've spent 1000 hours playing <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/uma-musume-pretty-derby">Umamusume: Pretty Derby</a> thus far, the annual report's dished out some fresh stats about how old the games everyone across the platform's user base has been playing this year are.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>To get a bit navel gazey for a second, these <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/replay/">Replays</a> usually stand more than anything to remind me how much doing this job generally warps the game playing habits of myself and my peers away from the norm. For instance, 28% of my personal playtime this year was spent on games which came out in 2025, a decent chunk more than the worldwide average of 14% across the entirety of the Steamaverse. For context, that's also with some new releases I've <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-outer-worlds-2-review">spent a lot of time with</a> this year - <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-outer-worlds-2">The Outer Worlds 2</a> chief among them - not having been counted as part of that total due to circumstance dictating I didn't put my hours into them via my personal Steam account.</p>
<p>That 14% figure across all Steam users is only down a single percentage point from last year's total of 15%, with 2023 and 2022's figures sitting at 9% and 17% respectively. So, things very much look to have settled into a mid-teens ball park. The game playage this year's rounded out by 44% of our collective time being dedicated to games which have been out for one to seven years and 40% being dedicated to games eight years or older.</p>
<p>Those last two also generally stack up pretty similarly to previous years, though there was a pretty weird flip-flop in terms of the largest majority from 64% of the older lot to 52% in favour of the one-to-seven crowd from 2022 to 2023. Sadly, the data doesn't go back any further than that, let alone to pre-2008 so we could see what these numbers looked like prior to the first of the approximately ten million financial belt-tightenings we've all lived through since that point.</p><p>Anyway, as a palette cleanser following that maths, here's a very tragic personal factoid. Last year, I managed a longest streak of 69 consecutive days firing up a game on Steam. It was totally by accident that this ended up being the sex number, I swear. This year, I regret to inform you that my longest streak ran to 97 days, which - aside from inferring a slightly more dire state in terms of my ability to drag myself away from my keyboard - is not a funny number.</p>
<p>And what is life if you're not accidentally racking up funny numbers whenever possible?</p>

        </div>

      </article>




        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-replay-says-2025-releases-accounted-for-14-of-the-time-weve-collectively-spent-steamilygamening-this-year]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We may have glimpsed Silksong's Sea of Sorrow expansion in a six-year-old trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/we-may-have-glimpsed-silksongs-sea-of-sorrow-expansion-in-a-six-year-old-trailer</link>
            <guid>1385938</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hollow-knight-silksong-expansion-sea-of-sorrow-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hollow-knight-silksong-expansion-sea-of-sorrow-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hollow-knight-silksong-expansion-sea-of-sorrow-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hollow-knight-silksong-expansion-sea-of-sorrow-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hollow-knight-silksong-expansion-sea-of-sorrow-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hollow-knight-silksong-expansion-sea-of-sorrow-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hollow-knight-silksong-expansion-sea-of-sorrow-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hollow-knight-silksong-expansion-sea-of-sorrow-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hollow-knight-silksong-expansion-sea-of-sorrow-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Team Cherry</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>There won’t be any prizes for correctly guessing that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hollow-knight-silksong-walkthrough">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a>’s first expansion, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hollow-knight-silksongs-first-big-expansion-sea-of-sorrow-flows-into-our-lives-for-free-next-year">Sea of Sorrow</a>, will involve a) a sea and b) some kind of adverse emotion. But there is mounting evidence that the watery DLC will restore, or at be inspired by, places and bugs that developers Team Cherry had previously left on Silksong’s cutting room floor – yet had been shown in in marketing for the main game as far back as 2019.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>All credit for this goes to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kD0EZHwb9Zo">YouTube’s Hollow Knight loremaster Mossbag</a>, along with the loveable sickos that maintain the (non-Fextralife) <a href="https://hollowknight.wiki/w/Cut_Content_(Silksong)">Hollow Knight wiki</a>. Mossbag’s rain-lashed compass points towards Sea of Sorrows being at least partially based on <a href="https://hollowknight.wiki/w/Cut_Content_(Silksong)/Areas">Pharloom Bay</a>, which according to early development materials, would have been plopped at the far east of Silksong’s map, next to (eurghh) Bilewater. Pharloom Bay never made it into the game that finally released in September this year, but there is a distinctly nautical-lookin’ region shown at 1:13 in Silksong’s original reveal trailer, covered in barnacles and housing at least one conch-dwelling NPC:</p>
<figure><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pFAknD_9U7c">
</a>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pFAknD_9U7c" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>

<p>That area was never found in-game either, so it’s a pretty safe bet this was meant to be Pharloom Bay. And, as Mossbag notes, that old footage also shows the area being lit by distinct scythe-shaped bell lamps of an almost identical design to the lashed structures we see in the very first shot of Sea of Sorrow’s own teaser.</p><figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Hollow Knight: Silksong - Sea of Sorrow Teaser" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qDFEeeLy6ws?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Hollow Knight: Silksong - Sea of Sorrow Teaser</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qDFEeeLy6ws?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/qDFEeeLy6ws?autoplay=1" title="Hollow Knight: Silksong - Sea of Sorrow Teaser">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qDFEeeLy6ws" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>Pharloom Bay might not be the only resurrected concept, either. The mysterious, lightning-struck glass chamber shown halfway through the Sea of Sorrow trailer looks an awful lot like the Lifeblood Spire, another cut area that’s been documented since before Silksong’s release. Specifically, by helpful Australians, who <a href="https://x.com/arfa2706/status/2000736787040203098">snapped photos</a> of a Hollow Knight exhibit at Melbourne’s ACMI (Australian Centre for the Moving Image) museum in Melbourne. That one never made it into a trailer so, y’know, cheers mates.</p>
<p>I absolutely don’t want to sound like I’m disdaining the practice of developers recycling ideas for DLC or expansions. If anything, it’s quite cool to see individual concepts float in and out of the gamesmaking process, and to wonder – aloud, sometimes – how they might’ve changed in the meantime. Silksong itself has another interesting example of this, which I’ll spell out if you don’t mind light spoilers. See the coral-coated, seemingly underwater environment at 0:23 in the reveal trailer? Seasoned skongers will know that colourful design only accounts for a tiny, optional segment of the game’s <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hollow-knight-silksong-act-3">infamously tricky final act</a>, but paying attention to lore snippets will reveal that Team Cherry reworked the wider region into the Sands of Karak: the same coral kingdom hinted at in the earlier trailer, but lost to time, dried out, and claimed by the desert.</p>
<p>Whether or not Pharloom Bay has been as drastically rejigged, Sea of Sorrow is currently aiming for release in 2026. Like the original <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hollow-knight">Hollow Knight</a>’s expansions, it’ll be free to owners of the base game.</p>
</div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/we-may-have-glimpsed-silksongs-sea-of-sorrow-expansion-in-a-six-year-old-trailer]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>