<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 10:18:51 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AMD’s Radeon RX 9060 XT wants to be the cheapest 16GB GPU on the market]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amds-radeon-rx-9060-xt-wants-to-be-the-cheapest-16gb-gpu-on-the-market</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amd%E2%80%99s-radeon-rx-9060-xt-wants-to-be-the-cheapest-16gb-gpu-on-the-market.1194834/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amds-radeon-rx-9060-xt-wants-to-be-the-cheapest-16gb-gpu-on-the-market<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>$349 for an RTX 5060 Ti-botherer</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>AMD</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>AMD have rocked up to this year’s Computex tech conference with a <a href="https://ir.amd.com/news-events/press-releases/detail/1253/amd-introduces-new-radeon-graphics-cards-and-ryzen-threadripper-processors-at-computex-2025">handful of new Ryzen Threadripper</a> CPUs (not interested) and confirmation of a long-rumoured <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-graphics-card">graphics card</a>, the Radeon RX 9060 XT (cautiously interested). It’s a true mid-ranger in the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/nvidia-geforce-rtx-5060-ti-16gb-review">RTX 5060 Ti</a> vein, and like its Nvidia rival, will launch with both 8GB and 16GB versions – the latter of which will cost $349, the lowest MSRP of any current-gen 16GB gaming GPU, upon its release in June.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Whether or not that pricing holds remains to be seen; AMD’s higher-end <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-amd-radeon-rx-9070-series-prices-look-good-assuming-they-hold">RX 9070</a> GPUs have been famously difficult to find at their advertised starting price, and while the RTX 5060 Ti 16GB was supposed to launch from $379, in practice you’d be lucky to find one below $420. Although, if <em>everyone's</em> GPUs are inflated, then the cheapest one should still remain the cheapest? In theory?</p>
<p>Either way, there are other encouraging signs for the 16GB RX 9060 XT, even if its $299 8GB edition sounds like a bit of a non-starter. It’s the first of AMD’s mid-range cards, for example, to support PCIe 5.0 x16 bandwidth, meaning it will take better advantage of modern motherboard slots than previous Radeons (like the dud <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amd-radeon-rx-7600-review">RX 7600</a>). Performance-wise, AMD say it’s 6% faster on average than the 8GB RTX 5060 Ti at 1440p, though in a bit of graphs-bodging that Nvidia themselves would be proud of... that’s only the 8GB RTX 5060 Ti. Presumably the 16GB model puts up a better fight.</p>
<p>You do get the same FSR 4 upscaling compatibility as the RX 9070 family, though, so Nvidia’s <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/nvidia-dlss-4-explained">DLSS 4</a> advantage might not weigh so heavily. The RX 9060 XT also happens to be launching into what feels like a period of all-time-low goodwill towards the green team, who are currently mired in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/only-press-who-previewed-the-rtx-5060-under-nvidias-test-conditions-are-getting-review-drivers-reports-claim">accusations of giving preferential access to friendly media</a> and attempting to leverage undue pressure on independent review processes.</p>
<p>That won’t make the RX 9060 XT a better graphics card, obviously. But more VRAM, upgraded PCIe tech, and a lower price just might. We’ll find out next month, and I’ll update this story with UK pricing if I can get it.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>