<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 11:13:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valheim developers celebrate the game's fifth anniversary with flower garlands, sweetbread, and Steam Deck optimisations]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valheim-developers-celebrate-the-games-fifth-anniversary-with-flower-garlands-sweetbread-and-steam-deck-optimisations</link>
            <guid>1423666</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Come for the patch notes, stay for the gift ideas</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valheim-fifth-anniversary.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valheim-fifth-anniversary.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valheim-fifth-anniversary.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valheim-fifth-anniversary.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valheim-fifth-anniversary.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valheim-fifth-anniversary.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valheim-fifth-anniversary.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valheim-fifth-anniversary.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valheim-fifth-anniversary.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Coffee Stain Publishing / Iron Gate</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>I'm going to a toddler's birthday party on Saturday and I have it on good authority from Alva's dad that there will be trays of sandwiches and a couple of cakes from M&amp;S. There is no booze provided. I'm not sure if that's because there should be no booze consumed at a two-year-old's birthday, or only that we should bring our own. I guess I'll find out for sure if they frisk on the door. However, if <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/valheim">Valheim</a>'s latest anniversary update is anything to go by, I am now looking forward to Alva's fifth birthday.</p>
<p>To mark five years in Early Access, developer Iron Gate have released an anniversary patch that is a damn sight better than the prospect of watching a sad looking Colin the Caterpillar cake getting pawed at by hungry toddlers. There are flower garlands, mysterious axe heads, and a steady 60 fps on Steam Deck performance mode. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/shorts/d6gBu2Zd7Bc">Who doesn't want mysterious blades at a birthday party?</a></p>
<!--more-->
<p>While it may not be a name you would put on a banner, <a href="https://www.valheim.com/news/five-years-of-valheim-/">patch 0.221.10</a> offers a little something to both the players who love the idea of a party and those who would rather stay home.</p>
<p>For the partiers, there are Fey Lights to string up around your settlement, sweetbreads to bake and serve, and flower garlands to wear as you use the new Vibe and LoveYou emotes. If you want to keep things lowkey, you may just want to wear the celebratory cap.</p><p>On the midpoint of the partier to non-partier, you will find a pair of new materials – the mysterious axe head and the curious axehead. You'll need both if you want to craft Early Axes, a new dual-wielded axe you can attain much earlier than the Berserkir Axes.</p>
<p>Then on the non-partier end of the scale you will find a stack of quality of life changes. Engine optimisations to improve performance, fixes to reduce armour stands' exorbitant CPU usage, a less memory intensive minimap.</p>
<p>All those performance improvements have had a knock on effect for the Steam Deck's performance mode, which now sees Valheim reaching the all-important 60 fps.</p>
<p>What I really appreciate about this patch is not the improvements it's making the Early Access Viking simulation, but the gift ideas that it's given me for Alva's fifth birthday party. A nice cap and a pair of axe heads are easy enough to come by. And it saves me trying to work out which Famous Five books she's already read.</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valheim-developers-celebrate-the-games-fifth-anniversary-with-flower-garlands-sweetbread-and-steam-deck-optimisations]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["This shouldn’t have happened": GOG reportedly claim sale banner made with "Al tools" ended up on store by mistake]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-shouldnt-have-happened-gog-reportedly-claim-sale-banner-made-with-al-tools-ended-up-on-store-by-mistake</link>
            <guid>1423642</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"Some experiments are successful, and some (like this banner) are not"</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gog-payment-processor.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gog-payment-processor.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gog-payment-processor.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gog-payment-processor.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gog-payment-processor.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gog-payment-processor.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gog-payment-processor.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gog-payment-processor.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gog-payment-processor.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>GOG</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>After being <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gog-accused-of-using-ai-generated-art-to-promote-sale-as-job-listing-indicates-theyre-keen-to-adopt-ai-assisted-development-tools">accused last week</a> of using AI-generated artwork to promote their store's new year sale, retro game sellers GOG have reportedly addressed the issue in a private Discord server for paying supporters. According to this fresh response from a GOG staffer, the banner was made "with the help of Al tools" and was "mistakenly allowed" to be pushed live on the storefront.</p>
<!--more-->
<p><a href="https://kotaku.com/gog-ai-art-banner-ad-confirms-discord-message-small-team-slop-2000665056">Kotaku</a> report having been sent a screenshot of this response posted in a message to GOG's official Patron Discord server by an employee with the handle Arthur Slay. Beginning with Slay making clear that they're addressing the New Year Sale banner, their message as shared by Kotaku continues as follows:</p>
<blockquote>First of all, regarding the quality of the asset: This banner was a work-in-progress asset that we mistakenly allowed to be displayed on the storefront. This shouldn’t have happened. We failed on at least two levels: Quality-control of the asset that landed on the front page, and then reacting quickly enough when we noticed the error. Second, I want to confirm that this WIP asset was indeed made with the help of Al tools. We hear your disappointment with the use of this technology, and see that it’s a sensitive topic for many of you.</blockquote>
<p>Slay then reportedly went on to discuss GOG's general approach to the use of AI, emphasising that the game sellers "don’t have the infinite resources of the industry giants" and that they "experiment with tools that can allow us to do more with the limited hands we have" as part of their preservation efforts. "We’ve been testing different technologies since our beginnings," the staffer added. "Some experiments are successful, and some (like this banner) are not. Exploring various tech gives us the reach of a much larger team, so we never have to settle for doing less."</p><p>Approached for comment on the sale banner last week, GOG told RPS they were unable to "comment publicly on our internal processes or tools". I've reached out to the company for a second time in light of this Discord message.</p>
<p>The Polish storefront - noted for revamping and selling a bunch of classic games - changed ownership in late 2025, with Witcher developers CD Projekt opting to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gogs-new-owner-will-stick-to-its-revamped-classic-and-zero-drm-guns-but-does-think-lessons-lie-in-steams-overstuffed-embrace">sell to original GOG co-founder Michał Kiciński</a> in a deal worth about £18.6 million. So far, Kiciński's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gogs-new-owner-will-stick-to-its-revamped-classic-and-zero-drm-guns-but-does-think-lessons-lie-in-steams-overstuffed-embrace">suggested the plan for the store going forwards</a> is to remain focused on preservation and DRM-less games.</p>

        </div>

      </article>




        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-shouldnt-have-happened-gog-reportedly-claim-sale-banner-made-with-al-tools-ended-up-on-store-by-mistake]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>