<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 17:38:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pacific Drive's next update makes driving around endlessly sound pretty good, actually]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pacific-drives-next-update-makes-driving-around-endlessly-sound-pretty-good-actually</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pacific-drives-next-update-makes-driving-around-endlessly-sound-pretty-good-actually.1144389/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pacific-drives-next-update-makes-driving-around-endlessly-sound-pretty-good-actually<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>And there's a few quality of life improvements coming too</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/pacific-drive_abCc5qy.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Ironwood Studios</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
You would think that with a game that is pretty much all about driving like <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/pacific-drive">Pacific Drive</a>, the prospect of an update that promises "endless" driving wouldn't be all that exciting or interesting. In this case you'd be wrong, though, as the game's upcoming Endless Expeditions patch sounds like a pretty solid one. Developer <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/ironwood-studios">Ironwood Studios</a> revealed the update with a new trailer yesterday, showing off all the changes and additions coming to the game, the most notable one being expeditions, described as "new continuous drives" that are a bit more dangerous than you might be used to.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
Outside of offering "unique rewards", Ironwood kept quiet on what this new mode will be like, but that makes the mystery of it all the more intriguing, no? On top of that there's also a few quality of life improvements coming. There's a new feature called cluster spawning, though I couldn't tell you what that is right now. The thermal vacuum and plasma scrapper are seeing some improvements too. As well as all that, a new zone trader, Ida's Exchange, can be discovered too.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Pacific Drive | Endless Expeditions Spring 2025 Update" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZrUC6K2tMcM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Pacific Drive | Endless Expeditions Spring 2025 Update</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZrUC6K2tMcM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ZrUC6K2tMcM?autoplay=1" title="Pacific Drive | Endless Expeditions Spring 2025 Update">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZrUC6K2tMcM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
A suspend run feature is being added in too, meaning if you need to quit out of the game because you realised you forgot to file your taxes or something, you can save mid-trip and go do that without sacrificing progress.
</p>
<p>
Oh, and there's more cosmetics you can unlock for your garage, more than an hours worth of new music to listen to on the radio while you're on the aforementioned endless expeditions (and anywhere else), and more lore too - Ironwood described this one as their "biggest" update yet, unsurprisingly.
</p>
<p>
You've not got long to wait for the update either, as it's due out in a little over a week's time on April 3rd.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds title update 1 will release on PC in April, adding a Grand Hub, Mizutsune and new quests]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/monster-hunter-wilds-title-update-1-will-release-on-pc-in-april-adding-a-grand-hub-mizutsune-and-new-quests</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-title-update-1-will-release-on-pc-in-april-adding-a-grand-hub-mizutsune-and-new-quests.1144242/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/monster-hunter-wilds-title-update-1-will-release-on-pc-in-april-adding-a-grand-hub-mizutsune-and-new-quests<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/monster-hunter-wilds-walkthrough">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> will receive its first proper title update on Thursday, April 3rd PT and Friday, April 4th in the UK. The update adds a new social hub to the beast-bashing action-RPG, together with a new monster you might recognise from previous games, some tougher varieties of existing monsters, and a bunch of additional quest types and outfits. Plenty to chew on, once you pick out the bones. Here's a trailer.
</p><!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Monster Hunter Wilds - Free Title Update 1 | PS5 Games" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LryxlqiIi1A?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Monster Hunter Wilds - Free Title Update 1 | PS5 Games</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LryxlqiIi1A?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/LryxlqiIi1A?autoplay=1" title="Monster Hunter Wilds - Free Title Update 1 | PS5 Games">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LryxlqiIi1A" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
Let’s start with the monsters. These include the “dazzling and dangerous” Mizutsune, a returning face from <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/monster-hunter-rise">Monster Hunter Rise</a>, which will be available in both standard and eight-star Tempered varieties. It’s a big frilly rainbow lizard that “moves almost as if it’s dancing, and skillfully attacks foes with debilitating bubbles”, according to a PlayStation blog post. Hands up if you now wish there was a real-life dancing school that involved bubbles. (There probably is.) 
</p>
<p>
As with all of Monster Hunter’s apex predators, Mizutsune is a source of materials for new <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/monster-hunter-wilds-how-to-get-layered-armor">armour</a> sets. Where is my bubblesuit, Capcom? How am I supposed to do dancing emotes without a bubblesuit? To hunt (or <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/monster-hunter-wilds-how-to-capture-monsters">capture</a>) the Mizutsune, talk to Kanya in the Scarlet Forest Base Camp at Hunter Rank 21 or above. 
</p>
<p>
The first title update also begins Capcom’s rollout of “Arch-tempered” monsters - the toughest monster variations yet. First on the menu is the Arch-tempered Rey Dau, which will be available at Hunter Rank 50 or above as part of an event quest on Tuesday 30th April. 
</p>
<p>
Title update 1 also sees the return of the Zoh Shia in High Rank play, this being a critter that you could hitherto only fight once as part of the story. As of 3rd/4th April, you’ll be able to battle the Zoh Shia repeatedly. Look out for the High Rank Zoh Shia quest in the environment overview. You might also stumble on the poor dear during the Wyvern’s Wakening in the Ruins of Wyveria. Fell it and you can craft some new High Rank hunter and Palico equipment that, to my eye, makes you look like you’ve been tarred and feathered.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Monster-Hunter-Wilds-Zoh-Shia-High-Rank-armour.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Capcom</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>That’s it for new monsters. But what about the <em>real</em> monsters here – other human players? Well, title update 1 introduces the Grand Hub, a majestic social space that has “long served as a place of worship for the people of Suja”, where carved totems rear above the tents and you might occasionally hear the songs of the faithful after dark. Also, it’s got a bowling alley where you roll barrel bombs at targets to win items and pedants. 
</p>
<p>
To do this, you’ll need Barrel Bowling Vouchers, which you can earn via login bonuses among other means. It’s a retention mechanism, in other words. The Grand Hub will be available from Hunter Rank 16 – just chat to Tetsuzan in Suja, the Peaks of Accord.
</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Grand-Hub-Monster-Hunter-Wilds.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Capcom</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
What else? Well, they’re bringing back arena quests, which challenge you to complete a hunt as fast as possible using pre-determined equipment, together with limited-time Challenge Quests and Free Challenge Quests, where you can earn pendants. There’s a new free outfit for Alma, and some other cosmetic DLC gubbins. Read more on <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/03/25/monster-hunter-wilds-a-new-monster-challenges-and-more-content-arrives-on-april-4/">the PlayStation blog</a>.
</p>
<p>
Capcom are already teasing the game’s second title update, which lands this summer – there’s a glimpse of another new predator in the video above. There is, as yet, no word of any significant overhaul for the PC version’s <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/monster-hunter-wilds-pc-performance-best-settings">technical tribulations at launch</a>. I’m not sure how bad it is right now – have you had any frame rate issues lately?
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>