<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 08:46:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Just over a week on from the last one, there's a fresh Battlefield 6 leak here that shows the return of Rush]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/just-over-a-week-on-from-the-last-one-theres-a-fresh-battlefield-6-leak-here-that-shows-the-return-of-rush</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/just-over-a-week-on-from-the-last-one-theres-a-fresh-battlefield-6-leak-here-that-shows-the-return-of-rush.1231059/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main-content" data-component="article-header">
  

        <p>Guess the leakers were in a rush to show it off</p>

    </div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Yes, yes, you're reading that headline right. Yet another <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/battlefield-2025">Battlefield 6</a> leak has taken place, if you can believe it, showing 15 whole minutes of the game that we all know exists but hasn't really been shown off in an official capacity. This follows on from the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oops-battlefield-6-features-revealed-by-leaked-battlefield-labs-footage">leak in March</a>, and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-6-rumoured-to-get-a-battle-royale-mode-as-leaker-finds-footage-of-an-exploding-dam">even just last week</a>, which might have confirmed the presence of a battle royale mode. This latest leak offers something new though: the return of Rush mode, a mode that's appeared in a number of previous Battlefield entries.
</p>
<p>
The footage in question, which originated from the Chinese social media site bilibili, keeps getting taken down given that this is very obviously meant to be under NDA and not something the general public is meant to see. So, I'm not going to link to it anywhere, because inevitably whatever clip I do share here will be gone by the time I wake up tomorrow (here's a <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Battlefield/comments/1llyrat/battlefield_6_alpha_leak_rush_game_mode_27_06_2025/">link to a Reddit page</a> where the footage was available at one point, just for some amount of evidence). The footage in question shows off pretty much what you'd expect from a Battlefield game, i.e. unrealistic combat scenarios, destructible environments, commentary from gamers getting annoyed at other people but truthfully more at themselves due to their inner turmoil.
</p>
<p>
In terms of how this version of Rush might be different from previous incarnations, I honestly can't say. I've not played any Battlefield games, it all just looks like your typical military <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-fps-games">FPS</a> to me. From what I can tell a majority of the footage is from the perspective of the attacking team - Rush generally sees a team of attackers, who have a limited number of respawns, go against defenders, who have an unlimited number of respawns, the former trying to detonate two charges in the latter's base.
</p>
<p>
Keep in mind that this is all a work in progress, some of the vehicles aren't finished for example, and there's always the chance the mode doesn't make it into the full release. In any case, this is your regular reminder that NDAs will never stop gamers from sharing clips online.

</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/just-over-a-week-on-from-the-last-one-theres-a-fresh-battlefield-6-leak-here-that-shows-the-return-of-rush]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[With Palworld's Terraria collab now out in the wild, Terraria will be getting its own Palworld crossover... eventually]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/with-palworlds-terraria-collab-now-out-in-the-wild-terraria-will-be-getting-its-own-palworld-crossover-eventually</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/with-palworlds-terraria-collab-now-out-in-the-wild-terraria-will-be-getting-its-own-palworld-crossover-eventually.1231023/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Re-Logic/ Pocket Pair</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
You can <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/palworlds-terraria-collab-is-coming-this-summer-though-i-have-some-questions-about-it">put the Terraria in Palworld</a>, but can you put the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/palworld">Palworld</a> in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/terraria">Terraria</a>? Well, uh, yes, apparently. Earlier this week Palworld's Tides of Terraria update was released unto the world, adding in things like fishing, a new trust mechanic, and obviously some Terraria themed bits like monsters to fight and items to get. Now, in a <a href="https://forums.terraria.org/index.php?threads/terraria-state-of-the-game-june-2025.143573/#tmod">post shared on the Terraria forums</a>, a new look at the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-survival-games-on-pc">survival</a> game's next update, version 1.4.5, showed off its own Palworld update.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
Now, I should note that not much was shown off from the Palworld additions, but it was confirmed to be arriving with the next update. A GIF was also included in the post showing a new pet companion, Digtoise, a Pal that looks as if Blastoise and Bowser had a baby. Digtoise can, as its name suggests, can dig into the ground, adding blocks of dirt and presumably other materials to your inventory. 
</p>
<p>
The forum post also notes that the team is "working in secret to bring some of your favorite Pals to life in the world of Terraria! What other Pals might appear? What other Palworld content might you see? Who knows?" I'm assuming they know at the very least!
</p>
<p>
In terms of non-Palworld related things coming in the update, there's some new furniture sets coming, notably some fancy ones. Nothing that exciting, but more stuff is more stuff.
</p>
<p>
Aside from that, the post made one other thing clear: "we still do not have a release date to give out. Every day is one day closer, of course, but we are trying to remain overly cautious and conservative in regards to giving out any timing. We do not want to repeat the mistake of giving out a timing window and then have things change and it not be accurate. So, we must once again ask for your continued patience as we do the hard work that needs to be done in order to ensure a quality update for everyone."
</p>
<p>
It also notes that everything is moving along as fast as it can without making the team crunch on it, but completely ruled that out, which is a refreshing thing to hear at this point honestly. I'm sure it'll be ready when it's ready!

</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/with-palworlds-terraria-collab-now-out-in-the-wild-terraria-will-be-getting-its-own-palworld-crossover-eventually]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Guilty Gear Strive dev Arc System Works' first showcase had a lot of good games, and a hopeful goal for the industry's future]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/guilty-gear-strive-dev-arc-system-works-first-showcase-had-a-lot-of-good-games-and-a-hopeful-goal-for-the-industrys-future</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/guilty-gear-strive-dev-arc-system-works-first-showcase-had-a-lot-of-good-games-and-a-hopeful-goal-for-the-industrys-future.1231005/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"We feel the need to focus our efforts towards the future"</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Arc System Works</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/arc-system-works">Arc System Works</a> are a developer who more likely than not, you'll think of as a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-fighting-games">fighting</a> game studio. I wouldn't blame you, they're the folks behind Guilty Gear, BlazBlue, Persona 4 Arena, all really beloved fighting games. That doesn't paint a full picture though, and in a showcase held yesterday, they showed off a bunch of upcoming games, some of which they made themselves, others they're serving as publisher for. And not one fighting game in sight! Which plenty of people made comments about, but I think those people maybe need to play anything other than a fighting game for once.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
First up is possibly the most exciting announcement of the bunch, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Kt4ojxXBIck">Dear me, I was</a>, a dialogueless interactive adventure game that unfortunately isn't coming to PC but I need to make mention of. That's because Taisuke Kanasaki, the director and artist of Hotel Dusk and Another Code, is serving as art director on this project, with Maho Taguchi serving as director. Kanasaki's art is instantly recogniseable, so I've got my fingers tightly crossed it'll make its way to PC.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="ARC SYSTEM WORKS Showcase | 6.26.2025 | English Broadcast" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KTmGjSdePtU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>ARC SYSTEM WORKS Showcase | 6.26.2025 | English Broadcast</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KTmGjSdePtU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/KTmGjSdePtU?autoplay=1" title="ARC SYSTEM WORKS Showcase | 6.26.2025 | English Broadcast">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KTmGjSdePtU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
There was also a showcase for <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JyhbM6DtET8">Double Dragon Revive</a>, a new take on the classic side-scrolling beat-em-up, which is coming to PC for those looking for a dose of nostalgia. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bv5WxE-kLGM">Demon's Night Fever</a> is a currently platformless new stylish seeming "raising speedrun simulation RPG based on the concept of 'embrace being evil'" from Disgaea creator Sohei Niikawa. Kind of obsessed with whatever that explanation is, also hoping this one comes to PC. And there's a new Bubble Bobble called <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2937770/Bubble_Bobble_Sugar_Dungeons/">Sugar Dungeons</a>! Can't go wrong there, and this one is coming to PC. All of these are being published by Arc System Works.
</p>
<p>
Then, lastly, there's <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AX2ZvFP36M0">Damon and Baby</a>, an isometric action game where you play as a Demon King who's been cursed to be stuck to a human child, which Arc System Works is developing. Not much of this one was shown off, and again, no platforms were confirmed for this one, but it's how Guilty Gear creator Daisuke Ishiwatari introduced it that I think is worth highlighting.
</p>
<p>
Right off the bat he noted how the "game market is tough now. To overcome that, Arc System Works has launched a new project." He goes on to say how he knows that most people recognise the studio as a fighting game company, but to "achieve a new brand where we are known for quality mid-range action games, we decided to establish a new pillar outside of fighting games."
</p>
<p>
He notes how because of the fact that both ends of the AAA blockbuster and indie spectrum can find a lot of success, there's more risk for companies to create new series. "This has led to dwindling opportunities for young creators to have their own projects. We feel the need to focus our efforts towards the future, a decade from now, such as to build stable development schemes, and to accumulate technology and know-how."
</p>
<p>
Ishiwatari points out how Guilty Gear started out as a small-scale project, and has gone on to be a much bigger series. So he hopes that by making more mid-range titles, there'll be more opportunities for many more games and creators of games.
</p>
<p>
Quite honestly, hearing something like this is a breath of fresh air. I love an indie game, and I can enjoy the odd AAA title, but nothing gets me going like a mid-range, AA game (looking at you, Remedy). More importantly, attempting to create an environment where younger developers can learn and improve their skills to perhaps one day make something bigger and bolder is ridiculously needed. 
</p>
<p>
With all of the layoffs that have taken place, there's so many skilled developers being forcefully ousted, leaving little room for junior staff members to come in and work their way up. I've got my fingers crossed for Arc System Works' initiative, and hope to see more of it from other studios too.

</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/guilty-gear-strive-dev-arc-system-works-first-showcase-had-a-lot-of-good-games-and-a-hopeful-goal-for-the-industrys-future]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Kickstarter for Dragon Age writer David Gaider's demonic deckbuilder Malys didn't work, so here it is in early access instead]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-kickstarter-for-dragon-age-writer-david-gaiders-demonic-deckbuilder-malys-didnt-work-so-here-it-is-in-early-access-instead</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-kickstarter-for-dragon-age-writer-david-gaiders-demonic-deckbuilder-malys-didnt-work-so-here-it-is-in-early-access-instead.1230906/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Summerfall Studios</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Back in April, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/stray-gods-a-roleplaying-musical">Stray Gods: A Roleplaying Musical</a> developer Summerfall Studios <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dragon-age-writer-teases-a-new-arcane-deckbuilder-from-his-stray-gods-studio">launched their Kickstarter for Malys</a>, a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-roguelike-games-pc">roguelike</a> deckbuilder where you play as a "former priest turned demon-hunter" that certainly looked quite atmospheric. This is the same studio co-founded by <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dragon-age">Dragon Age</a> writer David Gaider, so it's not like they came out of nowhere. However, it fell a bit short of meeting its goal, something that quite often guarantees that death of a game. Except it just launched into early access this week. Go figure!
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
Let's add a bit of context as to how that came to be, as explained by <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/malys">Malys</a> project director Liam Esler in a <a href="https://www.summerfallstudios.com/malys-developer-updates/devlog-one-malys-early-access">devlog post</a>. The team always had a plan on how to get to 1.0 for Malys, "but games like this live and die on their communities." With the Kickstarter failing, that changed plans, leading them to need more feedback than they'd originally intended, hence the early access release.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Malys - Early Access Teaser" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PdOC7dwPUzM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Malys - Early Access Teaser</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PdOC7dwPUzM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/PdOC7dwPUzM?autoplay=1" title="Malys - Early Access Teaser">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PdOC7dwPUzM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
"The community response both to the game itself and to our team has been overwhelmingly kind, and even though Malys isn’t quite where we’d ideally like it to be for a public launch, we feel bringing this current version of the game to Early Access is the best step we can take", Esler explains.
</p>
<p>
One thing that he also made clear is that "this is very much a work in progress build of the game. Early Access on Steam in 2025 is nowadays games that are ‘mostly done’, excluding adding additional content. If you don’t want to play a version of the game that is in-progress, we don’t recommend buying this Early Access version and instead waiting for the 1.0." A caveat was added that the price will go up after early access too, so keep that in mind depending on how much faith you have in the team.
</p>
<p>
Apparently the plan is to put out gameplay updates "about once every three weeks", which will range from planned content, adjustments based on feedback, and bugs. In terms of what's currently included, there's the first region, a "segment" of story, and a "variety of cards/ curios to choose from." A <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/3449690/view/525346350588493892?l=english">Steam post</a> announcing the early access also lists some known bugs for you to keep in mind too.
</p>
<p>
Essentially, it sounds like Summerfall Studios are taking another big swing here after not quite managing to make contact with that Kickstarter. Good luck to them, I say, the game looks neat.

</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-kickstarter-for-dragon-age-writer-david-gaiders-demonic-deckbuilder-malys-didnt-work-so-here-it-is-in-early-access-instead]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Untitled Paper RPG is a game from the dev behind A Short Hike that you'll only ever be able to play a couple hours of]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/untitled-paper-rpg-is-a-game-from-the-dev-behind-a-short-hike-that-youll-only-ever-be-able-to-play-a-couple-hours-of</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/untitled-paper-rpg-is-a-game-from-the-dev-behind-a-short-hike-that-youll-only-ever-be-able-to-play-a-couple-hours-of.1230894/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Sometimes even cancelled games find a way to live on</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Adamgryu</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Right now, I can't really tell you much of what A Short Hike developer <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/a-short-hike">adamgryu</a> is working on. He <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/adamgryu.bsky.social/post/3ls5lvip3nc2j">shared a little look</a> at whatever is next last week, and it certainly looks adjacent to A Short Hike vibes wise - we'll come back to this one with the tiniest of details in a bit. At the very least, I can certainly tell you what he's not working on: a game called <a href="https://adamgryu.itch.io/paper-game">Untitled Paper RPG</a>.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
As described by adamgryu, Untitled Paper RPG is an "untitled <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> inspired by the classic Paper Mario games. It’s got turn-based combat with quick time events and a detailed overworld to explore." This of course begs the question why I'm telling you about this game at all if it's ostensibly cancelled. Well, last week the indie dev actually shared a short one to two hour long demo of the game, essentially the entirety of what was made. Adamgryu also offered up a <a href="https://adamgryu.itch.io/paper-game/devlog/971220/i-might-never-finish-this-game-so-im-releasing-the-demo">short blog post</a> explaining the project a bit, and what led to it now being officially cancelled.
</p>
<blockquote data-bluesky-cid="bafyreiemshpkbk46s6hswy6k5ywego3pvzwgcgtjnaedixw5obytfcsfie" data-bluesky-embed-color-mode="system" data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:4p73sts7tw5thrgzunjzw5jz/app.bsky.feed.post/3ls5krqbuqc2v"><div lang="en"><p>Back in 2018, I was working on an RPG inspired by the Paper Mario series. I don't think I'll end up finishing this game, but I figured I could share the demo that I had put together anyway. #gamedev

Blog post and demo here! 🔽
adamgryu.itch.io/paper-game/d...</p><p><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:4p73sts7tw5thrgzunjzw5jz/post/3ls5krqbuqc2v?ref_src=embed">[image or embed]</a></p></div>— Adam (<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:4p73sts7tw5thrgzunjzw5jz?ref_src=embed">@adamgryu.bsky.social</a>) <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:4p73sts7tw5thrgzunjzw5jz/post/3ls5krqbuqc2v?ref_src=embed">21 June 2025 at 23:06</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><p>
Untitled Paper RPG initially started development back in 2016, after adamgryu saw the announcement for Paper Mario Color Splash. "I was nostalgic for the old style of Paper Mario and thought - well, I make games, why not try making the game I want to see?" he explains. After leaving his job in 2017, he set out to make indie games, but while working on this one in late 2018 he took a break and started on A Short Hike. "It unexpectedly did really well for me! I had planned to go back to my RPG at some point, but there was still a lot of work I could do on A Short Hike."
</p>
<p>
In the end, his reason behind "sort of" cancelling the game was a simple one: after putting out A Short Hike, he just "didn’t really want to go back to this game? The development for the RPG had become difficult, which was why I took a break from it in the first place. I might return to this project someday, but I’ve been working on other things and don’t see myself making time for this RPG in near future."
</p>
<p>
Adamgryu then listed out a few of the reasons that working on the game felt "overwhelming," including the classic issue of the scope feeling too big, not actually having a story, and having doubts over the turn-based combat system. He ultimately decided to release this demo partially because some people still ask about it, so "sharing the demo is better than nothing."
</p>
<p>
Back to that GIF of one of his upcoming games, Adamgryu also shared that this is an action adventure game he's working on. It's one of three projects he's tinkering away at, including a micro-RPG with a claymation aesthetic, and an online platforming roguelike.
</p>
<p>
It's often sad when exciting games get cancelled, but it's also rare that we in the first instance get this much insight as to why, and in the second have the ability to actually play some of it. There's a value to be found in something that's incomplete. I often think about Satoshi Kon's Opus, a manga he never finished before his death in 2010, and how it's then forced to leave so much to the imagination of the reader. What would Untitled Paper RPG have become? Perhaps a worse game than what its demo presents! So let's appreciate what we do have instead.

</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/untitled-paper-rpg-is-a-game-from-the-dev-behind-a-short-hike-that-youll-only-ever-be-able-to-play-a-couple-hours-of]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>