<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 16:22:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater isn't getting Metal Gear Online, but it is getting its own quite fun looking online mode]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-isnt-getting-metal-gear-online-but-it-is-getting-its-own-quite-fun-looking-online-mode</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-isnt-getting-metal-gear-online-but-it-is-getting-its-own-quite-fun-looking-online-mode.1216884/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-isnt-getting-metal-gear-online-but-it-is-getting-its-own-quite-fun-looking-online-mode<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/metal-gear-online">Metal Gear Online</a>! I'm assuming that's the first thing you thought of when you heard that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater">Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</a> is getting an online mode, but I need you to throw that thought in the bin. The MGS3 remake is getting a multiplayer mode, but as shown off in today's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/konami">Konami</a> Press Start <a href="https://youtu.be/NXaDgU72gRI?si=EFZz0vU8kfrLvcOb">showcase</a>, it'll be its own, original thing called Fox Hunt.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
"Fox Hunt is a completely original online battle mode," said mode director Yu Sahara of the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-stealth-games">stealth game</a> during the showcase. "Although it shares the same worldview of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/metal-gear-solid">Metal Gear Solid</a> Delta, the gameplay is completely different. Perhaps many people will think of Metal Gear Online when hearing about a Metal Gear Online battle mode, but Fox Hunt is different from Metal Gear Online."
</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>
Because specifics weren't shared, I can't tell you how exactly it differs from the original multiplayer <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/metal-gear">Metal Gear</a>. One thing that does seem to be a pretty big element of it is an emphasis on camouflage. You can whip out some kind of thing that wraps around your character, and adapts to whatever surface you're sneaking around on.
</p>
<p>
Say there's a brick wall covered in vines - if you go up to it, your camouflage tool will make it look like you're a part of the vines. Or it'll make you look like a clump of rocks alongside a riverbed. It genuinely looks quite effective, and I can imagine it making for some pretty tense matches if you're not looking carefully at your surroundings. More details will be coming at a later date!
</p>
<p>
The showcase also revealed that, ugh, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/silent-hill-1-remake-announced-with-the-briefest-of-teaser-trailers">Silent Hill 1 is getting the remake treatment</a> this time around, with Bloober Team once again at the helm. I'll leave it at that before I go off on a rant about how Silent Hill 1 being so simplistic because it's a PS1 game is part of what makes it so interesting.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>