<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 11:56:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sure, why not: here's a Monster Hunter Wilds mod to make your Palico very large]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sure-why-not-heres-a-monster-hunter-wilds-mod-to-make-your-palico-very-large</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sure-why-not-heres-a-monster-hunter-wilds-mod-to-make-your-palico-very-large.1124523/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sure-why-not-heres-a-monster-hunter-wilds-mod-to-make-your-palico-very-large<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>There comes a time in every cat owner's life where they must ask themselves: how large would this creature need to be before it attempted to bat me around like a catnip mouse? I suspect the answer is "only as large as it needed to be", so it's fortunate that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a>' Palicoes are apparently bred for helpfulness. Is installing a mod to the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-action-games">action game</a> that makes them tall as humans a form of gene splicing? Don't worry, hunter. Gene splicing is how nature heals itself.</p>
<!--more-->
<p><a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/monsterhunterwilds/mods/35">The mod is called 'Kitty Big'. </a>There isn't much to say about it beyond that. You don't need to continue reading now, so here's a little story for anyone left.</p>
<p>Once, a peaceful and prosperous hamlet was terrorised by a beast that demanded regular sacrifices, lest it drag its lumpen form down from its mountain dwelling and drain the lifeblood from the villagers.</p>
<p>Not just any sacrifice would appease its capricious tastes, however. Some days, it demanded the flesh of storied warriors. Others, humble farm hands. Occasionally, it wanted those little cocktail sticks with pineapple and cheese on, which was bollocks because where do you even find pineapples in this climate?</p>
<p>One day, the people of the hamlet decided they'd had enough of catering to the beast's whims, especially since the one thing the creature was useful for - dispersing snippets of wisdom in response to specific queries and occasionally reverse image searching a nice shirt you didn't know where to buy - had recently been borked by a colony of parasites taken up residence in the monster's brain stem. So they refused to make any more sacrifices. And they all got eaten.</p>
<p>The moral of the story is that sometimes you just have to give Google what it wants. Today, that's the words '<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/monster-hunter-wilds-walkthrough">Monster Hunter Wilds</a>' followed by whatever mildly interesting nugget of disposable information I can dig up between my first and second morning coffee. Nice mod, though. I'll probably use it once I buy the game, which won't be until <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/monster-hunter-wilds-pc-performance-best-settings">they've sorted out the performance</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>