<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 20:46:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Spacefaring RPG Citizen Sleeper 2: Starward Vector gets a release date: January 31st 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/spacefaring-rpg-citizen-sleeper-2-starward-vector-gets-a-release-date-january-31st-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/spacefaring-rpg-citizen-sleeper-2-starward-vector-gets-a-release-date-january-31st-2025.1053057/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/spacefaring-rpg-citizen-sleeper-2-starward-vector-gets-a-release-date-january-31st-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/CS2_03.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Fellow Traveller</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Ah, it feels just like yesterday when <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/citizen-sleeper-2-still-has-around-a-year-of-development-left-likely-coming-in-2025">Citizen Sleeper 2: Starward Vector</a> had<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/citizen-sleeper-2-still-has-around-a-year-of-development-left-likely-coming-in-2025"> around a year of development time left</a>. Actually, I’d say it feels like it precisely around February 2nd of this year. Well, would you look at that. It seems making excellent <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a>s isn’t Jump Over The Age’s only skill. They’ve also predicted the exact release of their game to within a 3 day margin of error: the actual release date is the 31st of January, 2025.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Citizen Sleeper 2 - Date Announce Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rpiEhTVuISc?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Citizen Sleeper 2 - Date Announce Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rpiEhTVuISc?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/rpiEhTVuISc?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rpiEhTVuISc" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>As just revealed at the Percy Coswald Gamer show, the sequel to <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/citizen-sleeper">Citizen Sleeper</a> will be here next January, narrowed down from its previous ‘2025’ release date. There’s been a fair few sleeper-heads here at RPS, including Katharine (RPS in Peace), who couldn’t contain her excitement on learning <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/citizen-sleeper-2-is-real-and-i-couldnt-be-happier">the sequel was real</a>.</p>
<p>Brendan spoke to Jump Over The Age’s Gareth Damian Martin recently, too, about a variety of subjects including the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/can-you-guess-which-australian-tv-sci-fi-of-the-early-2000s-inspired-citizen-sleeper-2">early 2000’s Australian TV sci-fi show that inspired it</a>. There’s also some fun crunchy design talk in there.</p>
<blockquote><p>"When you make games you have to accept that you are inherently quantifying absolutely everything," says Martin, "because a game is just a load of numbers. And so even if the player can't see those numbers, they definitely exist.</p>
<p>"It's fun to push and pull at that, and have the player... maybe sometimes feel uncomfortable, if they're telling their favourite character what to do. I love the idea of that kind of narrative gameplay infecting the mechanical gameplay."</p></blockquote>
<p>You can currently grab the first Citizen Sleeper with a bunch of other games as part of the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/you-can-grab-shadows-of-doubt-citizen-sleeper-and-more-in-jingle-jams-2024-bundle-and-support-eight-worthy-causes">Jingle Jam 2024</a> bundle.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Northgard, Dune and Wartales devs Shiro Games reveal sci-fi MMO SpaceCraft]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/northgard-dune-and-wartales-devs-shiro-games-reveal-sci-fi-mmo-spacecraft</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/northgard-dune-and-wartales-devs-shiro-games-reveal-sci-fi-mmo-spacecraft.1053054/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/northgard-dune-and-wartales-devs-shiro-games-reveal-sci-fi-mmo-spacecraft<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Coming to early access in 2025</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_VjGuKPP.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Shiro Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>4X strategy and RPG stalwarts Shiro Games have announced SpaceCraft, a "massively multiplayer management and crafting adventure" set in Normandy during the Middle Ages, haha, of course not - it's set in space. They won't be winning the T.S. Eliot poetry prize with that title, but I guess it gets the job done. Here's a trailer.</p> <!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="SpaceCraft | REVEAL TRAILER" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bdd0avB3t-g?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>SpaceCraft | REVEAL TRAILER</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bdd0avB3t-g?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/bdd0avB3t-g?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bdd0avB3t-g" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>And here's a little blurb:</p>
<blockquote><p>"Explore the vast expanses of space in a custom-built starship. Gather vital resources from diverse planets throughout the universe to craft housing, production, communication, and other essential structures. Join forces with other players to form powerful trade organizations to take on challenging missions and shape a constantly evolving economy."</p></blockquote>
<p>You can read more on the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3276050/SpaceCraft/">Steam page</a>, which digs a little into the detail of mechanics like faster-than-light travel, automation and fleet combat. The game's coming to early access in 2025.</p>
<p>Shiro are best known for <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/northgard-review">"superb RTS"</a> <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/northgard">Northgard</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dune-spice-wars-review">"compulsive 4X"</a> <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dune-spice-wars">Dune: Spice Wars</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wartales-review">"grimy medieval fantasy RPG</a>" Wartales, all games I would hesitantly summarise as "teetering on the edge of serious greatness". Breaking into MMO territory feels like a real gamble for them, but then again, when is making an MMO not a gamble?</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Tactical Takedown is a bodacious turn-based battler from the Clickolding devs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-tactical-takedown-is-a-bodacious-turn-based-battler-from-the-clickolding-devs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-tactical-takedown-is-a-bodacious-turn-based-battler-from-the-clickolding-devs.1053051/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-tactical-takedown-is-a-bodacious-turn-based-battler-from-the-clickolding-devs<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/teenage-mutant-ninja-turtle-tactical-takedown.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Strange Scaffold</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Tactical Mutant Ninja Turtles? Turn-based Mutant Ninja Tactics? I'm undecided, but its actual name is Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Tactical Takedown, so maybe I should just call it that. It's just been announced and it's coming to PC next year.
</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Tactical Takedown Reveal Trailer – PC Gaming Show: Most Wanted 2024" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WwKmulVHmXI?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Tactical Takedown Reveal Trailer – PC Gaming Show: Most Wanted 2024</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WwKmulVHmXI?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/WwKmulVHmXI?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Tactical Takedown announcement trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WwKmulVHmXI" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>I'm extremely onboard with this for two reasons. One, it's a turn-based tactics game, and I always have a baseline of interest in them. Two, its battles apparently take just minutes to complete. It all looks a little bit Hoplite, at least in my head, and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/have-you-played-hoplite">that was a truly wonderful turn-based roguelike</a> with similarly bite-sized skirmishes. In Tactical Takedown, the missions are strung together in mini-campaigns, each one focused on a different Turtle with their own unique abilities.
</p>
<p>I suppose the third reason I'm intrigued is that I was mad into Teenage Mutant Hero Turtles, as the cartoon was called in the UK, when I was a kid. I had the figurines where their half-shells could open up and you could store their ninja stars (hero stars?) inside. Also that animated film last year, Mutant Mayhem, was pretty great.
</p><p>There have been a bunch of Turtles games recently, including the revival of the beat 'em ups with <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-shredders-revenge">Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Shredder's Revenge</a>, and Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Splintered Fate, a sorta action RPG roguelike that came out last month, which I have installed but not yet played.
</p>
<p>Here's a fourth and final reason you might be interested in Tactical Takedown: it's being developed by Strange Scaffold, the folks behind recent indine hits <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/i-am-your-beast">I Am Your Beast</a> and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/clickolding">Clickolding</a>. It's an unexpected matchup, and for now there's <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3229100/Teenage_Mutant_Ninja_Turtles_Tactical_Takedown/">more screenshots on Steam</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Moonlighter 2: The Endless Vault is the sequel to the shopkeeping dungeon crawler, out next year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/moonlighter-2-the-endless-vault-is-the-sequel-to-the-shopkeeping-dungeon-crawler-out-next-year</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/moonlighter-2-the-endless-vault-is-the-sequel-to-the-shopkeeping-dungeon-crawler-out-next-year.1052982/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/moonlighter-2-the-endless-vault-is-the-sequel-to-the-shopkeeping-dungeon-crawler-out-next-year<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/moonlighter-2.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Digital Sun</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Dealing with perpetually unsatisfied, stunningly entitled hordes of chittering monsters and the occasional visit from a lumbering oaf of a boss can be tough work. But enough about working in retail - dungeon crawling <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-action-games">action</a> sell’em up <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/topics/moonlighter">Moonlighter</a> is getting a sequel! <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/moonlighter">Moonlighter</a> 2: The Endless Vault looks to be just what you want from a follow-up. Created once again by Digital Sun, whose recent works include the excellent <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/cataclismo">Cataclismo</a>, it’s prettier and vaster, with expanded merchanting and deeper dungeoneering. It's out sometime in 2025.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>This time around, white-haired hero Will and his companions are “stranded in a mysterious dimension in the village of Tresna”. Will simply cannot wait to get back to more retail work, and soon discovers “a tantalizing opportunity to return home, thanks to a curious relic collector”. If horror stories of antiquity have taught me anything, it’s to immediately purchase any curious relics you find. Bonus points if its mysterious power only grows in tandem with your own hubris. Sounds fun! Here are some features:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Revive Tresna’s Splendor:</strong> Invest in the village’s development by supporting local businesses, upgrading gear, and unlocking new opportunities. As Tresna flourishes, so will your shop’s fortunes.</p>
<p><strong>Loot Like a Legend:</strong> Prepare your gear, restrain your nerves, and delve into treacherous vaults filled with unimaginable treasures. But beware: the deeper you go, the higher the stakes—and the greater the risks.</p>
<p><strong>Master the Art of Shopkeeping:</strong> Transform your hard-earned loot into profits by charming customers and haggling like a pro. Customize your shop with dazzling decorations to draw even more eager buyers.</p></blockquote>
<p>“It definitely needs more variety earlier on, but when Moonlighter gets going, it's tremendously compelling,” is wot John (RPS in peace) thunk <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/moonlighter-review">of the original back</a> in 2018. “It's very charming, very beautiful, and both its comprising halves are enjoyable in their own ways.”</p>
<p><em>Disclosure: Brendan did some words for this. I asked him five random words he used but he wouldn’t tell me. </em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>