<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:03:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2 gets new stealth missions today, and its super-slimmed install size version is finally ready to take over]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2-gets-new-stealth-missions-today-and-its-super-slimmed-install-size-version-is-finally-ready-to-take-over</link>
            <guid>1412929</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Sneakiness and smallness abounds</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/helldivers-2-patch-stealth-missions-slim-build-default-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/helldivers-2-patch-stealth-missions-slim-build-default-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/helldivers-2-patch-stealth-missions-slim-build-default-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/helldivers-2-patch-stealth-missions-slim-build-default-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/helldivers-2-patch-stealth-missions-slim-build-default-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/helldivers-2-patch-stealth-missions-slim-build-default-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/helldivers-2-patch-stealth-missions-slim-build-default-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/helldivers-2-patch-stealth-missions-slim-build-default-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/helldivers-2-patch-stealth-missions-slim-build-default-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Arrowhead</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>A new <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/helldivers-2">Helldivers 2</a> patch has arrived ahead of the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/shush-helldivers-2s-redacted-regiment-warbond-is-all-about-being-sneakily-stealthy-and-silently-suppressed">slightly delayed Redacted Regiment warbond</a> also making its sneaky debut today, January 22nd. In line with that warbond's stealthy shushness, this patch has seen Arrowhead add in new commando missions designed to reward those who know when to crouch-walk. They've also revealed that the slim build that's been in beta for a little while is finally ready to take the reigns from the standard version and its very chunky install size.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>First of all, the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/553850/view/509603414731129453?l=english">patch notes</a> describe the new commando missions as follows: "<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/helldivers">Helldivers</a> are going deep behind enemy lines where their normal reliance on air superiority is no longer an option. Reinforcements have to be deployed in advance and destroyer support is a risky business with limited time." As such, knowing when to kill quietly or co-ordinate a rush with other players will be key.</p>
<p>You'll also be able to test out some tuning up of suppressed guns, which should now be "more valuable in stealth gameplay and attract less attention from enemies", as a result of firing noise radius tweaks. As part of that, foes like the devastator, berserker, spewer, charger, impaler, and observer have been made a bit more chill about bullets landing vaguely in their vicinity, so non-hits are less likely to instantly draw their ire.</p>
<p>Outside of the sneaky stuff, the slim build of Helldivers 2 which Arrowhead have been <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2-install-size-reduction-effort-yields-131gb-in-cuts-and-you-can-try-the-slim-build-right-now">beta testing as part of efforts to cut the 154GB game down to just 23GB</a> in terms of install size will no longer be in beta at some point soon.</p><p>"We are ready to make the slim PC build default for all players," The studio wrote. "We’ll keep the larger version online for a short time to ensure a smooth transition for everyone; so you’ll continue to have the option to switch back should you wish. Once this transition has been completed we’ll look to sunset the large build permanently in the near future." As of writing, no exact date for the initial switch appears to have been given, but it sounds like it'll be ASAP.</p>
<p>Rounding out this first drop of new Helldivers 2 stuff for 2026 was a promise that there's "much more to come in February and beyond", as you'd hope. For now, in the spirit of these sneaky missions, Arrowhead aren't giving too much away.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2-gets-new-stealth-missions-today-and-its-super-slimmed-install-size-version-is-finally-ready-to-take-over]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Beware: the Killer Egg will return to Battlefield 6 multiplayer, along with Battlefield 4's Golmund Railway map]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/beware-the-killer-egg-will-return-to-battlefield-6-multiplayer-along-with-battlefield-4s-golmund-railway-map</link>
            <guid>1412926</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Nice to see Dr Robotnik getting work</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bf6-map.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bf6-map.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bf6-map.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bf6-map.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bf6-map.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bf6-map.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bf6-map.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bf6-map.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bf6-map.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>EA</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-6-weapons-list">Battlefield 6</a>’s efforts to break ground while Gittin’ Back To When Battlefield Was Gud continue with the announcement of two forthcoming maps in the EA shooter’s second season, which begins 17th February. One of the maps is Contaminated, a brand new field of battle that is comparable in scale to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/battlefield-1">Battlefield 1</a>’s St Quentin Scar and Arras in Battlefield 5. The other is a remake of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/battlefield-4">Battlefield 4</a>’s Golmud Railway – a big, grassy vehicular affair, based on China’s actually existing Golmud-Lhasa railway line.
</p>
<p>
“In this next session, we’ll be testing content on one of Season 2’s new maps: Contaminated,” explains <a href="https://x.com/BattlefieldComm/status/2014005415114310024">an EA social post</a>. “We’ll be evaluating how vehicle gameplay and aerial presence interact with infantry combat, alongside cover and asset placement, and objective boundaries. We’ll also be testing how the map’s unique gameplay mechanics function in live matches, as well as the tools available to players to interact with them.
</p>
<p>
“While we’re saving full details on the new map for a later time,” it continues, “we can share that in terms of size, Contaminated falls between Eastwood and Mirak Valley, and is comparable to classic Battlefield maps such as St. Quentin Scar (Battlefield 1) or Arras (<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/battlefield-v">Battlefield V</a>).”
</p>
<p>
As for Golmud Railway, EA’s goal is “to preserve what made the map so memorable in Battlefield 4, particularly its combined arms gameplay, while improving how it plays and supports Battlefield 6 systems”. It’ll be the biggest Battlefield 6 map ever. EA will release it first in Battlefield Labs so that they can “test changes such as larger flight space, increased cover for aircraft, and other adjustments as the map evolves over time”.
</p><p>
Speaking of those wily airplanes, the devs are also testing out changes to vehicle handling in the run-up to Season 2. This includes tweaks to the AH-6 Little Bird, aka <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MD_Helicopters_MH-6_Little_Bird">Killer Egg</a>, which looks much like how an egg might look if you mounted cannons on it and parked a bunch of screaming jarheads on each side. The fan favourite chopper appears in the game's singleplayer, and can be spawned in Battlefield Portal, but is not formally part of BF6 multiplayer right now. The devs are considering “how it fits within the broader vehicle ecosystem and how it performs across different combat scenarios”.
</p>
<p>
They’re also doing some initial testing on “Aircraft Radar, an important part of the aircraft gameplay experience and a system we’re actively evaluating as part of future air combat improvements”. As I understand it, this is a feature that extends your radar range so you can better track aircraft, which tend to be pretty fast. Unless I’m piloting them, in which case they tend to explode on the runway.
</p>
<p>
“In parallel, we’ll be exploring a tuning package focused on rocket and vehicle interactions, including early adjustments to weapons such as RPGs and TOW launchers, as well as vehicle handling considerations when countering rockets,” the devs continue. There’s some talk of testing improvements “to hit registration and overall combat consistency”, to avoid “scenarios where players may be eliminated after reaching cover, often referred to as ‘death behind cover’ or desync-related behavior.”
</p>
<p>
Last and maybe, possibly not least, the devs are doing more testing around solo play in the battle royale mode. They want to understand “where Solo play can best fit within the broader Battle Royale roster, including how it affects match flow, survivability, and long-term engagement when featured alongside other Battle Royale experiences”. They note that there will never be a “single permanent configuration” for the game’s Plunkbat equivalent. It shall shift and alter like wind through the grasses of Golmund Railway when some absolute plonker crashlands a Killer Egg on take-off.
</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/beware-the-killer-egg-will-return-to-battlefield-6-multiplayer-along-with-battlefield-4s-golmund-railway-map]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["It is out of the question to let a boss run rampant" - Ubisoft workers strike against "disastrous" cutbacks]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/it-is-out-of-the-question-to-let-a-boss-run-rampant-ubisoft-workers-strike-against-disastrous-cutbacks</link>
            <guid>1412827</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Publisher's RTO announcement decried as effort to "destroy our working conditions"</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1(5).png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1(5).png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1(5).png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1(5).png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1(5).png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1(5).png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1(5).png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1(5).png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1(5).png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Ubisoft</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Ubisoft’s <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/prince-of-persia-the-sands-of-time-remake-and-more-cancelled-by-ubisoft-with-layoffs-potentially-on-the-horizon">bloodbath of game cancellations and restructuring</a> yesterday has attracted the expected fiery response from unionised workers, with the French game industry union Solidaires Informatique <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:gwmurecu4lbyaqjzsyv2orat/post/3mcxfxwczwk2z">calling a half-day strike today</a>. Cost-cutting and potential layoffs aside, the strikers are protesting against Ubisoft’s decision to mandate a full return to office, with workers given an annual allowance of work from home days instead - something a publisher executive has justified as a move “to enhance collective efficiency” and “the sense of belonging”.</p><!--more-->
<p>Ubisoft management’s latest bout of corpobutchery has seen them bin off six games, including the Prince Of Persia: The Sands Of Time remake, delay seven others, and confirm the closure of Ubisoft Stockholm. </p>
<p>More layoffs will follow, though Ubisoft have yet to share any precise numbers. It’s all part of the company’s Age of Sigmar-esque transformation into a collection of “Creative Houses” <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tencent-hand-ubisoft-a-big-wad-of-cash-to-spin-out-assassins-creed-far-cry-and-rainbow-six-as-a-separate-business">with heavy investment from Tencent</a>, dedicated to a smaller number of hopefully better-selling games – in particular, open world and live service projects, with generative AI dutifully touted as a means of boosting production.</p>
<p>As part of this transition, Ubisoft <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ubisoft-close-the-studio-behind-assassins-creed-rebellion-days-after-the-developers-vote-to-unionise">recently shuttered Ubisoft Halifax</a> (a few weeks after the studio voted to unionise – no connection, they insist) and announced <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/having-asked-division-devs-to-lay-themselves-off-ubisoft-are-now-cutting-55-jobs-at-massive-and-ubisoft-stockholm">layoffs at Tom Clancy’s The Division developers Massive</a>.</p>
<p>In a statement, Solidaires Informatique describe today’s strike as "an initial response to the absurdity of management decisions”, with more action probably to follow. "It is out of the question to let a boss run rampant and destroy our working conditions,” they write, addressing Ubisoft CEO Yves Guillemot. “Perhaps he needs to be reminded that it is his employees who make the games." The union are also calling for “decent pay rises this year” and “maintaining and extending the teleworking conditions”.</p>
<p>RTO policies are frequently the focus of union action. In October 2024, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/700-ubisoft-staff-in-france-hold-strikes-in-response-to-worldwide-return-to-office-mandate-from-assassins-creed-publisher">700 Ubisoft staff went on strike</a> over a requirement to work in-office three days a week. </p>
<p>Detractors of remote working argue that it’s less efficient and hinders teamwork. As Ubisoft’s senior vice-president of studio operations Marie-Sophie de Waubert told <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/we-want-them-to-be-the-best-in-the-world-in-every-segment-were-in-ubisofts-vision-for-its-new-creative-houses">GamesIndustry</a> yesterday, “the one and only objective [for the new RTO policy] is to enhance collective efficiency, to drive the dynamics, the creativity, the sense of belonging.”</p><p>Advocates for remote working argue that it doesn’t materially affect how much workers contribute, and that it can be vital for people with disabilities, family commitments and other practical challenges that make commuting or sharing office space unfeasible. When EA implemented a partial return to the office in May last year, anonymous staff <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ea-employees-upset-and-confused-at-return-to-office-mandate">offered</a> childcare, medical conditions, and long commutes as reasons for needing an exemption from in-office work.</p>
<p>Advocates for remote working also argue that forbidding hybrid or full remote-working is a “soft layoff” strategy, since some remote workers may have no choice but to move on. That was <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/following-mass-layoffs-microsoft-exec-insists-return-to-office-mandate-is-not-about-reducing-headcount">the claim levelled at Microsoft last September</a>, when they imposed a return to the office following thousands of layoffs.</p>
<p>I am very much Team Homeworking, inasmuch as I couldn’t do this job if I had to work in-office 9-5. In general, I think RTO mandates reflect an unexamined belief among managers that people become shirkers and layabouts unless they're kept firmly inside the panopticon.</p>
<p>Arguments continue about RTO beyond Ubisoft. Rockstar’s recent <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rockstar-reportedly-orders-gta-6-developers-to-end-hybrid-working-in-the-name-of-quality-and-polish">implementation of RTO in the name of “quality and polish”</a> is <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/stop-this-from-happening-again-uk-politician-calls-out-rockstar-over-gta-6-developer-firings">one of the reasons some GTA 6 workers chose to unionise</a>, shortly before Rockstar laid off a number of workers for “gross misconduct”, in what British unions have called a case of “union-busting”.</p>

        </div>

      </article>




        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/it-is-out-of-the-question-to-let-a-boss-run-rampant-ubisoft-workers-strike-against-disastrous-cutbacks]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nexus Mods' latest modathon isn't a typical modathon, it's a first go at the same for multi-mod collections]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/nexus-mods-latest-modathon-isnt-a-typical-modathon-its-a-first-go-at-the-same-for-multi-mod-collections</link>
            <guid>1412803</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>As the modding hosts continue to encourage giving one-click mod collections a go</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-4-modding-eight-years-on-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-4-modding-eight-years-on-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-4-modding-eight-years-on-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-4-modding-eight-years-on-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-4-modding-eight-years-on-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-4-modding-eight-years-on-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-4-modding-eight-years-on-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-4-modding-eight-years-on-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-4-modding-eight-years-on-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Bethesda</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>With their latest Fallout modathon having wrapped up at the close of last year, mod-hosting site Nexus Mods have decided to try something new with their latest event designed to supercharge mod creation around a specific game or theme. Rather than asking folks to submit fresh individual mods like usual, the modathon that's about to kick off is all about putting together chunky multi-mod lists which can overhaul a game in one fell swoop.</p>
<p>These user-assembled modlists, dubbed Collections, are a feature Nexus Mods have been <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fallout-4s-anniversary-update-didnt-quite-land-with-the-impact-many-hoped-for-so-nexus-mods-have-assembled-their-own">pushing</a> for a number of years now, so it's not surprising they're now serving as the subject of a modathon for the first time.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Set to run from January 26th to February 8th, the <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout-collectionathon">first "Collectionathon"</a> is a Fallout-themed one, with season two of a certain radioactive TV show putting out the remainder of its weekly episodes in the coming weeks.</p>
<p>"We want to see you reimagine the Wasteland in bold new ways, whether that’s by taking one of your favourite games from the series and amping it up or by bringing the world of Fallout to a brand new title," reads the brief from the nexus of modders. "Through survival overhauls, lore-friendly refreshes, or wild experiments, we want to see it all, and whatever your idea, we can’t wait to see your creativity in action!"</p><p>If you fancy getting involved, you'll need to do so via Vortex, Nexus Mods' Windows-only mod manager. As a bit of extra context, Vortex is now the only mod manager the mod hosts are working on, with them having <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/news/15424">announced plans to can development of a multiplatform Nexus Mods App</a> earlier this month. Central to the pitch behind that app was the idea it'd work on the likes of the Steam Deck and PCs running Linux. Though, Nexus Mods haven't totally ruled out that functionality potentially making its way to Vortex further down the line.</p>
<p>"We’re also exploring what Linux support might look like for Vortex in the future," Nexus mods owner Victor Folmann wrote in a post about the decision. "While getting every game and mod working on Linux might not be possible, it’s an area we want to keep evaluating where it makes sense."</p>
<p>While I can see the appeal of curated modlists designed for folks to be able to install in one click, having dabbled a bit with Vortex during my early modding days, I can't say I've ever given one of these collections a proper go. I momentarily considered it when setting up my last <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/cyberpunk-2077">Cyberpunk 2077</a> run, but instead chose simply to install manually so I could stick exclusively to mods I wanted and regularly pause to check everything was working as intended as my load order grew.</p>
<p>To be fair, I was benefitting from years worth of built-up knowledge in terms of mod installation and what's out there Cyberpunk mod-wise, so I might simply not be in main target audience for collections at this point. Still, it's a lot of faith to be putting in the people who curate such lists to keep them up to date and regularly tested. Then again, that's arguably the same sort of trust you have to put in mod creators anyway, if you're installing works one-by-one.</p>
<p>As of writing, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/fallout-4">Fallout 4</a>'s already got just over <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/games/fallout4/collections?sort=downloads">2,200 collections</a>, while <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/fallout-new-vegas">New Vegas</a> <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/games/newvegas/collections">has 961</a>, and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/fallout-3">Fallout 3</a> <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/games/fallout3/collections">99</a>. We'll have to see what sort of boost this collection jam gives to those numbers.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/nexus-mods-latest-modathon-isnt-a-typical-modathon-its-a-first-go-at-the-same-for-multi-mod-collections]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>