<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 09:52:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Relaxing" horror game LiDAR Exploration Program is PowerWash Simulator but with lasers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/relaxing-horror-game-lidar-exploration-program-is-powerwash-simulator-but-with-lasers</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/relaxing-horror-game-lidar-exploration-program-is-powerwash-simulator-but-with-lasers.1144959/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/relaxing-horror-game-lidar-exploration-program-is-powerwash-simulator-but-with-lasers<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_JgoAREy.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>KenForest / Rock Paper Shotgun</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
LiDAR or "light detection and ranging" is a way of working out and picturing the distance to an object by shooting laser beams at it, and timing how long it takes the laser to bounce back to the scanner. It's been used for a bunch of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lidar">Hard Science-y purposes</a>, from mapping cave systems to measuring changes in the Amazon forest canopy. It's also become popular among artists, who use it to create high-fidelity yet abstractly coloured and ethereal visualisations of, for example, <a href="https://mymodernmet.com/daniel-coe-lidar-data-river-art/">rivers</a>. Now here's LiDAR Exploration Program, a "relaxing atmospheric <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-horror-games">horror</a>" game from KenForest, in which you roam maps with a handheld LiDAR gun scanning the geography into being.
</p><!--more-->
<p>
I've just been playing the Itch demo, and it's sort of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/powerwash-simulator">PowerWash Simulator</a> but for ghosts. I'm assuming the game doesn't physically calculate the passage of individual laser beams for the simple reason that my work laptop can run it without shuddering to pieces. Each level gives you a list of individual objects to scan. It certainly works as a chillout play: the landscapes appear to be wholly static, and you can take your time going over every surface, using the mouse wheel to expand or tighten the cone of lasers emitted by your gun. There's an alt-fire on right-click which scans the whole screen from top to bottom. All very methodical and restful. But also unnerving. 
</p>
<p>
LiDAR can't reveal the interior of an opaque object, or anything behind the surface you're scanning. As such, using it to explore a 3D environment involves the repeated discovery that any objects you've painted into existence are hollow when viewed from other angles. In encouraging you to hold yourself and the perspective motionless, the right-click full screen scan also subtly has you thinking that you're printing out a 2D photograph, but then you move, and the flat illustration twitches into three dimensions. 
</p>
<figure data-count="2" role="group">
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/4_r2XEs3P.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
</figure>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/2_tX06rF6.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
</figure>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>KenForest / Rock Paper Shotgun</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
I like the unassuming delicacy of these chills, the way they emerge 'organically' from the central conceit. There are more outright horror touches, mind you: the scanner is the only way to see, and sometimes, it reveals things you'd rather have left in the dark. There's a top-down rotatable level map view on tab which somehow doesn't quite ruin the mood. Studying my luminous forays from on high, I was reminded of Arnie following the Predator's green blood through the jungle.
</p>
<p>
Still, I enjoy the demo more as an artistic tool than a horror game. I like narrowing the beams and drilling a density of detail through trees, then circling around to analyse the quiet violence of my vision as it spills out from more intensely illuminated surfaces, closer at hand, to stray puffs of photons in the depths of the forest. I wish more games drew this much attention to the properties of light. Find the LiDAR Exploration Program demo on <a href="https://kenforest.itch.io/lidar-exploration-program">Itch</a> and <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1882190/LiDAR_Exploration_Program/">Steam</a>. KenForest's other projects include <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dont-mind-me-im-simply-microwaving-an-instant-frog-in-creature-packets">Creature Packets</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40,000: Darktide's Nightmares and Visions update adds in a sprinkle of Left 4 Dead, and you can try it out now]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/warhammer-40000-darktides-nightmares-and-visions-update-adds-in-a-sprinkle-of-left-4-dead-and-you-can-try-it-out-now</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40-000-darktides-nightmares-and-visions-update-adds-in-a-sprinkle-of-left-4-dead-and-you-can-try-it-out-now.1144794/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/warhammer-40000-darktides-nightmares-and-visions-update-adds-in-a-sprinkle-of-left-4-dead-and-you-can-try-it-out-now<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Fancy a bit of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/left-4-dead">Left 4 Dead</a> in your <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/warhammer-40000-darktide">Warhammer 40,000: Darktide</a>? Oh, well that's convenient, as the game's Nightmare and Visions update just dropped today, adding in Mortis Trials, a new wave-based game mode. The wave-based nature really is what it says on the tin: scores of enemies come after you round after round, but in this mode you'll get Indulgences, which is just lorespeak for upgrades you can unlock on different runs.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
You'll also start with an archetype that lets you deal elemental damage like electricity or fire, while doing more damage to electrified or burning enemies. Another archetype simply lets you switch or reload weapons faster, and you get a second small buff for the second wave (there's a total of 12 to get through, which doesn't sound easy, but I suppose that's the point). There are also objective waves that take place on the 3rd, 6th, and 9th waves, but you'll have to play to find out what those are like.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Warhammer 40,000: Darktide - Nightmares and Visions Update | Release Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/z_OKJUZKHe8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Warhammer 40,000: Darktide - Nightmares and Visions Update | Release Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/z_OKJUZKHe8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/z_OKJUZKHe8?autoplay=1" title="Warhammer 40,000: Darktide - Nightmares and Visions Update | Release Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z_OKJUZKHe8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
Developer <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/fatsharkgames">Fatshark</a> released the <a href="https://www.playdarktide.com/news/nightmares-visions-patch-notes">full patch notes</a> for the new update earlier today too, and if you want me to list out every single change, you can jog on, because it's massive. There are a few changes I'll highlight though, just to help you out a bit. For one, Havoc is receiving campaigns, with plans to release new ones with "different mutators and a rotating mission pool" alongside major updates.
</p>
<p>
There's some quality of life changes too, like DLSS 4 support now being a feature in the game, and there's been a bunch of weapon balance tweaks too - possibly worth having a closer look at if your weapon of choice has been affected.
</p>
<p>
It's also worth noting that Warhammer 40,000: Darktide is <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1361210/Warhammer_40000_Darktide/">half off on Steam right now too</a>. Quite convenient with this new update, 'ey?

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wildgate is a spacey crew-based shooter from the same ex-Blizzard folks working on Sunderfolk]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wildgate-is-a-spacey-crew-based-shooter-from-the-same-ex-blizzard-folks-working-on-sunderfolk</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wildgate-is-a-spacey-crew-based-shooter-from-the-same-ex-blizzard-folks-working-on-sunderfolk.1144755/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wildgate-is-a-spacey-crew-based-shooter-from-the-same-ex-blizzard-folks-working-on-sunderfolk<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/wildgate.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Moonshot Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/blizzard-co-founder-opens-new-studios-with-loads-of-ex-blizzard-folks">Back in 2020</a>, co-founder and former CEO of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/blizzard">Blizzard</a> Mike Morhaime formed Dreamhaven, essentially Blizzard 2, albeit a bit more explicit in the fact that it has different studios working under it. One of said studios, Secret Door, is currently working on co-op strategy game <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/sunderfolk">Sunderfolk</a>, and today as part of a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0Uwjr0raU7k&amp;ab_channel=thegameawards">showcase</a> presented by The Game Awards, the other studio Moonshot Games revealed its first title: Wildgate, a sci-fi shooter that sees you piloting ships around space looking for loot as you face off against other players.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
The way it works is that in each match, you and crews of other players are after an artifact, each of you with your own ship you use to get to your destination. Sometimes you'll have to use said ship to fight against other players, though while the reveal trailer offered a look at space combat, it wasn't too detailed. It looks like all the ships have shields and turrets to shoot at each other with, and you can even disembark your own ship to go and board an enemies' one. Looks pretty neat honestly! Not sure how I feel about it being match based, but hey, can't win 'em all.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Wildgate | Reveal Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/f2jvZzieaBo?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Wildgate | Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/f2jvZzieaBo?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/f2jvZzieaBo?autoplay=1" title="Wildgate | Reveal Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f2jvZzieaBo" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
Your crew is made up of prospectors, like that one guy voiced by Kelsey Grammer in Toy Story 2, all of which have different abilities and tools, typical hero shooter kind of thing. It looks like there's a few different gun options, and even tools to put out fires on your ship. 
</p>
<p>
Again, it doesn't look like there's necessarily anything massively unique on the shooting front, there's only so many different ways you can do a shooter, but it looks fun enough, and I like the character designs. One prospector looks like some kind of axolotl thing in a fishbowl with robot limbs? That'll probably be my main day one.
</p>
<p>
Wildgate doesn't currently have a release date other than sometime this year, i.e. 2025, but you can <a href="https://playtest.playwildgate.com/signup/communitypreview/account">sign-up to playtest it</a> if the trailer piques your interest.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>