<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 13:57:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This week in PC games: Wuchang, Killing Floor 3, open world spirit biking and some eerie glyph puzzles]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-week-in-pc-games-wuchang-killing-floor-3-open-world-spirit-biking-and-some-eerie-glyph-puzzles</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-week-in-pc-games-wuchang-killing-floor-3-open-world-spirit-biking-and-some-eerie-glyph-puzzles.1248664/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>What we're feeding the Maw</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun / 505 Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Sometimes our patron news deity the Maw opens beneath my feet like a toothy sinkhole, and sometimes it leaps up and slobbers all over my face like an exhilarated labradoodle after a weekend at the kennels.</p>
<p>Down boy! Down, you ridiculous creature! Stop putting your tentacles in my ear. Who wanna biscuit? Do you wanna biscuit? Well, you can't have a biscuit - the only things I have to offer are new PC games. Here's what's coming down the chute this week.</p><!--more-->
<h2>Monday 21st July</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-king-is-watching">The King Is Watching</a>, but perhaps his gaze will be lured away by <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3214400/Rainbow_Cloud_A_GAY_RPG/">Rainbow Cloud: A Gay RPG</a>, which demo players have described as a "homoerotic Castlevania".</li>
<li>It's never too early in the week to play a horror game. <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1729740/Luto/">Luto</a> is about the dread of going outside, while <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3076240/True_Nightmare__Roadside_Safe/">True Nightmare: Roadside Cafe</a> is part of a growing category of chillers featuring lonely service jobs.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Tuesday 22nd July</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3504780/Wildgate/">Wildgate</a> is the latest "Sea Of Thieves in space". Based on the trailer, I rate it six warps out of Picard.</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1332180/CIPHER_ZERO/">Cipher Zero</a> has you solving glyph puzzles that appear to correspond to evolving pixel landscapes and a mood of mounting historical cataclysm. Slight Gorogoa vibes.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hell-clock">Hell Clock</a> is a dark fantasy action roguelite inspired by the "War of Canudos" in 19th century Brazil. </li>
</ul>
<h2>Wednesday 23rd July</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/ghost-bike">Wheel World</a> - the latest from Nidhogg devs Messhof - is an open world biking sim about saving spirits and crafting the slickest bloody Penny Farthing known to science. </li>
</ul>
<h2>Thursday 24th July</h2>
<ul>
<li>It's time to bosh some peacocking bosses in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/wuchang-fallen-feathers">Wuchang: Fallen Feathers</a> (pictured in header) and kill exactly three floors in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/killing-floor-3">Killing Floor 3</a>. </li>
<li>Today's Bemused Chin-Stroking Award goes to <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2454960/The_Great_Villainess_Strategy_of_Lily/">The Great Villainess: Strategy of Lily</a>, which is a strategy RPG in which you fly around in an airship-sized Twitch feed you can use to distract enemy generals into submission.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Friday 25th July</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2752180/No_Sleep_For_Kaname_Date__From_AI_THE_SOMNIUM_FILES/">No Sleep For Kaname Date</a> is the latest bizarro detective RPG from AI: The Somnium Files creators Spike Chunsoft.</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3570070/Paddle_Paddle_Paddle/">Paddle Paddle Paddle</a> is here to kill off any friendships left standing by <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/chained-together">Chained Together</a>.</li>
</ul><p>


I can't remember what the rest of the RPS editorial team are up to this week because I spent the whole morning meeting dying for the loo. I believe there are reviews, guides, news and features in the works. My plans include some tentative follow-up necromancy. How about you?

        </p></div>

        </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-week-in-pc-games-wuchang-killing-floor-3-open-world-spirit-biking-and-some-eerie-glyph-puzzles]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The current developers of Vampire: The Masquerade - Bloodlines 2 are going "fully" indie again]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-current-developers-of-vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-are-going-fully-indie-again</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-current-developers-of-vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-are-going-fully-indie-again.1248622/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Still Wakes The Deep creators The Chinese Room secure management buyout</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Secret Mode</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>A few of the UK's fanciest former indie developers are going indie again... with help from venture capital. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/still-wakes-the-deep">Still Wakes The Deep</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dear-esther">Dear Esther</a> creators The Chinese Room have slipped the surly bonds of former parent company Sumo Digital in the course of a management buyout, with "facilitation" from Hiro Capital. Now "fully independent", they're focussing on the creation of original games, with two unannounced projects in the offing once they've finished developing <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2">Vampire: The Masquerade - Bloodlines 2</a>.</p><!--more-->
<p>Founded in 2007 by a group of academically minded <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/half-life-2">Half-Life 2</a> modders, The Chinese Room made waves initially with Dear Esther, an introspective first-person exploration game that emphasised environmental storytelling over mechanics, aggressively and affectionately described as a "walking sim".</p>
<p>They later worked with Frictional on Amnesia: A Machine For Pigs - sequel to The Dark Descent and perhaps the best-written Amnesia game - and Sony's Santa Monica Studio on <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/everybodys-gone-to-the-rapture">Everybody's Gone To The Rapture</a>, in which you chase golden phantoms around a sorrowful English village. I once <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2020/dec/08/a-video-game-garden-the-delights-of-virtual-botany">took a botanist on a walking tour of Rapture</a> and we both thought the flowers were excellent. I also love the soundtrack, which makes me want to wander off into the hills of Shropshire and die tragically of, nudge-wink, "Spanish flu".</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Mourning Tree" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cREJyD1eN00?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Mourning Tree</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cREJyD1eN00?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/cREJyD1eN00?autoplay=1" title="The Mourning Tree">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cREJyD1eN00" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>The Chinese Room were acquired by Sumo Digital in 2018, who were themselves later acquired by Tencent. The developers' most recent project is Still Wakes The Deep, a creature feature set aboard a Scottish oil rig: in his <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/still-wakes-the-deep-review">review</a>, Brendy concluded that it "doesn't push the boat out but still excels within its genre". Sadly, there has been some belt-tightening of late. Sumo <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/layoffs-at-vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-studio-as-paradox-promise-rpg-will-still-release-in-october">confirmed layoffs at The Chinese Room and elsewhere in their operations this June</a>, as part of plans to move away from original game creation and "focus exclusively on development services for partners".</p>
<p>According to a PR email this week, Sumo put The Chinese Room up for sale earlier this year, with the expectation that it would be sold to private equity or an overseas buyer. The management buyout ensures that the studio will remain UK-owned, according to the email, though it's not clear how exactly Hiro Capital (who are based in London and Luxembourg) have "faciliated" the deal, and what they'll expect in return. Compare and contrast how <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/endless-legends-how-amplitude-bought-their-independence-back-from-sega">Amplitude bought their independence back from Sega</a>.</p>
<p>According to studio director Ed Daly, "this management buyout allows us to scratch the creative itch of continuing to work on new, original intellectual property, but also to partner with other studios on other projects when they fit in with our vision." Best of luck with it all, peeps. Please make another game about a subterranean hellfactory.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-current-developers-of-vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-are-going-fully-indie-again]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>