<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 09:31:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Embrace your messy, cringey teenage emo years in rhythm game X visual novel I Write Games Not Tragedies]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/embrace-your-messy-cringey-teenage-emo-years-in-rhythm-game-x-visual-novel-i-write-games-not-tragedies</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/embrace-your-messy-cringey-teenage-emo-years-in-rhythm-game-x-visual-novel-i-write-games-not-tragedies.1354858/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/i-write-games-not-tragedies.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/i-write-games-not-tragedies.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/i-write-games-not-tragedies.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/i-write-games-not-tragedies.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/i-write-games-not-tragedies.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/i-write-games-not-tragedies.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/i-write-games-not-tragedies.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/i-write-games-not-tragedies.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/i-write-games-not-tragedies.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Studio Wife</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
I'm not sure I've ever been so quickly transported back in time than I have in I Write Games Not Tragedies. It's not that I completely relate to what takes place in the game, but its sense of place, of atmosphere and feeling, is one I understand in my soul. The emo amongst you have probably already caught on to the vibe with its title, and for those of you that haven't, the game's aesthetics, writing, and soundscape certainly will.
</p>
<p>
Set in some nowhere British town in the distant past of 2009, you play as Ash, a babby goth who thinks everything in his life is unbearably terrible, and that everyone around him is insufferable and deserving of his (internally narrated) belittlement. The popular kids are much too popular, his parents won't let him hang out on the roof in the rain, and of course there's school, yuck! No one understands him, but when he puts on his red Skullcandy headphones (what a throwback), he can escape into the world of music… which is where this <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-10-best-visual-novels-on-pc">visual novel</a> game morphs into a rhythm game, uh, game.
</p>
<p>
Now, this isn't a revolution of rhythm game mechanics. There are three buttons to tap, and you must time your taps to certain words in the lyrics of whatever song is playing. You can jam out at certain moments, but in the demo I couldn't get that to work, a point I'm sure could be solved with some updated tutorialisation.
</p>
<p>
I'm not particularly bothered by the fairly lackluster rhythm mechanics because of the ways it commits to itself in so many other ways. The soundtrack, for one, is composed of tracks from indie punk artists from the UK, Japan, and Hong Kong, which itself is a thematically appropriate commitment to make. The backgrounds look like they were made on Paint circa 2009 (complementary), but there are also cringey anime drawings of Ash's classmates, as well as some of his himself where he looks much too cool. This pencilly, sketchy, crayony vibe translates to certain bits of character art too, albeit a bit more refined, and very much in the vein of something like Scott Pilgrim.
</p><p>
That feeling of cringe permeates a lot of the demo, and presumably the rest of the game. Ash kind of sucks, specifically in the way that teenagers sucked in the late 2000s. He drinks WKD at some canal with a boy he clearly has a crush on, a drink so notoriously unable to get you drunk unless you are literally 14, and one anyone would be mocked for drinking as an adult. I was not Ash, but I've known Ash, and I have cringed at Ash.
</p>
<p>
In the years since knowing my own Ash, or Ashes I supposed, I've since acquired some rose tinted goggles thick enough that at least allow me to look back on such a time and chuckle a little bit, even if it's also a bit embarrassing to think about. That same feeling comes through in I Write Games Not Tragedies, and that might not be for everyone. If you've ever listened to My Chemical Romance and you grew up in some nowhere British town, however, you probably owe it to yourself to give it a go.
</p>
<p>
I Write Games Not Tragedies is <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3396670/I_Write_Games_Not_Tragedies/">available on Steam now</a>.

</p>

        </div>

      </article>




        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/embrace-your-messy-cringey-teenage-emo-years-in-rhythm-game-x-visual-novel-i-write-games-not-tragedies]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horizon was always thought about as a multiplayer game, says studio director, which speaks volumes about modern day Sony]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/horizon-was-always-thought-about-as-a-multiplayer-game-says-studio-director-which-speaks-volumes-about-modern-day-sony</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/horizon-was-always-thought-about-as-a-multiplayer-game-says-studio-director-which-speaks-volumes-about-modern-day-sony.1354840/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"There is much more to come"</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/horizon-zero-dawn-thunderjaw-fight.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/horizon-zero-dawn-thunderjaw-fight.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/horizon-zero-dawn-thunderjaw-fight.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/horizon-zero-dawn-thunderjaw-fight.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/horizon-zero-dawn-thunderjaw-fight.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/horizon-zero-dawn-thunderjaw-fight.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/horizon-zero-dawn-thunderjaw-fight.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/horizon-zero-dawn-thunderjaw-fight.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/horizon-zero-dawn-thunderjaw-fight.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>PlayStation PC LLC</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
I think <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/horizon-zero-dawn">Horizon Zero Dawn</a> was much more of a turning point for Sony than most people really discuss. The argument for PlayStation used to be its exclusives, those tentpole games like Uncharted, Ratchet and Clank, LittleBigPlanet, the list does go on but you get the point. On the PS5, completely original first-party games feel few and far between, as Sony has joined in on the whole intellectual property above all else train that every other company has hopped aboard. So hearing Guerilla Games' studio director Jan-Bart van Beek say the Horizon series was always thought about as a multiplayer game feels like the last piece of the puzzle has been inserted.
</p>
<p>
Here's what van Beek said specifically, in referencing the just announced Horizon MMO <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/horizon-steel-frontiers-an-mmorpg-twist-on-sonys-series-about-plinking-robo-animals-with-arrows-is-coming-to-pc">Steel Frontiers</a>: "From the first moment we imagined Horizon, we always thought about it as a multiplayer game. LEGO Horizon Adventures was our first small step, with Steel Frontiers we’re taking a bigger one. There is much more to come, and we’re excited to show you what is coming."
</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>From the first moment we imagined Horizon, we always thought about it as a multiplayer game. </p><p>LEGO Horizon Adventures was our first small step, with Steel Frontiers we’re taking a bigger one. There is much more to come, and we’re excited to show you what is coming. <a href="https://t.co/acdlCWJPG9">https://t.co/acdlCWJPG9</a></p></div>— Jan-Bart van Beek (@janbartvanbeek) <a href="https://twitter.com/janbartvanbeek/status/1989193333491790157?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 14, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>
Apologies for taking a curmudgeonly attitude towards this, but of course that's how it was always thought about! Well, assuming this is true across the board. I imagine there are plenty who worked on the original that won't feel that way. The top brass feeling that way does make sense, however. Ultimately the goal isn't striving to make something fresh, but something that can keep you playing, and presumably paying, for longer.
</p>
<p>
Live service is constantly on Sony's mind, and it is pretty clear that multiplayer is on Guerilla's. Clearing up some confusion, industry secrets knower <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jasonschreier.bsky.social/post/3m5jd6otif22v">Jason Schreier took to Bluesky</a> to say that the NCSoft developer Horizon Steel Frontiers MMO isn't that rumoured - <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/over-12-minutes-of-early-horizon-multiplayer-game-footage-leaks-online">and leaked</a> - Horizon Multiplayer game. That one is still in the works at Guerilla, and is apparently their next big project.
</p><p>
But it's this reality where Horizon was supposedly always meant to be multiplayer that my feelings on the original being a turning point come from. A mobile-only Ratchet and Clank multiplayer shooter was <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AlblXRS14Mg">just announced this week</a>, for heaven's sake. As much of a farce as the Sony first-party game was, at least every now and then it would offer up something new. Ah well, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pilot-a-shrimp-and-do-battle-with-giant-eldritch-sea-monsters-in-the-armored-core-adjacent-shrimp-game?view=comments">at least we have Shrimp Game</a>.

</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/horizon-was-always-thought-about-as-a-multiplayer-game-says-studio-director-which-speaks-volumes-about-modern-day-sony]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blue Prince is a game full of secrets, and its developer has no intention of telling you if you've solved them all]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/blue-prince-is-a-game-full-of-secrets-and-its-developer-has-no-intention-of-telling-you-if-youve-solved-them-all</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/blue-prince-is-a-game-full-of-secrets-and-its-developer-has-no-intention-of-telling-you-if-youve-solved-them-all.1354777/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/blue-prince-screenshot.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/blue-prince-screenshot.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/blue-prince-screenshot.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/blue-prince-screenshot.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/blue-prince-screenshot.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/blue-prince-screenshot.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/blue-prince-screenshot.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/blue-prince-screenshot.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/blue-prince-screenshot.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Dogubomb</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Video games don't have mysteries any more. There are too many people and too much internet to allow for such a thing, anything without an answer can, must, and will be solved by someone, often in a timeframe faster than developers expect. So I appreciate when developers refuse to divulge details, or indulge individuals in their desire to know exactly how much they have on their checklist, one such developer being Tonda Ros of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-blue-prince">Blue Prince</a> developer Dogubomb.
</p>
<p>
In response to a question from <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/puzzle/i-will-probably-never-fully-acknowledge-whether-or-not-everything-has-been-solved-says-blue-prince-creator-there-are-certainly-mysteries-still-in-the-game/">PC Gamer</a> regarding whether there are any mysteries left to be found in the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-puzzle-games">puzzle</a> game, Ros said that there certainly are, and that "there will probably always be some mysteries in the game. And in order to preserve that mystery, I will probably never fully acknowledge whether or not everything has been solved." Music to my ears!
</p>
<p>
Ros goes further, saying, "I know that for some games, they'll have, like, a canary in the coal mine, right? I think it's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/animal-well">Animal Well</a> that has a website that's like, 'Has everything been found yet?' That kind of serves as a canary." As it turns out, such a website does exist, it's <a href="http://haseverythinginanimalwellbeenfoundyet.com/">haseverythinginanimalwellbeenfoundyet.com</a>, and I'll let you click to find out what the answer is.
</p>
<p>
For Ros, that question of whether everything has been found in Blue Prince is one he thinks people will always ask. "The only thing I will say is that there are still mysteries," he said. "Not to say that they're necessarily things that can be solved in definitive ways, but they are things that you can piece together answers to, oftentimes intuitively."
</p><p>
I truly hope this is something we see more of from developers going forwards. There is such a massive inclination towards complete and utter player satisfaction, but to me there is nothing more satisfying than to be left wanting more, a reason to keep coming back, even if the gaps between return trips end up being days, weeks, months or years at a time. Lay unto me your mysterious developers! I may not solve them, but I will think about them.
</p>
<p>
And while you're here, I'd like to remind you that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-team-behind-blue-prince-puts-out-a-call-to-get-one-of-the-puzzle-games-devs-a-life-saving-kidney">one of the lead playtesters on Blue Prince is in desperate need of a kidney</a>, something you genuinely might be able to help with.

</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/blue-prince-is-a-game-full-of-secrets-and-its-developer-has-no-intention-of-telling-you-if-youve-solved-them-all]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Concord lives! Or, lived, as community efforts to revive it already appear to be on hold after some DMCA strikes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/concord-lives-or-lived-as-community-efforts-to-revive-it-already-appear-to-be-on-hold-after-some-dmca-strikes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/concord-lives-or-lived-as-community-efforts-to-revive-it-already-appear-to-be-on-hold-after-some-dmca-strikes.1354738/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Can't catch a break, this one</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/concord-headline_tYrsdqn.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/concord-headline_tYrsdqn.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/concord-headline_tYrsdqn.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/concord-headline_tYrsdqn.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/concord-headline_tYrsdqn.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/concord-headline_tYrsdqn.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/concord-headline_tYrsdqn.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/concord-headline_tYrsdqn.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/concord-headline_tYrsdqn.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Sony</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
I do have to admit that bringing up <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/concord">Concord</a> feels like digging up a dead dog that perished in a horrendous, preventable accident, but it feels important given how quickly it died and what the means for how we engage with it. You see, it seems that this week the largely panned hero <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-fps-games">shooter</a> was revived through community-run custom servers. Except it seems like this may be over before it truly begins.
</p>
<p>
As reported by <a href="https://thegamepost.com/sony-concord-playable-again-custom-servers/">The Game Post</a>, developers that go by the names Red, open_wizard, and gwog opened up a Discord server where you could try out Concord through said custom servers. This is apparently possible through the trio recreating the game's backend API and thusly reverse engineering it. Some videos were even posted to YouTube showing off these custom servers in action, which is where things have started to go legally iffy.
</p>
<p>
Both videos, as again reported by <a href="https://thegamepost.com/sony-cracks-down-concord-custom-servers-dmca-takedowns/">The Game Post</a>, were taken down through a copyright claim filed by MarkScan Enforcement, most likely on Sony's behalf. I say most likely, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/nightmare-kart-is-getting-a-free-dlc-but-sonys-plague-ridden-rats-have-come-for-bloodborne-psx">as MarkScan did the exact same thing to Bloodborne PSX</a> on behalf of Sony earlier this year. It's not surprising the same thing has been done to Concord here, especially as the custom servers won't have much legal ground to stand on.
</p>
<p>
It should be noted that these takedowns are for the videos themselves. So far nothing seems to have been done about the custom servers themselves, but in a statement in the Discord for the project, developer Red said "Due to worrying legal action we’ve decided to pause invites for the time being." At the time of writing, any links to the Discord server no longer work.
</p><p>
This all feels pertinent to the ongoing situation with <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/stop-killing-games-uk-petition-has-been-debated-in-parliament-the-law-works-but-companies-may-need-to-communicate-better">Stop Killing Games</a>, a campaign that seeks to "challenge the legality of publishers destroying video games they have sold to customers." Personally, I don't love the consumerist angle to the campaign, but there is something to be said of the need to protect online-only games from certain doom. 
</p>
<p>
Games like Concord are toys, you smash action figures together in them for ridiculous results, yet you can only do it in the way you've been told to. That stinks! I often think of the success of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/team-fortress-2">Team Fortress 2</a> in particular, and the playful space Valve created with it that allowed for many a machinima. That feels like more important a reason to preserve online games, to allow for a freer sense of play once the corporate overlords have stopped making money from their toy business. Let's see how things play out for new, slightly less legal Concord.

</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/concord-lives-or-lived-as-community-efforts-to-revive-it-already-appear-to-be-on-hold-after-some-dmca-strikes]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>