<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 10:55:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Identify the scary numbers in macrodata refinement with this free Severance-inspired game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/identify-the-scary-numbers-in-macrodata-refinement-with-this-free-severance-inspired-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/identify-the-scary-numbers-in-macrodata-refinement-with-this-free-severance-inspired-game.1086753/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/identify-the-scary-numbers-in-macrodata-refinement-with-this-free-severance-inspired-game<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/lumon-game.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Mark Gomersall</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>As much as I'd like to dredge up an old RPS tradition and write "Severance is back!" repeatedly for 500 words, I'll resist the urge and instead just slide a nice free game over to your side of the table, hidden underneath an inconspicuous pile of photocopies. <a href="https://tydes.itch.io/lumon">Lumon by Mark Gomersall</a> is a free number clicker based the fourth best television show ever made (Succession, Hannibal, Scavenger's Reign, discuss). It's not a rip-roaring videogame time or anything, but it is cute. More importantly, it's topical. <em>More</em> importantly, it means I get to write "Severance is back!" a bunch. It's back! It is!</p>
<!--more-->
<p>The idea here is that you colour match floating numbers with your mouse cursor before exporting them. It's neither challenging or exciting, but it is mildly meditative in the way that all highly repetitive drudgery is, and I imagine that's the point. The show's own macrodata refinement is itself a play on gamified busywork, complete with addictive-looking animated flourishes like a magnifying glass cursor and a satisfying crate-opening action. It's the archetypal <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bullshit_Jobs">bullshit job</a>, but with a lingering mystery to whether the data is actually significant in some way.</p>
<p>Lumon is the only game I've found that's a direct tribute to Severance, although there are a few others either inspired by the show or that inspired it directly.<a href="https://unnamedgamecompany.itch.io/fractured"> Fractured</a>, for one, is a TTRPG with a very similar concept. Creator Dan Erickson has also <a href="https://www.inverse.com/entertainment/severance-apple-tv-plus-interview-dan-erickson-ben-stiller-adam-scott">spoken about</a> the direct influence of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-stanley-parable">The Stanley Parable</a> on the show. There are also approximately a scary number's worth of games based on creepypasta-adjacent Severance influence <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Backrooms">The Backrooms</a>.</p>
<p>As for the show, I need to sit with the latest episode a bit more, but I did enjoy it. There's a fun echo of the idea of capitalism subsuming critique in Lumon making the team's uprising part of its own corporate legend. Also, the camera work was immaculate.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dino Crisis-esque horror Code Violet won't be coming to PC because the risk of "vulgar" mods isn't worth the "extra money"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dino-crisis-esque-horror-code-violet-wont-be-coming-to-pc-because-the-risk-of-vulgar-mods-isnt-worth-the-extra-money</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dino-crisis-esque-horror-code-violet-wont-be-coming-to-pc-because-the-risk-of-vulgar-mods-isnt-worth-the-extra-money.1086705/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dino-crisis-esque-horror-code-violet-wont-be-coming-to-pc-because-the-risk-of-vulgar-mods-isnt-worth-the-extra-money<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Diplodocus's big naturals</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/code-violet.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>TeamKill Media</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Ok, let's get it out of the way up top: I probably won't be losing any sleep over dinosaur <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-horror-games">horror </a>game <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/code-violet">Code Violet</a> not coming to PC either. While I've still got a pavlovian response to anything that reminds me even a little of Capcom's sadly abandoned <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dino-crisis">Dino Crisis</a> series, the trailer below doesn't inspire all that much confidence this one will pick up the mantle.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Code Violet - Announcement Trailer | PS5 Games" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gDFBxMOcp4k?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Code Violet - Announcement Trailer | PS5 Games</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gDFBxMOcp4k?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/gDFBxMOcp4k?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gDFBxMOcp4k" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>What's interesting here though is the developer TeamKill Media's reasoning for keeping their game away from your desktop <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/henry-cavills-good-but-hes-got-nothing-on-these-five-celebrity-pc-builds?view=comments">thinking telly</a>. As spotted by <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/news/2025/01/code-violet-takes-aim-at-dinosaur-horror-in-june-on-ps5">Pushsquare</a>, Here's their <a href="https://x.com/TeamKillMedia/status/1880780993813987541">post in full</a>:</p>
<p>"For those asking us about a PC version of Code Violet… the reason we are not bringing it to PC is we do not want anyone modding vulgar versions of the main character as well as other characters in the game. We hold our voice actresses and actors with high regard, as well as our artistic vision for the game and story and reject any form of destroying that with sexual mods. Making a joke out of our art and possibly tarnishing the reputation of our voice actresses and actors is not worth the extra money we can make."</p><p>I…don't know what to make of it, honestly. As far as reasoning goes, it isn't unprecedented. The talent agency for <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/judgment">Judgement</a> star Takuya Kimura <a href="https://kotaku.com/report-judgment-series-is-ending-over-pc-version-disag-1847271300">got in a tangle with SEGA</a> over not wanting to have the series ported to PC for similar reasons. In 2021,<a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/cdpr-shuts-down-cyberpunk-mod-that-let-players-have-sex-with-keanu-reeves/"> CD Projekt shut down</a> a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/cyberpunk-2077">Cyberpunk 2077 </a>mod that reskinned a boneable joytoy to look like Keanu Reeves ("It's always nice when it's nice" was Reeves' own response.)</p>
<p>So, the wording of the tweet focusing on the actors might suggest a similar case of talent agency reticence to that of Judgement. And, hey, if this is genuinely a case of a developer sticking to their guns about their vision for their work to the point where it excludes an entire massive market, then fair play. They <em>probably</em> could have worded in such a way that doesn't suggest the entire PC owning market is a bunch of slavering boob goblins. But then again, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/balatro-mod-jimbos-big-naturals-is-a-lot-funnier-and-safer-for-work-than-it-sounds">Jimbo's Big Naturals</a> suggests otherwise.</p>
<p>Teamkill previously released dino FPS <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3200540/Son_and_Bone/">Son and Bone</a> to Steam. The only mod I could find was <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/sonandbone?tab=latest">this one</a>, which removes the splash screen. Maybe they're just really, really proud of Code Violet's splash screen?</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>