<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 09:23:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Train 2 rolls up with a release date]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/monster-train-2-rolls-up-with-a-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-train-2-rolls-up-with-a-release-date.1151787/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/monster-train-2-rolls-up-with-a-release-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>The last one was rail-y good</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/monster-train-2-release-date-announced-2.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Big Fan Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The makers of cardy <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-roguelike-games-pc">roguelike</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/monster-train-2">Monster Train 2</a> announced a release date yesterday, revealing that it'll be pulling into Steam libraries and honking its big "all aboard" horn in less than two months. Do you have the capacity to allow another deckbuilder into the overcrowded dining car of your brain? I probably don't. But I do have fond memories of the first game's crunchy runs and over-the-top card combos. Hmmm, maybe another rail trip or two hundred <em>would</em> be nice. </p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Monster Train 2 - Official Release Date Announce Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VjUmYGhzYec?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Monster Train 2 - Official Release Date Announce Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VjUmYGhzYec?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/VjUmYGhzYec?autoplay=1" title="Monster Train 2 - Official Release Date Announce Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VjUmYGhzYec" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>The release date is May 21st, said developers Shiny Shoe in <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1102190/view/502820742193219263">a Steam post</a>. They shared the news on April 1st, and so felt the need to clarify that this was an actual factual release date announcement - not a silly April Fools jest. They opted for a straightforward announcement because they didn't want to do "a disservice to the entire dating sim genre" by revealing a shallow <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/monster-train">Monster Train</a> dating sim spinoff called "You Stole My Pyre Heart".</p>
<p>"This does not exist," they say, "please do not ask for it. We’re giving you Monster Train 2. Please."</p>
<p>The sequel will involve a similar violent train ride as the first game, in which you essentially play three or four games of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/slay-the-spire">Slay The Spire</a> at once. But whereas you previously fought as the demons of hell against the angels of heaven, this time you'll combine the warring forces to battle a new enemy - the ancient Titans. </p>
<p>It's set to include "five all-new clans, dozens of new cards, and surprises of all shapes and sizes". This includes "Room" cards which will have some effect on the space you're fighting within. You'll also be able to get "new parts for your train and customize it to suit your personal style". A fashionable new cow catcher perhaps?</p>
<p>The first Monster Train was a maximalist numberwang of flashing delights, according to Matt (RPS in peace), who said it was "at least as good as Slay The Spire." Here's a snippet of thoughts I enjoy from his <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/monster-train-review">Monster Train review</a>. </p>
<blockquote>I'm not comfortable saying it's outright better. Not yet, at least, but I will say this: before Monster Train came along I couldn't see myself ever obsessing over a deckbuilder in the same way that I did with the Spire. It seemed too immaculate to meaningfully improve on, but there are plenty of specific ways in which the Train does exactly that.</blockquote>
<p>Good thing you can play <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/monster-train-2-revealed-for-2025-release-and-you-can-play-the-demo-right-now">a demo of the upcoming sequel</a> already, if you, like Matt and I, are inclined to monstering with numbers. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Schedule I creator seems to have vastly undersold how much content is in his new Steam hit]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/schedule-i-creator-seems-to-have-vastly-undersold-how-much-content-is-in-his-new-steam-hit</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/schedule-i-creator-seems-to-have-vastly-undersold-how-much-content-is-in-his-new-steam-hit.1151757/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/schedule-i-creator-seems-to-have-vastly-undersold-how-much-content-is-in-his-new-steam-hit<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>I ate a weed once but I'm better now</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/schedule-1-gun.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>TVGS</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>There are few things more heartwarming than a solo developer seeing breakout success, especially if their game is a wholesome testament to community spirit, entrepreneurship, and innovative street cleaning solutions like <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/schedule-1">Schedule I</a>. Pretty close, though, is a solo developer pulling a 'Miyazaki lying about <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-boss-locations">Elden Ring</a>', and underselling just how big their game actually is in the run-up to release.</p>
<p>Developer Tyler has been updating the bud flinging <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-simulation-games">simulator</a> steadily throughout the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3205720/Schedule_I_Free_Sample/">demo release</a> and into the current early access, and they've also got a roadmap <a href="https://trello.com/b/VQQpru3F/schedule-i-roadmap">over at Trello here</a> (featuring: raids, parkour, jukeboxes, and controller support among other things). Some of the most relevant communication is actually in the Steam forums though. Tyler revealed yesterday that he's currently working on getting the game <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-steam-deck-games">Steam Deck</a> verified. It's also where he first revealed the full list of planned sellables that are now in the roadmap (Marijuana, Meth, Cocaine, Shrooms, MDMA, and delicious + cool Heroin), with plans to take community suggestions once they're all in.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Schedule I Release Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dUxiQ1qN0rg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Schedule I Release Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dUxiQ1qN0rg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/dUxiQ1qN0rg?autoplay=1" title="Schedule I Release Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dUxiQ1qN0rg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>But my favourite interaction I've seen is one where Tyler comments on a thread simply titled <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/app/3164500/discussions/1/591764116171920329/">"Raise The Price"</a>, where the poster offers 50 or even $100. "Haha I appreciate it but I think $20 is fair," writes Tyler. "On release I'm confident the game will be able to easily provide 15+ hours of entertainment (not just mindless grinding)".</p>
<p>I'm only a few hours into the demo myself, but as far as I can tell, that's either vastly underselling how much stuff there is to actually do in Schedule I, or vastly underestimating how much a good portion of the game's 30,000 or so players enjoy just pissing around in this thing. It's got that crackful combination of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/powerwash-simulator">PowerWash Sim</a> zen mixed with the steady, bankable progress of the the self-replicating factory genre. You buy one plant, earn enough for two plants, two plants turns into six plants. You automate certain tasks, you expand others. You can rope a co-op mate in to grind like mad, but you can also just explore the streets picking up litter at your own pace.</p>
<p>I'm actually left wondering if Tyler only ever intended that 15 hours, and the community has just found myriad unforeseen methods of piss aboutery. Either way, it's refreshing to see a game pull the rare underpromise, although I imagine its easier when you haven't got a publisher hounding you to promise free back massages and cures for depression with every copy.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/schedule-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption>Same. | <span>Image credit: <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun/TVGS</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Tyler also <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/3164500/view/546730838559032913">dropped a patch</a> yesterday. Blackjack dealers will no longer reveal their hand early to non-host players, an image I enjoy greatly. First person jackets are less janky now, and you'll have to work harder for the 'Master Chef' achievement, which was being awarded prematurely.</p>
<p>Are you playing [new viral Steam game we're required to write about to stay relevant and profitable in these dark times]? What do you think of [new viral Steam game we're required to write about to stay relevant and profitable in these dark times]? Would you…kiss [new viral Steam game we're required to write about to stay relevant and profitable in these dark times]? I'm half joking here, honestly. I think Schedule I is pretty good. It avoids the self-seriousness of other drug dealer sims I've seen while also having a bit more meat to it than just "eh, drugs are funny, right? No need to make an actual game". Do add that parkour, though. I want to find out how high up I have to be to knock someone out with a cigarette butt.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>