<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 12:31:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2's latest patch lets you impale baddies with flags, as the bots take aim at the Democracy Space Station]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2s-latest-patch-lets-you-impale-baddies-with-flags-as-the-bots-take-aim-at-the-democracy-space-station</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/helldivers-2s-latest-patch-lets-you-impale-baddies-with-flags-as-the-bots-take-aim-at-the-democracy-space-station.1243842/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Plus, a bunch of weapon balancing tweaks</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Arrowhead</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Fresh <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/helldivers-2">Helldivers 2</a> patch alert. This one's patch 01.003.200, and it brings the latest in pointy flag tip technology, in addition to another round of weapon balancing. You'll need that flag stabbiness too, as the latest Galactic War twist has seen the Automatons try to wrestle control of Super Earth's space station.</p>
<p>Yep, stop trying to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2-players-are-pushing-to-rename-one-of-super-earths-cities-gun">rename a city 'Gun'</a> for five minutes, some stuff's going down in HD2 that you need to be clued in on, even if its just so you can run around the room cheering at how much more effective your Flame <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/sentry">Sentry</a>'ll now be.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>As has become the standard for Helldivers 2 updates that pass a certain beefiness threshold, patch 01.003.200 has both <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/553850/view/601909716088521243?l=english">notes</a> and a video explainer that sees design director Niklas Malmborg joined by senior designer Patrik 'Fluffy' Lasorta to talk through the changes.</p>
<p>First of all, the devs have slightly reduced the time it takes your diver to get up after ragdolling, as well as boosting chest injury bleed damage because the latter was previously at a level so low that "it appeared to have no effect". There are also a bunch of tweaks to weapons, mainly aimed at boosting how effective stunning, bayonet-induced stagger, and the firestarting capabilities of stuff like the aforementioned Flame Sentry are.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Helldivers 2 Patch Notes - Patch 01.003.200" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MK8T0QldvN4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Helldivers 2 Patch Notes - Patch 01.003.200</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MK8T0QldvN4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/MK8T0QldvN4?autoplay=1" title="Helldivers 2 Patch Notes - Patch 01.003.200">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MK8T0QldvN4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>By far the most important change, however, is the following one to the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldiver-2s-next-warbond-will-let-you-look-even-more-fascist-than-normal-adds-in-a-literal-sword">Masters of Ceremony warbond</a>'s One True Flag stratagem. "Thanks to some groundbreaking military research into pointier flag tips, the flag can now be proudly planted directly into enemies — dead or alive — ensuring the eternal colors of Super Earth are never tainted, only quenched by the blood of its foes," Arrowhead wrote, with Malmborg adding in the video that "a surprising amount of code" needed messing with to pull this off.</p>
<p>Hellpods and enemies have also undergone some tweaks, but I'm now gonna pivot to something far more urgent. A <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/1394621065032106064">fresh Major Order</a> dropped alongside this patch, and it's seeing the Automatons move to secure sites key to the running of the Democracy Space Station - which the divers have been using to help further Super Earth's goals since late last year.</p>
<p>Claorell, Tarsh, and Gaellivare are the planets folks are being tasked with holding to prevent the DSS being destroyed or falling into enemy hands. Arrowhead also notes that "enemy troop movements indicate this is only the first of several planned waves of attack", meaning "additional invasions are anticipated".</p>
<p>So, it looks like defending the floating hunk of metal is gonna be the next big goal.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2s-latest-patch-lets-you-impale-baddies-with-flags-as-the-bots-take-aim-at-the-democracy-space-station]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ZeniMax Union say they're fighting for staff left in limbo by Microsoft cancelling MMO as part of mass layoffs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/zenimax-union-say-theyre-fighting-for-staff-left-in-limbo-by-microsoft-cancelling-mmo-as-part-of-mass-layoffs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zenimax-union-say-theyre-fighting-for-staff-left-in-limbo-by-microsoft-cancelling-mmo-as-part-of-mass-layoffs.1243743/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"Undoubtedly, a future has been stolen from many of us"</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>ZeniMax Online Studios</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>As part of their <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/microsoft-layoffs-are-reportedly-underway-with-zenimax-and-king-employees-losing-their-jobs">mass layoffs</a> earlier this month, Microsoft cancelled an MMORPG that was in the works at The <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-online">Elder Scrolls Online</a> developers ZeniMax Online Studios. Now, the union that represents a number of devs left in limbo by that game's canning have issued an update about the process of fighting for their futures.</p>
<p>ZOS' MMO, codenamed Project Blackbird, wasn't the only game Microsoft pulled the plug on as they let go of around 9k people. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rares-mysterious-nature-sim-everwild-has-been-cancelled-as-part-of-xbox-mass-layoffs-according-to-reports">Rare's Everwild</a> and The Initiative's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/perfect-dark">Perfect Dark</a> reboot were also wiped out, with the latter studio being shuttered to boot.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>"Earlier this month, Microsoft indefinitely shelved an unannounced MMORPG at ZeniMax Online Studios, a shock to the 222 ZOSU-CWA developers working on the project," wrote ZeniMax Online Studios United (ZOSU), not to be confused with similarly named union ZeniMax Workers United. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/while-ceos-got-dressed-up-for-the-game-awards-461-workers-at-zenimax-online-studios-unionised">The former</a> represents web developers, designers, engineers, and graphic artists who were working on ESO and this unannounced MMO, while <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/zenimax-qa-workers-have-reached-a-tentative-contract-agreement-with-microsoft-paving-the-way-for-better-wages-and-more">the latter</a> is focused on QA staff.</p>
<p>"Undoubtedly, a future has been stolen from many of us and our community will never experience an amazing game," they continued, "However, despite discussions regarding the status of our employment, the fact is: we have not yet been laid off."</p>
<blockquote data-bluesky-cid="bafyreihmbu2b6jaytvr3wgwbge6nxsovljjay3jnze7ahfd3iz3vheppte" data-bluesky-embed-color-mode="system" data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:2qgtgzo6vqeqmwanve5fsnam/app.bsky.feed.post/3ltx2f4ffl22r"><div lang="en"><p>On July 2nd, Microsoft announced they were shelving an unannounced project at ZOS, a shock to over 200 of our devs working on the project.

However, despite discussions regarding the status of our employment, the fact is: we have not yet been laid off. 

Our full statement can be found below.</p><p><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:2qgtgzo6vqeqmwanve5fsnam/post/3ltx2f4ffl22r?ref_src=embed">[image or embed]</a></p></div>— ZOS United-CWA (<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:2qgtgzo6vqeqmwanve5fsnam?ref_src=embed">@zosunited.bsky.social</a>) <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:2qgtgzo6vqeqmwanve5fsnam/post/3ltx2f4ffl22r?ref_src=embed">14 July 2025 at 19:47</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><p>The current state of play the union outline is that their "worker-volunteers" are busy bargaining with Microsoft on behalf of those affected members.</p>
<p>"Where Microsoft has failed to support the talented craftspeople who have generated billions in revenue, our union has stepped up to provide clarity and support," they wrote. "It is true that a layoff may be in the future for some of our members. However, as a result of our organising, we are able to ensure that those impacted will be able to depart with dignity."</p>
<p>While being able to "depart with dignity" potentially being the best outcome some of these devs can hope for doesn't sound all that comforting, one can only imagine how much worse a situation these devs might be in without something in place to help fight their case.</p>
<p>We've reached out to Microsoft for comment.</p>
<p>Here's hoping that if any of these devs do end up out of a job, they are able to at least go with favourable exit terms and compensation. It's the least they'd deserve following, in the union's words, a situation that's meant "lives were upended <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/romero-games-have-completely-closed-doors-but-theres-still-hope-for-the-doom-creators-new-fps">without prior notice or communication</a> from Microsoft leadership".</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/zenimax-union-say-theyre-fighting-for-staff-left-in-limbo-by-microsoft-cancelling-mmo-as-part-of-mass-layoffs]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Finally, a game about a boy who thinks he's a tomb searching for a dead body to bury inside of him]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/finally-a-game-about-a-boy-who-thinks-hes-a-tomb-searching-for-a-dead-body-to-bury-inside-of-him</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/finally-a-game-about-a-boy-who-thinks-hes-a-tomb-searching-for-a-dead-body-to-bury-inside-of-him.1243722/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>The Little Tomb: The Maholova Club And The Search For A Dead Body has a demo on Steam</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Cavyhouse</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The first thing that happened to me <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3218790/The_Little_Tomb_The_Maholova_Club_and_the_Search_for_a_Dead_Body/">in the demo</a> for <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-little-tomb-the-maholova-club-and-the-search-for-a-dead-body">The Little Tomb: The Maholova Club And The Search For A Dead Body</a> was a stuffed horse on a spring telling me it knew when and how I'd die. Many such horses. You play as Kofun, a boy shaped like a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kofun">keyhole tomb</a> who is also sort of an actual keyhole tomb but also a boy who wants to fulfill his destiny <em>as</em> a keyhole tomb, namely by finding a dead body to bury inside of himself. He lives in a park with his mate Haniwa, who is a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Haniwa">Haniwa</a>. Haniwa's secret is that he's very good at calligraphy. Here's some visual orientation in case you're not caught up yet.</p>
<!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Little Tomb: The Maholova Club and the Search for a Dead Body - Reveal Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/J-xFztYyJtM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Little Tomb: The Maholova Club and the Search for a Dead Body - Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/J-xFztYyJtM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/J-xFztYyJtM?autoplay=1" title="The Little Tomb: The Maholova Club and the Search for a Dead Body - Reveal Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J-xFztYyJtM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>It's from Cavyhouse, whose previous offering was “dungeon agriculturalization roguelite game” <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1396980/The_Sealed_Ampoule">The Sealed Ampoule</a>. The demo itself is a little too short to get a good feel for things, but if it's at all representative, the game is primarily about hanging out with good weirdos and poking objects.</p>
<p>You hang about in the park Kofun and Hanawa live in. You slide down a slide. Swing on a swing. Swing on a bar, an annoying object for its refusal to bend to the verb-noun symmetry found elsewhere. You collect points for doing all this, then spend them on pondering various objects. I very much enjoy the idea of a <em>pondering currency</em>, both conceptually and in practise. It's all suitably whimsical but then Kofun will occasionally gesture at the fact that he is, undoubtedly, a tomb. I am nothing if not curious to see where this all goes. <a href="https://www.artribune.com/progettazione/2025/07/anticipazioni-videogiochi/">Cheers to The Attribune</a> for the spot.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/finally-a-game-about-a-boy-who-thinks-hes-a-tomb-searching-for-a-dead-body-to-bury-inside-of-him]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>