<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 18:38:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After getting delisted in March, Dark and Darker will be completely inaccessible on the Epic Games Store later this year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/after-getting-delisted-in-march-dark-and-darker-will-be-completely-inaccessible-on-the-epic-games-store-later-this-year</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/after-getting-delisted-in-march-dark-and-darker-will-be-completely-inaccessible-on-the-epic-games-store-later-this-year.1221039/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/after-getting-delisted-in-march-dark-and-darker-will-be-completely-inaccessible-on-the-epic-games-store-later-this-year<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dark-and-darker">Dark and Darker</a> is a bit of a Schroedinger's video game, isn't it? Seemingly fleeting back and forth between a state of being available for sale and being outright delisted. Back in March, the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-multiplayer-games-on-pc">multiplayer</a> extraction game was delisted from the Epic Games Store, with developer Ironmace saying at the time that the "decision appears to be based on claims made by opposing parties in an ongoing legal dispute." 
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
Now, Epic appear to be sending out emails to those that have the game in their libraries informing them that the game will no longer be playable this year (I've received this email myself as I apparently added it to my library at some point despite not having played it). 
</p>
<p>
"We removed Dark and Darker from sale on the Epic Games Store on March 5 in consideration of a court decision in Korea between Nexon and the game's publisher, Ironmace," Epic wrote in the email. "On November 1, 2025, we will be removing Dark and Darker from your library, at which point it will no longer be playable via the Epic Games Store." Anyone that paid for the Legendary Status upgrade will be getting a refund, though those that bought Redstone shards won't be. Both of these are no longer available for purchase as well.
</p>
<p>
The court decision Epic referenced is likely the <a href="https://www.koreatimes.co.kr/business/tech-science/20250213/seoul-court-rules-pc-game-dark-and-darker-did-not-infringe-nexons-copyright-but-orders-compensation">one from February</a>, which found that Ironmace didn't infringe on Nexon's copyright of project P3, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/nexon-are-suing-dark-and-darker-developers-over-copyright-infringement">a game that Nexon alleged was then turned into Dark and Darker using stolen code and assets</a>. However, the court did also instruct Ironmace to pay Nexon 8.5 billion won (about $6.18 million) in damages.
</p>
<p>
Ironically, at this point in time it doesn't seem like the game is being booted off of Steam, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dark-and-darker-removed-from-steam-following-accusations-of-stolen-trade-secrets">despite previously facing this in 2023</a>. It's a messy situation, one that I would guess isn't quite done yet.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Out Fishing is a horror fishing-sim with only one goal: "reel in the one thing that was never meant to be found"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/out-fishing-is-a-horror-fishing-sim-with-only-one-goal-reel-in-the-one-thing-that-was-never-meant-to-be-found</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/out-fishing-is-a-horror-fishing-sim-with-only-one-goal-reel-in-the-one-thing-that-was-never-meant-to-be-found.1220928/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/out-fishing-is-a-horror-fishing-sim-with-only-one-goal-reel-in-the-one-thing-that-was-never-meant-to-be-found<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Something's fishy around here</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Mūn Mūn Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Fishing, I think, is the truest of all video game power fantasies. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-action-games">Action</a> hero combat, romance wish fulfilment, god like abilities, all of that sort of thing pales in comparison to the act of fishing in a game. Just you, your rod, and a whole load of open water. I love to fish in video games, despite not being someone that has a strong desire to 100% genres like collectathons, I do love getting as many fish as I can, and I love a twist on the format. Enter Out Fishing, a mysterious sounding horror fishing game.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
Where <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dredge">Dredge</a> sees you setting out into the open ocean on a boat to get the eldritch catch of the day, Out Fishing almost takes a calmer, more laid back approach. You have your own little camp near a lake, you can improve things like your rod strength and your reeling speed. Classic gamey kind of things, things you'd expect from a cosier game than this one, but then there's the fact that if you stay past sunset, you're greeted with… something, in the forest. Don't know what, but I hate the woods at night, so I'm already just a little bit anxious thinking about it.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Out Fishing - Official Reveal Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EfKH7wpy9OU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Out Fishing - Official Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EfKH7wpy9OU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/EfKH7wpy9OU?autoplay=1" title="Out Fishing - Official Reveal Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EfKH7wpy9OU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
I also really like one of the key features listed over on the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3660260/Out_Fishing/">game's Steam page</a>: "A single, horrifying goal: reel in the one thing that was never meant to be found." That could literally mean anything. A dead body? A really weird fish? Repressed memories of a traumatic event? That last one sounds likely given that the devs cited Silent Hill as an influence (alongside <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/alan-wake">Alan Wake</a> and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/mundaun">Mundaun</a>).
</p>
<p>
What I am curious about is how connected the horror elements will actually feel to the fishing side of things. I'm hoping the two will tie into each other rather than feeling like separate games. I won't find out for a while though, as there's no release date. I'll stick to the slightly less scary Sega Bass Fishing in the meantime.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>