<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 18:08:51 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Witcher 4 has entered "the most intensive phase of development", say CD Projekt]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-witcher-4-has-entered-the-most-intensive-phase-of-development-say-cd-projekt</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-witcher-4-has-entered-the-most-intensive-phase-of-development-say-cd-projekt.1045842/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-witcher-4-has-entered-the-most-intensive-phase-of-development-say-cd-projekt<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_uVCC3Im.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=1200&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Sebastian Kalemba / Rock Paper Shotgun</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Just when you thought you'd played all the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPGs</a> - maxed every last stat, drained the XP of every last creature, tap-danced your way along every branching questline - CD Projekt have announced that <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-witcher-4">The Witcher 4</a> is in "full-scale production".
</p><!--more-->
<p>
"I'm pleased to announce that several weeks ago it moved on to full-scale production," chief financial officer Piotr Nielubowicz said of the game, currently codenamed Polaris, during the company's <a href="https://www.cdprojekt.com/en/wp-content/uploads-en/2024/11/cd-projekt-group-presentation-q3-2024.pdf">latest quarterly earnings presentation</a> to investors (thanks, <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/the-witcher-4-has-entered-full-scale-production-cd-projekt-says/">VGC</a>). "Of all our projects, this one is currently the most far along, and we're starting the most intensive phase of development."
</p>
<p>
Game director Sebastian Kalemba has also been <a href="https://x.com/Skalemba/status/1861446070858846571">talking the announcement up on social media</a>. "No stopping now!" he thrilled. "Stay tuned for what's on the other side of the coin!" The post accompanies a photograph of a coin - see this article's header - on which are engraved rays of light above a cliffside and some runes. Do you know what, I bet there's a picture of a Witcher on the other side of that coin! Perhaps a picture of a Witcher accompanying the words "Witcher 4".
</p>
<p>
The next Witcher game may not be called The Witcher 4, mind you. I attended a sci-fi writing class once in which the tutor grouchily remarked that book publishers get leery about overtly episodic fantasy stories, because "why would I buy Frostblazen Book XII when I haven't bought and read Frostblazen Books I-XI". I imagine video game publishers have similar concerns. It's been a fair old while since The Witcher 3's release - calling it Witcher 4 might scare away players who missed the last game. Perhaps they'll give it an annoying subtitle, instead, or just chicken out and call it "The Witcher", as with Lords Of The Fallen.
</p><p>
As of this March, there were <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/witcher-4-is-more-than-the-witcher-3-in-new-clothing-promise-cdpr-as-over-400-devs-work-on-polaris">over 400 CD Projekt staff</a> working on Polaris. It'll be the first in a new trilogy of Witcher games. CD Projekt's other current endeavours include a Witcher 1 Remake, developed in collaboration with Fool's Theory, Project Sirius, a Witcher spin-off with multiplayer elements from The Molasses Flood, and Project Orion, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cd-project-devs-want-to-call-out-big-problems-like-homelessness-and-the-wealth-gap-in-cyberpunk-2077-sequel">the next Cyberpunk game</a>. 
</p>
<p>
What does "full-scale production" mean? It's a blurry category, but basically, it's the longer part of development after the more open-ended <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cd-projekt-latest-next-cyberpunk-game-might-have-multiplayer-witcher-4-enters-production-phase">pre-production phase</a> when things like character models, environments and combat systems are actually being made and finished. I am very much squinting at the tea leaves, here, but it's probably safe to say that CD Projekt will formally announce the thing and share a few videos and images next year.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Madonna, Dark Souls and Mario meet in a sweet and confounding swimming experiment based on a PS1 obscurity]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/madonna-dark-souls-and-mario-meet-in-a-sweet-and-confounding-swimming-experiment-based-on-a-ps1-obscurity</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/madonna-dark-souls-and-mario-meet-in-a-sweet-and-confounding-swimming-experiment-based-on-a-ps1-obscurity.1045746/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/madonna-dark-souls-and-mario-meet-in-a-sweet-and-confounding-swimming-experiment-based-on-a-ps1-obscurity<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_T9ib6a3.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Hatim Benhsain</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>If you're playing a "PS1-style" game these days, odds are it's a horror game. Sometimes, I worry that the association of PS1 with moody, Silent Hillian dankness has gotten to the point that younger players no longer perceive the original PS1 as a video game console at all. Going by Itch.io's Halloween output, the PS1 was just a rusty bucket of rot and gore in which the faithful might periodically hallucinate the face of Spyro the Dragon.</p>
<p>Here to remind us that the PS1 was capable of colours beside "existential grey" is <a href="https://hatimb00.itch.io/blue-exploration">Water Level/b.l.u.e. EXPLORATION</a>, from New York City-based game designer <a href="https://hatimbenhsain.github.io/">Hatim Benhsain</a>. It's a free downloadable experiment inspired by b.l.u.e.: Legend of Water, a Japan-only PS1 adventure in which you are a girl swimming through alien ruins with her dolphin.</p><!--more-->
<p>In Benhsain's rework, b.l.u.e. has become a game about games swimming through each other. Levels from the original Legend Of Water appear within it via emulator, but they're molten and deferred and spliced with other media to the point that you can't really call this emulation (let alone piracy). The older PS1 game occupies a screen within the screen that zooms and blurs, tilts and dissolves and reappears as you no-clip through a larger, enclosing world of azure and stone, awash with "borrowed" chunks from <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dark-souls">Dark Souls</a>, Super Mario 64 and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/kingdom-hearts">Kingdom Hearts</a>. The soundtrack, meanwhile, slops together waterlogged excerpts from American Idol performances and Madonna, as GameFAQ text unfolds across the top of the screen. </p>
<p>The controls are straightforwardly adapted from Legend Of Water - ah, how strange and joyful to play a 3D controller-based game from the pre-Dualshock era - but what they actually do seems to shift in accordance with the game's steady remixing and refocussing of its source materials. It reminds me a little of synthesising the geography in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mu-cartographer">Mu Cartographer</a>.</p><p>The creator's term for all this is a "plunderludic", or "game made of other games". I hadn't come across this concept before, and am curious to understand what distinguishes a plunderludic from, say, an interactive 3D collage. Benhsain includes a link to a <a href="https://plunderludics.github.io/">resource page</a> with some tools and examples of plunderludic games. It makes connections with the 19th century playwright Bertolt Brecht and George Maciunas, a member of the mid-20th century Fluxus art movement. I'm looking forward to giving it a proper read at some point.</p>
<p>In the short term, I'll only say that it's a delight to play something that takes such delight in swimming, as both a physical practice and an artistic methodology. It's been a while since I enjoyed swimming in a video game - today's aquatic physics and lighting may seem miraculous by PS1 standards, but I wonder if somewhere along the road from Legend Of Water to <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/subnautica">Subnautica</a>, video games have lost the art of making underwater exploration feel magical. If you have any favourite water levels to share, old or new, sing out.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>