<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 10:55:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Nightreign is getting an "endless mode" with special relics and "magmafied" bosses, claim dataminers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-nightreign-is-getting-an-endless-mode-with-special-relics-and-magmafied-bosses-claim-dataminers</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-nightreign-is-getting-an-endless-mode-with-special-relics-and-magmafied-bosses-claim-dataminers.1264182/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>It's allegedly dubbed Deep of Night, and you've got to dig pretty deep into the net to find much info on it</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>FromSoftware</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Some dataminers digging into <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/elden-ring-nightreign">Elden Ring Nightreign</a>'s files following the arrival of its <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-nightreign-duos-update-delayed-due-to-tsunami-warning">Duos update</a> claim to have uncovered some details about an endless mode.</p>
<p>As reported by <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/rpg/elden-ring-nightreign-dataminers-have-uncovered-plans-for-a-new-endless-mode-with-armored-core-6s-rank-system-and-skill-based-matchmaking/">PC Gamer</a>, said new mode is allegedly called 'Deep of Night', and will see you grouped with similarly skiller nighfarers to fight your way up through the ranks of a new rating system that players reckon could work similarly to Armored Core 6's rankings.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>As of writing, the main sources of info about this endless mode are a Reddit thread penned by a user with the handle Adminisitrator and a video from YouTuber <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vkLAD97-hCA">Scavinjx</a>. Having delved through a number of Reddit threads on the subject, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Nightreign/comments/1mgb1gf/comment/n6ncwnh/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">it appears</a> the original discovery of the files might have been by a user named <a href="https://space.bilibili.com/3286774?spm_id_from=333.1369.opus.module_author_name.click">Supuritto</a>, who <a href="https://www.bilibili.com/opus/1096362317248987138">shared their findings</a> on Chinese social media site BiliBili.</p>
<p>According to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Adminisitrator/comments/1mh908l/elden_ring_nightreign_new_mode_deep_of_night/">Adminisitrator's thread</a>, the in-game description of the mode reads as follows: "The Deep of Night is is a battlefield of endless Night. Victory will increase your rating, burnishing your depth. The darkness extends unto infinity." So, a long series of fights with the lights turned off, getting deeper and harder as you go, if you'll forgive the inherent Kenneth Williams 'ooh, Matron' nature of that last bit.</p>
<p>The dataminers claim you'll be working your way through five depths, with each having 999 rating levels to work your way up through, aside from depth five, which is for those elite boss battlers who reach rating 6000 or more. If you lose a fight, you'll slide back down the ratings and depths, but it looks like once you're through depth one, you can't be sent back beyond depth two. I assume that last bit might be a measure to limit cheeky low-level grinding by hardened vets.</p>
<p>As for new rewards, the post shows off screenshots of "depth relics" which it says you'll be able to equip in three new slots just for Deep of Night runs. These come with two buffs, plus one pesky debuff. New weapons work along the same lines, such as a great omenkiller cleaver that boosts your health restoration and damage negation, but increases the damage dealt to by by the encroaching night. Some enemies and bosses also look to be getting "magmafied" variants, which as you might expect see them turned a bit more orange, and I assume able to dish out some toasty damage.</p>
<p>As ever with leaks and datamines, it's worth taking all of this with a grain of salt unless FromSoftware announce that we are all going into the Deep of Night. The mode certainly looks like it could be an interesting alternative to the current weekly boss rotation that arguably leaves a bit to be desired, though I'll likely end up doing a Sum 41 and be in too deep fairly quickly.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-nightreign-is-getting-an-endless-mode-with-special-relics-and-magmafied-bosses-claim-dataminers]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>