<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - rockpapershotgun_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/rockpapershotgun_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for rockpapershotgun_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 11:06:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This week in PC games: deep-sea roguelite raids, first-person horror cookery, and a spruced-up Dawn of War]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-week-in-pc-games-deep-sea-roguelite-raids-first-person-horror-cookery-and-a-spruced-up-dawn-of-war</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-week-in-pc-games-deep-sea-roguelite-raids-first-person-horror-cookery-and-a-spruced-up-dawn-of-war.1266885/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>What we’re feeding the Maw</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Relic Entertainment</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Edwin’s off for a few days – something to do with the thesis that he’s recently started using to make us call him "Dr Edwin" in meetings, turning his camera off and muting himself if we forget. So, for this week’s rundown of new PC game releases, you’ve got me, fresh from my recent encroachments into WAWAPW and the Sunday Papers. You thought AI would steal everyone’s jobs? Wrong. It was the hardware editors.</p>
<!--more-->
<h2>Monday 11th August</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3134810/Nebelmer/">Nebelmer</a> is a compact open world explorer, with just a whiff of that Breath Wot Was In The Wilds. Bet Nintendo never won Best Student Game at the <a href="https://awards.belgiangames.be/game/nebelmer/">Belgian Game Awards</a>, though.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Tuesday 12th August</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2821610/Echoes_of_the_End/">Echoes of the End</a> is a story-heavy, sword-heavier fantasy hack n' slash inspired by ancient Iceland.</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1721110/Abyssus/">Abyssus</a> is a 4-player roguelike co-op shooter about raiding enormous sunken temples and blasting the oceanic monsters within. Deep Sea Galactic?</li>
</ul>
<h2>Wednesday 13th</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2468730/Dungeon_Stalkers/">Dungeon Stalkers</a>, a moderately horny "extraction PvPvE dungeon crawler" with added puzzling, enters early access.</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2788430/Alchemy_of_the_Earth/">Alchemy of the Earth</a> casts you as a lone potion mixer at the end of the world, where you’ll harvest ingredients, brew concoctions, and use them to fight off janky skeletons.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Thursday 14th</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3556750/Warhammer_40000_Dawn_of_War__Definitive_Edition/">Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War – Definitive Edition</a> lightly remasters the classic 40K RTS and all its expansions. Yes, including the SPESS MEHREENS one.</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3230400/EA_SPORTS_Madden_NFL_26/">Madden NFL 26</a> is a new Madden. I got nothin'.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Friday 15th</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3843830/Stomach/">Stomach</a> is a survival horror cooking game in which you, seemingly while being hunted by ghoulies, must craft "increasingly disturbing" dishes using ingredients scavenged from an abandoned cruise ship.</li>
</ul>
<p>Fair warning that it might be a relatively quiet week from us, with both Edwin and Nic on leave, Mark living out his Costa Nostra fantasies in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/mafia-the-old-country">Mafia: The Old Country</a>, and me still trying to figure out which of our sister sites I can make lightly hypocritical tech nerd jokes about now that <a href="https://youtu.be/tl7bIJ2yu4I?si=N7ZVf8hfjpCRfTAZ">Digital Foundry have gone indie</a>. It’s Gamescom next week, mind, so consider this the calm before the Geoffstorm.</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-week-in-pc-games-deep-sea-roguelite-raids-first-person-horror-cookery-and-a-spruced-up-dawn-of-war]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>