<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 22:54:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Massive Darkness: Dungeons of Shadowreach Brings Improved Co-op Action Alongside A D&D Supplement]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/massive-darkness-dungeons-of-shadowreach-brings-improved-co-op-action-alongside-dd</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/massive-darkness-dungeons-of-shadowreach-brings-improved-co-op-action-alongside-a-d-d-supplement.1100277/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/massive-darkness-dungeons-of-shadowreach-brings-improved-co-op-action-alongside-dd<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A new <em>Massive Darkness</em> board game campaign is coming. CMON Interactive has announced the latest iteration of the co-op dungeon-crawling experience, <em>Massive Darkness: Dungeons of Shadowreach, </em>and an official TTRPG supplement based on the setting.</p>



<p>According to the Gamefound campaign page, <em>Massive Darkness: Dungeons of Shadowreach</em> will build upon the gameplay foundation of the previous Massive Darkness board games.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/massive-darkness-dungeons-of-shadowreach-lightbringer-miniatures.jpg?itok=WXEZiMl- 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/massive-darkness-dungeons-of-shadowreach-lightbringer-miniatures.jpg?itok=o4-A1HjJ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The broad strokes are still here. 1-6 players will take on the roles of six new Lightbringers as they fight against the forces of Darkness in the depths of a forgotten land of danger known as Shadowreach.</p>

<p>It is a standalone experience; you do not need any previous entry in the <em>Massive Darkness</em> series to play it. The game does not require a Game Master. You just need a group willing to work together, surviving twisted caverns, fighting monsters, and toppling mighty bosses.</p>

<p>Much like a fantasy RPG, pulling off such feats involves finding treasure, powerful magic items, and leveling up your party. The higher the level, the better loot they can acquire.</p>

<p>If you backed previous <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/massive-darkness-2-hellscape-review" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Massive Darkness</em></a> games, backing <em>Massive Darkness: Shadows of Dungeonreach </em>will provide you with some extra. A Gamefound exclusive Fire Giant roaming monster will be added to your pledge at no additional cost.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/massive-darkness-dungeons-of-shadowreach-ttrpg-banner.jpg?itok=l0-UnZ81 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/massive-darkness-dungeons-of-shadowreach-ttrpg-banner.jpg?itok=JoME7p-d 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Lastly, according to the campaign,&nbsp; <em>Massive Darkness: Dungeons of Shadowreach</em> will have official TTRPG books. A Bestiary and an Adventure Book using the <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/dungeons-dragons" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em></a> 2014 ruleset. Given the series' grotesque and creative monster designs, these books can be valuable resources for GMs at their tables.</p>

<p>For those curious, the campaign page does have a work-in-progress guidebook for the board game that is free to download. Alternatively, the TTRPG has a freely available Quickstart Guide. It contains new lore, a prewritten adventure, premade characters, monsters, magic items, and more.</p>

<p>The <em>Massive Darkness: Shadows of Dungeonreach</em> campaign goes live tomorrow. At time of writing, there are no details regarding pledge levels or the MSRP of the game or the TTRPG books.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>