<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 15:49:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Genshin Impact Version 5.6 Takes You Back to Mondstadt in May]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/genshin-impact-version-56</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/genshin-impact-version-5-6-takes-you-back-to-mondstadt-in-may.1173753/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/genshin-impact-version-56<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>HoYoverse has revealed the release date for&nbsp;<em>Genshin Impact&nbsp;</em>Version 5.6, and the main story chapter in this update will take you back to the land of Mondstadt for an "interlude chapter".</p>

<p>After the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/genshin-impact-version-5-5-release-date" rel="nofollow">last update</a> took you to a lava-filled volcano and introduced you to the last tribe of Natlan, Version 5.6, also known as "Paralogism", takes things in a more nostalgic direction. It's launching across all platforms on May 7th.</p>

<p>In the new Archon Quest Interlude chapter, you'll travel back to Mondstadt in order to take part in an "unexpected trial" involving Albedo. You'll be investigating the crime associated with the trial, meeting figures from your past like Venti and the Knights of Favonius.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/genshin-impact-version-5.6-release-date-escoffier.jpg?itok=EjgsvBwf 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/genshin-impact-version-5.6-release-date-escoffier.jpg?itok=ytNa1910 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>As ever,&nbsp;<em>Genshin Impact&nbsp;</em>Version 5.6 will introduce new characters for your team.</figcaption></figure><p>Not only that, but you'll be defending Mondstadt from monsters (or perhaps that should be mondsters), as well as taking part in a "magical trial" to secure the support of powerful mage Lady Alice in the defense of the city.</p>

<p>Two new characters will also be joining&nbsp;<em>Genshin Impact&nbsp;</em>in Version 5.6. The first, Escoffier, is a spear-wielding Cryo user who "blends culinary flair with elemental power". She can deal pretty heavy damage and heal allies thanks to her Cooking Mek.</p>

<p>Joining Escoffier in this update is Ifa, a 4-star Anemo catalyst wielder who hails from Natlan. He can automatically heal active characters when their HP drops below a certain point, making him ideal for players who prefer to get stuck into the action.</p>

<p>Escoffier and Ifa will be available during Version 5.6's first half, along with <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/genshin-impact-celebrates-version-43s-release-with-navias-graceful-gunbrella-gameplay" rel="nofollow">Navia</a>. Following that, reruns of Kinich and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/guides/genshin-impact-raiden-shogun-baal-build-guide" rel="nofollow">Raiden Shogun</a> will be available in the second half, and the Chronicled Wish is also coming back, this time with characters from Inazuma up for grabs.</p>




<p>As always, three codes are also available for you to grab some free stuff in&nbsp;<em>Genshin Impact</em>, and here they are.</p>

<ul><li>GI56Paralogism - 100 Primogems, 10 Mystic Enhancement Ore</li>
	<li>ChefEscoffier0507 - 100 Primogems, 5 Hero's Wit</li>
	<li>IfaCacucu0507 - 100 Primogems, 50,000 Mora</li>
</ul><p><em>Genshin Impact&nbsp;</em>is available to <a href="https://genshin.hoyoverse.com/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">play for free right now</a> on PC, PlayStation, Xbox Series X|S, and mobile devices. Version 5.6, "Paralogism", launches on May 7th.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cult Hit JRPG Breath of Fire IV Returns Via GOG]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/breath-of-fire-iv-gog</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cult-hit-jrpg-breath-of-fire-iv-returns-via-gog.1173705/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/breath-of-fire-iv-gog<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>GOG has announced a re-release of the classic PS1-era JRPG&nbsp;<em>Breath of Fire IV</em>, which is now available via PC a quarter-century after its initial release on the PlayStation.</p>

<p>As revealed in a <a href="https://x.com/GOGcom/status/1915692579011649567" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">post</a> on X, over 22,000 people voted for <i>Breath of Fire IV</i>'s inclusion as part of GOG's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gog-preservation-program" rel="nofollow">Preservation Program</a>, which aims to support games long after their publishers or developers cease doing so.</p>

<p>According to GOG, the new PC release of&nbsp;<em>Breath of Fire IV</em>, which appears to be based on the original 2003 PC version rather than the PS1 version, is "fully optimized" for modern machines, sporting Windows 10 and 11 support, English and Japanese localizations, and various new options.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/breath-of-fire-iv-gog-planks.jpg?itok=qe_nIIan 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/breath-of-fire-iv-gog-planks.jpg?itok=lhmfTILX 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Breath of Fire IV&nbsp;</em>is now available on PC thanks to the folks at GOG.</figcaption></figure><p>Other than those improvements, though, this remains very much the same&nbsp;<em>Breath of Fire IV&nbsp;</em>you may already know and love from 2000, and if you don't (and you're a JRPG fan), then I'd recommend checking it out tout de suite.</p>

<p>It's not just&nbsp;<em>Breath of Fire IV</em>, either. Other games joining the GOG Preservation Program today include the likes of&nbsp;<em>Worms Armageddon</em>,&nbsp;<em>Realms of the Haunting</em>, and three&nbsp;<em>Ultima&nbsp;</em>games, thus "completing the&nbsp;<em>Ultima&nbsp;</em>series in the Program", according to GOG.</p>

<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Breath of Fire IV</em>, it is, as the name suggests, the fourth game in Capcom's&nbsp;<em>Breath of Fire&nbsp;</em>series. Like previous games, this one also has you playing as Ryu, although it's not the same Ryu in each game.</p>

<p>This time around, your perspective is split between Ryu, who's found naked in a sand ditch by allies Nina and Cray, and Fou-Lu, a recently-reawoken emperor looking to regain the throne he lost hundreds of years ago.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/breath-of-fire-iv-gog-fou-lu.jpg?itok=pFM54y93 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/breath-of-fire-iv-gog-fou-lu.jpg?itok=3tlLjr-m 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>You'll spend your time with both Ryu and Fou-Lu in&nbsp;<em>Breath of Fire IV</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>Gameplay-wise, the game is a fairly straightforward turn-based JRPG, although it's got some tricks up its sleeve that make it stand out in what was a pretty crowded market at the time.</p>

<p><em>Breath of Fire IV&nbsp;</em>is available right now on <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/breath_of_fire_iv" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC via GOG</a>. Here's hoping for a&nbsp;<em>Breath of Fire III&nbsp;</em>release sometime soon, as unlikely as that might be.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>