<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor.net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor.net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 16:12:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty Tops US Gaming Sales Chart for January 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/us-gaming-sales-chart-january-2026-call-of-duty</link>
            <guid>1441690</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>US sales analysis firm Circana has published its data for January 2026, and a certain perennially popular first-person shooter franchise has topped the all-format chart once again.</p><p>That's right: according to <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3mfcbfnjphk2r" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Circana's Mat Piscatella</a>, <em>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 </em>is once again at the top of the chart across all platforms, and that includes both physical and digital sales. Not bad for a game that's just had <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/uk-asa-bans-call-of-duty-black-ops-7-ad" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="62705299-3fce-436c-813b-920cf2f9c7f2" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">an ad banned in the UK</a>.</p><p>The rest of the chart honestly isn't too surprising. <em>NBA 2K26 </em>is in second place, and <em>Madden NFL 26 </em>brings up third. That's to be expected; they're both from hugely popular sports franchises, after all. Fourth place is occupied by <em>Minecraft</em>, and <em>Battlefield 6 </em>is in fifth.</p><figure role="group">
<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-january-2026-sales-chart-robot.jpg?itok=KX7J-vAy 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-january-2026-sales-chart-robot.jpg?itok=PnFqGfLG 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>
<figcaption>You're still a draw, <em>Call of Duty</em>.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p><em>EA Sports FC 26 </em>is in sixth, with <em>Grand Theft Auto V </em>and <em>Red Dead Redemption II </em>providing a Rockstar double-threat in seventh and eighth place, respectively.</p><p>In ninth is a surprise reappearance for <em>Final Fantasy VII Remake</em>, probably spurred on by its launch on Xbox Series X|S <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/final-fantasy-vii-remake-feels-great-on-switch-2" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="63655fa9-d0f7-4f98-85db-1101520be7c1" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">and Switch 2</a> that month, and <em>Forza Horizon 5 </em>is in tenth place.</p><p>When it comes to individual formats, <em>Black Ops 7 </em>rather boringly tops the PlayStation chart, with <em>NBA 2K26 </em>riding high on the Xbox list and <em>Pokemon Legends: Z-A </em>continuing its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pokemon-legends-z-a-sales" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="2d5d3818-49a2-4447-89bf-e19e298fa0df" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">sales dominance</a> across Nintendo's platforms.</p><p>Impressively enough, Bandai Namco's <em>Code Vein II </em>put in a strong showing on PC, topping the aggregated PC storefront chart for January, with <em>Red Dead Redemption II </em>and <em>Battlefield 6 </em>bringing up second and third place respectively.</p><figure role="group">
<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/code-vein-ii-circana-us-sales-data-january-2026.jpg?itok=UWrdo4UV 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/code-vein-ii-circana-us-sales-data-january-2026.jpg?itok=abiDBfI_ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>
<figcaption><em>Code Vein II </em>is no slouch in the PC sales department.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>In total, subscription services and hardware drove a modest 3% increase in the gaming industry in January, when compared to a year prior.</p><p>As usual, I'd recommend checking out Piscatella's <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3mfcbfldifc2r" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">full thread on Bluesky</a> if you want to know more. It's full of fun, nerdy stats to unpick and pore over.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/us-gaming-sales-chart-january-2026-call-of-duty]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Night in the Woods, Tunic Publisher Finji Slams Unauthorized "Racist" TikTok Gen AI Ads]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/finji-tiktok-racist-gen-ai-ads</link>
            <guid>1441687</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Finji, the publisher behind indie hits like <em>Tunic </em>and <em>Night in the Woods</em>, has accused social media platform TikTok of creating "racist" and "sexist" generative AI ads for its games without its permission.</p><p>As reported by <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/tunic-night-in-the-woods-publisher-says-tiktok-is-creating-and-running-racist-genai-ads-for-its-games-without-permission" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">IGN</a>, Finji first became aware of these ads through comments on its non-AI ads from concerned fans. One ad reportedly depicts the protagonist of Finji's game <em>Usual June</em>, a Black woman, in a way that, in IGN's words, seemingly "invokes a harmful stereotype".</p><p>Creatives and businesses on TikTok can choose to opt into a program called Smart Creative, which essentially grants TikTok permission to remix their content and ads with generative AI. You've probably already guessed this, but Finji's account had this option resolutely switched off.</p><figure role="group">
<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/finji-tiktok-racist-gen-ai-ads-usual-june.jpg?itok=uLMsCYX2 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/finji-tiktok-racist-gen-ai-ads-usual-june.jpg?itok=7zf5kDcI 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>
<figcaption><em>Usual June </em>and <em>Night in the Woods </em>publisher Finji has some harsh words for TikTok, and rightly so.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Needless to say, Finji CEO Rebekah Saltsman raised this issue with TikTok's support center, and what follows can only be described as a descent into Kafkaesque absurdity.</p><p>At first, TikTok seems supportive, with a support agent pledging to "raise a ticket" to alert the relevant teams to what's going on. Following that, however, Finji and Saltsman received a response claiming that there was no "indication" of generative AI being used for the ads in question.</p><p>Naturally, a Finji rep then responds by providing evidence that this is not the case, upon which TikTok backtracks and promises to "initiate an internal escalation".</p><p>Finji still can't breathe easy at this point, though, because upon following up with TikTok, the studio was told that it was included in an automated ad initiative, again without its consent, and that said initiative "typically [brings] a 1.4x return on ad spend lift" for those enrolled.</p>
<p>Saltsman and Finji demand that the issue be re-escalated, and TikTok demurs, claiming that it's already passed the issue on to "the highest internal team" available, and that said team has "already provided [its] final findings and actions".</p><p>Finji replies yet again, upon which TikTok pledges to "re-escalate" the problem, but according to IGN and Saltsman, that's the last the studio heard from TikTok, and a followup message sent a few days ago yielded nothing.</p><p>Generative AI is already an intensely controversial topic in the gaming industry, with some studios <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/divinity-larian-gen-ai-concept-art" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="456b3d42-117f-4386-bca9-617e6237ee89" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">throwing their weight behind it</a> and others <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hooded-horse-no-gen-ai-contracts" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="4bf049e2-a4f8-41a0-b834-8030bfbcc977" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">opposing it for all they're worth</a>.</p><p>To me, though, it seems like this usage of the technology - generating AI ads without the consent of the studio concerned, then seemingly deflecting and even essentially gaslighting the studio into believing that no, it's a good thing, actually - is beyond the pale.</p><p>We'll have to wait and see whether Finji and TikTok's issue gets resolved in future, but judging by the correspondence shared by the studio thus far, I don't think there's much cause for optimism. Stay tuned for more.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/finji-tiktok-racist-gen-ai-ads]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>