<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 14:31:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Ditches Co-CEO Strategy in Leadership Shakeup]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sony-leadership-shakeup</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-ditches-co-ceo-strategy-in-leadership-shakeup.1094748/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sony-leadership-shakeup<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Sony has made some major leadership changes, ditching the co-CEO strategy that saw Hermen Hulst and Hideaki Nishino heading up PlayStation together and switching to a more traditional hierarchy.</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://sonyinteractive.com/en/press-releases/2025/new-leadership-at-sony-interactive-entertainment/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">press release</a>, Sony reveals that Nishino has been appointed the sole president and CEO of Sony Interactive Entertainment. Hulst will remain in his position as head of PlayStation Studios, but he'll be reporting to Nishino now.</p>

<p>Additionally, Sony president and COO Hiroki Totoki, who served as interim Interactive CEO after Jim Ryan <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/jim-ryan-retiring-as-playstation-ceo-after-30-years-at-sony" rel="nofollow">retired last year</a>, will now serve as Sony president and CEO, while SIE corporate strategy SVP Lin Tao will become the CFO of Sony as a whole. Her successor at SIE hasn't yet been appointed.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/hermen-hulst-playstation-leadership-shakeup.jpg?itok=VgjfS5a4 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/hermen-hulst-playstation-leadership-shakeup.jpg?itok=FOrUN63C 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Hermen Hulst will remain as head of PlayStation Studios, but he's no longer the co-CEO of Sony Interactive Entertainment.</figcaption></figure><p>In essence, not much has actually changed in terms of Hulst and Nishino's roles; Sony says that Nishino will still serve as president of the "Platform Business Group", and that Hulst will remain head of "Studio Business Group".</p>

<p>In that role, Hulst will "continue to lead the development, publishing, and business operations of SIE's first-party content", and he'll also continue working with PlayStation Productions on bringing Sony IP to other media, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sony-helldivers-horizon-movies-ghost-of-tsushima-anime" rel="nofollow">like movies</a>.</p>

<p>This change is more of a hierarchical one; rather than serving on the same level, Hulst will now report to Nishino.</p>

<p>It's not clear what's prompted this change, but we do know that it's coming after the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/concord-shutting-down-refunds" rel="nofollow">failure of first-person shooter&nbsp;<em>Concord</em></a>, which is arguably one of the most disastrous flops in the company's gaming history.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/sony-leadership-shakeup-concord.jpg?itok=yvFkoe0c 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/sony-leadership-shakeup-concord.jpg?itok=IJTlj4ng 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Last year, PlayStation experienced what is probably one of its biggest flops ever in&nbsp;<em>Concord</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>Recently, Sony also <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sony-live-service-games-canceled" rel="nofollow">canceled live-service projects</a> in development at PlayStation subsidiaries Bend and Bluepoint, and an in-development MMO based on the&nbsp;<em>Horizon&nbsp;</em>IP was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/horizon-mmo-canceled-report" rel="nofollow">reportedly shut down</a>&nbsp;recently as well.</p>

<p>Given the fact that Hulst is remaining in his position, it's not clear whether these developments are related to the leadership shakeup, but the fact Nishino alone will head up Sony Interactive Entertainment feels significant on that front.</p>

<p>Whether or not this has a material effect on PlayStation's strategy in the future remains to be seen. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Upcoming Age of Empires III: Definitive Edition DLC Officially Canceled]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/age-of-empires-iii-definitive-edition-dlc-canceled</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/upcoming-age-of-empires-iii-definitive-edition-dlc-officially-canceled.1094703/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/age-of-empires-iii-definitive-edition-dlc-canceled<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Xbox has announced that the upcoming&nbsp;<em>Age of Empires III: Definitive Edition&nbsp;</em>DLC announced last year has officially been canceled, a decision the devs say "was not made lightly".</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/933110/view/498311439425996116" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">post</a> on Steam announcing the cancellation, the&nbsp;<em>Age of Empires III: Definitive Edition&nbsp;</em>development team says it canceled the DLC "after serious consideration", apologizing for not providing updates regarding said DLC since its announcement last February.</p>

<p>The DLC, which was revealed as part of the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/age-of-mythology-retold-coming-in-2024-age-of-empires-ii-definitive-edition-dlc" rel="nofollow">New Year, New Age event</a>, came about because Xbox and the&nbsp;<em>Age of Empires&nbsp;</em>team wanted players to feel like "part of the franchise celebration", but that enthusiasm led to DLC being revealed "before it had been built".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/age-of-empires-iii-definitive-edition-dlc-canceled-teaser.jpg?itok=duQ5mNvS 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/age-of-empires-iii-definitive-edition-dlc-canceled-teaser.jpg?itok=71co9Bp1 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Age of Empires III: Definitive Edition</em>'s upcoming DLC has been canceled.</figcaption></figure><p>Xbox and the&nbsp;<em>Age of Empires III: Definitive Edition&nbsp;</em>development teams say they now feel the DLC's announcement was "premature", hence the cancellation. They acknowledge this will come as a "huge disappointment" and pledge to continue maintaining the game's servers.</p>

<p>While the DLC was indeed announced last year, Xbox never officially revealed exactly what it would entail. All the studio released was a teaser showing World's Edge production director Earnest Yuen pointing to two flags: the Danish flag, and the flag of the old Polish-Lithuanian Commonwealth.</p>

<p>Since neither of these civilizations are available in&nbsp;<em>Definitive Edition&nbsp;</em>as it stands, it's logical to assume they'd have been introduced as part of the DLC, but since said DLC has been canned, it's a moot point now.</p>

<p>If you're wondering exactly what&nbsp;<em>Age of Empires III: Definitive Edition&nbsp;</em>is, it's a remastered version of the original&nbsp;<em>Age of Empires III</em>, complete with improved presentation and new content.</p>




<p>Revealed in full <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/age-of-empires-iii-announces-definitive-edition" rel="nofollow">during Gamescom 2020</a>,&nbsp;<em>Age of Empires III: Definitive Edition&nbsp;</em>packs in the base game and all DLC that had been released up to that point, as well as two new civilizations in the form of the Incans and the Swedes.</p>

<p>You can check&nbsp;<em>Age of Empires III: Definitive Edition&nbsp;</em>out right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/933110/Age_of_Empires_III_Definitive_Edition/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, and it's included as part of the PC Game Pass and Game Pass Ultimate tiers as well.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>