<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 16:16:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tormented Souls 2 Sales Top 100,000, New Content Coming]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tormented-souls-2-sales-100k</link>
            <guid>1367419</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer Dual Effect and publisher PQube have announced that survival horror game&nbsp;<em>Tormented Souls 2&nbsp;</em>has hit a major sales milestone just over a month after its release.</p>

<p>Per <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/tormented-souls-ii-sales-top-100000" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Gematsu</a>,&nbsp;<em>Tormented Souls 2&nbsp;</em>sales have hit 100,000 since the game launched across PC and current-gen consoles on October 23rd. That means it's reached that figure in the span of just a little over five weeks.</p>

<p>PQube marketing chief Andy Pearson says his company had "high hopes" for&nbsp;<em>Tormented Souls 2</em>, and that PQube has been "blown away" by the reception to the game, which has received a much-coveted <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2464280/Tormented_Souls_2/#app_reviews_hash" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Very Positive Steam rating</a> across just under 1000 reviews since launch.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tormented-souls-2-sales-100k-monster.jpg?itok=71JhQJ2c 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tormented-souls-2-sales-100k-monster.jpg?itok=cxHDVO7S 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Tormented Souls 2&nbsp;</em>has hit 100,000 sales since release in October.</figcaption></figure><p>Pearson says that PQube and Dual Effect are also "working on some exciting new content", for which there will be more news "in a few weeks". Keep your eyes peeled for that if you're a&nbsp;<em>Tormented Souls&nbsp;</em>fan.</p>

<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Tormented Souls 2</em>, it is, as the name suggests, the sequel to 2021 survival horror throwback&nbsp;<em>Tormented Souls</em>, which was inspired by classic tank control-fixed camera-style survival horror experiences like&nbsp;<em>Resident Evil&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill</em>.</p>

<p>The followup once again sees you taking the role of Caroline Walker, who travels to a clinic in a remote town in order to deal with the horrifying nightmares she's been having since the events of the first game.</p>

<p>However, it soon becomes apparent that the clinic isn't all it's cracked up to be (after all, when are they?), and Caroline soon finds herself drawn into another survival horror adventure complete with resource management, puzzle-solving, and panicked combat against grotesque monsters.</p>




<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Tormented Souls 2&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2464280/Tormented_Souls_2/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/EP4293-PPSA17322_00-TORMENTED2SIEEPS" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/tormented-souls-2/9mz5l5tf8p55" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>, and if you want to remind yourself about the original, you can read our <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/tormented-souls-review" rel="nofollow">review of that game right here</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tormented-souls-2-sales-100k]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Islanders Studio Coatsink Lays Off Half of Its Workforce]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/coatsink-layoffs-half-workforce</link>
            <guid>1367413</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Islanders&nbsp;</em>studio Coatsink has announced a round of layoffs targeting around half of the workforce, which parent company Thunderful hopes will result in cost reductions of around $3 million for the year.</p>

<p>As revealed on the Thunderful <a href="https://thunderfulgroup.com/news-room/press-releases/2025-11-24-thunderful-group-initiates-restructuring-in-its-co-development-segment" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">website</a>, about 50 to 60 Coatsink employees will be losing their jobs. Thunderful says Coatsink is "currently unable to support all existing employees", and that the layoffs are necessary to navigate a "more challenging co-development market".</p>

<p>Despite the hefty layoffs, Coatsink isn't closing down. Thunderful says the studio is still "a market leader in full-service co-development", and that it remains "well-positioned to deliver on all existing and upcoming top-tier projects".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/coatsink-layoffs-islanders-new-shores.jpg?itok=e0IiffM2 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/coatsink-layoffs-islanders-new-shores.jpg?itok=UECnaL5W 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Coatsink's best-known franchise is probably cozy city-builder series&nbsp;<em>Islanders</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>These Coatsink layoffs are part of what appears to be a downward trend for parent company Thunderful; over the last couple of years, Thunderful has <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/thunderful-layoffs-restructuring" rel="nofollow">laid off</a> a large <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/thunderful-layoffs-development" rel="nofollow">number</a> of its employees and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/thunderful-closes-studio-financials" rel="nofollow">closed down studios</a> as a result of declining financial performance.</p>

<p>Thunderful's struggles did not, however, prevent Atari from <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/atari-thunderful-majority-stake" rel="nofollow">purchasing a majority stake in the company</a> in July, although that, in turn, hasn't stopped Thunderful and its subsidiaries seemingly continuing to hemorrhage employees.</p>

<p>As for Coatsink itself, if you're not familiar with its name, you might be familiar with some of the games it's published, including cozy city-builder&nbsp;<em>Islanders&nbsp;</em>and its followup&nbsp;<em>New Shores</em>, as well as laid-back angling sim&nbsp;<em>Moonglow Bay&nbsp;</em>and "immersive tactical VR shooter"&nbsp;<em>Onward</em>.</p>

<p>The studio's latest effort,&nbsp;<em>Islanders: New Shores</em>, is a followup to the original&nbsp;<em>Islanders</em>, offering much the same relaxing city-building experience as its predecessor, albeit with some new bells and whistles.</p>




<p>Whether or not Coatsink and Thunderful can recover from this slump remains to be seen, but sadly, the studio is far from the only one undergoing layoffs, with both <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/new-world-development-ending-amazon-layoffs" rel="nofollow">big</a> and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hyper-light-breaker-development-ending-layoffs" rel="nofollow">small</a> companies across the gaming industry letting employees go on a regular basis in recent months.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/coatsink-layoffs-half-workforce]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gears Tactics Dev Splash Damage Hit by Layoffs]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/splash-damage-layoffs</link>
            <guid>1367407</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Gears Tactics&nbsp;</em>developer Splash Damage has announced a round of layoffs, although the exact number of staff members losing their jobs wasn't specified by the studio.</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7399486098588196864/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">post</a> on LinkedIn, Splash Damage explains its latest wave of staff cuts with the usual corporate jargon; the studio says it's letting employees go to "remain agile and adaptable in what has been a very challenging market".</p>

<p>The company goes on to say that it understands "this kind of change is emotionally tough", and that it will do what it can to ensure "those affected have meaningful support throughout" the layoff process. It's nothing you haven't heard before.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/splash-damage-layoffs-gears-tactics.jpg?itok=NtWemNMz 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/splash-damage-layoffs-gears-tactics.jpg?itok=Lc2_8p6L 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Splash Damage's last big release was 2020's&nbsp;<em>Gears Tactics</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>Splash Damage didn't give a specific reason for this round of layoffs, but since the studio hasn't released anything big since 2020's&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/gears-tactics" rel="nofollow"><em>Gears Tactics</em></a>, it's probably pretty easy to guess why staff members are being let go.</p>

<p>What's more, this isn't the first time Splash Damage has come into contact with layoffs this year. Back in January, the studio canceled its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/transformers-reactivate-canceled-as-splash-damage-staff-at-risk-of-redundancy" rel="nofollow">online multiplayer-focused game </a><i><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/transformers-reactivate-canceled-as-splash-damage-staff-at-risk-of-redundancy" rel="nofollow">Transformers: Reactivate</a>&nbsp;</i>and warned that a number of roles were now "at risk of redundancy".</p>

<p>As far as we know, Splash Damage is still currently working on open-world survival game&nbsp;<em>Project Astrid</em>, which was announced <a href="https://www.splashdamage.com/news/announcing-project-astrid/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">back in 2023</a>, although we haven't seen much of that game since its initial reveal either.</p>

<p>Splash Damage's most recent layoffs are part of an ongoing wave that continues to sweep the gaming industry, affecting studios both big and small. Just in the last couple of months, we've seen companies like <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/crystal-dynamics-layoffs-november-2025" rel="nofollow">Crystal Dynamics</a>, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/new-world-development-ending-amazon-layoffs" rel="nofollow">Amazon Games</a>, and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/massive-entertainment-ubisoft-layoffs" rel="nofollow">Ubisoft</a> hit by staff cuts.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/shadow-of-the-tomb-raider-splash-damage-layoffs.jpg?itok=TKxbJTUI 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/shadow-of-the-tomb-raider-splash-damage-layoffs.jpg?itok=ZB8Q3rHO 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Tomb Raider</em>'s Crystal Dynamics has also been hit by layoffs recently.</figcaption></figure><p>As far as we know,&nbsp;<em>Project Astrid</em>, which still hasn't been fully revealed, is Splash Damage's only ongoing project at the moment. We'll have to wait and see whether the game survives what is becoming an increasingly brutal industry. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/splash-damage-layoffs]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>