<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 16:24:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Palworld Crossplay Update Officially Slated for Late March]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/palworld-crossplay-update-late-march</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/palworld-crossplay-update-officially-slated-for-late-march.1132341/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/palworld-crossplay-update-late-march<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Pocketpair has announced that the&nbsp;<em>Palworld&nbsp;</em>crossplay update is coming later this month, so you'll soon be able to play with your friends across different platforms.</p>

<p>Per a Steam <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1623730/view/541100079887417458" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">news post</a>, the crossplay update will bring not only the ability to play with other&nbsp;<em>Palworld&nbsp;</em>players across PC and console, but also the ability to move Pals between worlds, which should make your Pal management a little bit easier.</p>

<p>Pocketpair says that if you want more information about the crossplay update, you should check the patch notes, which will be revealed "on the day of the update", although the studio doesn't reveal what the day of the update actually is.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/palworld-crossplay-update-release-window-world.jpg?itok=wzoJ01Ty 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/palworld-crossplay-update-release-window-world.jpg?itok=KpO_T49E 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The&nbsp;<em>Palworld&nbsp;</em>crossplay update is coming later this month.</figcaption></figure><p>As you'd expect, crossplay will be supported between all of the platforms on which&nbsp;<em>Palworld&nbsp;</em>is currently available, including the PS5, for which the game was released <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/palworld-ps5-release" rel="nofollow">back in September</a>.</p>

<p>It's not clear whether the crossplay update will extend to the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/palworld-mobile-version-krafton" rel="nofollow">mobile version</a> of&nbsp;<em>Palworld&nbsp;</em>when it's eventually released, but given that the mobile version sounds as though it'll be a completely separate game, that's unlikely.</p>

<p>Crossplay and world transfers for Pals are just two of the features promised on the&nbsp;<em>Palworld&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/palworld-roadmap-january-2025" rel="nofollow">roadmap</a> that was revealed back in January. Others include an "ending scenario" for the game, as well as more ways to improve your Pals, new Pals and technologies, and more game collaborations, including the&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/palworld-terraria-crossover-2025" rel="nofollow"><em>Terraria&nbsp;</em>crossover</a>&nbsp;announced back in November.</p>

<p>Pocketpair hasn't specified whether any of those features will be included in the crossover update, but it's likely we'll have to wait a little while for those.</p>




<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Palworld</em>, it's a creature-collecting survival game that tasks you with building a base and surviving in a world filled with&nbsp;<em>Pokemon</em>-esque creatures known as Pals.</p>

<p>The similarities between&nbsp;<em>Palworld&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Pokemon&nbsp;</em>are often disputed, but Nintendo thought they were similar enough to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/palworld-lawsuit-patents-demands-nintendo" rel="nofollow">bring a lawsuit against Pocketpair</a>, which hasn't yet been settled at time of writing.</p>

<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Palworld&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1623730/Palworld/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/palworld/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/palworld-game-preview/9NKV34XDW014" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox</a>, and you can also play it as part of Xbox Game Pass.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>