<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 05:19:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cattle Country Preview - A Tootin' Time]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/cattle-country-preview-tootin-time</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cattle-country-preview-a-tootin-time.1019856/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/cattle-country-preview-tootin-time<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Farming (or in this case, ranching) simulators are a dime a dozen now, and <em>Cattle Country</em> doesn’t quite do enough to stand out in the nearly oversaturated genre despite doing a few things pretty well.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/cattle-country-character-creator.jpg?itok=_aQyarBh 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/cattle-country-character-creator.jpg?itok=OYCtY4qe 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The character creator in&nbsp;<em>Cattle Country&nbsp;</em>isn't complex, but the outfits and customization options were cute.</figcaption></figure><h2>Welcome to Cattle Country</h2>

<p>In <em>Cattle Country</em>, players are moving to a small, Western settlement to start up a ranch. I got my hands on the preview, which features the first week of play. The playable week highlights the Welcoming Committee, a group of townspeople who will introduce you to areas around town. At the end of the week, there’s a festival to close the chapter.</p>

<p>That’s where the beta ends (although, I was able to restart the festival over and over again as it was quite buggy and would restart instead of ending).&nbsp;</p>

<p>For the most part, <em>Cattle Country</em> plays like what you’d expect. A day consists of taking care of your plants and livestock, talking to the village people, exploring, and mining.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/cattle-country-morning-on-the-ranch.jpg?itok=5R3ORnQu 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/cattle-country-morning-on-the-ranch.jpg?itok=WrHc8Zb_ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The aesthetics of&nbsp;<em>Cattle Country&nbsp;</em>are so adorable.</figcaption></figure><h2>The Good Side of the Western Front</h2>

<p>The aesthetics of <em>Cattle Country</em> are cute, especially on the actual farm. Decorating and designing were some of the highlights of the game for me, though the <em>Cattle Country</em> beta gives players quite a bit of indoor and outdoor items to decorate and build with right from the start.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Another aspect of gameplay that stands out is the mining. It’s very unique for the genre, with a vertical, blocky design that’s more reminiscent of <em>Terraria </em>or <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/minecraft-dungeons-review"><em>Minecraft</em></a>&nbsp;than any popular farming sim. This wasn’t a bad thing, and it’s a big bonus for the other vanilla parts of <em>Cattle Country</em>.</p>

<p><em>Cattle Country</em> is also very solid about its theme. The Western font is impossible to ignore, and every player has a heavy accent and lingo to match. While this could be a bit overdone, I liked the fact that it stayed true to what it aims to be.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/mining-in-cattle-country.jpg?itok=16EoLZMk 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/mining-in-cattle-country.jpg?itok=DFbHKGTi 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Surprisingly,&nbsp;<em>​​​​​</em>the mining in&nbsp;<em>Cattle Country&nbsp;</em>was one of the best parts.</figcaption></figure><h2>Cattle Country’s People Were Interesting, But Sparse</h2>

<p>The biggest problem with <em>Cattle Country</em> was easily the village. Indie farming sims are largely beloved because of the people within them. The most successful titles understand and utilize this, and <em>Cattle Country</em> doesn’t hit the mark.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Nearly every NPC in the beta is a romanceable NPC. It feels like a spot for the hot singles to migrate to, and there are very few people outside of them. This makes the town feel really shallow and like it’s built around the player instead of a place the player is moving to.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It doesn’t help that the NPCs don’t really go anywhere. They mostly stood around and didn’t feel like they had any purpose in the game except to exist for the player to talk to. It doesn’t feel like you’re part of a community at all, and it really hampers how immersed you can get.</p>

<p>However, the Welcoming Committee of characters who players can spend time with throughout the week was very well-written. It’s unfortunate that the town feels so shallow when the writing of the characters feels so deep.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/opening-scene-in-cattle-country.jpg?itok=np0uQXDi 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/opening-scene-in-cattle-country.jpg?itok=XN8acYuO 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The start of&nbsp;<em>Cattle Country&nbsp;</em>with Jeb was really cute, and it reminded me of several well-loved games.</figcaption></figure><h2>Overall, Cattle Country Has Some Major Beta Woes</h2>

<p><em>Cattle Country</em> is still in beta, so there’s a good chance that the issues can be worked out. Considering the high parts of gameplay, it would be really great if <em>Cattle Country</em> felt more immersive by launch – cozy farming sims might be around every corner, but those of us who love them will keep playing them.&nbsp;</p>

<hr><p><em><strong>Cattle Country</strong> was previewed over approximately 3 hours of gameplay on PC with a key provided by developers. All screenshots were taken during the preview process.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Brittany's been gaming since she could walk -- literally. A doctor told her parents to get her a handled console to improve her hand-eye coordination… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/brittany-alva">More about Brittany</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Games Workshop Announces Da Red Gobbo 2024, Bringing Holiday Cheer to Warhammer 40,000]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/games-workshop-announces-da-red-gobbo-2024-bringing-holiday-cheer-to-warhammer-40000</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/games-workshop-announces-da-red-gobbo-2024-bringing-holiday-cheer-to-warhammer-40-000.1019832/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/games-workshop-announces-da-red-gobbo-2024-bringing-holiday-cheer-to-warhammer-40000<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Games Workshop has revealed Da Red Gobbo 2024. The tabletop publisher has a tradition of releasing Christmas novelty miniatures for Warhammer 40,000, and this year's miniature continues it proudly, sporting a red coat and a snowman with a deadly surprise.</p>

<h2>Da Red Gobbo 2024 Announcement</h2>

<p>In an official <a href="https://www.warhammer-community.com/en-gb/articles/uzmeyw69/have-a-blast-with-the-red-gobbo-in-this-years-christmas-commemorative-miniature/">Warhammer-Community post</a>, Games Workshop shows off photos and features of Da Red Gobbo 2024. Referred to as the A-Bomb-inable Snowman, the miniature, much <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/da-red-gobbo-returns-this-holiday-season" rel="noopener" target="_blank">like last year's</a>, is a gretchin unit for the Ork army.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/da-red-gobbo-2024-snowman-bomb.jpg?itok=ra5AfyF8 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/da-red-gobbo-2024-snowman-bomb.jpg?itok=9wVfIqmy 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>As the name implies, the miniature depicts a gobbo in a red coat, a smaller gobbo in an elf outfit, and a happy looking snowman wearing the <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/ork-goff-rocker-brings-moozik-to-warhammer-40k" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Goff Rocker's</a> top hat.</p>

<p>That snowman contains a surprise. You can pop the snowman's head off, revealing the snowman's body is built around a gigantic bomb. This destructive mischief is compounded with a pile of snowballs next to the gobbos. Snowballs that are barely concealing what appear to be live grenades.</p>

<p>Da Red Gobbo 2024 is a great continuation of the Ork's farcical nature in the world of <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/games/warhammer-40000" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Warhammer 40,000</em></a>. The grimdark sci-fi setting is mostly characterized by the bleak and grotesque. Interdimensional demons, torturous death cults, fascistic authoritarian states enforced by religious zealots.</p>

<p>By contrast, the Orks are inherently absurd creatures. Battle-obsessed meathead warriors whose simplistic reductive perspective, referred to by the fans as "Ork logic," can subtly break physical reality.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/da-red-gobbo-2024-snowball-grenades.jpg?itok=eqiDtNZW 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/da-red-gobbo-2024-snowball-grenades.jpg?itok=HlZbD186 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Battle vehicles can drive through a warzone despite having no engine or fuel. Guns that fire hundreds of rounds despite being just twisted pieces of metal. A giant hunk of space junk becomes space-worthy because Orks drew red spikes on them. The list goes on.</p>

<p>In that context, a gretchin unit showing up with snowball grenades and an explosive snowman is absurd, but does remain in line with the lore of the setting and its maximalist design sensibilities.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>