<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 13:56:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dissidia Duellum Final Fantasy Might Not Be the Dissidia You Wanted]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dissidia-duellum-final-fantasy</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dissidia-duellum-final-fantasy-might-not-be-the-dissidia-you-wanted.1324288/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Square Enix has revealed&nbsp;<em>Dissidia Duellum Final Fantasy</em>, a brand new entry in the&nbsp;<em>Dissidia&nbsp;</em>series of spinoff fighting games, but if you were hoping for a fully-fledged PC and console title, you're going to be disappointed.</p>

<p><em>Dissidia Duellum Final Fantasy&nbsp;</em>is intended for release on mobile devices sometime next year, and there's no mention in the debut trailer of a PC or console version for the game, so it sounds like it'll be the usual free-to-play procedure for this one.</p>

<p>In the new trailer's description, Square Enix describes&nbsp;<em>Duellum&nbsp;</em>as a "3v3 team boss battle arena" game in which you'll be taking part in "exhilarating, action-packed battles" to defeat bosses faster than an opposing team.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dissidia-duellum-final-fantasy-3v3.jpg?itok=fU00VfcX 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dissidia-duellum-final-fantasy-3v3.jpg?itok=l6OqV-Rl 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Dissidia Duellum Final Fantasy&nbsp;</em>is a new mobile-oriented fighting game spinoff, and it's coming next year.</figcaption></figure><p><em>Dissidia Duellum Final Fantasy&nbsp;</em>will sport modern redesigns of classic&nbsp;<em>Final Fantasy&nbsp;</em>characters; Square Enix has already confirmed the likes of the Warrior of Light,&nbsp;<em>Final Fantasy IV</em>'s Kain Highwind, and&nbsp;<em>Final Fantasy VI</em>'s Terra Branford, among <a href="https://www.square-enix.com/ddff/en/character/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">many others</a>.</p>

<p>The redesigns are intended to slot into a story that takes place in modern Tokyo, wherein warriors known as "Ghosts" appear to do battle with strange monsters born from a crystal. That sounds like a pretty typical&nbsp;<em>Final Fantasy&nbsp;</em>plot if you ask me.</p>

<p>With that said, many of these characters' classic looks can also be seen, so perhaps you'll be able to choose from various different costumes. I'd be astounded if Square Enix didn't embed those costume changes in microtransactions or a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/opinions/fortnites-battle-passes-how-did-they-take-over-gaming-industry" rel="nofollow">battle pass of some kind</a>.</p>

<p>The new game's <a href="https://www.square-enix.com/ddff/en/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">official website</a> promises "simple controls", so you should be able to jump into the action quickly. Gameplay revolves around accumulating Bravery by battling monsters, then unleashing that Bravery to deal big damage to bosses and secure the win.</p>




<p>This isn't the&nbsp;<em>Dissidia&nbsp;</em>franchise's first foray into mobile gaming; it's preceded by the RPG&nbsp;<em>Dissidia Final Fantasy Opera Omnia</em>, which <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dissidia-final-fantasy-opera-omnia-shutting-down" rel="nofollow">closed its servers for good last year</a>. Let's hope&nbsp;<em>Duellum&nbsp;</em>is a bit luckier.</p>

<p>If you want to get a chance to try out&nbsp;<em>Dissidia Duellum Final Fantasy</em>, then you can sign up for the game's closed Android beta <a href="https://www.square-enix.com/ddff/en/cbt/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">right here</a>&nbsp;(as long as you're in the US or Canada). It's due to take place between November 7th and 14th, and recruitment ends on October 28th.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dissidia-duellum-final-fantasy]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Huge Pokemon Leak Reveals Gen 10 Info, New Projects, and More]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pokemon-leak-2025-gen-10-more</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/huge-pokemon-leak-reveals-gen-10-info-new-projects-and-more.1324285/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Another huge&nbsp;<em>Pokemon&nbsp;</em>leak has revealed new information about what we can expect from the upcoming tenth generation of mainline games, as well as new projects in the works and more.</p>

<p>As spotted by ResetEra user <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-suffers-major-leak-all-upcoming-titles-up-to-2030-leaked.1323781/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Atheerios</a> (as well as <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1o5qz6r/gamefreaks_plans_up_to_2030_just_leaked/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">others</a> around the <a href="https://x.com/CentroLeaks/status/1977869125147058256" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">web</a>), this leak, which appears to come from the same source as <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pokemon-teraleak-online-co-op-battler" rel="nofollow">last year's so-called Teraleak</a>, reveals developer Game Freak's plans for the franchise through the next five years or so.</p>

<p>It goes without saying that this story will contain some spoilers for what's in the leak; we don't intend to reveal everything, but if you don't want to know anything about what's in store for&nbsp;<em>Pokemon</em>, you might want to avert your eyes. I won't be mad, I promise.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pokemon-leak-2025-z-a.jpg?itok=W1poDr6i 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pokemon-leak-2025-z-a.jpg?itok=jVA-wZ5L 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>A huge&nbsp;<em>Pokemon&nbsp;</em>leak has seemingly revealed what's coming next for the franchise.</figcaption></figure><p>With regards to Gen 10, the leak shows that the setting will be Southeast Asia-inspired, and that you'll not only be exploring a huge open world just like in&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/pokemon-scarlet-and-violet" rel="nofollow"><em>Scarlet and Violet</em></a>, but delving beneath the waves to explore underwater as well.</p>

<p>Not only that, but the game will supposedly feature a system of procedurally-generated islands you'll be able to wander around as well, in addition to a new graphics engine. The leaks refer to this generation as&nbsp;<em>Pokemon Wind and Wave</em>, although that name is far from official, and it's apparently set for release next year on Switch 2.</p>

<p>According to the leaks, a game known as "Project Seed" is <a href="https://x.com/CentroLeaks/status/1977803554770604239" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">also in development</a>, and it will apparently take the form of a multi-region&nbsp;<em>Pokemon&nbsp;</em>MMO in which you'll be able to travel seamlessly between the first four regions of the series (Kanto, Johto, Hoenn, and Sinnoh).</p>

<p>That's in addition to a new game in the&nbsp;<em>Pokemon Legends&nbsp;</em>series that will take place in&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/pokemon-sword-and-shield" rel="nofollow"><em>Sword and Shield</em></a>'s Galar region, so if you were hoping for that Unova&nbsp;<em>Legends&nbsp;</em>title, you're out of luck, it seems.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pokemon-sword-and-shield-leak-2025.jpg?itok=qr4hYsP2 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pokemon-sword-and-shield-leak-2025.jpg?itok=v6LiNxl- 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Supposedly, a&nbsp;<em>Pokemon Legends&nbsp;</em>game set in the Galar region is being worked on at Game Freak.</figcaption></figure><p>It is worth noting that a lot of what's been reported in this leak could be inaccurate since it hasn't officially been announced. Not only that, but Nintendo and Game Freak could choose to kill the development of any of the projects that have been leaked, or alter their content significantly.</p>

<h2>This leak also reveals something about&nbsp;<em>Pokemon&nbsp;</em>budgets</h2>

<p>It's not just new&nbsp;<em>Pokemon&nbsp;</em>games the leak reveals, either. There's also <a href="https://x.com/Stealth40k/status/1977787802646708402" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">some information</a> about the kind of money Game Freak and Nintendo spend on&nbsp;<em>Pokemon&nbsp;</em>games, and if it's accurate, it could be very illuminating indeed.</p>

<p>According to the leaks,&nbsp;<em>Pokemon Legends: Z-A</em>, which is <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pokemon-legends-z-release-date-pokemon-presents" rel="nofollow">due to launch on Friday</a>, was made for a budget of around $13 million, while the upcoming tenth-generation games had $20 million allocated to them.</p>




<p>If those figures are to be believed, then we can assume&nbsp;<em>Pokemon Scarlet and Violet</em>'s budgets weren't astronomically higher than the ones outlined above; if anything, the money spent on the last generation of&nbsp;<em>Pokemon&nbsp;</em>games may even have been lower.</p>

<p>That might go some way towards explaining why the games launched in such a messy state technically; $10-$20 million seems like a very low figure indeed for one of the highest-grossing media franchises in the world, even if we factor in extra money spent on the likes of marketing or publishing.</p>

<p>We'll have to wait and see what comes of these leaks. If I know Nintendo, the company will be <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-subpoena-request-pokemon-teraleak-identity" rel="nofollow">vicious in pursuing the perpetrator</a>, and much of what's been revealed might be thrown out or altered significantly in response to the leak. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pokemon-leak-2025-gen-10-more]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>