<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 16:49:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Cosmic Invasion Release Date Confirmed for December]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/marvel-cosmic-invasion-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-cosmic-invasion-release-date-confirmed-for-december.1331860/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Publisher Dotemu and developer Tribute Games have announced the release date for their upcoming star-studded superhero brawler&nbsp;<em>Marvel Cosmic Invasion</em>, and it won't be long before you get to check it out.</p>

<p>As revealed in a press release,&nbsp;<em>Marvel Cosmic Invasion</em>, which was first announced as part of a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-direct-march-2025-all-news-and-announcements" rel="nofollow">Nintendo Direct show earlier this year</a>, will be launching across PC and consoles on December 1st.</p>

<p>Not only that, but the two studios have also announced the two final characters to round out the game's 15-fighter-strong roster: Phoenix and Invincible Iron Man. They join a lineup that also includes iconic characters like Venom, Spider-Man, Storm, and Wolverine.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/marvel-cosmic-invasion-release-date-phoenix-iron-man.jpg?itok=Z3NcFVem 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/marvel-cosmic-invasion-release-date-phoenix-iron-man.jpg?itok=oH26KpMm 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Marvel Cosmic Invasion</em>'s two final fighters are Phoenix and Invincible Iron Man.</figcaption></figure><p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Marvel Cosmic Invasion</em>, it's a side-scrolling beat-'em-up developed by Tribute Games, the folks behind 2022's&nbsp;<em>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Shredder's Revenge</em>&nbsp;(of which our Alex <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/tmnt-shredders-revenge-review" rel="nofollow">was a big fan</a>).</p>

<p>Published by&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/absolum-200k-sales" rel="nofollow"><em>Absolum&nbsp;</em>outfit Dotemu</a>,&nbsp;<em>Marvel Cosmic Invasion&nbsp;</em>sees Marvel heroes banding together to fight the villainous Annihilus (the clue's in the name, I suppose), who's "launched an unprecedented attack across the galaxy".</p>

<p>You'll choose a team of two Marvel heroes, swapping between them as necessary and creating "unique team-ups" to deal "devastating damage" to your foes.</p>

<p><em>Marvel Cosmic Invasion&nbsp;</em>supports co-op play for up to four players, and you can play either locally or online. Drop-in-drop-out co-op is supported as well, so if you can't enjoy the entire adventure alongside the same people, it's no big deal.</p>




<p>Each player chooses their own team of two heroes, too, so you may well have up to eight heroes battling through the streets of New York towards the sinister-sounding Negative Zone to defeat Annihilus.</p>

<p><em>Marvel Cosmic Invasion&nbsp;</em>launches across <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2753970/MARVEL_Cosmic_Invasion/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10012545" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/marvel-cosmic-invasion/9n79tqtztqq4" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>, and Nintendo Switch (although not for Switch 2, it seems) on December 1st. Stay tuned for more on this one.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/marvel-cosmic-invasion-release-date]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PowerWash Simulator 2 Roadmap Promises New Crossover DLC and More]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/powerwash-simulator-2-roadmap</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/powerwash-simulator-2-roadmap-promises-new-crossover-dlc-and-more.1331857/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>FuturLab has revealed the first&nbsp;<em>PowerWash Simulator 2&nbsp;</em>roadmap, and if you're a fan of the franchise's crossover DLC, then you'll be pleased by what's in store for the next year or so.</p>

<p>As revealed in a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2968420/view/517476466977407328" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">news post</a> on Steam,&nbsp;<em>PowerWash Simulator 2&nbsp;</em>has three packs of "paid IP DLC" on the way, with one due to launch in each of the first three quarters of 2026.</p>

<p>It's not clear which IPs these DLCs will revolve around, but&nbsp;<em>PowerWash Simulator&nbsp;</em>has teamed up with some pretty big names in the past, including&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/powerwash-simulator-final-fantasy-vii-crossover-dlc-arrives-in-march" rel="nofollow"><em>Final Fantasy</em></a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/powerwash-simulator-warhammer-40k-dlc" rel="nofollow"><em>Warhammer 40,000</em></a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/powerwash-simulator-back-to-future-dlc" rel="nofollow"><em>Back to the Future</em></a>, plus more.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/powerwash-simulator-2-roadmap-40k-dlc-powerwash-1.jpg?itok=15E-Pn14 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/powerwash-simulator-2-roadmap-40k-dlc-powerwash-1.jpg?itok=GhDEZQ8N 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Will&nbsp;<em>PowerWash Simulator 2</em>'s "IP DLC" be as big as its&nbsp;<em>Warhammer 40k&nbsp;</em>collaboration?</figcaption></figure><p>The paid DLC packs will be arriving in conjunction with a host of free content, including three jobs forming part of the game's "Caldera Chronicles" series, as well as plenty of new features, bug fixes, and quality-of-life improvements.</p>

<p>FuturLab says that for the rest of the year, it's focusing on these fixes and QOL improvements, and that its top priority at the moment is to "get key bindings back into the game", so hopefully, your&nbsp;<em>PowerWash Simulator 2&nbsp;</em>experience should improve soon.</p>

<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>PowerWash Simulator 2</em>, it's the sequel to the original&nbsp;<em>PowerWash Simulator</em>, offering much the same gameplay experience as its predecessor (albeit with some extra bells and whistles to make things more exciting).</p>

<p>You'll once again be let loose on a variety of filthy environments and asked to clean them with your power washer, but you've also got access to new tools like an abseiling rig, a powerful new surface cleaner, and a cherry picker.</p>




<p><em>PowerWash Simulator 2&nbsp;</em>is available right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2968420/PowerWash_Simulator_2/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10011314" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/powerwash-simulator-2/9p45ggdtfnsm" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/powerwash-simulator-2-switch-2/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Nintendo Switch 2</a>. While you wait for the roadmap's content to be delivered, why not take a trip down memory lane and read our very own Blair's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/powerwash-simulator-review" rel="nofollow">review of the first game</a>?</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/powerwash-simulator-2-roadmap]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scarface: The World Is Yours Steam Release Canceled Over "Unexpected Complications"]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/scarface-world-is-yours-steam-port-taken-down</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/scarface-the-world-is-yours-steam-release-canceled-over-unexpected-complications.1331854/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A recent Steam port of 2006 action-adventure game&nbsp;<em>Scarface: The World Is Yours&nbsp;</em>has been taken down by publisher EC Digital owing to what the studio describes as "unexpected complications and concerns".</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/app/4113570/discussions/0/594037660640685944/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">news post</a>, EC Digital says that "certain builds" of the game were released on "other platforms", and that this release was "unintended", so the studio feels it's "necessary to pause and reevaluate" with regards to&nbsp;<em>Scarface: The World Is Yours</em>' re-release.</p>

<p>Apparently, the Steam page for the game was "initially intended as a placeholder" while EC Digital worked through what it calls "ongoing licensing and technical matters". The company also points to something it mysteriously calls "urgent discussions with multiple parties concerning the project's status".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/scarface-the-world-is-yours-steam-boat.jpg?itok=DsZhJVwa 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/scarface-the-world-is-yours-steam-boat.jpg?itok=c7TamcIB 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The recent Steam re-release of&nbsp;<em>Scarface: The World Is Yours&nbsp;</em>was an error, apparently.</figcaption></figure><p>Rather confusingly, the game remains available via the <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/scarface-the-world-is-yours-7c3e6f" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a>, which is presumably one of the "other platforms" on which its release caused this trouble in the first place. It's not clear why the game has been removed from Steam, but not from Epic.</p>

<p>As spotted by <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/action/19-years-later-scarface-game-mysteriously-resurfaces-on-steam-and-epic-but-not-for-long-weve-recently-entered-urgent-discussions-with-multiple-parties-concerning-the-projects-status/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">GamesRadar</a>, however, the re-release of&nbsp;<em>Scarface: The World Is Yours&nbsp;</em>contains two mods created by community members, both of which are intended to enhance the original Windows version and make it playable on modern systems.</p>

<p>One of the modders, Silent, who created the eponymous SilentPatch, <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:x6zaxkp46jrfqieaczwuc4il/post/3m3rcwjmhps2b" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">says</a> they weren't contacted about&nbsp;<em>Scarface: The World Is Yours</em>' re-release on PC.</p>

<p>The author of FusionFix, the other mod included in this re-release, <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/cookieplmonster.bsky.social/post/3m3rv3y5bqs2r" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">was contacted</a>, but&nbsp;Silent says it's unlikely the original&nbsp;<em>Scarface&nbsp;</em>IP holders are aware of this new version. In short, this seems like a pretty big mess, and I'd be amazed if the game re-appears on PC storefronts following this debacle.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/scarface-the-world-is-yours-steam-car.jpg?itok=LlSVbCTa 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/scarface-the-world-is-yours-steam-car.jpg?itok=QttEYXfq 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The new PC port of&nbsp;<em>Scarface: The World Is Yours&nbsp;</em>is suspicious, to say the least.</figcaption></figure><p>EC Digital doesn't appear to have any other games published under its name on Steam, so I think it's fair to say this re-release is suspect, to say the least. It sounds as though the publisher may not have acquired the appropriate licenses or talked to the right people before going ahead with this.</p>

<p>In any case, if you do want to check out this PC port of&nbsp;<em>Scarface: The World Is Yours</em>...well, it's technically available via the Epic Games Store, but I'd save my money and wait for more concrete confirmation of the port's legitimacy if I were you.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/scarface-world-is-yours-steam-port-taken-down]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokemon Legends ZA Review - A Mega Adventure]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/pokemon-legends-za-review-mega-adventure</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pokemon-legends-za-review-a-mega-adventure.1331731/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>While the <em><a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="8e948d2c-e718-4b87-9a04-0d0bc246614c" href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/pokemon-legends-z-preview-another-reason-to-get-switch-2" rel="nofollow">Pokémon </a></em>formula has been slow-moving over the years, with <em><a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="ab965b69-179c-4525-9aa0-c19799509f61" href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/pokemon-legends-arceus" rel="nofollow">Pokémon Legends Arceus</a></em>, a big change was made in exploration and story format. The release of <em>Pokémon Legends ZA</em> makes some steps even further from the formula, but also many closer. Do these differences make it a better <em>Pokémon </em>game, or something harder to recognize?</p>

<p><em>Pokémon Legends ZA</em> is set in the town of Lumiose City, which was a central setpiece for the events of <em>Pokémon X and Y</em> for the Nintendo 3DS, and now is the sole location for your <em>Legends ZA</em> adventure. You play as a newcomer, visiting Lumiose City for a holiday before you get wrapped up in taking part in a city-wide night-time battle tournament called the Z-A Royale, investigating mysterious Rogue Mega Evolution events, and exploring the city.</p>

<h2>Revisit Kalos And Become A Pokémon Master</h2>

<p>The start of the story is strong, introducing you to the primary cast of characters while also teaching you about the Pokémon-inhabited Wild Zones of the city. You'll meet characters like your rival Taunie/Urbain, fellow members of Team MZ, Naveen and Lida, and AZ, the mysterious hotel keeper, as well as some major players in the city, like Emma the detective.</p>

<p>There isn't any level of collecting badges; instead, your simple goal is to join a battle royal event called the Z-A Royal and work your way from Rank Z to Rank A (as the name implies). As you progress through the game, you're also introduced to the mystery of mega energy seeping out all over Lumiose City, which has been leading certain Pokémon to go rogue, leaving people in danger. This drive to become stronger, as well as the mystery of the rogue Mega Evolution, is the core thread that will pull you through the game.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pokemon-legends-za-review-exploration_0.jpg?itok=DbckCvYg 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pokemon-legends-za-review-exploration_0.jpg?itok=XqEYkzhA 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>While the story is very much present, it also gives plenty of breathing room. Your next objective might be to reach a new rank or to take out a rampaging Rogue Mega Pokémon. You can reach these objectives quite easily, but it's in the amount of exploration that can be done and side-quests to accomplish that you'll find yourself stopping to smell the roses and take in everything that the game has to offer.</p>

<p>Something I really enjoyed about the story of <em>Legends ZA</em> compared to other, more traditional, titles in the <em>Pokemon </em>franchise is that it wasn't that you got to spend 50-60% of the game completing your main objective of badges/Z-A Royale, then get an interlude story where the evil team tries to take over the world, and then back to completing your goal of being the very best, like no one ever was. Instead, the story is constantly being woven in and out of the Z-A Royale storyline, culminating in what might be one of <em>Pokémon</em>'s most impressive finale setpieces.</p>

<p>The story did a great job highlighting not just the protagonist's ability to be the greatest Pokémon trainer, but also managed to create a group that actually felt like they were friends with each other and not just the main character, and fill the city with a unique and colorful supporting cast of characters.</p>

<h2>A New Way To Battle</h2>

<p>One of the largest changes to the Pokémon formula is in the new active battles. Instead of a static turn-based experience, the combat in <em>Pokémon Legends ZA</em> lets you roam around with your Pokémon to your side, calling out attacks for it to you as it maneuvers into place, trying to hit your opponent while not getting hit yourself.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pokemon-legends-za-review-combat.jpg?itok=Ha0RsYOs 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pokemon-legends-za-review-combat.jpg?itok=2PpkrCj_ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>I am a huge fan of this gameplay style, possibly because it's the closest I'll ever expect we get to an anime-style Pokémon battle, but also because at its core it's not too different from classic Pokémon battling, and there's plenty of room to grow.</p>

<p>If you want, you can send out your Pokémon, and you and your opponent can stand statically, hitting each other until one of you faints. There are a number of things you can factor into your strategy that will allow you to deal more damage faster, or even avoid damage in certain scenarios.</p>

<p>Speed and range of attacks are far more important in <em>Pokémon Legends ZA</em>, as with the right loadout, you can get 2-3 attacks in while your opponent is still queuing up their second attack. Each move will have the Pokémon move to a specific spot or within close range. This means there's a new level of strategy to how you want to respond to your opponents' attacks, too.</p>

<p>When an enemy uses Fly, you can begin to move, and with enough skill, might avoid your opponent crashing down. Similarly, for massive attacks like Hyper Beam, you could find a way to avoid it by strafing or even putting the environment between yourself and the attacks. I loved learning the different ways I could fight with my Pokémon, how to best chain attacks into each other, and what type advantages I could come up with on the fly.</p>

<p>In Ranked Play, this causes the 4-player free-for-all battles to be truly chaotic. Moving from lobby to lobby, your team of three might be perfectly set up to sweep the enemy, or you could truly be out of luck as you get countered by something super-effective to you at every turn. There's nothing more satisfying than sniping an enemy's kill with a long-range flamethrower, and alternatively, there's nothing worse than being so close to the kill and having it stolen away.</p>

<p>I don't expect this combat to replace the classic formula, or even have anywhere near as much popularity, but as someone who never got into the competitive side of Pokémon, I was excited to Hyper Train some Pokémon to compete in Ranked Play.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pokemon-legends-za-review-rogue-mega-battle.jpg?itok=uhmoglb5 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pokemon-legends-za-review-rogue-mega-battle.jpg?itok=4bd0TH_A 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2>Bullet (Seed) Hell</h2>

<p>The best use of the active combat is in the Raid-like Rogue Mega Evolution battles, where you need to fight an enraged Mega Pokémon. For these battles, you're paired with one of your story companions and end up on a battlefield to take on this gargantuan Pokémon.</p>

<p>The basic formula of the battle is to deal super-effective damage to the Mega Pokémon, siphon off some Mega Energy in the shape of dropped orbs, and then Mega Evolve your own Pokémon to deal as much damage as possible until they revert. While you're doing this, you'll also need to be dodging the Pokémon's attacks.</p>

<p>This Rogue Mega Pokémon doesn't just attack your Pokémon, but also focuses on the player. You'll be running, dodge rolling, and even recalling your Pokémon to keep them out of harm's way during battles.</p>

<p>Some of these Pokémon set off incredible effects like tornadoes that follow you around the stage, violent rocky shockwaves, and a classic massive beam of energy that follows you as you run from it.</p>

<p>The biggest downside of these Rogue Mega Encounters for me was that while they're repeatable, there was no way to enjoy them with a friend. As the Pokémon franchise has promoted Max Raids and Tera Raids, I was disappointed to learn that there wasn't any way to pair up with even a single friend and take on these gargantuan foes together, especially when there's already local battle multiplayer.</p>

<h2>The City Is Alive</h2>

<p>It's clear that <em>Pokémon </em>has taken inspiration from other recent Nintendo successes like <em>Breath of the Wild,&nbsp;</em>where, after completing the tutorial, the whole map is open to you. You've got a variety of Pokémon-filled areas to explore, as well as a multitude of side quests to immediately involve yourself even further with the city.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pokemon-legends-za-review-veritcality.jpg?itok=qwS9uaAL 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pokemon-legends-za-review-veritcality.jpg?itok=XJcouFqN 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Even on the ground level, at nearly any point, you can rotate in a complete circle and see one or possibly two Wild Zones, a shop or cafe, wild Pokémon, or an NPC with a side-quest ready to ask of you. This also felt like a lesson learned from <em>Breath of the Wild</em>: the world doesn't have to be the largest, but if you pack it densely, then players won't be able to stop getting sidetracked as they move from main objective to main objective. 99 times out of 100, I'll prefer a smaller but more densely packed world that one that can promise landscapes that you can walk in a straight line for hours in, but there's nothing to see or do.</p>

<p>The way that <em>Pokémon </em>has further enhanced Lumiose City is through the amount of verticality it has. You can walk along all of the main and side streets, discovering little parks or water features along the way, but you can also take to the roofs filled with Pokémon and hidden items. Unlocking elevators to different roofs and traversal options are other perks of progressing through the storyline, letting what seems like a static world at first grow in size while not physically getting larger.</p>

<p>Going into <em>Pokémon Legends ZA</em>, and honestly, even for the first hour or two while the game has you on rails, I was concerned that the map would be too small, and now that I'm 50-60 hours in, I couldn't have been more incorrect, as I keep turning corners and finding new interesting places.</p>

<h2>Side-Quest Variety Impressed</h2>

<p>What fuels a lot of your exploration is the Side-Quests, with around 100 in total for the whole game. Some of these are quite basic, can you battle with me or show me a certain type of Pokémon, while others are side-quests masquerading as tutorials teaching new players about the benefits or drawbacks of poison vs paralysis, or how moves like Protect are helpful.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pokemon-legends-za-review-side-quest.jpg?itok=4tWsPg50 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pokemon-legends-za-review-side-quest.jpg?itok=yNlAgmfJ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>A number of side-quests that long for a lot of games can be a red flag to certain people; the strength of the side-quests in <em>Pokémon Legends ZA </em>comes down to two simple things.</p>

<p>The first is that there was a health variety in the types of things being asked of you. A fair number were battles, which for a <em>Pokémon </em>game didn't even entirely feel like a side-quest, while others would have you collect certain Pokémon, trade Pokémon, search for hidden Pokémon in a museum (one of my favorites), and even chase down fleeing Pokémon.</p>

<p><em>Legends ZA</em> also used side-quests as a way to gift the player with Pokémon such as Froakie, Fennekin, and Chespin in interesting and unusual ways.</p>

<p>The second major strength is that none of these side-missions were very long. Depending on how much time you have to sit down and play, you might be able to complete a night of Z-A Royale, or you might just want to finish 'one more' quest. These quick quests mean there's always just one more little thing for you to do, and then when you realize you still have a bit more time then you can squeeze in another.</p>

<h2><em>Pokémon</em>&nbsp;<em>Legends ZA</em> Review | Final Thoughts</h2>

<p>Going into <em>Pokémon Legends ZA </em>I had a lot of fears. How will it run? Is Lumoise City going to feel too small? Will it be able to compare with the epic story of <em>Pokémon Legends Arceus</em>? Will the new combat style be fun?</p>

<p>Thankfully, I was impressed with pretty much every aspect of the game. <em>Pokémon Legends AZ</em> is an incredibly polished game from start to finish with an entertaining story that's fun for newcomers and veterans alike. Lumiose City might not physically expand, but with the introduction of new areas and Wild Zones throughout the story progression, you get to experience it growing as you do.</p>

<p>Best of all, the core mechanic of <em>Pokémon Legends ZA</em>, the new active combat, is incredibly fun. It was such a fun experience taking Pokémon and attacks I knew and seeing them played out in motion instead of stuck in place. It made the combat more engaging and opened up new levels of strategy for a lot of moves that might not otherwise get much love.</p>

<hr><p><em><strong>Pokémon Legends ZA </strong>was reviewed on Nintendo Switch with a copy purchased by the reviewer over the course of 55 hours of gameplay - all screenshots were taken during the process of review.</em></p>
</div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/pokemon-legends-za-review-mega-adventure]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>