<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 15:25:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Sales Top 30 Million, Bandai Namco Announces]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/elden-ring-sales-30m</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-sales-top-30-million-bandai-namco-announces.1175421/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/elden-ring-sales-30m<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>It's time once again to cast your gaze to the Lands Between, as publisher Bandai Namco and developer FromSoftware have revealed another major&nbsp;<em>Elden Ring&nbsp;</em>sales milestone has been passed.</p>

<p>According to a <a href="https://x.com/ELDENRING/status/1916855058097938564" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">post</a> on X,&nbsp;<em>Elden Ring&nbsp;</em>has managed to pass the 30 million sales mark, which means the open-world Soulslike action RPG has picked up another five million sales for itself <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/elden-ring-sales-25-million" rel="nofollow">since June last year</a>.</p>

<p>It's worth noting that this figure refers to sales across all platforms, and it also appears to include both digital and physical shipments. Additionally, the figure doesn't include sales for&nbsp;<em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em>, which <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/elden-ring-shadow-of-erdtree-sales" rel="nofollow">hit five million after just three days</a>&nbsp;on its release last year.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/elden-ring-sales-30m-cliff.jpg?itok=3_--U5rJ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/elden-ring-sales-30m-cliff.jpg?itok=Nbh0jMGK 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Elden Ring&nbsp;</em>has managed to cross the 30 million sales mark.</figcaption></figure><p>It's fair to say that by any metric, this new milestone further cements&nbsp;<em>Elden Ring</em>'s remarkable success. The figure puts the game in the same league as Warner Bros' phenomenally popular&nbsp;<em>Hogwarts Legacy</em>, which <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hogwarts-legacy-sales-30m" rel="nofollow">crossed the same milestone back in November</a>.</p>

<p>Given&nbsp;<em>Elden Ring</em>'s huge success, then, FromSoftware and Bandai Namco's decision to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/elden-ring-nighreign-release-date" rel="nofollow">create a followup to the game</a> in the form of the multiplayer-focused&nbsp;<em>Elden Ring Nightreign&nbsp;</em>makes a lot of sense, at least from an intellectual property-focused perspective.</p>

<p>Even if you're not feeling up to trying out&nbsp;<em>Nightreign</em>'s formula-departing&nbsp;<em>Fortnite</em>-inspired gameplay, though, you needn't fret.&nbsp;<em>Elden Ring&nbsp;</em>is also making its way to the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-switch-2-release-date" rel="nofollow">Nintendo Switch 2</a> this year, complete with the&nbsp;<em>Shadow of the Erdtree&nbsp;</em>expansion and some special new armor.</p>

<p>The game isn't even the only FromSoftware title in development for Nintendo's new console; it's joined by&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/the-duskbloods-fromsoftware-nintendo-switch-2" rel="nofollow"><em>The Duskbloods</em></a>, a PvPvE-focused title coming to the new machine in 2026.</p>




<p>While you wait for&nbsp;<em>Elden Ring&nbsp;</em>to land on Switch, you can pick the game up right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1245620/ELDEN_RING/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/elden-ring/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/elden-ring/9p3j32ctxlrz" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox</a>. Make sure to give our very own Will's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/elden-ring-review" rel="nofollow">review of the game</a> a read as well.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wii Homebrew Channel Shut Down, Dev Says Community Built on "Lies"]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/wii-homebrew-channel-shut-down</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wii-homebrew-channel-shut-down-dev-says-community-built-on-lies.1175418/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/wii-homebrew-channel-shut-down<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Popular Wii homebrew tool Wii Homebrew Channel has been shut down, and its developers have launched an excoriating attack on the originators of the software on which the channel is (or was) based.</p>

<p>As spotted by X user <a href="https://x.com/OatmealDome/status/1916557212509478946" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">OatmealDome</a>, the Wii Homebrew Channel <a href="https://github.com/fail0verflow/hbc" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">GitHub repository</a> has now been archived, and homebrew group Fail0verflow has blamed the shutdown on the discovery that the libogc library, on which Wii Homebrew Channel is based, contains stolen code.</p>

<p>According to Fail0verflow, "large portions of libogc were stolen directly from the Nintendo SDK (software development kit) or games using the Nintendo SDK". The group says it "thought that at least significant parts" of the library "were original", and so "reluctantly continued to use the project".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/wii-homebrew-channel-shut-down-github.jpg?itok=WcPtCnIt 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/wii-homebrew-channel-shut-down-github.jpg?itok=KWi5liHs 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>This is what you'll find if you visit the Wii Homebrew Channel GitHub page (at time of writing).</figcaption></figure><p>However, Fail0verflow says it was recently revealed that certain parts of libogc were "stolen from RTEMS", an open-source real-time operating system for which the library "remove[d] all attribution and copyright information".</p>

<p>According to the group, libogc's developers' actions go "far beyond ignorance about the copyright implications of reverse engineering Nintendo binaries" and stray into "outright deliberate, malicious code theft and copyright infringement".</p>

<p>Fail0verflow says libogc's developers are "not interested in tracking this issue, finding a solution, [or] informing the community of the problematic copyright status of the project", going as far as to say the Wii homebrew community as a whole is "built on top of a pile of lies and copyright infringement".</p>

<p>As OatmealDome further <a href="https://x.com/OatmealDome/status/1916557214904430754" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">points out</a>, libogc serves as "the core of all homebrew apps" when it comes to GameCube and Wii homebrew solutions, so Fail0verflow's accusations aren't small potatoes in this regard.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/gamecube-libogc-homebrew.jpg?itok=0DIBWMLl 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/gamecube-libogc-homebrew.jpg?itok=2n6xU0zE 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>libogc also forms the basis of GameCube homebrew.</figcaption></figure><p>The shutdown of the Wii Homebrew Channel, or rather the cessation of ongoing development, is a massive blow to the Wii homebrew scene, but unfortunately, Fail0verflow says it can't encourage further development as it's "impossible to legally and legitimately compile this software".</p>

<p>Some might say Fail0verflow is being hypocritical given emulation is a common usage for Wii homebrew software, but I don't think that's entirely fair. Modding a Wii with homebrew software is far from illegal; it's playing copyrighted games or software that crosses that particular line.</p>

<p>In any case, we'll have to wait and see what impact this has on the Wii homebrew scene as a whole, but it's not likely to be a positive one. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wizordum Review - An Homage to Heretic]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/wizordum-review-homage-to-heretic</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wizordum-review-an-homage-to-heretic.1175370/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/wizordum-review-homage-to-heretic<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>We live in a time where remasters for games are a dime a dozen, doubly so for boomer shooters. So why, then, is it the year 2025 and we still haven't seen a remaster for <em>Heretic</em> and <em>Hexen</em>, two of the most influential shooters of all time? Thankfully, Emberheart Games and <a href="https://techraptor.net/companies/apogee-entertainment" rel="nofollow">Apogee Entertainment</a> have created a worthy successor to those two with <em>Wizordum</em>.</p>

<p>I'm still going to beg the powers that be to remaster those two absolute classics, but <em>Wizordum</em> certainly tickles that <em>Heretic</em> itch. It's deeply inspired by those titles, of course, but also incorporates modern elements to liven up the gameplay into something more than just an imitation.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/wizordum-spooky-mansion.jpg?itok=Qwk_oBVO 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/wizordum-spooky-mansion.jpg?itok=bvjYi57_ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The best solution to killing a ghost is with a giant fireball, of course.</figcaption></figure><h2><em>Wizordum: </em>Every Level, an Adventure</h2>

<p>If you pay attention to the retro shooter scene, <em>Wizordum</em>'s been around for a bit. It's an <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/wizordum-preview-nostalgic-dungeon-delving-fps" rel="nofollow">Early Access</a> title, but the final episode (and a slew of fixes and tweaks to existing episodes) make this now a complete package. With three episodes, a bunch of magical weapons, and a ton of treasure, expect <em>Wizordum </em>to take you on quite an adventure.</p>

<p>And indeed, if there is one word that comes to mind with <em>Wizordum</em>, it's that: "Adventure." Boomer shooters are often known for their winding paths, getting lost, or hunting for keys.&nbsp;But constantly retreading old paths isn't an adventure. It can feel tedious. That's not the case with <em>Wizordum</em>, thankfully, despite how vast the levels feel.</p>

<p><em>Wizordum</em>'s levels are chock-full of treasure and secrets, and if you're into secret hunting, this game is absolutely for you. If you like running into walls, pressing the action button, and hoping to find a secret area, <em>Wizordum </em>fulfills that satisfaction. Usually, you gain treasure or ammo for your curiosity, meaning exploration is rewarding.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/wizordum-shop.jpg?itok=tN591-G_ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/wizordum-shop.jpg?itok=yzEASQ7a 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>What are ya buyin'?</figcaption></figure><p>Treasure can then be taken and exchanged for various upgrades at the end of levels. This is one part that I didn't see in Early Access; basically, complete a level, and you can buy secondary actions for weapons, or increase your capacity to fire spells attached to your chosen character. It adds a sense of progression in a genre that doesn't usually have much of that.</p>

<p>And yes, I mentioned characters. There are two, in fact, and they come with different spells and a unique primary weapon. The Cleric with his mace, or the Sorceress with her wand, whatever you choose, means your experience will vary. The Cleric and Sorceress also vary in health, armor, and speed, so pick what fits your play style.</p>

<p>The choice of two characters does merit some replayability, but the gameplay differences aren't so vast that it's a completely different experience. Nonetheless, I could see myself going back as the Cleric in a second playthrough, once more scrounging the world for the vast amounts of treasure I missed.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/wizordum-episode3_1.jpg?itok=ge3fJ-4D 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/wizordum-episode3_1.jpg?itok=3gBrCKDR 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Nice.</figcaption></figure><h2>A Strong Finish for <em>Wizordum</em>'s Episode 3</h2>

<p>If exploration is so greatly emphasized in <em>Wizordum</em>, one would hope that levels have creative and distinct layouts, and that's definitely the case here. Across <em>Wizordum</em><u>'</u>s three separate episodes, you can expect to fight in monster-infested villages, swampy ruins, spooky mansions, caverns of lava, and so much more.</p>

<p>You can tell, developer Emberheart Games got more confident and creative with level design after each episode. Episode 1 plays it pretty safe, and as such is the most bland of the three. It's not bad by any means, but compared to Episode 2 and especially Episode 3, it takes some time for <em>Wizordum</em> to build up.</p>

<p>Episode 2, then, is better than Episode 1, with more creative level design and elaborate puzzles. One level, for instance, takes place on a ship full of goblins. The ship feels a bit more claustrophobic and smaller in comparison to other levels, but that layout keeps things feeling fresh.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/wizordum-ep-3.jpg?itok=K8v9GLrT 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/wizordum-ep-3.jpg?itok=FTJ4xRHE 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>It's also gonna get chilly.</figcaption></figure><p>Episode 3 is the cream of the crop, with much larger levels, a higher difficulty curve, and essentially just combines all of what makes <em>Wizordum</em> great into a satisfying conclusion. One level, for instance, takes place in this sprawling, maze-like mine.&nbsp;</p>

<p>There were numerous approaches players could take in this interconnected network of tunnels. The goal was to find several gems to unlock a certain door in the center, and the path I took to gather all of these likely will look different than yours. Even still, I didn't feel lost, which is a testament to <em>Wizordum</em>'s handy map.</p>

<p>In general,&nbsp;the final episode has a much stronger visual design, too. Episode 1 and some aspects of Episode 2 are repetitive. Episode 1, for instance, has a lot of dilapidated villages and stone buildings to the point where much of it feels like you're walking in circles.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/wizordum-gauntlets.jpg?itok=qOeKNvMX 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/wizordum-gauntlets.jpg?itok=koC1urOq 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Unlimited powerrrrr!!!!</figcaption></figure><h2>Runnin' and Slingin' Spells in <em>Wizordum</em></h2>

<p>Like any good retro shooter, though, level design is just one piece of the pie. Gunplay, with a diverse set of weapons, is the other crucial component for a good shooter. Thankfully, I don't have much to complain about in that regard. By and large, <em>Wizordum</em>'s gunplay feels satisfying, and players are powerful.</p>

<p>It's easy to make guns sound powerful and intimidating, but spells, that's another story. With the exception of a magic pistol, every other weapon has that wizard flavor to it. Rings that let you cast fireballs, an icicle-shooting staff, or even lightning gauntlets -- I'm a fan of them all.</p>

<p>The ice staff, in particular, makes a satisfying sound when its projectiles impact enemies. The staff freezes them in place, so you can hit them once more with a weapon to shatter them; better yet, freeze a bunch of enemies in a group and shatter them at the same time for a satisfying end to your battle.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/wizordum-ice-staff.jpg?itok=yH6tNNuX 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/wizordum-ice-staff.jpg?itok=VRCQP-bv 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Time to freeze, pal.</figcaption></figure><p>You're also armed with a supply of items a la <em>Heretic </em>and <em>Hexen</em>. These all give gameplay benefits in one way or another, be it by healing you, turning you invisible, and the like. As mentioned, characters have specific spells, and those will also come in handy a great deal, especially on higher difficulties.</p>

<p>The Sorceress, for example, can reflect projectiles with one of her spells, which is a godsend when you're being overwhelmed. There's a time-based spell that greatly increases your attack speed, and that's also handy when taking down more powerful foes.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/wizordum-rat.jpg?itok=aB2Q8Z2G 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/wizordum-rat.jpg?itok=M7aC5PzL 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Sometimes you can find a rat mount, and I just like how this screenshot turned out. Looks like I'm about to run over this stupid little goblin.</figcaption></figure><h2>Wizordum Review | Final Thoughts</h2>

<p>Every episode is capped off with a boss. My review build didn't have a final boss, so my opinion could very well change, but the first two were rather dull. Like most boomer shooters, bosses amount to bullet sponges, and that just doesn't do much for me anymore. The second boss had a hint of nuance, but at the end of the day, it's point and shoot.</p>

<p>There were also a fair number of bugs, some of which I hope are fixed upon release. I fell below a level once and had to revert back to a save, for instance. Sometimes, enemies would be stuck in walls. Heck, the first boss just sat there and let me shoot him without any resistance.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/wizordum-screenshot.jpg?itok=HZkLgz83 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/wizordum-screenshot.jpg?itok=t8td7Bl3 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Such ambiance!</figcaption></figure><p>Despite a few flaws, <em>Wizordum</em> is a competent retro shooter with a lot of creativity and charm. The bright visuals serve as a nice contrast to the usual dark-and-gritty shooters, and it has a calming and whimsical soundtrack as opposed to a high-octane, all gas, no breaks sort of deal.</p>

<p>Whether you're diving into <em>Wizordum</em> for the first time or checking out the brand new Episode 3, you'll find this to be quite the enjoyable boomer shooter. No, it doesn't reinvent the wheel, but not every game needs to, so with that said, it's hard to go wrong with a bit of spell-slinging action.</p>

<hr><p><strong><em>Wizordum </em></strong><em>was reviewed over approximately 15 hours of gameplay on PC with a key provided by the publisher. All screenshots were taken during the review process.</em></p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Five Classic Star Wars Games Join GOG Preservation Program]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gog-preservation-program-star-wars</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/five-classic-star-wars-games-join-gog-preservation-program.1175367/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gog-preservation-program-star-wars<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>GOG has announced that five more games have joined its Preservation Program, and since May 4th is just around the corner, it's&nbsp;<em>Star Wars</em>' turn to be recognized this time.</p>

<p>In an announcement <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/news/lets_celebrate_may_the_4th_with_classic_star_wars_games_joining_the_gog_preservation_program" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">post</a>, GOG says it wants to honor the&nbsp;<em>Star Wars&nbsp;</em>franchise "by adding iconic classics from a galaxy far, far away" to the Preservation Program.</p>

<p>Just in case you need a reminder, the Preservation Program is <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gog-preservation-program" rel="nofollow">an initiative</a> through which GOG is pledging to keep certain games updated forever, ensuring that they'll be able to run on any PC hardware whether or not their developers are still officially supporting them.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/star-wars-gog-preservation-program-battlefront.jpg?itok=prBu0gBt 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/star-wars-gog-preservation-program-battlefront.jpg?itok=6d8LCx_S 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Star Wars: Battlefront&nbsp;</em>is one of the games being added to the GOG Preservation Program today.</figcaption></figure><p>Here are the five games that have been added to the GOG Preservation Program today. Bear in mind these are the originals, so remasters for games like&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/star-wars-dark-forces-remaster-release-date" rel="nofollow">Dark Forces</a>&nbsp;</em>and<i>&nbsp;Battlefront&nbsp;</i>aren't included here (and in the case of&nbsp;<em>Battlefront</em>, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/star-wars-battlefront-classic-collection-aspyr-response" rel="nofollow">that might be a good thing</a>).</p>

<ul><li><em>Star Wars: Dark Forces&nbsp;</em>(1995)</li>
	<li><em>Star Wars: X-Wing Special Edition&nbsp;</em>(1993)</li>
	<li><em>Star Wars: TIE Fighter Special Edition&nbsp;</em>(1994)</li>
	<li><em>Star Wars Battlefront&nbsp;</em>(2004)</li>
	<li><em>Star Wars: Rebel Assault 1&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>2&nbsp;</em>(1993 and 1995, respectively)</li>
</ul><p>To celebrate these games' addition to the Preservation Program, GOG has also slapped a pretty hefty 75% discount on all of them. That discount runs until May 6th, so make sure you pick them up before then if you want any of them.</p>




<p>As for what lies ahead when it comes to&nbsp;<em>Star Wars&nbsp;</em>games, the future looks bright for the franchise. Recently, Respawn and Bit Reactor <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/star-wars-zero-company-respawn-bit-reactor" rel="nofollow">revealed</a>&nbsp;<em>Star Wars Zero Company</em>, a turn-based tactics game set towards the end of the Clone Wars.</p>

<p>In addition,&nbsp;<em>Star Wars Outlaws&nbsp;</em>is <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/star-wars-outlaws-switch-2-release-date-dlc-2" rel="nofollow">making its way to the Nintendo Switch 2</a>, and&nbsp;<em>Star Wars Eclipse&nbsp;</em>developer Quantic Dream <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/quantic-dream-unaffected-netease-layoffs" rel="nofollow">recently confirmed it was "unaffected"</a> by sweeping <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/marvel-rivals-studio-shockingly-closed-by-netease-laying-off-everyone" rel="nofollow">layoffs</a> at parent company NetEase, so hopefully, we'll be hearing from that game sooner rather than later.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oblivion to Starfield: Bethesda's 20 Year Journey to The Elder Scrolls 6]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/opinions/oblivion-to-starfield-bethesdas-20-year-journey-to-elder-scrolls-6</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/oblivion-to-starfield-bethesdas-20-year-journey-to-the-elder-scrolls-6.1175364/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/opinions/oblivion-to-starfield-bethesdas-20-year-journey-to-elder-scrolls-6<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>There's something to be said about the loyalty of <em>The Elder Scrolls</em> fans when Bethesda can re-release a 20-year-old game with no official marketing and it still ends up at the top of Steam's bestseller list. Amusingly, there's even a non-zero chance that some of the people who are currently playing <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-released" rel="nofollow"><em>The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered</em></a> weren't born when the game first came out.</p>

<p>Admittedly, this loyalty isn't entirely undeserved when you look at Bethesda's history. For all the complaining that people do, and some of it quite justifiable, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-15th-anniversary" rel="nofollow">Bethesda's games are very much one of a kind</a>. For RPG fans, they somewhat literally define a console generation.</p>

<p>There have been no shortage of competitors either. Every so often, an RPG comes out with better mechanics than what any Bethesda game has to offer, yet time and again, people keep flocking back to <em>The Elder Scrolls</em>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/morrowind-imperial-legion.jpg?itok=tiix8Oa6 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/morrowind-imperial-legion.jpg?itok=bFS7P9Ka 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>"Patrolling Morrowind almost makes you wish for a volcanic eruption."</figcaption></figure><p>After all, it's hard to argue that contemporary games like <em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/avowed-review-pillars-of-excellence" rel="nofollow">Avowed</a> </em>don't have objectively better role playing mechanics. The <em>Dragon Age</em> and <em>Mass Effect</em> games blow Bethesda games out of the water when it comes to the writing for romances and companions, not to mention actual reputation systems. <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/baldurs-gate-3-review" rel="nofollow"><em>Baldur's Gate 3</em></a> is in an entirely different league in almost every practical metric if you overlook the differences in sub-genre.</p>

<h2>What's in the Secret Sauce, Todd?</h2>

<p>Indeed, most people would fully acknowledge that <em>The Elder Scrolls'</em>&nbsp;approach to combat has historically been its weak point. The writing for faction quests in particular can be hit or miss too. Throw in the increasingly simplified reputation system and ever present bugs and you might wonder what do <em>The Elder Scrolls</em> games actually offer to deserve their fame.</p>

<p>The answer is that very few games on the market have player-to-NPC interaction, player-to-world interaction, NPC-to-NPC interaction, and NPC-to-world interaction running more or less seamlessly and simultaneously. To put it simply, Bethesda specializes in creating living worlds, and sometimes "it just works."</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/oblivion-remaster-spriggan.jpg?itok=5iXcb-8d 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/oblivion-remaster-spriggan.jpg?itok=xYvkvINp 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>With graphics such as these, it's time for another <em>Skyrim </em>remaster!</figcaption></figure><p>Case in point, <em>Oblivion </em>is a 20-year-old game where NPCs have their own schedules and can react to changes in their environment. They'll walk around, go to sleep, talk to each other, and if you commit crimes, they'll react appropriately. You can then walk up and talk to, rob, murder, or simply observe most NPCs and they'll more or less act logically. The same feature (with some tweaks) has since been a key feature of Bethesda's major RPGs.</p>

<p>By comparison, most developers opt for static NPCs because it's (presumably) easier, faster, and less prone to causing problems. Recently, <em>Avowed </em>was criticized for this as you could literally steal food off people's plates and they wouldn't react at all. Was it easier for the developers? Most likely. Did it bother people who care about such things? Almost certainly.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/skyrim-riverwood.jpg?itok=m4G9XizD 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/skyrim-riverwood.jpg?itok=0QEPpxL3 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>If the NPCs are standing around and doing nothing in a Bethsda game, that's usually a sign that you might want to reload the area or restart the game entirely.</figcaption></figure><p>In purely practical terms, there's no difference between the two approaches. At the very least it seems doubtful that the average player is following <em>Oblivion </em>or <em>Skyrim's </em>NPCs around to make sure that they are eating and sleeping. The difference is that Bethesda's approach maintains an illusion of a living world, and for such games it goes a long way to engaging with players.</p>

<p>A living virtual world isn't created "simply" by having NPCs that can move though. The world itself needs to feel like people lived in it. In <em>The Elder Scrolls'</em>&nbsp;case, that means making up 10,000 years of history. Civilizations rise and civilizations fall, so Bethesda isn't just writing a made up culture for each of the playable races, they're also creating societies that might have gone extinct for peoples who no longer exist or have simply undergone a culture shift.</p>

<p>This means distinct clothing styles, architecture, religions, languages and naming conventions, even literature. While inspiration can be taken from real life, as evidenced by <em>Oblivion's</em> Western European-themed Cyrodiil, you've still got the truly alien Shivering Isles in the eponymous DLC and the planes of Oblivion to contend with.</p>

<p>It's nothing short of a herculean task, and while other game developers can and have produced similarly amazing work, Bethesda remains one of the best in the field for a good reason.</p>

<h2>Did Bethesda Forget The Strength of Their Own Games?</h2>

<p>Unfortunately, Bethesda seems to struggle once they leave their area of expertise. <em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/fallout-76-review-total-wasteland" rel="nofollow">Fallout 76's</a> </em>early years certainly didn't do much to disprove this notion. Between the lack of NPCs, live-service multiplayer with no private servers, and PvP where you can lose your loot, it's a small miracle that the game survived long enough to be updated to a more palatable state.</p>

<p><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/starfield-review-interstellar-adventure" rel="nofollow"><em>Starfield</em>'s mixed reception</a>&nbsp;only intensified people's concerns regarding the future of <em>The Elder Scrolls VI</em>. Make no mistake, <em>Starfield </em>had some novel gameplay mechanics, but features like randomly generating the surfaces of 1,000 planets lacks widespread practical appeal. If anything, Bethesda should've realized this when <em>Oblivion </em>was first released, if not earlier with <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/22320/The_Elder_Scrolls_III_Morrowind_Game_of_the_Year_Edition/" rel="nofollow"><em>Morrowind</em></a>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/eso-content-pass.jpg?itok=_uheZOIT 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/eso-content-pass.jpg?itok=aLnJr93Z 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Supposedly, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/306130/The_Elder_Scrolls_Online/" rel="nofollow"><em>Elder Scrolls Online</em></a> is a decent way to get your<em> Elder Scrolls</em> fix if you don't mind MMO mechanics</figcaption></figure><p>That AAA game development is trending towards greater complexity is not a comforting fact either. Bethesda's games are notoriously buggy as is. One can only imagine the problems that can arise when you add more features, more NPCs, more of everything. Granted, most of the common bugs in Bethesda's games aren't really game breaking, so it's more of an unfounded fear than anything else unless you are diving deep into modding.</p>

<p>The potential for feature creep is a far greater concern. We went from building our own houses in <em>Skyrim </em>to building settlements in<em> <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/fallout-4-5-year-anniversary" rel="nofollow">Fallout 4</a></em> to building spaceships in <em>Starfield</em>. It's a very neat feature that can be improved upon in <em>The Elder Scrolls VI</em>. However, if Bethesda intends to treat the building aspect the same way that they "improved" the settlement system in <em>Starfield </em>by making it needlessly complex and tedious, then it's better to omit it altogether.</p>

<h2><em>The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered&nbsp;</em>- From Oblivion to Skyrim to Hammerfell and High Rock?</h2>

<p>That being said, it seems questionable that anyone genuinely believes that <em>The Elder Scrolls VI</em>&nbsp;will be literally unplayable at launch. Whether or not it will live up to people's high expectations of both the franchise and the developer is up to debate, which is the real cause for concern.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/eso-alliances.jpg?itok=Z0Ae46We 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/eso-alliances.jpg?itok=_SbD_7VC 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>If there's anything that <em>The Elder Scrolls 6</em> should borrow from <em>The Elder Scrolls Online</em>, it's the fashion styles and transmog system.</figcaption></figure><p>Thankfully, the success of the <em>Oblivion</em>&nbsp;remaster should provide at least two bits of good news for Bethesda. The first is that people still love the <em>Elder Scrolls</em> games, warts and all. <em>Oblivion </em>is fundamentally the same game as it was 20 years ago, and if people can overlook the strange quirks of the game today, then that's a good enough baseline for determining the absolute bare minimum of what <em>The Elder Scrolls VI</em>&nbsp;should feel like.</p>

<p>Secondly, and perhaps more importantly, is that Bethesda should be able to get relatively fresh feedback. Again, it should be pointed out that there is a non-zero chance that some of the people who are playing <em>Oblivion Remastered</em> weren't born when the original was released. Even returning players should be able to provide better feedback with an additional 20 years of context. That there is no release date for <em>The Elder Scrolls VI&nbsp;</em>means that time is on Bethesda's side, and they can and should course correct if needed before it's too late.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Anson is a Writer at TechRaptor and has been playing games for as long as he can remember. As far as he's concerned, games are one of the greatest forms of… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/anson-chan">More about Anson</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>