<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 13:54:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metal Gear Solid Delta Release Date Seemingly Leaked Via PlayStation Store]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/metal-gear-solid-delta-release-date-leak-playstation</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metal-gear-solid-delta-release-date-seemingly-leaked-via-playstation-store.1101852/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/metal-gear-solid-delta-release-date-leak-playstation<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear Solid Delta&nbsp;</em>release date appears to have been leaked via the game's PlayStation Store listing, and if the leak is correct, then the hotly-anticipated remake will be launching in summer.</p>

<p>As spotted by ResetEra user <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/metal-gear-solid-delta-releases-august-25th-2025-new-trailer-on-ps-store-snake-vs-monkey-teased.1101735/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">NateDog</a>, a new <a href="https://vulcan.dl.playstation.net/img/rnd/202502/0611/2c429928f5c5b20df3c78f5053ace69c011d4f391782ab47.mp4" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">trailer</a> has appeared on the PlayStation Store's backend that shows off some of the game's content, including various iconic scenes and boss battles from&nbsp;<em>Snake Eater</em>. The release date is then given as August 28th.</p>

<p>Perhaps most excitingly, the trailer also seems to confirm the release of the Snake vs. Monkey gameplay mode, which saw the worlds of&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Ape Escape&nbsp;</em>collide in an unlikely crossover.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/metal-gear-solid-delta-release-date-snake.jpg?itok=Aw9T2VUp 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/metal-gear-solid-delta-release-date-snake.jpg?itok=g0UYVW71 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Metal Gear Solid Delta&nbsp;</em>looks set for an August release.</figcaption></figure><p>If the Snake vs. Monkey minigame is indeed included, it could well mark the<em>&nbsp;Ape Escape</em>&nbsp;series' first appearance outside the PlayStation ecosystem, although there's also every chance that the minigame is PlayStation-exclusive.</p>

<p>A quick look at the current <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-gb/concept/10007293/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation Store page</a> for&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear Solid Delta&nbsp;</em>also shows the August 28th release date, so it's likely Konami will soon officially release the trailer and confirm the date.</p>

<p>According to leaker <a href="https://x.com/NateTheHate2/status/1885592410589110653" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">NateTheHate</a>, who accurately predicted the date on which the Nintendo Switch 2 would be revealed, a PlayStation State of Play showcase will air this month. He currently seems to be suggesting that it'll take place <a href="https://x.com/NateTheHate2/status/1885748440132456877" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">on Valentine's Day</a>.</p>

<p>If that is indeed the case, then I wouldn't be surprised if the&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear Solid Delta&nbsp;</em>release date trailer aired during that presentation, which would also probably be why the Snake vs. Monkey minigame is shown.</p>




<p>As for&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater&nbsp;</em>itself, it's a remake of the classic 2004 PS2 stealth-action game&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear Solid 3: Snake Eater</em>.</p>

<p>Announced <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/metal-gear-solid-3-remake-announced-at-state-of-play" rel="nofollow">during a PlayStation showcase in May 2023</a>, the remake will offer completely reworked visuals and gameplay, complete with a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/metal-gear-solid-d-snake-eater-remake-reveals-first-spectacular-gameplay-in-unreal" rel="nofollow">transition to Unreal Engine 5</a>. It will, however, retain the voice audio of the original game and won't recast any actors.</p>

<p>The game is also being developed without the involvement of series creator Hideo Kojima, who's currently <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/death-stranding-2-filming-and-recording-completed" rel="nofollow">hard at work on&nbsp;</a><em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/death-stranding-2-filming-and-recording-completed" rel="nofollow">Death Stranding 2</a>&nbsp;</em>(as well as a stealth action game of his own mysteriously codenamed&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hideo-kojima-announces-next-generation-espionage-action-game" rel="nofollow"><em>Physint</em></a>).</p>

<p>Assuming this leak is indeed correct,&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater&nbsp;</em>is due to launch for <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2417610/METAL_GEAR_SOLID_D_SNAKE_EATER/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-gb/concept/10007293/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/metal-gear-solid-d-snake-eater/9pjln214rtkq" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a> on August 28th. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>