<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 23:15:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blood: Refreshed Supply Review - Inject It In My Veins]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/blood-refreshed-supply-review-inject-it-in-my-veins</link>
            <guid>1373764</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Typically lauded as one of the best shooters of its era, <em>Blood</em> is a game I've tried to enjoy so many times, but things just never clicked. It's weird, because I voraciously consume games like <em>Shadow Warrior, </em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/quake-remastered-review" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow"><em>Quake</em></a>, and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/duke-nukem-3d-world-tour-review-world-star" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow"><em>Duke Nukem 3D</em></a>, all of which have similar gameplay and came out within a year or so of <em>Blood</em>.&nbsp;</p><p>I love the work <a href="https://techraptor.net/companies/nightdive-studios/" rel="nofollow">Nightdive</a> does and, though I was apprehensive about trying <em>Blood: Refreshed Supply -- </em>a remaster built from the ground up with new code and tons of enhancements -- I bit the bullet and went for it. I'm happy to say that <em>Blood</em> finally clicked for me, and now I see why it's such a cherished title.&nbsp;</p><figure role="group">
<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/blood-refreshed-supply.jpg?itok=MYxYjReb 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/blood-refreshed-supply.jpg?itok=34QgriC9 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>
<figcaption>It's time to make a boom.</figcaption>
</figure>
<h3>My Interest in <em>Blood </em>is Refreshed</h3><p>If you've read my Nightdive reviews, you know the drill by now: We start with the enhancements and improvements. Nightdive always exceeds expectations in this regard. Nightdive's previous touch-ups with <em>Blood: Fresh Supply</em> (not to be confused with <em>Refreshed Supply) </em>felt a bit too antiquated for me. With all the improvements from this remaster, things feel on par with Nightdive's most recent ports.</p><p>Rebuilding the entirety of <em>Blood</em> from its source code seems to have done wonders in terms of feel, because the gameplay is buttery smooth. Movement feels perfect, and the gunplay is impactful. Not to mention, it looks fantastic. <em>Blood: Refreshed Supply</em>'s revitalized visuals proves this is one of the best looking games from its era.</p><p>This is comparing the visuals to the original, but when comparing the two ports, I want to say there might be just a <em>slight</em> improvement over <em>Fresh Supply</em>. Perhaps the most noticeable change is the re-done cutscenes. These are done with brand new 3D models.&nbsp;</p><figure role="group">
<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/blood-refreshed-supply-cutscene.jpg?itok=dh5PdkWU 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/blood-refreshed-supply-cutscene.jpg?itok=yAaXzJdc 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>
<figcaption>Bro's friend is a spider-web.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The old cutscenes were often too dark, muddy, and compressed for me to even tell what was going on. With these new changes, <em>Blood: Refreshed Supply</em> allowed me to get engaged with the story, even if cutscenes are few and far between. Everything still looks pretty retro, mind you, so Nightdive keeps the old-school aesthetic in these.</p><p>Outside of these revamped cutscenes, <em>Blood:</em> <em>Refreshed Supply </em>stands out by adding fixes to enemy behavior. These include "Improve Monster Navigation Around Water" and "Fix Gargoyle Aiming," and a bunch of other things, all of which can be toggled on and off. Oldheads will probably appreciate these changes, but as someone who hasn't gotten too far in <em>Blood</em> in the past, I'll just appreciate that these made the game more accessible.</p><figure role="group">
<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/blood-refreshed-supply-unreleased-level.jpg?itok=AjY44MU6 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/blood-refreshed-supply-unreleased-level.jpg?itok=zWNAgbn8 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>
<figcaption>Very interesting to see an in-progress level, untouched since the 90s!</figcaption>
</figure>
<p><em>Blood: Refreshed </em>supply also includes a new scenario called Marrow, and another one in a future update. More content is great, and while I haven't had a chance to dive into this scenario yet, I understand there's also another on the way, so that's super exciting.</p><p>And besides that, there are <em>tons</em>, and I mean <em>tons, </em>of prototype and unreleased levels available in <em>Blood: Refreshed Supply</em>. Nightdive likes to include the "Vault" in their games, which has a bunch of concept art and behind-the-scenes documents and videos, but sometimes they even come with unreleased levels.&nbsp;</p><p>There are quite literally dozens of these to play and choose from, so I can see how this feature would be appreciated by longtime fans. It's fascinating to see a behind-the-scenes look at the level creation process, especially so for a game almost 30 years old.</p><figure role="group">
<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/blood-refreshed-supply-boss.jpg?itok=hcTViRyi 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/blood-refreshed-supply-boss.jpg?itok=X6DInHpG 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>
<figcaption>Pump this boss full of lead!</figcaption>
</figure>
<h3>Dynamite!</h3><p>By now, you know my history with <em>Blood</em>: It just never clicked with me. I found it too difficult, at least in the beginning stages. Because of that, this time I opted for a lower difficulty, and I'm glad I did.&nbsp;</p><p>A few issues with my previous forays into <em>Blood: </em>Ammo and health are stingy at the start, and you feel outmatched. This isn't inherently a bad thing, but when cultists hitscan you with their guns, it becomes a nuisance. I got past the initial hump on the now lower difficulty and completed several episodes, which is way further than I've ever gone before.</p><p>Yes, cultists still hitscan you and that's annoying, but at least I'm able to get the lay of the land and grasp the basics of <em>Blood</em>. And because I gave the game a chance with <em>Blood: Refreshed Supply</em>'s new improvements and my change in mindset, I found that this shooter has some of the most creative weapons and level design in the genre.</p><figure role="group">
<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/blood-refreshed-supply-voodoo-doll.jpg?itok=p8mahzUQ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/blood-refreshed-supply-voodoo-doll.jpg?itok=yK9_iM6p 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>
<figcaption>Get poked, bozo.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>While weapon variety is wanting (there are like several different types of dynamite, which isn't all that compelling), the rest of the roster feels great to use. <em>Blood: Refreshed Supply</em>'s weapons are super unconventional: A flare gun that takes a few seconds to alight, a very short-ranged shotgun, and the double-edged sword that is the dynamite.</p><p>The dynamite feels great to use once you have a bunch of bundles at your disposal. Causing a bunch of explosions and gibbing enemies is great, and it also requires you to be careful of your position to the dyanmite considering it also hurts <em>you</em>. So, when your back is against the wall, and a bunch of zombies are attacking you, do you clear them out fast with dynamite and risk getting blown up, or try a less practical alternative?&nbsp;</p><p>Eventually, you'll find a napalm launcher, a Tesla cannon, and most -- if not all -- weapons also have an alt-fire. My favorite weapon of the bunch would have to be the voodoo doll. You poke it with a needle to damage enemies, and it packs a surprising punch. It's super goofy and creative, adding so much charm to the aesthetic of <em>Blood: Refreshed Supply</em>.</p><figure role="group">
<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/blood-refreshed-supply-the-shining.jpg?itok=6h8s1baz 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/blood-refreshed-supply-the-shining.jpg?itok=eYuOXkwe 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>
<figcaption>Here's Johnny!</figcaption>
</figure>
<h3><em>Blood: Refreshed Supply </em>is a Quirky Horror Game With Undeniably 90s DNA</h3><p>Level design is another standout. The first two levels are arguably the weakest, and where I'd most often get bored and frustrated, and just quit in my previous playthroughs. Get past that initial hump and you start to see the personality of <em>Blood: Refreshed Supply </em>shine.&nbsp;</p><p>One of the most memorable levels early on is a circus, complete with poppable balloons, tons of attractions, and mimes that you can just kill for no reason at all. The non-linear layout of this level makes it engaging, and you can tell the original developers put a lot of love and care into <em>Blood</em>.</p><figure role="group">
<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/blood-refreshed-supply-jojo.jpg?itok=8tx0BOMv 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/blood-refreshed-supply-jojo.jpg?itok=AelEUs2j 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>
<figcaption>Sign me the heck up for some monkey wrestling.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>I also deeply enjoyed exploring the interiors of a hotel inspired by <em>The Shining</em>, complete with a wintery maze and tons of creepy surprises waiting for you. After seeing what <em>Blood: Refreshed Supply</em> had to offer in terms of level design, it has this cheesy horror feel that only a game from the 90s could achieve; previously, I thought it to be a more sinister, creepy game.</p><p>To be clear, <em>Blood: Refreshed Supply</em> is still a dark game in terms of subject matter -- you're killing demons, cultists, and gore is aplenty -- but the quirkiness of the 90s adds a lot to my enjoyment of this game.</p><figure role="group">
<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/blood-refreshed-supply-akimbo.jpg?itok=5kn-jkCN 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/blood-refreshed-supply-akimbo.jpg?itok=GLWthSYw 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>
<figcaption>Gunplay feels oh so good.</figcaption>
</figure>
<h3><em>Blood: Refreshed Supply</em> Review | Final Thoughts</h3><p><em>Blood: Refreshed Supply</em> is an excellent port of an excellent game. In all likelihood, you didn't need me to tell you this. What I do hope is that my review encourages those similar to me -- individuals who couldn't get into <em>Blood</em> for one reason or another -- to give it another shot with this revitalized version.</p><p><em>Blood: Refreshed Supply</em> is a case of Nightdive doing what Nightdive does best: Taking a game with, let's say, some antiquated features, and making it more accessible for modern audiences. Now, it's time for me to dive back in and play more of this fantastic remaster, and you best bet I'll be waiting for that new and upcoming scenario with eager anticipation.&nbsp;</p><hr><p><em><strong>Blood: Refreshed Supply</strong> was reviewed on PC using a code provided by the developer over the course of 6 hours of gameplay - all screenshots were taken during the process of review.</em></p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Austin cut his teeth writing various&nbsp; fan-fiction stories on the RuneScape forums when he was in elementary school. Later on, he developed a deep love… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/austin-suther">More about Austin</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/blood-refreshed-supply-review-inject-it-in-my-veins]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Asymmetrical Horror Adaptation Halloween Reveals Haddonfield Heights Map]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/asymmetrical-horror-adaptation-halloween-reveals-haddonfield-heights-map</link>
            <guid>1373725</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer and publisher IllFonic has revealed the first map for its upcoming asymmetrical <em>Halloween </em>multiplayer game, and it'll be a familiar one if you're a <em>Halloween </em>movie series aficionado.</p><p>The Haddonfield Heights map is, according to the developer, a "meticulously recreated map straight out of the 1978 horror classic", and it'll bring you "deep into the heart of the town", with a view of the "iconic" Haddonfield water tower in the distance.</p><p>You'll be able to explore "plenty of front yards and winding side streets", according to IllFonic, and since <em>Halloween </em>is a <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/dead-by-daylight" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="8e3308ac-c5b5-4add-9d7d-6c0f8a246189" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Dead by Daylight</em></a>-style asymmetrical experience, you can do so either as the terrifying Michael Myers or as a desperate survivor attempting to escape his wrath.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption>Haddonfield Heights should provide a thrill if you're a <em>Halloween</em> movie fan.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>IllFonic design director Jordan Mathewson says Haddonfield allowed the team to "reimagine the tension" of the town "in a way that feels both intimate and terrifying".</p><p>He says the studio wanted players to "feel the comfort of the neighborhood they recognize from the film" before it quickly descends into "panic", with each "hedge, hallway, and backyard" intended to "heighten suspense and reward clever play".</p><p>If you're not familiar with <em>Halloween</em>, it's an upcoming asymmetrical multiplayer horror game along the same lines as Behaviour's <em>Dead by Daylight </em>or IllFonic's own <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/friday-13th-dedicated-servers-shutting-down-this-month" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="c879cbbc-8ea0-4c10-a2ef-2b4cd295e2a3" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">ill-fated</a> <em>Friday the 13th: The Game</em>.</p><p>Playing as either The Shape (also known as Michael Myers) or one of his victims, you'll be tasked with either slaughtering everyone who's playing as a survivor or attempting to phone the police for help before Myers catches you.</p>
<p>You'll be able to check out IllFonic's new take on the <em>Halloween </em>series when the game launches across <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3219630/Halloween/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">PC</a>, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X|S on September 8th. Stay tuned for more on this and all other things (belatedly) spooky.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/asymmetrical-horror-adaptation-halloween-reveals-haddonfield-heights-map]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>