<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 14:43:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Spooky GameCube Classic Luigi's Mansion Hits Nintendo Switch Online This Month]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/luigis-mansion-nintendo-switch-online</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/spooky-gamecube-classic-luigis-mansion-hits-nintendo-switch-online-this-month.1331461/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Nintendo has announced the latest GameCube game to join the Nintendo Switch Online library, and just in time for Halloween, it's spooky horror classic&nbsp;<em>Luigi's Mansion</em>'s turn in the spotlight.</p>

<p>Alright, so perhaps&nbsp;<em>Luigi's Mansion&nbsp;</em>isn't the scariest game in the GameCube's lineup; that honor arguably goes to Silicon Knights' <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/horror-gaming-obscura-eternal-darkness-sanitys-requiem" rel="nofollow">excellent&nbsp;<em>Eternal Darkness: Sanity's Requiem</em></a>, which remains unavailable on Switch Online for some baffling reason.</p>

<p>Still, if you want a survival horror-tinged game the whole family can gather around the Switch 2 to play, then&nbsp;<em>Luigi's Mansion&nbsp;</em>is a very solid choice. It's landing on Switch Online on October 30th, although you're <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-gamecube-switch-2-online" rel="nofollow">going to need a Switch 2</a> to play it.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/nintendo-switch-online-luigis-mansion-gameplay.jpg?itok=T-dUiGLF 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/nintendo-switch-online-luigis-mansion-gameplay.jpg?itok=BdmOz_4b 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Luigi's Mansion&nbsp;</em>is finally coming to Nintendo Switch Online. Hooray!</figcaption></figure><p>This is the original&nbsp;<em>Luigi's Mansion&nbsp;</em>release, rather than the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-direct-march-2018-luigis-mansion-remake" rel="nofollow">Nintendo 3DS remake</a> that launched back in 2018. Like pretty much all games that originated on the 3DS, that remake isn't playable on modern hardware (through conventional methods, at least).</p>

<p>If you're unfamiliar with&nbsp;<em>Luigi's Mansion</em>, it's essentially a sort of Nintendo-ified take on the&nbsp;<em>Resident Evil&nbsp;</em>formula. Luigi has inherited a mansion in a competition he doesn't remember entering, and he must explore said mansion in order to uncover its mysteries and find out what's happened to his brother Mario.</p>

<p>To do so, he'll have to battle ghosts using his iconic Poltergust 3000, a vacuum cleaner that's been specially tuned to hoover up spirits (although it'll also deal with various other items in Luigi's environment).</p>

<p><em>Luigi's Mansion&nbsp;</em>also features a somewhat similar structure to&nbsp;<em>Resident Evil</em>, with Luigi hunting for keys around the mansion and periodically battling boss ghosts to progress through the game's story.</p>




<p>This re-release means that all three&nbsp;<em>Luigi's Mansion&nbsp;</em>games are now available to play on Switch or Switch 2 hardware; a remake of sequel&nbsp;<em>Dark Moon</em>&nbsp;is available now on Switch, as is the <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/luigis-mansion-3" rel="nofollow">third mainline entry in the series</a>.</p>

<p>You'll be able to check out&nbsp;<em>Luigi's Mansion&nbsp;</em>via Switch Online starting from October 30th, but you'll need a subscription and the Expansion Pack addon to do so.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/luigis-mansion-nintendo-switch-online]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Remedy CEO Tero Virtala Steps Down "With Immediate Effect"]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/remedy-ceo-tero-virtala-steps-down</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/remedy-ceo-tero-virtala-steps-down-with-immediate-effect.1331458/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Remedy CEO Tero Virtala is to step down with immediate effect, and the&nbsp;<em>Alan Wake&nbsp;</em>and<i>&nbsp;Control&nbsp;</i>studio hasn't found itself a permanent replacement for him yet.</p>

<p>That's according to a <a href="https://investors.remedygames.com/releases-and-events/announcements-and-releases/?publicationId=49a7f7db-a1c3-400f-948b-f25b3b7426f8" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">news post</a> on the official Remedy website, in which the studio reveals that Virtala will be stepping down and that his interim replacement will be&nbsp;Markus Mäki, who previously served as Remedy's Chairman of the Board.</p>

<p>Naturally,&nbsp;Mäki will be vacating that role in order to serve as interim CEO. He'll be replaced as Chairman by&nbsp;Henri Österlund, who's served on Remedy's board for eight years.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/remedy-ceo-tero-virtala-steps-down-control.jpg?itok=IQyx8ZZL 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/remedy-ceo-tero-virtala-steps-down-control.jpg?itok=7iChKOL1 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Tero Virtala, CEO of&nbsp;<em>Control&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Alan Wake&nbsp;</em>studio Remedy, is stepping down.</figcaption></figure><p>Remedy says it's initiating its search for a new CEO "immediately", and that Virtala will remain in his position in order to assist with handover once a permanent replacement is found.</p>

<p>No reason for Virtala's departure was given, but it's been a rough year or two for Remedy, to say the least. Back in August, the studio admitted that sales of its latest release, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/fbc-firebreak-control-spinoff-announced" rel="nofollow">multiplayer shooter</a>&nbsp;<em>FBC: Firebreak</em>, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/remedy-fbc-firebreak-launch-sales-financials" rel="nofollow">had been unsatisfying</a>.</p>

<p>A major update for the game, Breakpoint, was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/fbc-firebreak-breakpoint-update" rel="nofollow">released back in September</a>, and while it briefly injected a little life back into&nbsp;<em>FBC: Firebreak</em>, it hasn't been enough to sustain player interest, if <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/2272540/charts/#3m" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">SteamDB's numbers</a> are anything to go by.</p>

<p>It hasn't all been dire for Virtala and Remedy over the last twelve months or so, though; back in February, Remedy announced that survival horror title&nbsp;<em>Alan Wake 2&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/alan-wake-2-profitable-sales-2m" rel="nofollow">was finally profitable</a>, having hit the two million sales mark around that time.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/alan-wake-2-remedy-ceo-steps-down.jpg?itok=didfl9OL 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/alan-wake-2-remedy-ceo-steps-down.jpg?itok=gaDT1WZv 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Alan Wake 2&nbsp;</em>proved profitable for Remedy, but it seems&nbsp;<em>FBC: Firebreak&nbsp;</em>has not.</figcaption></figure><p>With regards to Remedy's future, the company is currently working on a sequel to&nbsp;<em>Control&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/remedy-annapurna-control-2-tv-movies" rel="nofollow">alongside publisher Annapurna</a>, and remakes of the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/max-payne-remakes-control-spinoff-remedy" rel="nofollow">first two games in the&nbsp;<em>Max Payne&nbsp;</em>series</a> are also on the way.</p>

<p>It remains to be seen whether Virtala stepping down will affect Remedy's future plans in any way, but I'd imagine the studio will think twice before greenlighting a project like&nbsp;<em>FBC: Firebreak&nbsp;</em>again. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/remedy-ceo-tero-virtala-steps-down]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>