<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 22:48:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yacht Club Games' Mina the Hollower Set to Launch in October]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/mina-the-hollower-release-date-yacht-club</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/yacht-club-games-mina-the-hollower-set-to-launch-in-october.1210080/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/mina-the-hollower-release-date-yacht-club<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Mina the Hollower</em>&nbsp;made it to the biggest show of the season, with its release day being unveiled during Geoff Keighley's Summer Games Fest presentation. Finally, players can get their hands on the full release later this year -- but if you can't wait, there's also a demo.</p>



<h2>When&nbsp;can you play&nbsp;<em>Mina the Hollower</em>?</h2>

<p>The <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1875580/Mina_the_Hollower/" rel="nofollow">full version</a> of&nbsp;<em>Mina the Hollower&nbsp;</em>comes out on October 31, 2025, the perfect date for the game's spooky and gothic aesthetic. Meanwhile, a demo is available to play now and during Steam Next Fest, which starts on June 9 and ends on June 16.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This comes after a series of delays in order to improve the quality and widen the scope of&nbsp;<em>Mina the Hollower</em>. Developer <a href="https://techraptor.net/companies/yacht-club-games" rel="nofollow">Yacht Club Games</a> launched a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/mina-hollower-yacht-club-games-sets-sail-with-new-ip" rel="nofollow">Kickstarter</a> for&nbsp;<em>Mina the Hollower</em>&nbsp;in 2022 and surpassed its goal quickly. It earned over a million dollars in funding from its campaign and achieved numerous stretch goals in the process.</p>



<h2>What's&nbsp;<em>Mina the Hollower </em>about?</h2>

<p>Having gotten a chance to play the game several times during its development,&nbsp;TechRaptor's very own Austin Suther (that's me) found it to be an <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/mina-the-hollower-preview-small-mouse-big-world" rel="nofollow">excellent homage</a> to classic Game Boy Color titles. This is in the same vein as Yacht Club Games' previous title,&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/shovel-knight" rel="nofollow"><em>Shovel Knight</em></a>, which was a modern interpretation of classic NES games.</p>

<p>The demo on Steam Next Fest takes players through the opening half hour-or-so of&nbsp;<em>Mina the Hollower.&nbsp;</em>Players take the role of the eponymous mouse and inventor, Mina, who, on the way to visit a friend, finds herself shipwrecked on the coast of Tenebrous Isle.&nbsp;</p>



<p>From there, players will fight and dig their way across the isle and arrive at their destination: the town of Ossex. The path forward is fraught with peril as you fight off monsters and get a grasp for&nbsp;<em>Mina the Hollower</em>'s mechanics. Near the end of the demo, we also get a taste for the narrative, which has a darker tone compared to that of&nbsp;<em>Shovel Knight</em>.</p>

<p>You'll be able to pick your starter weapon, and from there find others later on in the game. The demo ends with an exciting boss fight against one of&nbsp;<em>Mina the Hollower</em>'s main antagonists.&nbsp;</p>

<p>If you choose to pick up the full release, progress from this demo will carry over to the final game once <em>Mina the Hollower</em>&nbsp;launches later this year on Halloween, which is, as always, October 31st.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Austin cut his teeth writing various&nbsp; fan-fiction stories on the RuneScape forums when he was in elementary school. Later on, he developed a deep love for… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/austin-suther">More about Austin</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>