<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 14:19:30 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age: The Veilguard and EA Sports FC 25 "Underperformed", EA Says]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dragon-age-veilguard-ea-sports-fc-25-underperformed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-the-veilguard-and-ea-sports-fc-25-underperformed-ea-says.1089744/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dragon-age-veilguard-ea-sports-fc-25-underperformed<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>EA has released its preliminary financial report for the third quarter of the 2024-25 fiscal year, and the company says that two of its biggest releases for the period underperformed.</p>

<p>Per a <a href="https://ir.ea.com/press-releases/press-release-details/2025/Electronic-Arts-Pre-Announces-Preliminary-Q3-FY25-Results/default.aspx" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">press release</a>, both&nbsp;<em>Dragon Age: The Veilguard&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>EA Sports FC 25&nbsp;</em>were financial disappointments for EA, with CEO Andrew Wilson confirming that both games "underperformed our net bookings expectations", which is essentially a fancy way of saying they undersold.</p>

<p>As a result of both games' failures, EA says it's revising its outlook for the year, predicting a "mid-single-digit decline" and pinning most of the blame for that decline on&nbsp;<em>EA Sports FC 25</em>'s underperformance.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ea-sports-fc-25-dragon-age-the-veilguard-underperformed-5v5-rush.jpg?itok=eEUGKwf1 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ea-sports-fc-25-dragon-age-the-veilguard-underperformed-5v5-rush.jpg?itok=qrgXnlc9 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>EA says two of its flagship games underperformed in the last quarter.</figcaption></figure><p>EA doesn't specify how far&nbsp;<em>EA Sports FC 25&nbsp;</em>fell below its expectations, but the company does say that the game put an end to "two consecutive fiscal years of double-digit net bookings growth" for football (sorry, Americans) games.</p>

<p>Apparently, the&nbsp;<em>EA Sports FC&nbsp;</em>franchise "experienced a slowdown" as early momentum gathered at the start of the quarter "did not sustain through to the end". As a reminder, the quarter runs from September through December, and&nbsp;<em>EA Sports FC 25&nbsp;</em>launched on September 27th.</p>

<p>Separately, EA says that&nbsp;<em>Dragon Age: The Veilguard&nbsp;</em>"engaged approximately 1.5 million players" during the period, which presumably means that's how many copies it sold. EA was expecting the game to sell somewhere in the region of three million copies in the same time period.</p>

<p>Wilson says he and his company "remain confident in our long-term strategy" and that EA expects to return to growth in the next financial year. CFO Stuart Canfield agrees, pointing to EA launching "more of [its] iconic franchises" next year.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dragon-age-the-veilguard-ea-sports-fc-25-sales-disappointing-combat.jpg?itok=9s7C-NLz 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dragon-age-the-veilguard-ea-sports-fc-25-sales-disappointing-combat.jpg?itok=wqIMXF1k 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Dragon Age: The Veilguard&nbsp;</em>didn't do the kind of numbers EA was hoping for.</figcaption></figure><p>Of course, it's unlikely that the underperformance of these games will reflect poorly on what will <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ea-ceo-25-million-income-layoffs" rel="nofollow">inevitably be another massive bonus</a> for Wilson this year.</p>

<p>Instead, I wouldn't be surprised if devs across BioWare and EA's&nbsp;<em>Sports FC&nbsp;</em>teams were laid off in the coming months.&nbsp;<em>Veilguard&nbsp;</em>director Corinne Busche <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/veilguard-director-corinne-busche-leaving-bioware" rel="nofollow">left BioWare last week</a>, although it's unclear whether or not that decision was related to the game's disappointing sales.</p>

<p>As for the reasons both games underperformed, it's hard to say. Wilson and EA don't speculate, but&nbsp;<em>EA Sports FC 25&nbsp;</em>has attracted its fair share of <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/ea-sports-fc-25/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">player vitriol</a> in <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2669320/EA_SPORTS_FC_25/#app_reviews_hash" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">user reviews</a> online (although very few&nbsp;<em>EA Sports FC&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>FIFA&nbsp;</em>games in the last few years haven't).</p>

<p>As for&nbsp;<em>Dragon Age: The Veilguard</em>, criticism has been aimed at the game's writing and storytelling, as well as other elements, although for what it's worth, our own reviewer Erren <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/dragon-age-veilguard-review-homecoming" rel="nofollow">looked more kindly on the game</a> than some did.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>