<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 20:03:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exciting Commanders From Avatar: The Last Airbender To Build Around]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/exciting-commanders-from-avatar-last-airbender-to-build-around</link>
            <guid>1369600</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>It’s another set release, and with over 100 different new commander options we debated what to do with a set that had more Commander options than there are episodes of the show. In the end, we decided on not repeating the odyssey of ranking over 100 commanders like we did with <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/ranking-all-of-magic-gathering-final-fantasy-legendary-creatures-part-1" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title=" Ranking ALL of Magic: The Gathering Final Fantasy Legendary Creatures Part 1"><em>Final Fantasy Magic The Gathering </em>Parts 1</a> <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/ranking-all-of-magic-gathering-final-fantasy-legendary-creatures-part-2" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/ranking-all-of-magic-gathering-final-fantasy-legendary-creatures-part-2">and 2</a> because a lot of the individual uncommons aren’t really that interesting.</p>

<p>Instead, we’ll be doing a bit of a medley: looking at a handful of the commanders in <em>Avatar: The Last Airbender </em>for <em>Magic: The Gathering&nbsp;</em>(from both the main set and Jumpstart), discussing lore of Avatar with the representation of them (like we once did with <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/best-lore-deep-cuts-of-doctor-who-commander-universes-beyond" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title=" Doctor Who Commander: Deep Lore Only True Whovians Would Notice"><em>Doctor Who MTG</em></a>), and ranking some of the characters who got significant representation.</p>

<h2><a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tla/207/avatar-aang-aang-master-of-elements" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Avatar Aang">Avatar Aang</a></h2>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/avatar-aang.jpg?itok=Pym2Zejr 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/avatar-aang.jpg?itok=RDE7JIkk 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Kicking it off is Aang depicted at the end of the series, where he is fully realizing his powers in a duel with Ozai. This representation of Aang is a powerful 5 color value engine on the front face with him providing solid size as a 4/4 flier, who draws whenever you do bending – such as when you firebend by attacking with Aang! He’s the perfect leader for an ‘all-Avatar’ Commander deck with the 5 color identity, and being generally powerful caring about prominent set mechanics.</p>

<p>He gets stronger when you can do all of them, and flip him over for a large cost reduction mechanic that can give you a bevy of resources while returning your card draw engine, as well as being a beating. Unlike most colored cost reducers, Aang, Master of Elements also reduces the cost of generic mana, which means is incredibly strong with cards that have buyback, like doing infinite damage with <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tmp/201/searing-touch" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Searing Touch">Searing Touch</a>. You can also trigger his avatar mode in emergency form without having mastered bending with <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/isd/195/moonmist" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Moonmist">Moonmist</a>&nbsp;to get to that sweet cost reduction even quicker.</p>

<h3>Ranking All Aang Commander Options&nbsp;</h3>

<p>There are 8 unique legendary Aang cards in the Avatar sets and here they are ranked:<br>
8) <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tle/146/aang-a-lot-to-learn" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Aang, A Lot to Learn">Aang, a Lot to Learn</a><br>
7) <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tla/4/aang-the-last-airbender" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Aang, the Last Airbender">Aang, the Last Airbender</a><br>
6) <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tle/210/aang-air-nomad" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Aang, Air Nomad">Aang, Air Nomad</a><br>
5) <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tla/204/aang-swift-savior-aang-and-la-oceans-fury" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Aang, Swift Savior /// Aang and La, Ocean's Fury">Aang, Swift Savior</a><br>
4) <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tle/74/aang-airbending-master" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Aang, Airbending Master">Aang, Airbending Master</a><br>
3) <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tla/203/aang-at-the-crossroads-aang-destined-savior" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Aang, at the Crossroads //  Aang, Destined Savior ">Aang, at the Crossroads</a><br>
2) <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tle/69/aang-and-katara" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Aang and Katara">Aang and Katara</a><br>
1) <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tla/207/avatar-aang-aang-master-of-elements" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Avatar Aang /// Aang, Master of Elements">Avatar Aang</a></p>

<p>Any of the top 5 are good or better Commander options, with 2 and 4 providing Ally centric gameplay, while Aang, at the Crossroads shows Aang at the end of Book 2/Season 2 in a wonderfully flavorful card that manages to capture the fight going on, and how Aang was unable to enter the Avatar state until someone he cared for was hurt, and how even then a <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/8ed/200/lightning-blast" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Lightning Blast">Lightning Blast</a> could take him down (if it hits the right rock...).</p>

<h2><a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tle/130/avatar-kyoshi-earthbender" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Avatar Kyoshi, Earthbender">Avatar Kyoshi, Earthbender</a></h2>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/avatar-kiyoshi-earthbender.jpg?itok=svxxC6bT 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/avatar-kiyoshi-earthbender.jpg?itok=Cbft5ssR 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Kyoshi is one of the past avatars represented by a saga in the main set (<a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tla/186/the-legend-of-kyoshi-avatar-kyoshi" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="The Legend of Kyoshi /// The Legend of Kyoshi">The Legend of Kyoshi</a>, which transforms into Avatar Kyoshi), and gets a full card in the Jumpstart product. Kyoshi is famed in the world of Avatar for her conviction and seeking justice she created a peaceful world, in contrast to Aang’s struggles and ties to the other people he loves and considers friends. Famously, she killed Chin, the Conqueror with a powerful feat of earthbending when she split the peninsula of her home off from the main land of the Earth Kingdom, and the cliff edge he stood on collapsed under him.</p>

<p>In Magic, we see Kyoshi shown at this height of her power, and focused on her use of earthbending. 8 Mana is a lot, but green is able to ramp like no one, and she wants to be in a deck with a lot of lands that she can animate with her earthbending each turn. She is one of the only repeatable earthbenders in the set, and each turn she can earthbend 8, turning a land into an 8/8. Her saga is also a perfect inclusion in the deck for double the Kiyoshi representation</p>

<h3><a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tle/112/avatar-roku-firebender" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Avatar Roku, Firebender">Avatar Roku, Firebender</a></h3>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/avatar-roku-firebender_0.jpg?itok=hrGlBy6s 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/avatar-roku-firebender_0.jpg?itok=TOGwzo2c 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>After Kyoshi’s status as the Avatar for 230 years, the next Avatar was Roku from the Fire Nation. Born on the same day as <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tla/117/the-rise-of-sozin-fire-lord-sozin" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="The Rise of Sozin ///  Fire Lord Sozin ">Fire Lord Sozin</a>, the two would be friends with Roku tempering his friend’s tendency to extremism, until he leaves for training as the Avatar. Without Roku, Sozin would continue his descent, even when his friend returned. Those old ties would make Roku reluctant to confront his old friend, letting the firelord prepare for his strike in secret, with only occasional confrontations between the two old friends. His <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tla/145/the-legend-of-roku-avatar-roku?back" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="The Legend of Roku ///  Avatar Roku ">saga card</a>, which works well with Avatar Roku, Firebender, depicts him giving the advise to Aang to be more decisive than he was, as well as showing how he was close to dragons who Fire Lords would have largely killed off.</p>

<p>Roku’s card shows his part in a world that was growing closer together, and how he was less confrontational than Kyoshi. Getting 6 mana whenever anyone attacks for that combat is obviously useful, and Roku himself provides the ability to tilt combat and play politics with his +3/+0 to target creature. Use it to punish aggressors by buffing blockers, or to help take on a stronger foe with the attacker, or to fund your <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tle/64/fire-nation-turret" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Fire Nation Turret">Fire Nation Turret</a>.</p>

<h3><a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tla/211/bumi-unleashed" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Bumi, Unleashed">Bumi, Unleashed</a></h3>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/bumi-unleashed.jpg?itok=RsGjgwBV 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/bumi-unleashed.jpg?itok=Sv-PW5Nn 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The King of Omashu got 3 cards in the Avatar set, showing him at different times during the series. This old man was in fact a friend of Aang’s before the Avatar hid away in an iceberg, and in his first appearance is a trickster mentor to Aang and friends as shown in <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tla/169/bumi-king-of-three-trials" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Bumi, King of Three Trials">Bumi of Three Trials</a>, while <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tle/248/bumi-eclectic-earthbender" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Bumi, Eclectic Earthbender">Bumi, Eclectic Earthbender</a>&nbsp;shows him at the end of that when they chose to duel the old man instead of his obviously muscular <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tla/179/flopsie-bumis-buddy" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Flopsie, Bumi's Buddy">Ape-Goat pet Flopsie</a>. An eccentric and openminded thinker, Bumi is also a brilliant tactician and strategist, who after the capture of Omashu waited his time to take action against the fire nation.</p>

<p>Bumi, Unleashed shows him breaking out and leading an assault to retake his city at the end of the series, around the same time that Aang is fighting Ozai as depicted in Avatar Aang. He gives you 9 power for 5 mana over two creatures, and will provide double combat opportunities for all your earthbended and otherwise animated land. There’s a lot of competition in <em>Avatar </em>for land attack leaders, but Bumi is one of the best, and just wants you to invite&nbsp;<a href="https://scryfall.com/card/dsc/170/ashaya-soul-of-the-wild" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Ashaya, Soul of the Wild">Ashaya, Soul of the Wild</a>&nbsp;to the party as well.</p>

<h3><a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tla/220/fire-lord-azula" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Fire Lord Azula">Fire Lord Azula</a></h3>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/fire-lord-azula_0.jpg?itok=E9GYf-x4 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/fire-lord-azula_0.jpg?itok=Jkk1NVbW 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>One of the most prominent villains of <em>Avatar: The Last Airbender</em>, Azula is the younger sister of Zuko. She begins appearing in the second season, and is perhaps at the height of her power at the end of that season when she takes over Ba Sing Se. While the other young characters in Avatar grow, Azula fails to and it is a bit sad that this card depicting her at the end of the third season doesn’t really capture her fall into paranoia and general mental break, although she remains a formidable bending prodigy, which it does aptly capture as she is going to duel her brother.</p>

<p>Leaving aside it being one of the weaker flavor alignments, Fire Lord Azula is a powerhouse. A 4/4 for 4 in Grixis color identity, she will copy any spells you cast while she’s attacking, and fuel those spells with firebending 2. This can work well for a lot of strategies like storm combo, spell slinger, or even something along the lines of voltron making use of pump spells. Note that she copies any type of spell, including creatures like <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/c21/165/dualcaster-mage" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Dualcaster Mage">Dualcaster Mage</a>&nbsp;if you want to make all the copies.</p>

<h3>Ranking All Azula Commander Options</h3>

<p>There are 4 unique Azula cards across the Avatar product line, and I would rank them:</p>

<p>4) <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tla/85/azula-on-the-hunt" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Azula, On the Hunt">Azula, On the Hunt</a><br>
3) <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/Azula,%20Ruthless%20Firebender" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="https://scryfall.com/card/tle/101/azula-ruthless-firebender">Azula, Ruthless Firebender</a><br>
2) <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tla/208/azula-cunning-usurper" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Azula, Cunning Usurper">Azula, Cunning Usurper</a><br>
1) <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tla/220/fire-lord-azula" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Fire Lord Azula">Fire Lord Azula</a></p>

<p>(Side note: Firebending does not add red to the color identity of these cards. It is part of the reminder text, thus like <a href="https://scryfall.com/search?q=o%3Aextort&amp;unique=cards&amp;as=grid&amp;order=name" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Extort">extort</a>&nbsp;its not counted as part of the card's rule text setting its color identity in Commander.)</p>

<p>Azula, Cunning Usurper shows Azula at the height of her power at the end of Season 2, as mentioned above when emerges victorious after a fight with Aang and friends. This version of the card though has less color identity, and really wants you to be playing a blink deck to reset the cards she has exiled. As a bonus, there is a fifth Azula on the bonus sheet, which is a new version of <em>Portal Three Kingdom</em> card <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tle/27/diaochan-artful-beauty" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Azula, Flame of Ember Island">Diaochan, Artful Beauty</a>.</p>

<h3><a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tla/221/fire-lord-zuko" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Fire Lord Zuko">Fire Lord Zuko</a></h3>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/fire-lord-zuko.jpg?itok=LwYQXPpZ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/fire-lord-zuko.jpg?itok=lzBlZx2l 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Of all characters in Avatar, none has a greater character arc than Zuko. Beginning as an exile seeking to return home by accomplishing an impossible task (find the Avatar who had been missing for a century), he eventually evolves into the character we see depicted in Fire Lord Zuko. At the very end of the series, this shows Zuko as the new leader of the Fire Nation having defeated his sister and setting the nation on a path that ends the war, and lead to a more prosperous future.</p>

<p>In Mardu colors, Fire Lord Zuko is a payoff for exile casting or blinking of permanents. Take advantage of impulse draw (like Prosper, Tome Bound), and blink spells to grow your creatures and as you do Zuko gets bigger and firebends even more mana.&nbsp;</p>

<h3>Ranking All Zuko Commander Options&nbsp;</h3>

<p>There are 8 unique legendary Zuko cards in the Avatar sets (in addition to a bonus sheet printing of <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tle/52/rhys-the-redeemed" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Zuko, Redeemed">Zuko, Redeemed, an overlay of Rhys, the Redeemed</a>)&nbsp;and here they are ranked:</p>

<p>8) <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tle/150/zuko-seeking-honor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Zuko, Seeking Honor">Zuko, Seeking Honor</a><br>
7) <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tla/163/zuko-exiled-prince" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Zuko, Exiled Prince">Zuko, Exiled Prince</a><br>
6) <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tle/246/zuko-avatar-hunter" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Zuko, Avatar Hunter">Zuko, Avatar Hunter</a><br>
5)&nbsp;<a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tla/253/zuko-conflicted" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Zuko, Conflicted">Zuko, Conflicted</a><br>
4) <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tle/90/the-blue-spirit" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="The Blue Spirit">The Blue Spirit</a><br>
3) <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tle/127/zuko-firebending-master" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Zuko, Firebending Master">Zuko, Firebending Master</a><br>
2) <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tle/68/mai-and-zuko" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Mai and Zuko">Mai and Zuko</a><br>
1) <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tla/221/fire-lord-zuko" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Fire Lord Zuko">Fire Lord Zuko</a></p>

<p>For those who don’t know the show, the inclusion of the Blue Spirit here may be slightly confusing. In Season/Book 1, Aang is captured by Admiral Zhao, and Zuko, who needs to bring home himself to restore his honor and place in the family, realizes that Zhao will now get that credit. So, in the titular episode, Zuko dresses up as The Blue Spirit, and frees Aang from captivity, beginning the process of the two of them wondering if they could be friends, a trend which will eventually see culmination in Book 3: Fire. As for the card, flash appearing creatures is very much fitting the surprise appearance of The Blue Spirit, and the drawing represents the reinforcements.</p>

<hr><p><em>Avatar: The Last Airbender</em>&nbsp;is a set and Jumpstart set made with clear love of the source material. With a lot of great and flavorful design hits, there are also some excellent&nbsp;<em>Magic: The Gathering</em>&nbsp;shoutouts like <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tla/258/meteor-sword" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Meteor Sword">Meteor Sword</a>&nbsp;lining up with <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/fdn/256/meteor-golem" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Meteor Golem">Meteor Golem</a>.</p>


</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>A longtime lover of speculative fiction, in almost all its forms, Don joined TechRaptor in 2014 on a whim sending in an application as he was looking for… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/don-parsons">More about Don</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/exciting-commanders-from-avatar-last-airbender-to-build-around]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Cosmic Invasion Review - A Marvelous Time]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/marvel-cosmic-invasion-review-marvelous-time</link>
            <guid>1369543</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>It's the holiday season once again, and what better way to spend time with family and friends than with a brand new <a href="https://techraptor.net/genre/beat-em-up" rel="nofollow">beat 'em up</a>?&nbsp;<em>Marvel Cosmic Invasion</em>'s got you covered. From <a href="https://techraptor.net/companies/tribute-games" rel="nofollow">the team</a> that brought you the excellent&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/tmnt-shredders-revenge-review" rel="nofollow"><em>TMNT: Shredder's Revenge</em></a>,&nbsp;<em>Marvel</em>'<em>s Cosmic Invasion</em>&nbsp;is a blast from start to finish, and it doesn't hurt that it also has a bunch of iconic characters we know and love.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/marvel-cosmic-invasion-roster.jpg?itok=QdrccdK3 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/marvel-cosmic-invasion-roster.jpg?itok=Sd6w-fQ- 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Some characters you'll have to unlock by playing the campaign.</figcaption></figure><h2>Avengers, X-Men, and Others Too!</h2>

<p><em>Marvel Cosmic Invasion</em>'s a beat 'em up, so you already sort of know what you're getting into. It's not the most complex genre ever, that's for sure, but it's usually one that provides a great deal of fun, especially with friends. As with any beat 'em up, my favorite part is the roster, and this game has it in spades.</p>

<p>What helps&nbsp;<em>Marvel Cosmic Invasion</em>&nbsp;stand apart from the pack is its cast of characters -- and it's a large one, for sure. 15 total characters to choose from makes the variety almost overwhelming, but it's exciting to see a bunch of iconic characters (and some more niche ones) make an appearance.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/marvel-cosmic-invasion-phyla-vell.jpg?itok=9ahtHidd 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/marvel-cosmic-invasion-phyla-vell.jpg?itok=zmed1MLw 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Phyla-Vell is cool as hell though!</figcaption></figure><p>You have fan favorites like Spider-Man, Iron Man, and Captain America, of course, but other not-so-obvious picks like She-Hulk (instead of Hulk), Cosmic Ghost Rider (instead of regular Ghost Rider, I guess?), and even Nova.</p>

<p>Admittedly, I'm not the biggest Marvel-head, but I enjoy the character designs and their powers, so forgive me for not knowing who the hell, uhhhh, Beta Ray Bill is? And Phyla-Vell? These fringe choices, at least from a casual Marvel fan's perspective, are intriguing and make the roster all the more intriguing.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/marvel-cosmic-invasion-combat.jpg?itok=h7u77tPi 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/marvel-cosmic-invasion-combat.jpg?itok=FIOhwJKm 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Fighting alien worms is just another day for the Avengers.</figcaption></figure><h2>The Many Moves of&nbsp;<em>Marvel Cosmic Invasion</em>'s Diverse Roster</h2>

<p>When you're ready to start the campaign or run through the classic-styled Arcade mode, you choose not one but&nbsp;<em>two</em>&nbsp;characters, which is another area where&nbsp;<em>Marvel Cosmic Invasion&nbsp;</em>stands out. In combat, you're able to switch between two characters tag-team style. You can even call the benched character in for assists during combat.</p>

<p>Developer Tribute Games does a fine job at keeping characters distinct from one another in not just looks but in terms of gameplay, and move-sets are&nbsp;<em>mostly</em>&nbsp;unique, though some characters share similarities with each other.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/marvel-cosmic-invasion-flight.jpg?itok=i_V3nKjF 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/marvel-cosmic-invasion-flight.jpg?itok=uGywcV5n 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Oh yeah, CRT filter!</figcaption></figure><p>For example, some characters have the ability to fly and float around the stage -- I'd say roughly half the roster -- while the rest are grounded. Some characters can dodge, while others block. Blocking, by the way, seems way more useful than dodges since blocking at the right time can parry, so I wish dodges felt equally useful.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Even still, when you consider the combination of teams with a roster of 15 different heroes, each run has the potential to be quite different since there are 105 combinations in total. Throw in some friends with their own choice of two characters, and the variety here is quite impressive.</p>

<p>Let's dive into some characters and how they play specifically, because that's the bread and butter of<em>&nbsp;</em>beat 'em ups. I often chose Captain America because, weirdly enough, he felt the closest to your traditional brawler-type character from most beat 'em ups.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/marvel-cosmic-invasion-captain-america.jpg?itok=NsgaxJ9D 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/marvel-cosmic-invasion-captain-america.jpg?itok=aA9LCkCo 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Captain America is looking at him like "You call that a workout?"</figcaption></figure><p>Each character has a special ability, so Cap can throw his shield across the screen to hit enemies. His combos are really straightforward and punchy, and his rising attack opens up the ability for some good air combos.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Then there's Wolverine, and he's an absolute monster. Tribute captured the feel of Wolverine to a tee with his fast-moving, vicious attacks and the ability to latch onto enemies and plunge his claws into them.</p>

<p>Some characters I didn't enjoy purely because they didn't fit my playstyle, but I still had fun with the entire cast. She-Hulk was a total surprise, since I expected a big, punchy character like her male counterpart. She-Hulk is actually a bona fide grappler, with short-ranged wrestling moves and a few grabs as her special moves that throw enemies around the stage.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/marvel-cosmic-invasion-worm-race.jpg?itok=KzuMnT23 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/marvel-cosmic-invasion-worm-race.jpg?itok=i7qp1iHX 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Slug racing.</figcaption></figure><p>Interestingly, each character in&nbsp;<em>Marvel Cosmic Invasion</em>&nbsp;has a passive you gain as you level them up (like&nbsp;<em>Shredder</em>'<em>s Revenge</em>). These usually relate to a character thematically, so Wolverine uses his mutant healing powers to slowly regain health.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, a character like Rocket Raccoon has a grenade ability that changes depending on RNG. He also has a very powerful nuke grenade. With his passive, defeating enemies in a combo increases the chances of the nuke grenade coming up, so it's a passive that rewards skill and keeping your combos up.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/marvel-cosmic-invasion-she-hulk-and-rocket.jpg?itok=CaccH1Dg 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/marvel-cosmic-invasion-she-hulk-and-rocket.jpg?itok=ZOL196VW 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>An unlikely duo.</figcaption></figure><h2>Tag Team Time</h2>

<p>At this point, I feel like I've only scraped the surface. Characters also have a charge attack, used by holding down the standard attack button. These come in the form of additional projectiles, parries, gap closers, and more. For example, Spider-Man pulls in enemies from afar with his web by charging, closing the gap without actually having to run across the screen.</p>

<p>Each character has a dash attack, and one interesting thing my co-op partner found with these is that they can be animation-cancelled. Beta Ray Bill can fly forward hammer-first, and this can be spammed to cause absolute chaos.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Of course, each character also has a special that taps into a Focus gauge accrued while fighting. These are what you'd expect -- powerful, screen-clearing attacks that do big damage. Some feel better than others, though. Iron Man's special shoots across the screen and does big damage, while Rocket's, though powerful, requires you to be a bit closer to enemies.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/marvel-cosmic-invasion-tag-team.jpg?itok=NflOW-rG 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/marvel-cosmic-invasion-tag-team.jpg?itok=6jS9Bcav 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Tagging in Nova for some support!</figcaption></figure><p>This is all for individual characters, but consider that you have to choose two heroes from the roster. As I said, there's a bit of a tag-team element in&nbsp;<em>Marvel Cosmic Invasion</em>, so you can switch between characters on the fly. Each has their own Focus bar, so you can use two specials simultaneously if you want.</p>

<p>Similarly, a character's health is their own, so even if one hero dies, you can use the other. The main advantage of this system is calling in your second hero to assist in combos. For example, you can have your benched hero use their special while you're mid-combo with the other.</p>

<p>The assist system is more than just pressing a button, as there are a few options in addition to the combo assist. You can launch an enemy into the air and swap to your other character -- this is called a Launcher Cosmic Swap. The assist system adds another layer to the gameplay that few other beat 'ups have, so it's great to see this here.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/marvel-cosmic-invasion-dinosuars.jpg?itok=Y_F6MjDV 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/marvel-cosmic-invasion-dinosuars.jpg?itok=f3749AL4 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Isn't this pterodactyl the dude that doesn't want to cure cancer, he just wants to turn people into dinosaurs?</figcaption></figure><h2>A Quest Across the Cosmos</h2>

<p>For now, let's set characters and their specifics aside. There's a whole campaign here, and each level offers up a different theme within the Marvel universe. New York, with references to Spider-Man and the Daily Bugle, is the first level we see. As things go on, levels take us to some pretty wild locales.</p>

<p>Wakanda, sure, that's in Africa, but nothing we haven't seen before. We're going to different realms like Valhalla and fighting across the stars. The story was a bit hard to follow as a casual fan, and having dialogue in the middle of gameplay doesn't help. Even still, it was cool to see what the next stage would be.</p>

<p>The sprite work for these stages is almost distractingly beautiful; seriously, Tribute's pixel artists are an impressive bunch. Still, I wish levels had more gimmicks or some hook to make them more exciting beyond looking pretty. Most gimmicks are just annoying hazards, lava geysers, or projectiles from afar.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/marvel-cosmic-invasion-avenger-ship-spiderman-and-venom.jpg?itok=O8x40ihL 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/marvel-cosmic-invasion-avenger-ship-spiderman-and-venom.jpg?itok=4BwCR6OT 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Venom and Spidey fighting side-by-side is a good time.</figcaption></figure><p>The stage featuring Valhalla is actually a super cool one I won't spoil, but beyond that, it didn't feel like stages had enough of a hook for them to stand out. Nonetheless, running through the campaign with a few friends is a blast.</p>

<p>Enemy variety is also adequate, and I don't have much to say about this other than that there's enough to make encounters feel varied. Likewise, bosses are fine. Some of them are way more memorable than others, and one boss in particular felt like a letdown considering they are one of the most feared villains in the entire Marvel universe.</p>

<p>Surprisingly, the last boss is one of the weakest in terms of design -- probably the least memorable, too. They're bulky and have a lot of health, but I expected them to have more abilities or&nbsp;<em>something</em>&nbsp;since they were, you know, the very last fight.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/marvel-cosmic-invasion-matrix.jpg?itok=OLviMNu0 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/marvel-cosmic-invasion-matrix.jpg?itok=7_xIM7UH 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Unlocking stuff on the matrix kind of reminds me of <em>Smash Bros Brawl'</em>s unlock grid.&nbsp;</figcaption></figure><h2><em>Marvel Cosmic Invasion</em> Review | Final Thoughts</h2>

<p>Gripes aside, there are plenty of ways to replay&nbsp;<em>Marvel Cosmic Invasion.&nbsp;</em>I'm waiting for a good time to have friends together so we can play Arcade mode, which has a bunch of modifiers you can use to make things more difficult. As an example, you can play solo but fight the same amount of enemies four players would, double enemies' health, and much more.</p>

<p>There are also a handful of challenges to complete in the campaign, usually involving specific characters. These are usually quite simple, but it's another thing for completionists to tackle. Completing these allows you to unlock more nodes on the "Cosmic Matrix," which features new skins, lore entries, arcade mode modifiers, and more.&nbsp;</p>

<p>All-in-all,&nbsp;<em>Marvel Cosmic Invasion&nbsp;</em>is an exciting and enjoyable time. It throws in a few twists with the tag-team system and its large roster, and it looks amazing as well. It offers all that you'd want in a beat 'em up, and even if it isn't perfect, bring a few friends along for the ride, turn your brain off, and fight like heroes.&nbsp;</p>

<hr><p><em><strong>Marvel Cosmic Invasion</strong>&nbsp;was reviewed on PC using a code provided by the developer over the course of 10 hours of gameplay - all screenshots were taken during the process of review.</em></p>
</div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/marvel-cosmic-invasion-review-marvelous-time]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Eberron: Forge of the Artificer Review - Minor Tweaks Overall, But A Fun New Subclass]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/eberron-forge-of-artificer-review-minor-tweaks-overall-but-fun-new-subclass</link>
            <guid>1369540</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>With the release of <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="3579fb91-ffa9-4c99-a750-de9f92ba642f" href="https://techraptor.net/games/dungeons-dragons" rel="nofollow">Dungeons &amp; Dragons (2024) </a>last year, including the <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="ed2ad5c2-7b7b-4a5a-84ff-eb15f1121885" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/dungeons-dragons-5e-2024-player-handbook-review-mixed-messaging-around-strong" rel="nofollow">PHB </a>and what would be the new base character options, the one class omitted was that of the Artificer. A class that harnesses a mixture of technology and magic to create new wonders. With the release of <em>Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</em> now only this class is now only back with a 2024 coat of paint, but new spells, species, and Eberron-specific mechanics have been detailed.</p>

<h2>2024 D&amp;D Artificer</h2>

<p>The D&amp;D 2024 Artificer carries with it a few changes and is still of a comparable difficulty to run as it was in 2014.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/eberron-forge-of-the-artificer-artificer.jpg?itok=tV2G5-AH 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/eberron-forge-of-the-artificer-artificer.jpg?itok=ju6JTXML 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>As expected from the change between 2014's Artificer and 2024 Artificer, there are some differences, but for the most part, the change comes with a different rate of leveling up and with some naming differences. For example, the 2014 Artificer has Infuse Item, where the 2024 Artificer has Replicate Magic Item, but the effects of the ability are essentially the same, with some minor tweaks.</p>

<p>The Sub-Classes available to the 2024 D&amp;D Artificer are:</p>

<ul><li aria-level="1"><strong>Alchemist </strong>- Craft Magic Elixers and Potions</li>
	<li aria-level="1"><strong>Armorer </strong>- Craft Magic Armor to Enhance Your Abilities</li>
	<li aria-level="1"><strong>Artillerist </strong>- Wield Destructive Power from Afar</li>
	<li aria-level="1"><strong>Battlesmith </strong>- Command a Construct Guardian</li>
	<li aria-level="1">And the new class, <strong>Cartographer </strong>- Chart Advantageous Courses through Turmoil</li>
</ul><p>The Alchemist subclass has a focus on the creation of potions that can buff allies. On top of that, you can gain a bonus to healing spells, or spells that deal Acid, Fire, or Poison Damage. At higher levels, you also add Force Damage.</p>

<p>The Armorer lets you wear heavy armor and turn your normal armor into Arcane Armor of three different varieties: Dreadnought, Guardian, and Infiltrator, each with their own special abilities. At higher levels, the abilities that these suits of armor have also improved.</p>

<p>The Artillerist is all about attacking from afar with a powerful cannon. At higher levels, you can also increase the power of this cannon and cause it to detonate ,dealing even more damage.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/eberron-forge-of-the-artificer-artificer-subclasses.jpg?itok=lWuP-pfg 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/eberron-forge-of-the-artificer-artificer-subclasses.jpg?itok=i5S1K4P2 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The Battlesmith lets you create a Steel Defender, a companion of steel that will aid you in battle. Initially, you need to take a Bonus Action to command your Steel Defender to attack, but once you obtain Extra Attack at level 5, you can use your second attack to use the Steel Defender's Force-Empowered Rand action.</p>

<p>The new class, the Cartographer, focuses heavily on creating magical maps that you can share with your party. The recipients of these maps (1+ Intelligence Modifier) will get to add 1d4 to their initiative rolls, and they'll innately know the locations of the other map holders while in the same place.</p>

<p>Additionally, the Cartographer gets Faerie Fire that can be cast as many times os their Int modifier, and they can teleport short range anywhere or 30 feet to someone with a map.</p>

<p>It's a really fun and involved form of a support and protection class. At first, potentially only being able to cover and assist part of the party as the sub-classes' abilities grow it will be able to add protection to all of the party.</p>

<h2>New And Updates Species</h2>

<p>This sourcebook brings with it information for the Changeling, Kalashtar, and Shifter species.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/eberron-forge-of-the-artificer-khoravar-species.jpg?itok=rZcIv1aZ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/eberron-forge-of-the-artificer-khoravar-species.jpg?itok=9IU2TNfd 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>For the most part, there are minimal differences between the 2014 edition of these 'races' and the 2024 species. Interestingly for the Changeling, who got a revision in <em><a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="dc04fb34-c3df-4c25-a8d3-8a522fcb6796" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/mordenkainen-presents-monsters-of-multiverse-review" rel="nofollow">Mordenkainen Presents: Monsters of the Multiverse</a></em>, the main difference is that a Changeling now has Advantage on Charisma checks when shape-shifted.</p>

<p>The Kalashtar obtains an additional advantage to Charisma Saving Throws alongside the Wisdom saving throws it already had as part of Dual Mind. It's much the same for the Shifter and Warforged.</p>

<p>The new race added in <em>Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</em> is the Khoravar. This is a species descended from both humans and elves. It's an in-universe way of saying "children of Khorvaire", the city that the species descended from, as the people aren't a fan of Half-Elf.</p>

<p>Like most Elf-based species, you'll get Darkvision, Advantage to not be Charmed, a cantrip from the Cleric, Druid, or Wizard spell-list, a resistance to being Unconscious, and the ability to alter a proficiency with one skill or tool of choice.</p>

<p>There's a lot of versatility and ability to slightly tweak your build from day to day, but there's only so much use you can get out of a single rotating Cantrip or Skill.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/eberron-forge-of-the-artificer-eberron-backgrounds.jpg?itok=Xse8DT0s 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/eberron-forge-of-the-artificer-eberron-backgrounds.jpg?itok=hV4zHy8L 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2><em>Eberron -</em>&nbsp;World and Campaign Tools</h2>

<p>While the book directs readers back to the previous <em>Eberron </em>book for learning more about the setting, there is the Noir Detective theme of a Sharn Inquisitives campaign that is discussed in this book. This group, described as 'part private investigator, part police detective, and part spy' is a way to recreate hard-boiled detective stories in a D&amp;D setting.</p>

<p>While there isn't any pre-written campaign, the book does a good job of describing different ways that these detective stories can be approached, as well as an extremely broad approach to how you could create a story that is fitting for the adventure. There are guidelines for how to handle adventures at Lv 1-4, Lv 5-10, Lv 11-16, and Lv 17-20. Each is only a paragraph long, it gives the broad strokes that you can then fill in the many blanks for.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/eberron-forge-of-the-artificer-dragonmarked-house.jpg?itok=D53uln15 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/eberron-forge-of-the-artificer-dragonmarked-house.jpg?itok=5n0olmlu 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>This feels a lot like the different levels of adventure creation that the recent <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="9cb3f917-f831-4c81-8cb8-54e040b09040" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/dungeons-dragons-forgotten-realms-heroes-of-faerun-and-adventures-in-faerun-review" rel="nofollow"><em>Forgotten Realms</em></a> book has, with a mix of full adventures and single-page stories for the DM to use as a foundation to then grow from. It seems like a nice balance to allow there to be some level of 'adventure' in a book, without needing to create an entirely curated experience from start to finish. This approach is only helpful for DM who prefer to fill in those blanks, but that it's even present can help prompt the creative thinking.</p>

<p>If Noir Detective stories aren't your thing the book also has a similar section to prompt for stories about tense house conflict between the Dragonmarked with references to The Sopranos and Succession, and Morgrave Expeditions which leans into Indiana Jones and Lara Croft style adventures.</p>

<p>In addition to some added information about the world of Eberron this book also expands upon the Dragonmark feats and how they intertwine into the world.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>"The Mark of Healing, for example, has given the halflings of House Jorasco an edge in providing medical care; the house has exploited that edge to the point where it remains virtually the only provider of healing services.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>To maintain the story tied to these feat they're part of the Backgrounds available to the world of Eberron. You can pick to be an heir to the Cannith house, Ghallanda house, Orien house or more. This is a fantastic way to pair more gameplay elements to a background that is being chosen, as it also adds the opportunity for a character in a non-Eberron setting to be able to obtain a Dragonmark in a different way and minimal tweaking needs to be done.</p>

<h2>Bastion's And Airships</h2>

<p>As a world of Steampunk High-Fantasy it makes sense that it's the next place that we see an update to Bastions, a type of base for the players to build that was introduced in the <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="56eebec3-a321-4403-b71c-54e4edf91d0c" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/dungeons-dragons-5e-2024-dungeon-masters-guide-review-true-dms-best-friend" rel="nofollow">Dungeon Master's Guide</a>.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/eberron-forge-of-the-artificer-mobile-bastion.jpg?itok=SCcPTf-I 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/eberron-forge-of-the-artificer-mobile-bastion.jpg?itok=YaEMirzn 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Bastion's in <em>Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</em> introduce the idea of a Mobile Bastion where one of it's special facilities allows for propulsion. New special facilities have been added that are specific to Eberron like creating areas specifically related to the party's relationship with any of the major houses, and new forges.</p>

<p>Alongside Bastion's that can take you around the world there is also expanded resources about Airships, how they handle, and how to best tackle combat. There's a lot of information here about the different types of Airships, what kind of crew is needed to man them, and how to fix them up when things go wrong.</p>

<p>All of the information here is laid out fantastically to be able to quickly process it. Quick stats like AC, HP, Crew members, and speed are coupled with detailed maps showing the different floors, and a quick summary to let you know their best use.</p>

<p>When it comes up in your story you'll be happy to have all of this information at your fingerprints to create a unique adventure or combat opportunity for your parties.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/eberron-forge-of-the-artificer-airship-combat.jpg?itok=0QfHlCjC 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/eberron-forge-of-the-artificer-airship-combat.jpg?itok=5BiKMdgJ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2><em>Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</em> Review | Final Thoughts</h2>

<p>Normally, it's easy to say if a book is worth it or not based on the contents of the player options. With <em>Eberron: Forge of the Artificer,</em> you aren't just getting new sub-classes but this is the introduction to the Artificer class for D&amp;D 2024. It's definitely worth picking up if you know an Artificer is going to be rolled up for your table.</p>

<p>That being said, a lot of the changes are very minor tweaks, things that might not entirely seem worth it for the price of a new book.</p>

<p>The Cartographer is a very fun concept, leaning into passive support for all party members and a quick application of Faerie Fire. I can imagine a DM getting very tired of being rolled against with advantage when played correctly, even more frustrating when it teleports all over the place.</p>

<p>For the DM there's good info on running a detective, mob family, or dungeon delving campaign. There's also options for mobile bastions and airships but if you're not running a campaign explicitly in Eberron, then these are less important to have.</p>

<p>If you're running a campaign in Eberron, or your next character is an Artificer, then you should pick up this book, otherwise it likely isn't worth it.</p>

<hr><p><strong><em>Eberron: Forge of the Artificer was reviewed with a copy provided by the Publisher over the course of 10 hours.</em></strong></p>
</div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/eberron-forge-of-artificer-review-minor-tweaks-overall-but-fun-new-subclass]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>