<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 21:55:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Games Workshop Announces New Rules for The Golden Demon 2025 Mini Painting Tournament]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/games-workshop-announces-new-rules-for-golden-demon-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/games-workshop-announces-new-rules-for-the-golden-demon-2025-mini-painting-tournament.1073016/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/games-workshop-announces-new-rules-for-golden-demon-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Games Workshop has announced Golden Demon 2025. The official <em>Warhammer</em> miniature painting competition will return this year with changes to its various categories and awards.</p>

<h2>The Golden Demon 2025 Announcement</h2>

<p>According to an official <a href="https://www.warhammer-community.com/en-gb/articles/6vp4sdtr/golden-demon-2025-the-prestigious-painting-competition-returns-to-adepticon-with-a-new-category-and-new-awards/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Warhammer-Community</a> post, the first leg of Golden Demon 2025 will happen at this year's AdeptiCon, which will be held in the United States at the Baird Centre in Milwaukee, Wisconsin on March 26.</p>

<p>The post continues to describe changes to the competition's different categories. Duel will return as its own category, allowing entrants to showcase fierce battles between two opponents. Furthermore, both <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/warcry-briar-and-bone-review" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Warcry</em></a> and <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/warhammer-underworlds-grandfathers-gardeners-and-jaws-of-itzl-review" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Warhammer Underworlds</em></a> entries will be entered under the <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/games/warhammer-age-of-sigmar" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Warhammer Age of Sigmar</em></a> Unit umbrella category.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/golden-demon-2025-category-list.jpg?itok=FZTjEdZe 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/golden-demon-2025-category-list.jpg?itok=ImAmsy5X 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Otherwise, all other categories of Golden Demon 2025 are unchanged. <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/games/warhammer-40000" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Warhammer 40,000</em></a>, the <em>Middle-earth Strategy Battle Game</em>, <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/warhammer-old-world-core-boxes-announced" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Warhammer The Old World</em></a>, <em>Warhammer The Horus Heresy</em>, <em>Necromunda</em>, and <em>Blood Bowl</em> are all unchanged.</p>

<p>As for awards, Games Workshop adds some new achievements below the podium. In addition to the Gold, Silver, and Bronze awards, there are Finalist, Commended, and Notable awards. The latter three positions are for entries that have caught the judges' attention. It is a welcome consolation for entries that go that extra mile.</p>

<p>Games Workshop's changes to the Golden Demon continues their active support alongside listening to constructive fan feedback. This includes their update to Golden Demon 2024 entries <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/games-workshop-imposes-golden-demon-ai-ban-preventing-its-use-in-miniature-painting" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">banning AI-generated</a> materials in any submitted entry. This may have been caused by the use of an AI-generated backdrop by 12-time winner Neil Hollis.</p>

<p>Games Workshop will be providing more Golden Demon 2025 details in the lead-up to AdeptiCon. In the meantime, if you have an idea for an entry to submit, the sign-up form is the same as last year on the official <a href="https://citadelcolour.com/golden-demon-2025/" rel="nofollow">Golden Demon</a> website. Potential US winners, you have three months to start assembling and painting.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hell Let Loose Is Your Next Free Epic Games Store Game]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hell-let-loose-epic-games-store-free</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hell-let-loose-is-your-next-free-epic-games-store-game.1072830/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hell-let-loose-epic-games-store-free<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Epic has revealed the final free game being given away to PC gamers on the Epic Games Store during the 2024-25 holiday season, and it's the multiplayer-focused World War 2 first-person shooter&nbsp;<em>Hell Let Loose</em>.</p>

<p>Over the holiday period, Epic has given away a number of games on its Store, including&nbsp;<em>Control</em>,&nbsp;<em>Ghostrunner 2</em>, and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sifu-epic-games-store-free" rel="nofollow">martial arts action brawler&nbsp;<em>Sifu</em></a>, among others. Each of the games available over the last couple of weeks has been redeemable for a single day.</p>

<p><em>Hell Let Loose&nbsp;</em>marks the end of that period, however, as it's available until December 9th, which means Epic has gone back to its usual schedule of giving away one free game per week.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/hell-let-loose-epic-games-store-mortar.jpg?itok=R-A_eghK 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/hell-let-loose-epic-games-store-mortar.jpg?itok=G5XCE9Q6 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Hell Let Loose&nbsp;</em>is your final free Epic Games Store game for the holidays.</figcaption></figure><p>You can redeem your copy of&nbsp;<em>Hell Let Loose</em>, which would usually set you back a not-insignificant $50 on the Epic Store, until December 9th at 11am Eastern, at which point it'll be replaced by the 1800s-set oil-rush sim&nbsp;<em>Turmoil</em>.</p>

<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Hell Let Loose</em>, it's a hardcore World War 2-set first-person shooter that was originally developed by Australian outfit Black Matter. It was first released on Steam Early Access <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hell-let-loose-hits-steam-early-access-on-july-6" rel="nofollow">back in 2019</a> following a successful Kickstarter campaign two years prior.</p>

<p>In 2022, publisher Team17 <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/team17-expands-with-hell-let-loose-and-label-acquisitions" rel="nofollow">took over development</a>, with subsidiary Cover 6 Studios currently handling the bulk of ongoing work on the game in conjunction with British developer Expression Games.</p>

<p>Tragedy then struck&nbsp;<em>Hell Let Loose&nbsp;</em>in July that same year, when producer James Light <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hell-let-loose-producer-james-light-dies-aged-just-28" rel="nofollow">passed away</a> from "complications following cardiac surgery" aged just 28.</p>




<p>As for the game itself, it's a multiplayer-focused shooter that supports up to 100 players in each battle. Players can engage in on-foot battles or take to a number of different vehicles in order to wage war on their opponents.</p>

<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Hell Let Loose&nbsp;</em>right now for free <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/hell-let-loose-03f036" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">on the Epic Games Store</a>. It's also available on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/686810/Hell_Let_Loose/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Steam</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/hell-let-loose/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PS5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/hell-let-loose/9n44wk3wv2hj" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>