<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 01:39:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Achtung Cthulhu The Norway Projekt Brings Pulp Sci-Fi Action Northward]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/achtung-cthulhu-norway-projekt-brings-pulp-sci-fi-action-northward</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/achtung-cthulhu-the-norway-projekt-brings-pulp-sci-fi-action-northward.1327171/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Modiphius has announced a new campaign book for their WWII pulp action TTRPG. <em>Achtung Cthulhu The Norway Projekt</em> continues the war between the Allies and the Axis powers, with the latter delving into dark occult works, shifting the venue to the icy regions of Norway.</p>

<h2>The Achtung Cthulhu The Norway Projekt Pre-Order Announcement</h2>

<p><em>Achtung Cthulhu The Norway Projekt</em> is a 156-page hardcover campaign book. The campaign is divided into three parts and features nine linked missions across the Norwegian front of the game's alternate history of WWII. The campaign builds on Modiphius' 2d20 RPG system, which has powered other TTRPGs such as <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/fallout-royal-flush-ttrpg-adventure-set-in-new-vegas-is-now-available-for-pre-order" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Fallout</em></a>, <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/dishonored-role-playing-game-review" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Dishonored</em></a>, and <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/modiphius-announces-star-trek-adventures-second-edition-starter-sets-now-available" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Star Trek Adventures</em></a>.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/achtung-cthulhu-the-norway-projekt-book-promo.jpg?itok=TuW-GGLw 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/achtung-cthulhu-the-norway-projekt-book-promo.jpg?itok=BIByPs6e 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>As for that campaign, it is set in 1942. The Nazis are desperate to turn to the tide of the war and look to developing atomic weapons. To prevent this, the Allies launch Operation: Grouse, Freshman, and Gunnerside, where they race to prevent the Axis from acquiring the Norwegian heavy water plant at Vemork.</p>

<p>But, since this is <em>Achtung Cthulhu</em>, the threat of nuclear devastation isn't the only danger to contend with. Enter the little-known Norwegian cult the Flokk of the Allfather, whose arcane knowledge may provide a darker, and faster, source of atomic power than conventional science.</p>

<p>The mission is a race against the clock where the players must rescue resistance fighters, uncover a vast conspiracy threatening to rain atomic fire on Allied cities, and fighting tooth and nail against horrors beyond mortal ken such as the Daemon Sultan Azathoth.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>“We’re delighted to finally give fans a chance to get their hands on The Norway Projekt. If you’re looking to take your agents on an epic campaign through the coldest of fronts, with a chance to foil eldritch cults, battle Nazi super science and change the course of the Secret War, then this will be a perfect addition to your collection!’ - Achtung Cthulhu Line Editor John Houlihan</p>
</blockquote>

<p><em>Achtung Cthulhu The Norway Projekt</em> is available for pre-order now on Modiphius' store at an MSRP of $55. The book is expected to ship January 2026.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/achtung-cthulhu-norway-projekt-brings-pulp-sci-fi-action-northward]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>