<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 14:42:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Oblivion Remake Images Seemingly Leaked as Rumors Swirl]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/new-oblivion-remake-images-seemingly-leaked</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-oblivion-remake-images-seemingly-leaked-as-rumors-swirl.1164720/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/new-oblivion-remake-images-seemingly-leaked<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>More images of the much-mooted&nbsp;<em>Oblivion&nbsp;</em>remake, which is seemingly becoming the industry's worst-kept secret, have apparently leaked, and from none other than the purported developer's very own website this time.</p>

<p>Redditor <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/oblivion/comments/1jzppz9/oblivion_images_on_virtuos_website/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Taurnil</a>&nbsp;spotted the images in the backend of developer Virtuos' website. Although it hasn't been confirmed by Bethesda, it's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/oblivion-remake-reportedly-confirmed" rel="nofollow">been reported</a> that Virtuos is working on the <i>Oblivion&nbsp;</i>remake, and these images rather seem to back up that claim.</p>

<p>ResetEra user Mattmo831 also <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/images-of-oblivion-remake-from-virtuos-games-%E2%80%9Cleak%E2%80%9D.1164534/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">collected a number of images</a> from the&nbsp;Virtuos website, so although the images are no longer accessible via Virtuos' page, it's looking pretty unlikely that they're fake at this point. We won't be including them in this article, but they're easily accessible via the above links at time of writing.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/oblivion-remake-images-leaked-original-conversation.jpg?itok=zlfrXHOS 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/oblivion-remake-images-leaked-original-conversation.jpg?itok=A0qXEBKB 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Oblivion</em>'s upcoming remake now seems like a foregone conclusion.</figcaption></figure><p>The images depict a wide range of scenes from&nbsp;<em>Oblivion</em>, including one-to-one comparisons with the original, and surprise surprise, it looks like the new version will sport vastly improved visuals.</p>

<p>New key art has also seemingly been leaked, depicting an armored warrior standing in front of the game's logo, although there aren't any screenshots of the remake's conversation system yet, so we don't yet know if it's the same weird dead-eyed hoedown it was in the original.</p>

<p>Journalist Jeff Grubb <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remake-release-date-reportedly-narrowed-down/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">suggested recently</a> that the&nbsp;<em>Oblivion&nbsp;</em>remake will "shadowdrop" - that is, launch without any prior fanfare - sometime in April. The sudden appearance of these screenshots on Virtuos' website would seem to back up that claim.</p>

<p>It is, of course, worth bearing in mind that no announcement has officially been made by Bethesda or Virtuos, and so all of this is still technically speculation. Still, the evidence is mounting, so I'd be surprised if April passes with no word on the&nbsp;<em>Oblivion&nbsp;</em>remake.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/virtuos-metal-gear-solid-delta.jpg?itok=MDQy3q0u 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/virtuos-metal-gear-solid-delta.jpg?itok=i94dF2l7 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Virtuos has served as a co-development studio on games like&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>If Virtuos is indeed working on the <i>Oblivion&nbsp;</i>remake, past form would indicate it's a good choice for the project. Previous games worked on by Virtuos as a co-development studio include&nbsp;<em>Dead Island 2</em>,&nbsp;<em>Hogwarts Legacy</em>, and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/metal-gear-solid-delta-release-date-leak-playstation" rel="nofollow">the upcoming</a>&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater&nbsp;</em>(which, I suppose, would make the latter a Virtuos Mission).</p>

<p>We'll almost certainly hear something about the&nbsp;<em>Oblivion&nbsp;</em>remake in the coming weeks (assuming, of course, it doesn't get shadowdropped tomorrow). Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Palia Launches for PS5 and Xbox Series on May 13 Alongside New Expansion "Elderwood"]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/palia-launches-for-ps5-and-xbox-series-on-may-13-alongside-new-expansion-elderwood</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/palia-launches-for-ps5-and-xbox-series-on-may-13-alongside-new-expansion-elderwood.1164717/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/palia-launches-for-ps5-and-xbox-series-on-may-13-alongside-new-expansion-elderwood<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Singularity 6 is bringing its fantasy life sim adventure, <em>Palia</em>, to PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series on May 13. While the game has already been available for PC and Nintendo Switch for a time, this new batch of console players will be able to join in with full cross-platform support.</p>

<p>Originally released n 2023, <em>Palia</em> has thrived on its free-to-play multiplayer model that encourages people to explore, craft, and live the life sim they’ve always wanted. <em>Palia</em> has released over 24 content updates to date, including 800 housing items, seasonal events and minigames, trading and building mechanics, and immersive storylines.</p>

<p>Alongside the PS5 and Xbox Series launch, <em>Palia</em> will release its new round of content with the introduction of the Elderwood – a new Adventure Zone filled with a magical forest that is set to be the largest release since the original launch. Elderwood offers up new ways to explore, alongside familiar characters such as Nai’o and Subira with new quests.</p>

<p>In Elderwood, there’s new collectables, hostile huntable creatures such as the Ogapuu, and elusive ones like the Shmole. Players can also try their hand looking for various artifacts, which unlock a new equipment type called Relics, which can help buff up your party.</p>

<p><em>Palia</em> strives to be an experience the player can play at their own pace, with enough content for years to come.</p>




<p>Elderwood in particular sets off to prove as much with all of its addition. A brief demo included a further look at housing, and all the colorful collectables one can hold within. Of course, there’s fishing and farming to do too.</p>

<p>Once into the actual forest of the Elderwood, things start to get a little mysterious with plenty of purples and blues. There’s a lot of exploration to be had outside of the town, with plenty more materials to find for crafting and housing.</p>

<p>Palia’s resident NPCs are there too, and have plenty to say about what’s going on in the Edlerwood. Characters such as Nai’o are useful for learning more about the world, and taking on quests marked on the map.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/palia-01.jpg?itok=7zj2juD5 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/palia-01.jpg?itok=V5kKFJmQ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>There’s quite a lot to unpack with <em>Palia</em>’s latest, but again, the goal is to take things and play at a pace that feels comfortable.</p>

<p>All of this will be available on May 13 along with the return of the Refer a Friend program. Players can invite their friends to Palia to earn the Elderwood Fun Guy Plush in five different sizes.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Erren is a staff writer for TechRaptor whose writing experience stems from years of helming Nova Crystallis – a website dedicated to everything Square Enix… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/erren-van-duine">More about Erren</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft Releases Free Color Blindness Tool for Developers]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ubisoft-chroma-color-blindness</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-releases-free-color-blindness-tool-for-developers.1164639/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ubisoft-chroma-color-blindness<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Ubisoft has released a free color blindness simulation tool to help developers understand how to make their games accessible to those with three major types of color blindness.</p>

<p>The tool's name is Chroma, and it's available on <a href="https://github.com/ubisoft/Chroma" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">GitHub</a> as an open-source kit. It won't cost you anything to use it, either, so if you're a developer and you want to know how to make your game better for colorblind folks, Ubisoft's got you covered.</p>

<p>Per a <a href="https://news.ubisoft.com/en-gb/article/72j7U131efodyDK64WTJua" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">post</a> on Ubisoft's official website, Chroma's purpose is to "accurately replicate" the experience of colorblind gamers and help developers to "create accessible content to meet [those players'] needs".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ubisoft-chroma-color-blindness-tool-windows.jpg?itok=aumZzukO 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ubisoft-chroma-color-blindness-tool-windows.jpg?itok=xRgcz93m 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Ubisoft's Chroma color blindness tool is now free for all developers to use.</figcaption></figure><p>Ubisoft's accessibility director David Tisserand says Chroma has been a "highly efficient" tool for Ubisoft when developing its own games, and that he and his team believe "accessibility is a journey, not a race", which is why they're sharing Chroma with the wider industry.</p>

<p>Since Chroma is open-source, developers are welcome to "benefit from it, provide feedback, and contribute to its future development", according to Tisserand. That's a pretty nice touch.</p>

<p>You can use Chroma on either single or dual screens, and it's hotkey-compatible as well. What's more, you can customize its overlay to make it look the way that works best for you.</p>

<p>QC product manager Jawad Shakil says Chroma was created to "mak[e] color blindness accessibility a natural part of the creative and testing process", and that the Chroma team's work is "already making a difference in how we design games with accessibility in mind".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/the-last-of-us-2-accessibility.jpg?itok=NMhdk-ig 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/the-last-of-us-2-accessibility.jpg?itok=kya3ULOA 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Many games, like&nbsp;<em>The Last of Us Part 2</em>, now ship with color blindness options.</figcaption></figure><p>More and more games are including extensive accessibility options at launch. Games like&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/naughty-dog-showcases-expansive-last-of-us-part-1-accessibility-features" rel="nofollow"><em>The Last of Us Part 1</em></a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dragon-age-veilguard-accessibility-options" rel="nofollow">Dragon Age: The Veilguard</a></em>, among many others,&nbsp;are launching with options like color blindness modes and audio descriptions, and titles that don't launch with these concessions often receive them as updates.</p>

<p>Ubisoft's color blindness tool Chroma is available to download and use right now for free.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>