<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 13:54:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[N64 Classic Ridge Racer 64 Comes to Nintendo Switch Online]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ridge-racer-64-nintendo-switch-online</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/n64-classic-ridge-racer-64-comes-to-nintendo-switch-online.1096839/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ridge-racer-64-nintendo-switch-online<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Nintendo has announced another N64 classic for Nintendo Switch Online, and this one's perfect if you're a fan of retro racing games.</p>

<p>Today's new Switch Online addition is&nbsp;<em>Ridge Racer 64</em>, and just like <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-switch-online-banjo-tooie" rel="nofollow">other</a> N64 <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-switch-online-n64-halloween" rel="nofollow">games</a> on the service, you're going to need an Expansion Pack addon if you want to play it.</p>

<p>As a reminder, the basic Nintendo Switch Online subscription will get you access to the likes of <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-switch-online-january-2025" rel="nofollow">SNES</a> and NES games, as well as Game Boy classics, but you'll need to fork out a little extra if you want N64, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-switch-online-genesis-november-2024" rel="nofollow">Genesis</a>, and Game Boy Advance games (as well as DLC for a couple of Switch games).</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/nintendo-switch-online-ridge-racer-64-car.jpg?itok=ly6uTtsP 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/nintendo-switch-online-ridge-racer-64-car.jpg?itok=ZEyywH0G 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Ridge Racer 64&nbsp;</em>is yours to check out on Switch Online, assuming you have an Expansion Pack.</figcaption></figure><p>As for&nbsp;<em>Ridge Racer 64&nbsp;</em>itself, it was first released in 2000, and it's the series' first foray outside of PlayStation (not counting arcade versions, of course). Unusually, it's also one of the only times Nintendo itself has worked on an IP that isn't its own.</p>

<p>The game received a DS port in 2004, but obviously, it's the N64 version you'll be getting here, complete with its full track complement and range of unlockable extra cars.</p>

<p>You can also enjoy local multiplayer with up to three friends, as well as several different gameplay modes including Grand Prix, Quick Play, and special modes like Time Attack and Car Attack.</p>

<p>If you want to know what you're getting into when you play&nbsp;<em>Ridge Racer 64</em>, you can check out Nintendo's new trailer for the game on Switch Online right here.</p>




<p>Nintendo is currently gearing up for the impending launch of the Switch 2, having <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-switch-2-officially-announced" rel="nofollow">announced the console</a> earlier this month.</p>

<p>We don't know when it's releasing yet, but we do know that the Switch Online service will continue to be available on Switch 2, so it's likely that the current console's retro game lineup will also be accessible on the new machine.</p>

<p><em>Ridge Racer 64&nbsp;</em>is available right now for Nintendo Switch Online Expansion Pack holders.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>