<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:11:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deadpool VR Review - The Merc With The Headset]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/deadpool-vr-review-merc-with-headset</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/deadpool-vr-review-the-merc-with-the-headset.1355929/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I got a taste of <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="d21d65a5-4b5d-4746-8132-7a248cc992b2" href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/deadpool-vr-pushes-vr-automotion-while-creating-fun-and-frantic-experience" rel="nofollow"><em>Deadpool VR</em> earlier this year at Summer Game Fest</a>, and I was blown away. I'm no stranger to VR, but the kinds of rhythm games and small tech demos that I was used to when I first got my Vive ~10 years ago were a far cry from the improved movement, responsive controls, and entertaining plot as you shoot and slash your way through the Helicarrier as Deadpool. Having played it now for an additional 10 hours, does it still retain that charm?</p>

<p>In <em>Deadpool VR</em>, you take up the mantle of the Merc with a Mouth, this time voiced by Neil Patrick Harris. As Deadpool, you're initially hired to infiltrate a S.H.I.E.L.D. helicarrier whose operation has been taken over by Flag Smasher. Making your way through the corridors, you're taught how to be the best mercenary you can while building a witty rapport with the different characters that are talking to you over voice comms.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/deadpool-vr-review-flagsmasher.jpg?itok=Vl4UdWrI 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/deadpool-vr-review-flagsmasher.jpg?itok=glSOvE2x 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Be prepared to be a head on the ground a number of times</figcaption></figure><p>Near the conclusion of your battle with Flag Smasher, the true plot of the game is revealed as you're yanked through space and time and deposited into the lobby of Mojo TV. Here, you're hired (forced) to work for Mojo, building up ratings for his hyper-violent survival TV show by going out to recruit other contestants from across the Marvel multiverse. Characters include Lady Deathstroke, Omega Red, and Ultimo.</p>

<p>As you'd expect from anything Deadpool, the game is filled to the brim with crass jokes, witty one-liners, and fourth wall breaks. You'll get to hear Deadpool call himself Marvel Jesus, joke about a variety of inappropriate sex acts, and wish absurd violence on anyone who crosses his path. Honestly, there are not a lot of actors that I feel could get away with this level of crude verbal diarrhea, but Neil Patrick Harris absolutely nails the delivery of every line.</p>

<p>The only places that I really felt like the storyline could have been sped up or made a bit more snappy would be in the stand-still cutscenes. If a cutscene is playing on my TV with a traditional video game, I can just relax and watch. In VR, you're just awkwardly stuck there, standing still and waiting to get back to the action. A bit of walking and talking could have certainly tightened up aspects of the game.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/deadpool-vr-review-one-piece.jpg?itok=od892gYl 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/deadpool-vr-review-one-piece.jpg?itok=knnqdBXp 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>I'm always down for a One Piece joke, I just wish I could be doing something more than standing here...</figcaption></figure><p>The repeated combat dialogue is really the only place that Deadpool's chattering got a bit frustrating, but there's only so many times you can hear Deadpool make a decapitation quip before you begin to roll your eyes.</p>

<p>Overall, I was impressed with the story, it wasn't some grand epic, but it was a good way to pair Deadpool up with another interdimensional character like Mojo and give a good reason to drop Deadpool into a variety of unique settings like Ninja Temple or The Moon.</p>

<h2>Precise Shooting, But Flailing Sword Swings</h2>

<p>At its core, <em>Deadpool VR</em> is a hack-and-slash where you'll start in Mojo's hub world, pick a different stage to make your way through different themed rooms and corridors as you defeat a variety of nameless henchmen before taking on their boss to recruit (kidnap) them for Mojo TV.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/deadpool-vr-review-prologue-gameplay.jpg?itok=zYBNJ-8a 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/deadpool-vr-review-prologue-gameplay.jpg?itok=oMn4gfgr 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Your base loadout includes two pistols that are strapped to your digital thighs, swords strapped to your back that you can grab over your shoulder, and a grapple gun in the small of your back. For the moments you needed it, a grenade is also strapped to your left forearm.</p>

<p>I absolutely loved the way you accessed your inventory. As you're making your way through frantic waves of enemies or platforming challenges, each weapon having a unique point to draw from minimizes interaction issues and creates less of a gap between the player and Deadpool. There are no finicky menus to worry about or selecting from multitudes of weapons, just a quick reach or drop of a weapon to be ready to continue attacking.</p>

<p>The guns, and by extension other ranged weapons like Playing Cards or Bows, are a lot of fun to play with. The swords are a bit more frantic to use. With somewhat floaty movement, trying to stay in melee range with an enemy can be a bit difficult. You'll quickly find that the most effective way to use these swords is just by flailing your arms around while running in a circle.</p>

<blockquote>
<p><em>Deadpool VR</em> does a lot to make you feel cool while playing, but swordplay is not one of those times.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>You can temporarily get your hands on more powerful weapons by defeating the enemies that wield them in battle. These weapons are more powerful, like shotguns or SMGs, but they have limited ammunition.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/deadpool-vr-review-melee-combat.jpg?itok=KLuHY54b 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/deadpool-vr-review-melee-combat.jpg?itok=BR8WQlcs 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Waggling my hands like my life depends on it</figcaption></figure><p>This can prompt you to quickly move through them, trying to maximize killing enemies and continuously swapping out your weapons, but they can also be reloaded by throwing them and having them ricochet off enemies.</p>

<p>This interaction creates a unique opportunity to link together combos while mowing through enemies. You might be sprinting forward, shooting at an enemy, and finish them off by bouncing a shotgun off their face, before taking it back into your hand, starting on the next enemy.</p>

<p>There are some fantastic object interactions that you'll get to experience by experimenting with weapons. One of my favorites in Lady Deathstroke's levels is that after defeating a ninja, they'll leave two floating kunai daggers. You can pick these up and use them yourself, or if you have your sword handy, you can slash at them to send them flying towards nearby enemies.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/deadpool-vr-review-bouncing-weapons.jpg?itok=1gAu_EVK 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/deadpool-vr-review-bouncing-weapons.jpg?itok=UN2z9bNJ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Ricochet special weapons to reload them</figcaption></figure><p>There's a lot of help with magnetism that the game does to ensure a wild swing or thrown projectile hits it's target. You can tell the game is being nice to you, but you still feel like a badass while doing it, so I'll allow it.</p>

<p>The boss fights in <em>Deadpool VR</em> are, unfortunately, some of the weakest aspects. Each boss will sit back and take your gunfire or swordslashes while moving towards or away from you with a few very clearly telegraphed attacks.</p>

<p>There's an arcadey feel to fighting off the different waves of henchment enemies, trying to find the best line to completion or flashiest way to get the kills, but the boss fights are a bit more bullet sponger and basic.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/deadpool-vr-review-flag-smasher-qte.jpg?itok=HRAJP0Lb 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/deadpool-vr-review-flag-smasher-qte.jpg?itok=1PSA4RHD 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Press F to throw a katana into Flag Smasher</figcaption></figure><p>My favorite part of any of the boss fights was ironically the QTE moments, where a silhouette of a target or a sword position might show in your field of view. Here, the player gets to react in slow motion to more complicated combos. This reactive dance is one of the only times an enemy will really react to the different weapons you use.</p>

<h2>Upgrades And Replayability</h2>

<p>The weapons listed above aren't the only ones that you'll get access to as you progress through <em>Deadpool VR</em>. You aren't just trying to recruit new fighters to Mojo TV, but are also its star, as you'll gain viewers and earn money for killing competently.</p>

<p>More viewers mean more money, and more money means you can purchase a variety of upgrades.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/deadpool-vr-review-sword-upgrades_0.jpg?itok=_cZ9xUs8 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/deadpool-vr-review-sword-upgrades_0.jpg?itok=2xkEAXyH 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Doesn't change much gameplay wise, but it looks cooler</figcaption></figure><p>Gameplay upgrades include getting access to a variety of different weapons to augment your loadout. That might just mean that you get three grenades instead of one, or your guns are now a shiny new color. It can also mean you have different-bladed weapons or guns altogether.</p>

<p>On top of mechanical changes, there are also a variety of cosmetic options for Deadpool himself to pick from. Different themed outfits from Deadpools across the multiverse will unlock as you complete additional stages. After getting certain outfits, you can also return to different places in earlier stages that are themed to that character to open secret doors and get access to hidden content.</p>

<p>There is a lot of replayability that's built into this game, and a lot that I'm interested in checking out, but the length of the levels is also a bit of a detractor to this.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/deadpool-vr-review-collectibles.jpg?itok=eUtnL7HE 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/deadpool-vr-review-collectibles.jpg?itok=vlcqa_9H 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Deadpool comics can be found hidden around the world</figcaption></figure><p>Even when I was playing the game at SGF and tried to scan my hand on a Lady Deadpool doorway in the Helicarier, only to be told you can access that in the full game, I was interested to see what's behind the door, but when getting to a secret door in a level might be a 20-30 minute endeavor it makes it a bit harder to push for.</p>

<p>I feel that if the game had broken up the different missions into smaller chunks with checkpoints to quickly hop to, or just had more levels that were shorter, this kind of replayability would feel more like a detour, instead of an additional adventure like it currently feels.</p>

<h2>The Look And Feel Of A Comic Book World</h2>

<p>One thing that I was truly blown away with, especially after only really interacting with PC VR and Mobile Phone VR, was how great a VR game looked on a standalone system.</p>

<p>Another thing helping this is the comic book style of the world, filled with rich and saturated colors and heavy outlines. Many of the characters and locations felt like they were pulled straight from the pages of a comic book or from a Saturday Morning Cartoon.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/deadpool-vr-review-combat-score.jpg?itok=7feGGDcB 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/deadpool-vr-review-combat-score.jpg?itok=gj2ODJlZ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>New high score!</figcaption></figure><h2>Marvel's <em>Deadpool VR</em> Review | Final Thoughts</h2>

<p>Playing <em>Deadpool VR</em> at SGF I thoroughly enjoyed my time from the tight gameplay (maybe not so much the swordplay) to the witty and fast-paced dialogue. Having spent somewhere between 30-60 minutes on the game, I couldn't help but think as I was walking away, "Will this still be fun after 4-5 hours?"</p>

<p>I'm very happy to announce that it totally is.</p>

<p><em>Marvel's Deadpool VR</em> takes a pretty traditional level-based hack and slash and puts you in the middle of it. Leaning into some of the stranger aspects of the Marvel universe, like Mojo, this game delivers a Marvel experience filled with fast-paced combat and plenty of chuckles.</p>

<p>Melee combat is still something that needs to be worked on, but without a weight in your hand and resistance to swing against, I believe that's always going to be something near impossible to replicate.</p>

<p>If you have a Quest 3, this should be your next jaunt through Virtual Reality, whether it's on your own or something to share with friends and pass and play, trying for the most impressive kills.</p>

<hr><p><strong><em>Deadpool VR</em> </strong><em>was reviewed on Meta Quest 3 with a copy provided by the Developer over the course of 10 hours of gameplay - all screenshots were taken during the process of review.</em></p>
</div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/deadpool-vr-review-merc-with-headset]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>