<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 20:54:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alien RPG Evolved Edition Kickstarter Fully Funded in 15 Minutes]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/alien-rpg-evolved-edition-kickstarter-fully-funded-in-15-minutes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/alien-rpg-evolved-edition-kickstarter-fully-funded-in-15-minutes.1144557/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/alien-rpg-evolved-edition-kickstarter-fully-funded-in-15-minutes<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="page-content">
  
          
      
<article role="article">

  
    

  
  <div>
      
  
  
  <div>
      <div><p>Free League Publishing launched its Kickstarter campaign for <em>Alien RPG Evolved Edition</em> today. The campaign for the updated version of their officially licensed Alien TTRPG reached its initial funding goal within 15 minutes of it going live.</p>



<p>According to its Kickstarter page, <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1192053011/alien-rpg-second-edition-and-rapture-protocol/description" rel="nofollow"><em>Alien RPG Evolved Edition</em></a> contains an updated core rulebook, a new starter set, a cinematic adventure boxed set, and a set of miniatures.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/alien-rpg-evolved-edition-miniatures.jpg?itok=_DbutktH 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/alien-rpg-evolved-edition-miniatures.jpg?itok=VYmRy2rZ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>As the name implies, the updated core rulebook completely revises the systems and mechanics of the Ennie-winning <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/first-look-alien-roleplaying-game" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">TTRPG</a> set in the horror sci-fi world of <em>Alien</em>. The book will feature new items, spaceships, and locations from the recent feature film <em>Alien: Romulus</em>. In addition, it will contain improved and streamlined stealth mechanics, a solo mode, stress and panic rules, and even zero-gravity rules.</p>

<p>For aspiring collectors and early backers, the campaign has some extras. If you back the campaign within 48 hours, you will receive a crew patch of the USCSS Fidanza, the spaceship featured in the cinematic adventure <em>Rapture Protocol</em>, at no additional cost.Finally, there is a Kickstarter-exclusive Collectors Edition of the Core Rulebook.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/alien-rpg-evolved-edition-collectors-edition-book.jpg?itok=yljM6fON 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/alien-rpg-evolved-edition-collectors-edition-book.jpg?itok=mgA1F0yo 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Long-time players will also have reason to back the <em>Alien RPG Evolved Edition</em> Kickstarter. The campaign confirms that Free League will be publishing minor updates and reprints of two out-of-print <em>Alien RPG</em> supplements, <em>Colonial Marines Operations Manual</em> and <em>Building Better Worlds</em>. Both books are available in this campaign as separate add-ons.</p>

<p>The pledge levels for <em>Alien RPG Evolved Edition</em> are as follows:</p>

<ul><li><strong>Digital Core Book for $25:</strong> A PDF of the Evolved Edition Core Rulebook</li>
	<li><strong>Evolved Edition Starter Set for $30:</strong> A physical copy and PDF of the <em>Hope's Last Day</em> Starter Set Evolved Edition</li>
	<li><strong>Rapture Protocol Adventure Set for $40:</strong> A physical copy and PDF of the <em>Rapture Protocol</em> adventure set</li>
	<li><strong>Evolved Core Rulebook Standard Edition for $53:</strong> A physical copy and PDF of the standard Evolved Edition Core Rulebook</li>
	<li><strong>Rapture Protocol Miniatures Set for $60:</strong> A set of 17 physical miniatures for the Rapture Protocol adventure set</li>
	<li><strong>Cinematic Bundle for $90:</strong> A physical copy and PDF of <em>Rapture Protocol</em> and the miniatures set</li>
	<li><strong>Evolved Core Rulebook Collectors Edition for $99:</strong> A physical copy and PDF of the Kickstarter-exclusive Collectors Edition&nbsp; Evolved Edition Core Rulebook</li>
	<li><strong>Company Bundle for $159:</strong> Physical copies and PDF of the standard Core Rulebook, <em>Hope's Last Day</em> Starter Set, <em>Rapture Protocol</em> adventure set and miniatures set</li>
	<li><strong>Xenomorph Bundle for $278:</strong> Everything in the Company Bundle, a Collectors Edition Core Rulebook, a GM Screen, a set of base dice and stress dice, and a set of four brass lapel pins</li>
	<li><strong>Engineer Bundle for $297:</strong> Everything in the Xenomorph Bundle and physical copies and PDFs of the <em>Colonial Marines Operations</em> <em>Manual</em> and <em>Building Better Worlds</em> supplements</li>
</ul><p>At the time of writing, the <em>Alien RPG Evolved Edition</em> Kickstarter campaign has raised&nbsp;$772,398, completely obliterating the initial funding goal of&nbsp;<span><span><span>$49,558. The campaign concludes April 17.</span></span></span></p>
</div>


<div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div>

    </div>
  
  
  
  <div>
  <ul>
    <p>Additional topics:</p>
          <p>
        <li><a href="https://techraptor.net/topic/announcement" hreflang="en">Announcement</a></li>
      </p>
          <p>
        <li><a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/rpg-0" hreflang="en">RPG</a></li>
      </p>
      </ul>
</div>
  

  </div>

</article>

  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>