<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:28:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hametsu Ryu and The Rain and Musashi Review - The Cataclysm Expands]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/hametsu-ryu-and-rain-and-musashi-review-cataclysm-expands</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hametsu-ryu-and-the-rain-and-musashi-review-the-cataclysm-expands.1353949/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>As if the cataclysm and the horrors it unleashed weren't enough, the constant rain we've had for months has empowered the kappa that also plagues us. But a monk has a plan to stop the rain, and your group of adventurers is needed for the mission. In this article, we check out the 2 new supplements for <em>Hametsu</em>, The Ryu and the Rain narrative expansion, and <em>Hamestu</em> Legends Mushashi.</p>

<p><em>Hamestu</em> is an apocalyptic fantasy narrative wargame set in 16th-century Japan. You can check out our review of the <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/hametsu-core-rulebook-review" rel="nofollow">core rulebook</a>&nbsp;and a <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/hametsu-miniatures-showcase-heroes-and-enemies-of-cataclysm" rel="nofollow">miniatures showcase</a> for the heroes and enemies from the core rulebook.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/hametsu-ryu-and-the-rain-and-musashi-4.jpg?itok=X1LKZOkq 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/hametsu-ryu-and-the-rain-and-musashi-4.jpg?itok=6SRc67X_ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The rain. Always rain [Credit: Black Site Studios - <em>Hametsu</em> Legends Musashi]</figcaption></figure><h2>Playing In The Cataclysm</h2>

<p><em>Hametsu</em> is a tabletop wargame for 1 to 4 players, which means it can be played solo or cooperatively against AI-controlled enemies. While Black Site Studios produces miniatures for the heroes and enemies for <em>Hametsu</em> (along with some awesome scenery), it's a miniature agnostic system, so you can use any miniatures you wish to play (but you should absolutely pick up their official miniatures, or STLs to print yourself).</p>

<p>Games of <em>Hametsu</em> take place over 3 unique phases. In the Stealth phase, players try to sneak around, avoiding the AI-controlled enemies who use the orders detailed in the scenario. In the Clash phase, enemies are aware of the players and attack them using their individual instinct rules. During both phases, players try to investigate clues, looking to move the game into the Boss phase, where the lesser enemies flee to make way for a larger and more dangerous enemy.</p>

<p>If you want to know more about <em>Hametsu</em> and how it plays, check out our review of the <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/hametsu-core-rulebook-review" rel="nofollow">core rulebook</a>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/hametsu-ryu-and-the-rain-and-musashi-2.jpg?itok=NkdrHDw4 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/hametsu-ryu-and-the-rain-and-musashi-2.jpg?itok=tLJwo2Iz 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>As you grow, so do your enemies [Credit: Black Site Studios - <em>Hametsu</em> Ryu and the Rain]</figcaption></figure><h2>Only Rain</h2>

<p>The<em> Hametsu </em>Ryu and the Rain narrative<em>&nbsp;</em>expansion book&nbsp;includes a load of new content for your games, but it's aimed at veteran hunters who've reached level 8 or more. It includes an alternative wound tracking mode to speed up combat for higher-level hunters, and a path of mastery to take your hunters from level 8 to 12, along with the levelling up bonuses for all 12 classes from the <em>Hametsu</em> core rulebook.</p>

<p>To go along with the extra levels for your hunters, there are new scenarios, Time Trial, Dungeon Crawl, and Wave Defence, which all function as they sound, and an advanced version of all 6 of the bosses from the core rulebook. These advanced versions offer a real challenge, like the&nbsp;Shikigami Horde, of which you now have to face 3, who heal and upgrade every time you take one out, until you're left with one final super&nbsp;Shikigami to face.</p>

<p>The book closes with the Ryu and the Rain campaign, aimed at level 8 hunters who will level up using the book's path of mastery. The campaign sees the hunters traveling across Japan, using a map to track their route and guides for the scenery as they travel, detailing changes to the landscape as they progress. It also introduces a new enemy type, the Kappa. These turtle-like creatures are empowered by water, and taking them out of action can be difficult, as they have a 1 in 3 chance of coming back after being reduced to 0 wounds.</p>

<p>The book and campaign are a very welcome expansion, allowing you to progress with hunters that you've already invested time in. The advanced bosses offer a real challenge, even for path of mastery hunters, and it makes me wonder what's next if you can advance your hunters beyond level 12. Maybe no minions, only bosses in scenarios, multiple different bosses at the same time, or some brand new epic-level bosses to face. The Kappa are fun to fight, and very thematic in the rain-based campaign, which is captured very well as you travel across Japan using the map and changing scenery guide.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/hametsu-ryu-and-the-rain-and-musashi-3.jpg?itok=0yZFXwQk 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/hametsu-ryu-and-the-rain-and-musashi-3.jpg?itok=YDUZwFEU 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Musashi, the first <em>Hametsu</em> Legend [Credit: Black Site Studios - <em>Hametsu</em> Legends Musashi]</figcaption></figure><h2>Two Sword Legend</h2>

<p>The <em>Hametsu </em>Musashi expansion book is the start of a series of <em>Hametsu</em> Legends titles that will offer solo narrative campaigns featuring Japanese heroes of legend. This first one is about Miyamoto Musashi, a famous Japanese duelist and author of the classic Book of the Five Rings.</p>

<p><em>Hametsu</em> Legends Musashi features the profile for Musashi, including his path of legend to Level 8. Musashi, famous for his 2 swords technique, can use both the katana and the shorter wakizashi at the same time, gaining a bonus to melee and resilience (to show the offensive and defensive bonus of wielding 2 blades), and deals damage with both weapons on each success.</p>

<p>The core of the book features an 8-scenario campaign for Musashi to work through solo, and the rules for the Kappa enemies (as featured in the Ryu and the Rain expansion book) and a new Kappa boss for Musashi to face. It's a great campaign, and it works well as an intro to the Ryu and the Rain campaign, especially if you put Musashi into your group (as even capping at level 8, he still holds his own with level 12 hunters). The Musashi campaign is solo play, as it features Musashi as the only playable hero.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/hametsu-ryu-and-the-rain-and-musashi-5.jpg?itok=zHRtqXX2 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/hametsu-ryu-and-the-rain-and-musashi-5.jpg?itok=GAqG0C1v 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Musashi's miniature captures the master's famous 2-sword technique [Credit: Black Site Studios]</figcaption></figure><h2>Physically Present</h2>

<p>The rules for Ryu and the Rain and Musashi are available in both digital and physical formats. The miniatures, however, unlike the initial wave of <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/hametsu-miniatures-showcase-heroes-and-enemies-of-cataclysm" rel="nofollow">Hametsu miniatures</a>, were only available at preorder and are now only available as 3D-printable STL files from <a href="https://blacksitestudio.com/en-gb/pages/hametsu-digital-products" rel="nofollow">Black Site Studios</a>. There you can pick up a 3D file for Musashi and, separately as a bundle, all the Kappa miniatures for use in the Ryu and the Rain and Musashi campaign. This isn't great for those without a 3D printer, but as a miniatures agnostic system, you can use other available miniatures.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/hametsu-ryu-and-the-rain-and-musashi-6.jpg?itok=2R_p3N44 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/hametsu-ryu-and-the-rain-and-musashi-6.jpg?itok=bXdUVqgX 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The Hametsu Kappa stl bundle includes all the miniatures for both Ryu and the Rain and the Musashi expansions [Credit: Black Site Studios]</figcaption></figure><h2>Hametsu Ryu and The Rain and Musashi Final Thoughts?</h2>

<p><em>Hametsu</em>&nbsp;Ryu and the Rain and <em>Hametsu</em> Legends Musashi are both fantastic expansions.&nbsp;The Musashi campaign is a great solo campaign following one of Japan's most famous swordsmen and serves as a nice introduction to the Ryu and the Rain campaign. Ryu and the Rain is great for expanding your games beyond your heroes maxing out at Level 8, and is a full product for levelling them up. The new campaign, enemies, upgraded bosses, and paths of mastery are extremely welcome for keeping your games going, and the new scenario types provide challenging repeat play.</p>

<hr><p>The copies of&nbsp;<strong>Hametsu Ryu and The Rain, and Musashi</strong>&nbsp;<em>used to produce this guide&nbsp;were provided by Black Site Studios.</em></p>


</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Adam is a Tabletop Specialist for TechRaptor. He started writing for TechRaptor in 2017 and took over as Tabletop Editor in 2019 and has since stood down… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/adam-potts">More about Adam</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/hametsu-ryu-and-rain-and-musashi-review-cataclysm-expands]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>