<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 19:08:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Cloud Gaming Is Coming to LG Smart TVs]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/xbox-cloud-gaming-lg-smart-tvs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-cloud-gaming-is-coming-to-lg-smart-tvs.1075092/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/xbox-cloud-gaming-lg-smart-tvs<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>LG and Xbox have announced that they're teaming up in order to bring Xbox Cloud Gaming to LG smart TVs via an all-new Xbox app integration.</p>

<p>In an <a href="https://www.lgnewsroom.com/2025/01/lg-and-xbox-partner-to-expand-cloud-gaming-experience-on-lg-smart-tvs/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">announcement on its official website</a>, LG says you'll soon be able to access the Xbox app via its new Gaming Portal, although it also notes that said Gaming Portal's availability "can vary per TV model", so you'll probably have to pick up a newer smart TV to take advantage of it.</p>

<p>If you are lucky enough to own one of the LG TVs that supports the Gaming Portal, you can look forward to accessing "hundreds of games" via Xbox Cloud Gaming, though you'll need an Xbox Game Pass Ultimate subscription to take advantage of that feature as well.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/xbox-cloud-gaming-lg-smart-tvs-app.jpg?itok=92ELIiOv 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/xbox-cloud-gaming-lg-smart-tvs-app.jpg?itok=WgxzCLmH 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>LG and Xbox are teaming up to bring the latter's Cloud Gaming service to LG smart TVs.</figcaption></figure><p>You'll also be able to access a select few games that aren't included with Game Pass but that you can stream via the cloud nonetheless, including the likes of&nbsp;<em>NBA 2K25&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Hogwarts Legacy</em>.</p>

<p>The app will be powered by LG's webOS, and it sounds like it might be just one of several cloud gaming apps available via the Gaming Portal; LG says the service provides a "comprehensive overview with an app list that includes cloud gaming apps, webOS app games", and more.</p>

<p>Xbox Cloud Gaming is, of course, already available on Xbox consoles and web browsers, as well as in several other places, including Samsung's own smart TV line.</p>

<p>It's the cornerstone of Xbox's "This Is an Xbox" <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2024/11/14/this-is-an-xbox/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">campaign</a>, which seeks to paint any device capable of running Cloud Gaming via a browser or the desktop Xbox app as an Xbox device.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/lg-smart-tvs-xbox-cloud-gaming-this-is-an-xbox.jpg?itok=qEn7xTy8 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/lg-smart-tvs-xbox-cloud-gaming-this-is-an-xbox.jpg?itok=wV8p4zoJ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>If you say so, guys.</figcaption></figure><p>Elsewhere in Xbox news, the company <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/xbox-android-app-games" rel="nofollow">recently announced</a> it would allow players to purchase games directly from its Android app after a court ruling found in Epic's favor against Google.</p>

<p>Xbox boss Phil Spencer also confirmed that an Xbox <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/xbox-handheld-confirmed-but-years-away" rel="nofollow">handheld device</a> is currently being prototyped, although it's likely years away.</p>

<p>It's also unlikely you'll be able to play&nbsp;<em>Black Myth: Wukong&nbsp;</em>on that device if its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/black-myth-wukong-xbox-port-series-s" rel="nofollow">producer's comments</a> are anything to go by, although hey, maybe you'll be able to stream it via the cloud by then.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>