<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 16:47:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Just Cause Creator's Studio Liquid Swords Announces Layoffs]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/liquid-swords-layoffs-just-cause-creator</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/just-cause-creators-studio-liquid-swords-announces-layoffs.1111455/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/liquid-swords-layoffs-just-cause-creator<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Liquid Swords, the studio founded by&nbsp;<em>Just Cause&nbsp;</em>franchise creator Christofer Sundberg, has announced a round of layoffs, making it the latest NetEase studio to be hit by funding cuts or downsizing efforts.</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://www.liquidswords.com/news/liquid-swords-announces-proposed-workforce-reduction-amid-business-challenges" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">message</a> on the official Liquid Swords website, the studio says the layoffs are part of "an effort to scale back operations and adapt to current business conditions", which is becoming an increasingly common refrain across the industry.</p>

<p>Liquid Swords goes on to say that the layoffs will go towards ensuring the studio's "long-term sustainability" as it continues to work on its debut title, so it sounds as though that game - whatever it may be - hasn't been canceled, at the very least.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/liquid-swords-layoffs-just-cause-4.jpg?itok=OpWO8Crq 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/liquid-swords-layoffs-just-cause-4.jpg?itok=FsS_BBOJ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Liquid Swords founder Christofer Sundberg created the&nbsp;<em>Just Cause&nbsp;</em>franchise.</figcaption></figure><p>Sundberg says that his mission with Liquid Swords is to "build a studio redefining game development with a small, expert-driven team and a sustainable business model", and that "shifting market conditions" forced him to "part ways with talented individuals".</p>

<p>Despite this, Sundberg says he and Liquid Swords remain "committed to [their] vision" for the debut game and that work on the project will continue.</p>

<p>The game has yet to be announced, but Liquid Swords says it's "confident that this extremely unfortunate setback will not prevent it from realizing its original ambition" for the title. Here's hoping that we get an announcement for it at some point in the future.</p>

<p>Liquid Swords was originally founded <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/avalanche-studios-founder-announces-new-studio-liquid-swords" rel="nofollow">back in 2020</a>. Helmed by Sundberg, the studio also includes alumni from franchises like&nbsp;<em>Battlefield</em>,&nbsp;<em>Grand Theft Auto</em>, and&nbsp;<em>Payday</em>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/battlefield-liquid-swords.jpg?itok=-r-KYvVz 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/battlefield-liquid-swords.jpg?itok=t0M4mP2v 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Liquid Swords' staff includes folks who've worked on the likes of&nbsp;<em>Battlefield</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>Unfortunately, Liquid Swords isn't the only NetEase-funded studio to undergo downsizing or funding reduction in recent months.</p>

<p>Others include <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/worlds-untold-netease-pause-shutdown" rel="nofollow">Worlds Untold</a>, the studio <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/mac-walters-worlds-untold-netease" rel="nofollow">founded by BioWare veteran Mac Walters</a>, as well as <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/gaming-industry/netease-pulls-funding-for-another-studio-former-halo-infinite-design-head-says-jar-of-sparks-is-halting-work-while-it-looks-for-a-new-publisher/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Jar of Sparks</a>, which is <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/jar-of-sparks-is-new-aaa-studio-from-former-halo-infinite-head-of-design" rel="nofollow">headed up by&nbsp;<em>Halo&nbsp;</em>veteran Jerry Hook</a>.</p>

<p>It's not just NetEase studios, either; other smaller indie outfits are closing their doors or cancelling projects too, including the likes of <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/casey-hudson-humanoid-origin-closed-down" rel="nofollow">Casey Hudson's Humanoid Origin</a>&nbsp;and Dr. Disrespect's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/midnight-society-shutdown-dr-disrespect" rel="nofollow">former studio Midnight Society</a>, among many others.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 Sales Hit 2m in Under Two Weeks]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-sales-2m-two-weeks</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-sales-hit-2m-in-under-two-weeks.1111416/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-sales-2m-two-weeks<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Warhorse Studios has announced that&nbsp;<em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2&nbsp;</em>has hit another huge sales milestone, and the game hasn't even been on general release for two weeks yet.</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://x.com/WarhorseStudios/status/1891487776421638643" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">post</a> on X earlier today, the studio announced that its realistic medieval RPG has passed the two million sales mark, calling the achievement a "triumph" and thanking players who contributed to the game's sales.</p>

<p>Of course,&nbsp;<em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2&nbsp;</em>passing the two million mark probably won't come as a surprise to you if you've been following its progress. After all, the game passed a million sales <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-sales-1m" rel="nofollow">on its launch day</a>, and parent company Embracer Group announced sales were nearing two million <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-sales-2m-embracer" rel="nofollow">just last week</a>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-sales-2m-marriage.jpg?itok=sduZLym2 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-sales-2m-marriage.jpg?itok=dmp3uDfR 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2&nbsp;</em>has passed the two million sales mark.</figcaption></figure><p>As a reminder, the original&nbsp;<em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance&nbsp;</em>took <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/kingdom-come-deliverance-sales-six-million" rel="nofollow">six years to pass the six million mark</a>, eventually reaching eight million <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/kingdom-come-deliverance-sales-8m" rel="nofollow">by November last year</a>.</p>

<p>While there is, of course, no guarantee that the sequel will continue the momentum it's currently gathered, there's every chance that&nbsp;<em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2&nbsp;</em>will pass the six million point in a fraction of the time it took its predecessor to do so.</p>

<p>It looks like <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-rumors-director" rel="nofollow">those wild rumors about the game's content</a>, which director&nbsp;Daniel Vávra shot down prior to&nbsp;<em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2</em>'s release, have done absolutely nothing to dull its edge when it comes to popularity.</p>

<p>Lest you worry that the RPG is slowing down now that it's finally out there in the wild, you can think again.&nbsp;<em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-roadmap" rel="nofollow">has a roadmap in place</a> for the future, and it promises tons of new stuff for the game. Not only that, but <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-mod-support" rel="nofollow">official mod support via Steamworks</a> is also on the way.</p>




<p>In case you're not up to speed,&nbsp;<em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2&nbsp;</em>is a medieval RPG created by Czech studio Warhorse.</p>

<p>Like its predecessor, the game eschews overt fantasy elements in favor of historical accuracy and realism. It takes place in early 15th-century Bohemia and sees protagonist Henry of Skalitz once again navigating a perilous world of political intrigue.</p>

<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1771300/Kingdom_Come_Deliverance_II/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/kingdom-come-deliverance-ii/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PS5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/kingdom-come-deliverance-ii/9n4w31hsmvvd" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>. Our Ashley <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/kingdom-come-deliverance-ii-review-deliciously-executed-revenge" rel="nofollow">gave the game a glowing review</a>, praising its huge variety of activities and "outstanding" visual design.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Counter-Strike 2 Hits Highest Player Count Since 2023]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/counter-strike-2-player-count</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/counter-strike-2-hits-highest-player-count-since-2023.1111392/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/counter-strike-2-player-count<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Valve's first-person shooter&nbsp;<em>Counter-Strike 2&nbsp;</em>has hit its highest player count since May 2023, and it isn't really clear why that's happened.</p>

<p><em>Counter-Strike 2&nbsp;</em>was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/valve-surprise-releases-counter-strike-2" rel="nofollow">surprise-released in September 2023</a>, essentially serving as both a sequel to&nbsp;<em>Counter-Strike: Global Offensive&nbsp;</em>and a major update for that game as well. In May that year, when it was still&nbsp;<em>Global Offensive</em>, the game hit its all-time Steam player count high of 1,818,773 (<a href="https://steamdb.info/app/730/charts/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">per SteamDB</a>).</p>

<p>This weekend, again according to SteamDB's numbers (with thanks to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.dexerto.com/counter-strike-2/counter-strike-2-hits-massive-new-player-count-record-but-no-one-really-knows-why-3133997/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Dexerto</a>),&nbsp;<em>Counter-Strike 2&nbsp;</em>managed to hit a concurrent player count of 1,741,837, representing the game's highest player numbers since the Steam launch of both <i>Global Offensive&nbsp;</i>and&nbsp;<em>Counter-Strike 2&nbsp;</em>itself.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/counter-strike-2-concurrent-player-count-shooting.jpg?itok=jLhzaDON 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/counter-strike-2-concurrent-player-count-shooting.jpg?itok=-sLiONym 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Counter-Strike 2</em>'s player numbers have reached a recent high, and it's not clear why.</figcaption></figure><p>It's worth noting that&nbsp;<em>Counter-Strike 2</em>'s numbers (which were originally those of&nbsp;<em>Global Offensive</em>, lest we forget) have been trending upwards since 2012, and that the game has routinely been playing host to over a million players per day since 2022.</p>

<p>Still, there weren't any major&nbsp;<em>CS2&nbsp;</em>esports tournaments over the weekend, and as far as I know, no major&nbsp;<em>Counter-Strike 2&nbsp;</em>content creators have done anything particularly noteworthy over the past few days either.</p>

<p>It's entirely possible that&nbsp;<em>Counter-Strike 2</em>'s numbers have simply hit this high as part of the aforementioned general trend upwards for the game, but it's still interesting (and no doubt encouraging for Valve, given <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/counter-strike-2-600m-revenue-report" rel="nofollow">how much the shooter rakes in</a>) to see figures like this for the game.</p>

<p>Will&nbsp;<em>Counter-Strike 2&nbsp;</em>manage to eclipse its all-time player high within the next few weeks? If the player count continues to rise, then it's pretty much an inevitability, which can only mean more skin sales for Valve. Hooray, I guess!</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/counter-strike-2-concurrent-player-count-barrels.jpg?itok=6BWGNT17 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/counter-strike-2-concurrent-player-count-barrels.jpg?itok=KKveFkqD 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Counter-Strike 2&nbsp;</em>makes big money for Valve.</figcaption></figure><p>If you're still in the dark about&nbsp;<em>Counter-Strike 2</em>, it's a multiplayer first-person shooter that pits teams of terrorists against their counter-terrorist foes.</p>

<p>The game essentially plays the same as its predecessor; it's a reflex-based FPS with a focus on observation, quick thinking, and objective-based gameplay (unless you're playing in deathmatch, in which case it's a chaotic free-for-all).</p>

<p>When it made the switch to&nbsp;<em>Counter-Strike 2</em>, Valve's shooter got itself a new Source 2-based coat of paint, as well as new server architecture, updated maps, and more.</p>

<p><em>Counter-Strike 2&nbsp;</em>is available to play right now <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/730/CounterStrike_2/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">for free on PC via Steam</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hunter x Hunter Nen x Impact Release Date Revealed for July]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hunter-x-hunter-nen-x-impact-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hunter-x-hunter-nen-x-impact-release-date-revealed-for-july.1111335/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hunter-x-hunter-nen-x-impact-release-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Bushiroad Games and Arc System Works have announced the release date for upcoming anime fighter&nbsp;<em>Hunter x Hunter Nen x Impact</em>, which will serve as the first major fighting game adaptation of the popular manga and anime.</p>

<p>As revealed during this weekend's Evo event,&nbsp;<em>Hunter x Hunter Nen x Impact&nbsp;</em>will launch on July 17th. When it does, you'll be able to play it on PC, PS5, and Switch. No release has been announced for Xbox.</p>

<p>Originally <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hunter-x-hunter-fighting-game-announced-at-jump-festa" rel="nofollow">announced in December 2023</a>,&nbsp;<em>Hunter x Hunter Nen x Impact&nbsp;</em>was originally scheduled for a 2024 release, but in September, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hunter-x-hunter-nen-x-impact-delayed-rollback-netcode" rel="nofollow">it was delayed</a> in order to allow the developers to add rollback netcode to the game.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/hunter-x-hunter-nen-x-impact-release-date-fight.jpg?itok=LTE_vL72 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/hunter-x-hunter-nen-x-impact-release-date-fight.jpg?itok=KYgsXwlR 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Hunter x Hunter Nen x Impact&nbsp;</em>is locked in for a July launch.</figcaption></figure><p>If you're wondering what rollback netcode is, it's essentially tech that improves the quality of an online fighting game experience.</p>

<p>The long explanation is very technical, but in short, rollback netcode "rolls back" the state of the game if it detects a delay, but retains your own inputs, which makes online fights feel much more smooth.</p>

<p>Rollback netcode has been implemented in a number of hugely successful fighting games, including the likes of&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dragon-ball-fighterz-rollback-netcode-ps5-xbox" rel="nofollow"><em>Dragon Ball FighterZ</em></a>, Capcom's&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/street-fighter-6-rollback-netcode-will-be-better-open-worlds-detailed" rel="nofollow"><em>Street Fighter 6</em></a>, and Bandai Namco's&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/will-tekken-8-have-crossplay-and-rollback-netcode-katsuhiro-harada-responds" rel="nofollow"><em>Tekken 8</em></a>, as well as <i>Nen x Impact&nbsp;</i>publisher Arc System Works' own&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/guity-gear-strive-beta-impressions" rel="nofollow"><em>Guilty Gear Strive</em></a>.</p>

<p>In short, while a delay to&nbsp;<em>Hunter x Hunter Nen x Impact&nbsp;</em>was unfortunate, it was put into effect so the developers could make it a more satisfying online experience, which it's hard to complain about.</p>




<p><em>Hunter x Hunter Nen x Impact&nbsp;</em>is the first "full-fledged" fighting game to be based on the manga and anime series. It's a 3v3 battler in which you can play as a range of characters from the manga, including Gon, Hisoka, and Killua, among others.</p>

<p>You'll be able to check the game out when it launches on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2456420/HUNTERxHUNTER_NENxIMPACT/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-gb/concept/10007325" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PS5</a>, and Nintendo Switch on July 17th.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>