<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 14:41:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atomfall The Red Strain Story DLC Coming in September]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/atomfall-red-strain-story-dlc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/atomfall-the-red-strain-story-dlc-coming-in-september.1282905/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Rebellion has announced&nbsp;<em>The Red Strain</em>, a brand new DLC expansion for&nbsp;<em>Atomfall&nbsp;</em>that's launching next month, although the studio is keeping its cards close to its chest regarding what you can expect for now.</p>

<p><em>The Red Strain&nbsp;</em>was announced earlier today via a brand new teaser trailer, and "teaser" really is the word; the trailer reveals the name of the expansion, as well as a C.O.R.E. robot standing in front of some kind of red growth (presumably the Red Strain of the title).</p>

<p>What we do know is that this will be&nbsp;<em>Atomfall</em>'s second major story expansion, following on from <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/atomfall-wicked-isle-dlc-release-date" rel="nofollow">June's&nbsp;<em>Wicked Isle</em></a>, which introduced a brand new area and other goodies to Rebellion's open-ended shooter.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/atomfall-the-red-strain-dlc-wicked-isle.jpg?itok=jb20XuWE 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/atomfall-the-red-strain-dlc-wicked-isle.jpg?itok=W7D_8oYR 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>The Red Strain&nbsp;</em>will be&nbsp;<em>Atomfall</em>'s second story DLC, following on from&nbsp;<em>Wicked Isle</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>While Rebellion hasn't revealed exactly what will be introduced as part of&nbsp;<em>The Red Strain</em>, the studio does say you can expect "a highly confidential new location", as well as "plenty more mysteries to uncover". That sounds about right for an&nbsp;<em>Atomfall&nbsp;</em>expansion.</p>

<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Atomfall&nbsp;</em>itself, it's an open-ended first-person shooter developed by&nbsp;<em>Sniper Elite&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Zombie Army&nbsp;</em>studio Rebellion. It's set in a 1960s England that was a lot more heavily impacted by the Windscale nuclear disaster than the one in real life was.</p>

<p>At the outset of&nbsp;<em>Atomfall</em>, you awaken in a bunker with amnesia, and it's up to you to explore the Windscale plant and its surroundings in order to discover the truth behind Windscale and why a mysterious voice is telling you that a being known as Oberon "must die".</p>




<p>Somewhat unusually for modern games,&nbsp;<em>Atomfall&nbsp;</em>essentially allows you freedom in how you pursue your objectives; you'll have several leads to follow at any given time, and the order in which you chase those leads is largely up to you.</p>

<p><em>Atomfall&nbsp;</em>is available right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/801800/Atomfall/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/atomfall/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/atomfall/9NC4WDL5KZBL" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox</a>, and it's also a day one Game Pass title. You can read our very own Erren's review of the game to find out what she thought of it <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/atomfall-review-british-invasion" rel="nofollow">right here</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/atomfall-red-strain-story-dlc]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mega Hawlucha Officially Revealed for Pokemon Legends: Z-A]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/mega-hawlucha-pokemon-legends-z-a</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mega-hawlucha-officially-revealed-for-pokemon-legends-z-a.1282863/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The Pokemon Company has announced a brand new Mega Evolution for the upcoming&nbsp;<em>Pokemon Legends: Z-A</em>, and unlike the last two reveals, this one is a bona fide Generation VI native.</p>

<p><em>Pokemon Legends: Z-A&nbsp;</em>is <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pokemon-legends-z-release-date-pokemon-presents" rel="nofollow">set to launch on October 16th</a>, and the first major new Mega Evolution revealed for the game was Dragonite, with Grass/Poison-type plant <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/mega-victreebel-revealed-pokemon-legends-za" rel="nofollow">Victreebel following earlier this month</a>. Be sure to check out Mega Victreebel's horror-inflected announcement trailer if you haven't already.</p>

<p>Now, a brand new Mega Evolution has been revealed for the game, and it's none other than the Fighting/Flying-type luchador bird Hawlucha, which will transform into an even more magnificent form if you choose to Mega Evolve it.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/mega-hawlucha-announced-trailer.jpg?itok=kSFPRTR0 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/mega-hawlucha-announced-trailer.jpg?itok=xl4KvUbx 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Hawlucha is the latest Pokemon to get the Mega Evolution treatment.</figcaption></figure><p>The trailer in which Mega Hawlucha is revealed is a pretty heartwarming one; the luchador steps into the ring with Machamp, and the latter proves to be a tough opponent until Hawlucha draws on its memories of its trainer and steps it up a notch.</p>

<p>I would say that I won't spoil what happens next, but given that this is a trailer specifically announcing the existence of Mega Hawlucha, I'm sure you can put two and two together. Suffice it to say Hawlucha's trainer is delighted with the outcome.</p>

<p>You can check out the full trailer announcing Mega Hawlucha below; it essentially takes the form of a full wrestling match between the two Pokemon, complete with the kind of dramatic twists and turns you'd expect from a WWE bout.</p>




<p><em>Pokemon Legends: Z-A&nbsp;</em>is set to debut on <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/pokemon-legends-z-a-nintendo-switch-2-edition-switch-2/" rel="nofollow">Nintendo Switch 2</a> and the <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/en-gb/Games/Nintendo-Switch-games/Pokemon-Legends-Z-A-2533423.html" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">original Switch</a> on October 16th. Set entirely in Lumiose City in the Kalos region, the game sees players undertaking an urban redevelopment project by day and participating in an exciting battle tournament by night.</p>

<p>The game will also feature a more action-oriented battle system that will require players to physically dodge certain moves, as well as a number of new Mega Evolution forms, of which we've only seen a few. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/mega-hawlucha-pokemon-legends-z-a]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>