<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 17:32:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2077 Sales Pass 30 Million as New Witcher Game Production Ramps Up]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/cyberpunk-2077-sales-witcher-production</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cyberpunk-2077-sales-pass-30-million-as-new-witcher-game-production-ramps-up.1045749/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/cyberpunk-2077-sales-witcher-production<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>CD Projekt has revealed that open-world action RPG&nbsp;<em>Cyberpunk 2077&nbsp;</em>has hit another major sales milestone, and there's some good news if you're waiting on tenterhooks for the next&nbsp;<em>Witcher&nbsp;</em>game as well.</p>

<p>In <a href="https://x.com/CDPROJEKTRED_IR/status/1861447302260363516" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">a</a><a href="https://www.cdprojekt.com/en/wp-content/uploads-en/2024/11/cd-projekt-group-presentation-q3-2024.pdf" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">&nbsp;new financial presentation</a>, CD Projekt reveals that&nbsp;<em>Cyberpunk 2077&nbsp;</em>sales have hit 30 million as of today, with that number including both sales of the base game and the Ultimate Edition bundle.</p>

<p>What's more,&nbsp;<em>Phantom Liberty</em>, the DLC expansion for&nbsp;<em>Cyberpunk 2077&nbsp;</em>that launched last year, has managed to sell eight million copies, which is around the same number as the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/resident-evil-4-remake-sales-8m" rel="nofollow">lifetime sales of the&nbsp;<em>Resident Evil 4&nbsp;</em>remake</a>. That's pretty impressive considering&nbsp;<em>Phantom Liberty&nbsp;</em>isn't a full game.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/cyberpunk-2077-sales-phantom-liberty.jpg?itok=-ila7YeQ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/cyberpunk-2077-sales-phantom-liberty.jpg?itok=kn5dC9H3 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Cyberpunk 2077</em>'s&nbsp;<em>Phantom Liberty&nbsp;</em>expansion has done pretty well for itself sales-wise.</figcaption></figure><p>In that same presentation, CD Projekt revealed that&nbsp;<em>Project Polaris</em>, which is the codename for the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/new-witcher-game-in-development-cdpr-says" rel="nofollow">next major game in the&nbsp;<em>Witcher&nbsp;</em>franchise</a>, has entered full production.</p>

<p>Essentially, this means that the next&nbsp;<em>Witcher&nbsp;</em>game has left its planning stages and that staff are now working on creating the game in earnest, bringing it one step closer to completion. Of course, we're still a long, long way away from that point.</p>

<p>It's worth noting, too, that&nbsp;<em>Polaris&nbsp;</em>is an entirely new game in the&nbsp;<em>Witcher&nbsp;</em>series, and as such, it's distinct from the&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/witcher-remake-announced-by-cd-projekt-red" rel="nofollow"><em>Witcher&nbsp;</em>remake that was announced by CD Projekt Red</a> back in 2022.</p>

<p>According to the financial presentation, as of October 31st, 400 staff members were working on&nbsp;<em>Polaris</em>, with 64 devoted to&nbsp;<em>Cyberpunk 2077&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/project-orion-new-hires" rel="nofollow">sequel&nbsp;</a><em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/project-orion-new-hires" rel="nofollow">Orion</a>&nbsp;</em>and 42 working on&nbsp;<em>Witcher&nbsp;</em>spinoff&nbsp;<em>Sirius</em>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/the-witcher-polaris-geralt.jpg?itok=_WzXF7Ti 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/the-witcher-polaris-geralt.jpg?itok=V9LMiaFi 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The next major game in the&nbsp;<em>Witcher&nbsp;</em>series has entered full production.</figcaption></figure><p>From a financial perspective, CD Projekt has had a slightly more humble third quarter this year than it did last year. Revenue is significantly down, as is gross profit, but the company still hasn't posted a loss despite releasing no major projects this year.</p>

<p>When it comes to year-to-date financials, CD Projekt's sales are slightly down over the same period last year, although sales of the&nbsp;<em>Witcher&nbsp;</em>series remain steady, and the company's net profitability has actually slightly increased.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Frostpunk 2 Roadmap Looks Ahead to DLCs, Console Launch, and More]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/frostpunk-2-roadmap</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/frostpunk-2-roadmap-looks-ahead-to-dlcs-console-launch-and-more.1045692/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/frostpunk-2-roadmap<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>11 bit studios has revealed the first&nbsp;<em>Frostpunk 2&nbsp;</em>roadmap, detailing what's coming to the post-apocalyptic city-builder in the near future, and there's plenty on the way to keep you occupied.</p>

<p>Released in September,&nbsp;<em>Frostpunk 2&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/frostpunk-2-profitable-sales-350k" rel="nofollow">quickly crossed the profitability line</a>, selling 350,000 copies just a few days out from launch (which isn't bad considering the game is also available on Game Pass as a day one release).</p>

<p>Now, developer and publisher 11 bit is looking to the future, and following on from October's Patch 1.1, the next major drop you can expect for&nbsp;<em>Frostpunk 2&nbsp;</em>is the appropriately-named Patch 1.2, which will arrive sometime before the year is out.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/frostpunk-2-roadmap-full.jpg?itok=0_8kY5SF 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/frostpunk-2-roadmap-full.jpg?itok=kg11pbox 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>There's plenty coming to&nbsp;<em>Frostpunk 2&nbsp;</em>in the near future.</figcaption></figure><p>After Patch 1.2, you can expect a "free major content update" in 2025. 11 bit hasn't specified what will be included in this update, but the studio does say these updates are "inspired by [players'] feedback" and that they will "significantly impact your overall experience with the game".</p>

<p>A console launch is also on the cards for 2025, as are two major DLC packs, currently codenamed Spectrum and Aurora. The devs promise these DLCs will "add something completely new to the harsh world of&nbsp;<em>Frostpunk 2</em>", although they're remaining tight-lipped for now.</p>

<p>A third DLC launch is planned for 2026, but that's quite a ways off, as evidenced by the fact that this DLC doesn't even have a codename yet. Still, it shows that you shouldn't set your copy of&nbsp;<em>Frostpunk 2&nbsp;</em>down for too long.</p>




<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Frostpunk 2</em>, it's 11 bit studios' followup to the 2018 survival city-builder&nbsp;<em>Frostpunk</em>. It's largely a similar experience to its predecessor, but it adds new mechanics like factions, new resource types, and city districts, plus lots more thorny moral decision-making.</p>

<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Frostpunk 2&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1601580/Frostpunk_2/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC via Steam</a>. A release for PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S is also planned for the future. Our very own Andrew Stretch's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/frostpunk-2-review-balance-resources-or-city-will-burn" rel="nofollow">review of the game is right here</a> if you want to learn more about how it ticks.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Total War: Warhammer 3 Omens of Destruction DLC Announced for Next Month]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/total-war-warhammer-3-omens-of-destruction-dlc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/total-war-warhammer-3-omens-of-destruction-dlc-announced-for-next-month.1045617/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/total-war-warhammer-3-omens-of-destruction-dlc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Sega and Creative Assembly have announced&nbsp;<em>Omens of Destruction</em>, the next major DLC pack for grand strategy game&nbsp;<em>Total War: Warhammer 3</em>, and it's due to arrive alongside a major free update for the game next month.</p>

<p>As revealed in <a href="https://community.creative-assembly.com/total-war/total-war-warhammer/blogs/39" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">a post</a> on the official Creative Assembly website,&nbsp;<em>Omens of Destruction&nbsp;</em>launches on December 12th, and it brings three new Legendary Lords with it, all of whom have their own combat perks and campaign bonuses to look forward to.</p>

<p>Your first Legendary Lord is Skulltaker, a champion of Khorne who seeks - you guessed it - skulls for the skull throne. He brings new units with him as well, including legendary heroes Skarr Bloodwrath and Skyla Anfingrimm, as well as "a host of acolytes".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/total-war-warhammer-3-omens-of-destruction-dlc-skulltaker.jpg?itok=mzen7Cbv 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/total-war-warhammer-3-omens-of-destruction-dlc-skulltaker.jpg?itok=FF5mqwA1 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Total War: Warhammer 3</em>'s new&nbsp;<em>Omens of Destruction&nbsp;</em>DLC includes Legendary Lords like Khorne's Skulltaker.</figcaption></figure><p>The second Legendary Lord is Gorbad Ironclaw, "one of the most infamous of all Orc Warbosses" who's probably about the closest thing to a master strategist the Orc faction can boast. Like Skulltaker, he brings his own additional units and heroes.</p>

<p>Finally, the Ogre Kingdoms gain Golgfag Maneater, a mercenary with a fearsome reputation who'll fight for anyone if the price is right. He's an anti-infantry "blender" who can tear through soldiers using his "barbaric" weaponry.</p>

<p>These three will arrive alongside Update 6.0, which brings a free Legendary Lord in the form of Khorne's Arbaal the Undefeated, as well as faction updates for Khorne, Orcs &amp; Goblins, and the Ogre Kingdoms.</p>

<p>As with previous&nbsp;<em>Total War: Warhammer 3&nbsp;</em>DLC packs like&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/total-war-warhammer-3-reveals-shadows-of-change-dlc-with-3-legendary-lords-more" rel="nofollow">Shadows of Change</a>&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/total-war-warhammer-3-thrones-of-decay-lords" rel="nofollow"><em>Thrones of Decay</em></a>, it'll be possible to buy all three Legendary Lords separately if you'd rather pick up just one or two of them.</p>




<p><em>Total War: Warhammer 3&nbsp;</em>is available right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1142710/Total_War_WARHAMMER_III/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC via Steam</a>. Its&nbsp;<em>Omens of Destruction&nbsp;</em>DLC, as well as its major 6.0 update, both launch on December 12th. You can <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/total-war-warhammer-3-review" rel="nofollow">read our review of the base game here</a> to find out our thoughts.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo eShop and Online Services to Close Down in China in 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-eshop-online-closing-china-2026</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-eshop-and-online-services-to-close-down-in-china-in-2026.1045587/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-eshop-online-closing-china-2026<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Nintendo has announced that it will shut down the eShop and all Switch network services in China in 2026. No reason has been given for the shutdown.</p>

<p>According to <a href="https://www.nintendoswitch.com.cn/topics/57ea6913-1a17-4afa-b325-a1a1a8596e15" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">a notice</a> posted on the official Chinese Nintendo website (thanks, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-switch-eshop-closing-2026-in-china" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Eurogamer</a>), the eShop will cease selling games and software on March 31st, 2026, after which point you won't be able to buy any games from the eShop, nor will you be able to download demos, trials, or free games.</p>

<p>Following that, on May 15th of the same year, you won't be able to download games from the eShop, and you won't be able to redeem codes either. That means you won't be able to buy any DLC, and it also seems to mean you won't be able to download games you already own.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/super-mario-odyssey-eshop-closure-china.jpg?itok=clxwOBnG 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/super-mario-odyssey-eshop-closure-china.jpg?itok=0WvP487i 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The Nintendo Switch eShop, as well as all of the console's network services, will be coming to an end in 2026 in China.</figcaption></figure><p>On the same day, all Switch-related network services will also be shut down, so you'll no longer be able to play Switch games online with your friends at that point.</p>

<p>You can see a full list of all of the games that will be affected by the network shutdown <a href="https://www.nintendoswitch.com.cn/support/software_affected.html" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">here</a>. It's in Chinese, and we're using machine translation for it, but it seems relatively accurate to me (although I have little to no knowledge of Chinese as a language).</p>

<p>In order to compensate Chinese Switch gamers for this decision, Nintendo will give away up to four Nintendo games for users via their WeChat account. You'll need to have activated your Switch console, and you'll need to have stuck to the Terms of Use as well.</p>

<p>The list has a couple of...unusual entries using machine translation, but games like&nbsp;<em>Super Mario Odyssey</em>,&nbsp;<em>Mario Kart 8 Deluxe</em>, and&nbsp;<em>Yoshi's Crafted World&nbsp;</em>can be redeemed, as well as&nbsp;<em>Kirby Star Allies</em>,&nbsp;<em>New Pokemon Snap</em>, and more.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/nintendo-eshop-closure-china-new-pokemon-snap.jpg?itok=o1tMZUrf 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/nintendo-eshop-closure-china-new-pokemon-snap.jpg?itok=I6sOdYmB 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>If you're a Switch user in China, you could be entitled to a free copy of&nbsp;<em>New Pokemon Snap</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>The giveaway starts on November 27th and runs until March 31st, 2026, and you'll need to use WeChat's game redemption applet in order to take advantage of it.</p>

<p>Do note that you'll have to download whatever games you decide to grab before May 15th, or else your free games will be gone for good. It's also worth noting that as far as we know, this doesn't affect the eShop anywhere else in the world.</p>

<p>News of the eShop's closure in China comes amid fevered speculation about the Switch 2, which Nintendo is due to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-switch-2-announcement-confirmation" rel="nofollow">reveal sometime before April</a>. It's not clear what this might mean for the Switch 2 in China.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>