<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 16:22:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CEO of Plaion, Formerly Koch Media, to Step Down After 31 Years]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/plaion-koch-media-ceo-stepping-down</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ceo-of-plaion-formerly-koch-media-to-step-down-after-31-years.1077084/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/plaion-koch-media-ceo-stepping-down<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Klemens Kundratitz, the CEO and co-founder of Plaion (formerly known as Koch Media), will step down from his role after 31 years and take an advisory role with parent company Embracer Group.</p>

<p>Per a press release, Kundratitz has decided that it's time to "take a step back and spend more time with his family", and so he's handing over the CEO reins to Phil Rogers, an exec who's "leading the creation of the new Middle-earth &amp; Friends operating unit".</p>

<p>In case you need a reminder, Middle-earth &amp; Friends is one of the three companies <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/embracer-group-splitting-three-companies" rel="nofollow">into which Embracer Group will be splitting</a>&nbsp;during this year, alongside tabletop division Asmodee and indie label Coffee Stain &amp; Friends.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/plaion-koch-media-ceo-klemens-kundratitz-kingdom-come-deliverance.jpg?itok=NU5JGk3e 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/plaion-koch-media-ceo-klemens-kundratitz-kingdom-come-deliverance.jpg?itok=EbZDFiuL 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Through its various divisions, Plaion has published a number of games, including&nbsp;<em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>Kundratitz, who co-founded Plaion as Koch Media alongside Franz Koch back in 1994, says he's "delighted" to be handing over CEO duties to Rogers, and that he believes Rogers will continue Plaion's "excellent momentum".</p>

<p>For his part, Rogers says he's "excited" to start building Middle-earth &amp; Friends as Plaion's new CEO, and that Kundratitz has built an "incredible legacy" over the course of his 31 years with the company.</p>

<p>Though you might not recognize Plaion's name, you'll probably know at least one of the publishing labels under its stewardship, namely Deep Silver, Ravenscourt, and Prime Matter.</p>

<p>Through Deep Silver, Plaion has published games like&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/payday-3" rel="nofollow"><em>Payday 3</em></a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/dead-island-2" rel="nofollow"><em>Dead Island 2</em></a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/metro-exodus" rel="nofollow"><em>Metro Exodus</em></a>, while the Prime Matter label is responsible for the likes of&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/kingdom-come-deliverance" rel="nofollow">Kingdom Come: Deliverance</a>&nbsp;</em>(whose developer Warhorse Studios is also a subsidiary of Plaion) and 2023's&nbsp;<em>System Shock&nbsp;</em>remake.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/system-shock-remake-plaion-koch-media-ceo.jpg?itok=1865tiQI 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/system-shock-remake-plaion-koch-media-ceo.jpg?itok=gCCB_aF9 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>System Shock&nbsp;</em>is just one of the many pies in which Plaion has its fingers.</figcaption></figure><p>As for Kundratitz himself, while he's stepping back from CEO duties with Plaion, he's not leaving Embracer entirely. He'll now serve as a "strategic advisor" for the group, which, given its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/embracer-group-financials-q2-2024" rel="nofollow">recent financial woes</a>, I'm sure will be appreciated.</p>

<p>It's unlikely that Kundratitz's departure will have a material effect on Embracer or its companies from a public-facing perspective, but we'll have to wait and see whether anything changes as a result of this management shift. Stay tuned.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Freedom Wars Remastered Review - Abductor Slayer]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/freedom-wars-remastered-review-abductor-slayer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/freedom-wars-remastered-review-abductor-slayer.1077036/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/freedom-wars-remastered-review-abductor-slayer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>In September of last year, <em>Freedom Wars Remastered</em> was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/freedom-wars-remastered-announced" rel="nofollow">announced</a>. The circles I frequent online were quite enthusiastic about this, despite me having never heard of the game. I mean, I didn't even own a <a href="https://techraptor.net/platform/playstation-vita" rel="nofollow">PS Vita</a>, it seemed like a completely obscure title. Still, the excitement from my friends piqued my interest, so I had to see what <em>Freedom Wars Remastered</em> was all about.</p>

<p>It seemed like a weird choice to revive a dormant IP exclusive to the PS Vita, but I'm glad I took the chance to review it. Turns out, <em>Freedom Wars </em><em>Remastered</em> is a quirky and competent take on the <em><a href="https://techraptor.net/series/monster-hunter" rel="nofollow">Monster Hunter</a> </em>formula, and that makes for an addicting game.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/freedom-wars-remastered-screenshot-1_1.jpg?itok=BxiFgXLe 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/freedom-wars-remastered-screenshot-1_1.jpg?itok=2Nmk-fdF 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>I guess I'll take that as a compliment?</figcaption></figure><h2><em>Freedom Wars Remastered,</em> a Decade After the Original</h2>

<p>As <em>Freedom Wars</em> is a remaster of a PS Vita title from 2014, you might expect it to look a bit dated visually. The smaller screen of a Vita means lower resolution, so obviously graphics aren't going to be on par with that of consoles.</p>

<p>Still, developer Dimps Corporation makes a commendable effort to revitalize <em>Freedom Wars</em> with this remaster. With upgraded textures and running a higher resolution, <em>Freedom Wars</em> <em>Remastered</em> looks very good considering its origins.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/freedom-wars-remastered-gameplay-2.jpg?itok=AD2jGueH 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/freedom-wars-remastered-gameplay-2.jpg?itok=1iW1Ohiw 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The squad's here!</figcaption></figure><p>Supposedly, it can run on 4k resolution. I couldn't find any way to tweak graphics on the PS5 version of <em>Freedom Wars Remastered</em>, so I'll just have to take the developer's word for it. I presume PC versions will have more options to adjust visuals. At the very least, I can say <em>Freedom Wars Remastered</em> runs at 60 FPS, so it's a smooth ride.</p>

<p>Really, the only issue is some animations look a little janky, especially during dialogue. There's a lot of talking in <em>Freedom Wars Remastered, </em>and facial animations are super rudimentary. It's nothing that'll detract from the experience; in fact, it's usually the only <em>visual </em>reminder that this was once a PS Vita game.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/freedom-wars-remastered-gameplay.jpg?itok=nxl8UtQJ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/freedom-wars-remastered-gameplay.jpg?itok=8fGmfn3e 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>It's satisfying to drag down a big ol' monster!</figcaption></figure><h2>Fighting For the Cause in <em>Freedom Wars Remastered</em></h2>

<p>To put it simply, <em>Freedom Wars Remastered</em> takes the <em>Monster Hunter</em> formula and gives it a gratifying hook (as if <em>Monster Hunter </em>wasn't already addicting). Not only are you acquiring new materials to upgrade equipment, but you also have a million-year prison sentence. As a sinner, you're tasked with working off that sentence by taking on various operations.</p>

<p>Your player character's prison sentence literally looms over your head, and just about every action you do either contributes to or diminishes said sentence. Stand around in one place too long? The game will give you a few decades to think about your ungodly crime.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/freedom-wars-remastered-sentence-2.jpg?itok=5K79MwUD 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/freedom-wars-remastered-sentence-2.jpg?itok=5slMXScb 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Just a drop in the bucket.</figcaption></figure><p>And so, that's where these operations come in. Completing various missions, ranging from extermination of "Abductors" (<em>Freedom Wars' </em>version of monsters), rescuing citizens, and donating valuable resources to the cause, all help diminish that prison term.</p>

<p>Watching the prison sentence deteriorate over the course of the campaign and into the endgame is a very satisfying feeling, even if it's an arbitrary number. It's a way to catalog your rank among other players and track your progress. Having this little way to measure your efforts encouraged me to do "just one more mission."</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/freedom-wars-remastered-dragon.jpg?itok=viEelOT3 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/freedom-wars-remastered-dragon.jpg?itok=35ppx2Ns 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>We got Rathalos at home.</figcaption></figure><p>This progress is also tracked via online leaderboards. It's a multiplayer game with other sinners, and each sinner belongs to a Panopticon. Think of a Panopticon as your home base. You choose this at the beginning of the game when you're customizing your character, and each Panopticon represents a prefecture of Japan.</p>

<p>I'm not sure if this will change once the public has hands on it, but the original version of <em>Freedom Wars</em> split Panopticons as cities around the globe. Though, as far as I know, the only choice now is Japan's prefectures, so I went with Hokkaido.</p>

<p>The leaderboard tallies your contribution both within the Panopticon and against other prefectures, so it's again, a very neat little measure to see how everyone's progressing and incentivizes some friendly competition.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/freedom-wars-remastered-anductor.jpg?itok=PnRJ97GW 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/freedom-wars-remastered-anductor.jpg?itok=3xdoBSgM 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Sometimes, guns are the best option!</figcaption></figure><h2>On the Hunt in<em> Freedom Wars Remastered</em></h2>

<p>It's in <em>Freedom Wars Remastered</em>'s combat that many players will find some sort of familiarity with. I don't like to draw comparisons to other games if I can help it, but it's hard to ignore the fact that<em> Freedom Wars Remastered</em> plays a great deal like <em>Monster Hunter</em>.</p>

<p>The whole routine of fighting giant monsters (Abductors), severing parts, upgrading your equipment from said parts, and going back into the fray is the general gameplay loop here. Though, on its own, <em>Freedom Wars Remastered</em> is a competent action game, even if it's a bit light on game mechanics.</p>

<p>There are several different weapon types to choose from, each with its own skillset, as well as firearms. You can equip yourself with two different weapons at once, so that gives room for some versatility. You're also given several AI companions if you're playing solo, as well as your own customizable Accessory -- this is a robot companion that helps you out.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/freedom-wars-remastered-combat-2.jpg?itok=4jYnJyuJ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/freedom-wars-remastered-combat-2.jpg?itok=1BcP709u 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Once they're on the ground, it's time to lay on the hurt.</figcaption></figure><p>To top it all off, you have a thorn, which makes <em>Freedom Wars Remastered</em>'s gameplay quite enjoyable. By shooting a thorn onto a wall or enemy, you can launch yourself to that location and pull off some cool air attacks. It's especially useful against Abductors so you can sever parts that are higher up.</p>

<p>Thorns are super fun to use, launching yourself around gargantuan foes like you're from <em>Attack on Titan</em>. It adds just a bit of extra oomph to the gameplay, though the rest of <em>Freedom Wars Remastered</em> could do with either new weapons, a few new attacks, or just something else to help it stand out.</p>

<p>Enemy variety, too, is just a bit repetitive. Most enemies come in the form of Abductors, and they increase in power as you progress through the campaign. The thing is, most of them follow the same template of being bipeds, quadrupeds, and the like, and they don't look or act all that different as time goes on.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/freedom-wars-remastered-story.jpg?itok=PPPqQDfj 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/freedom-wars-remastered-story.jpg?itok=zdJCpUkl 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Aries, one of the story's several key characters.</figcaption></figure><h2>A Story That Never Reaches Its Potential in <em>Freedom Wars Remastered</em></h2>

<p>My thoughts on <em>Freedom Wars Remastered</em>'s story are conflicted. On one hand, I really like its premise and setting, but on the other, the way the story is told is not all that great. The setting is, you're in this resource war, as presumably the world's resources are sparse in that day and age.</p>

<p>As such, Sinners are required to gather resources. Regular civilians are kidnapped by rival Panopticons' Abductors, and Sinners have to go save them. Meanwhile, there are various factions working within and outside of your Panopticon with different agendas and motives, most of which remain vague throughout the duration.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/freedom-wars-remastered-story-2.jpg?itok=KXrymuDK 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/freedom-wars-remastered-story-2.jpg?itok=Rsv1EFyt 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Most of the characters are likable enough.</figcaption></figure><p>In fact, <em>Freedom Wars Remastered</em> ends on an absurdly disappointing note. There are some post-game activities, but as I understand it, the story was supposed to continue in a sequel that never was. It leads to some mysteries that are never solved, which is a shame.</p>

<p><em>Freedom Wars Remastered</em> also presents its story in a sloppy way. The start of the game is front-loaded with a ton of dialogue, so it's super slow-going at first and really could do better with its pacing. On top of that, walking around your Panopticon to continue the story is pretty sluggish and doesn't make for exciting gameplay.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/freedom-wars-customization.jpg?itok=WuNewecB 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/freedom-wars-customization.jpg?itok=ybAIuWRi 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>You get to create and customize your own Sinner!</figcaption></figure><h2><em>Freedom Wars Remastered </em>Review | Final Thoughts</h2>

<p>There are <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U1OD00IBWxM" rel="nofollow">a few enhancements</a> that returning players will enjoy. Apparently, upgrading weapons has become a more seamless experience. They've added subtle improvements to combat overall, and even a new difficulty mode. These are additions that I initially took for granted, but when I learned about how <em>Freedom Wars Remastered</em> changed for the better, I was very appreciative of these tweaks.</p>

<p>Despite some problems with <em>Freedom Wars Remastered</em>'s story and the lack of depth in its gameplay, I still had a lot of fun with this title. Seeing your sentence diminish as time goes on is a gratifying feeling. Moreover, once it launches for players worldwide, I imagine the conflict amongst other Panopticons will lead to some exciting rivalries.</p>

<p>Who knows, <em>Freedom Wars Remastered</em> might even lead to the long-awaited sequel. I'd absolutely love to see <em>Freedom Wars Remastered</em>'s formula expanded upon. More depth in its gameplay and a more developed story in a sequel would make it a strong rival to <em>Monster Hunter</em>.</p>

<hr><p><strong><em>Freedom Wars Remastered</em></strong> <em>was reviewed over approximately 28 hours of gameplay on PS5 with a key provided by the publisher. All screenshots were taken during the review process.</em></p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ravenswatch Nightmares Unleashed Update Lands Later This Month]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ravenswatch-nightmares-unleashed-update-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ravenswatch-nightmares-unleashed-update-lands-later-this-month.1077033/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ravenswatch-nightmares-unleashed-update-release-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer Passtech Games and publisher Nacon have announced the release date for the upcoming <i>Ravenswatch&nbsp;</i>Nightmares Unleashed update, and it's landing in just a couple of weeks.</p>

<p>The update will represent the first major free content drop since the game's launch back in September, and it's officially coming to all platforms simultaneously on January 23rd, so you'll have to split your time <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dwarf-fortress-adventure-mode-release-date" rel="nofollow">between this and&nbsp;<em>Dwarf Fortress</em></a>.</p>

<p>New features you can look forward to in the Nightmares Unleashed update include improvements to the Key system, new minibosses to take down, and alternate Master Nightmare encounter patterns to keep you on your toes.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ravenswatch-nightmares-unleashed-update-new-minibosses.jpg?itok=r_pJW0nj 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ravenswatch-nightmares-unleashed-update-new-minibosses.jpg?itok=qLNNVWjj 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Ravenswatch</em>'s Nightmares Unleashed update lands very soon indeed.</figcaption></figure><p>Specifically, the two new minibosses you'll get to face are Abu Al Jaan, a Jinn ancestor who resides on Storm Island, and Melion, a servant knight "transformed into a werewolf by his mischievous wife".</p>

<p>New activities can also be found throughout&nbsp;<em>Ravenswatch</em>, including Blood Rituals, which allow you to get your hands on Keys by battling a new enemy and halting the ritual. Other new events include Locked Chests, for which you'll need Keys, and the Sacrificial Idol, which lets you give up health for damage.</p>

<p>New NPCs have also been added in the form of the Refugees, a small group of unfortunate souls who will ask for your help if they encounter you. Passtech says they either represent "a glimmer of hope in your journey, or a bad decision around the corner".</p>

<p>If you want to know everything that'll be added as part of&nbsp;<em>Ravenswatch</em>'s Nightmares Unleashed update, you can check out Passtech's rundown of the update's new features <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2071280/view/511819072878411875" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">right here</a>.</p>




<p>If you're unfamiliar with&nbsp;<em>Ravenswatch</em>, it's an action roguelike from the developers behind&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/curse-of-dead-gods" rel="nofollow"><em>Curse of the Dead Gods</em></a>. You and your friends play as "heroes of tales and legends", and you must band together to battle an encroaching nightmare that threatens to engulf your world.</p>

<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Ravenswatch&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2071280/Ravenswatch/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10005682" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/ravenswatch/9P4NX9RD7FRG" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/ravenswatch-switch/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Nintendo Switch</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dwarf Fortress Adventure Mode Lands Later This Month, Beta 28 Out Now]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dwarf-fortress-adventure-mode-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dwarf-fortress-adventure-mode-lands-later-this-month-beta-28-out-now.1076997/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dwarf-fortress-adventure-mode-release-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer Bay 12 Games and publisher Kitfox Games have announced that the&nbsp;<em>Dwarf Fortress&nbsp;</em>Adventure Mode will be launching out of beta later this month.</p>

<p>In an update on Steam, Bay 12's Tarn Adams and Kitfox's Alexandra Orlando reveal that Adventure Mode will arrive on January 23rd, having been available as part of <i>Dwarf Fortress</i>' beta branch <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/975370/view/4186734162819864096" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">since April</a> last year.</p>

<p>Just in case you're not aware of Adventure Mode, it's effectively a roguelike-style RPG gameplay mode in which you can explore the worlds you've generated as part of&nbsp;<em>Dwarf Fortress</em>' main colony management gameplay, taking on quests and discovering all manner of exciting things.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dwarf-fortress-adventure-mode-release-date-exploration.jpg?itok=yKUTx2CM 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dwarf-fortress-adventure-mode-release-date-exploration.jpg?itok=rEgyJLzA 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Adventure Mode officially lands in&nbsp;<em>Dwarf Fortress&nbsp;</em>on January 23rd.</figcaption></figure><p>Although Adams and Orlando say that focus will shift "back to Fortress Mode very soon", they also promise that Adventure Mode's full release is "not the end" of development for the feature.</p>

<p>Rather, there will be "many updates" for both Fortress Mode and Adventure Mode in future, and the two say there's "more to add" to the roguelike mode as well, so you'll be getting extra features in the months to come.</p>

<p>As well as the Adventure Mode release date announcement, a new&nbsp;<em>Dwarf Fortress&nbsp;</em>beta update has also arrived today. Beta 28 adds tons of new features including new graphics, changes to character creation, and tons of gameplay tweaks.</p>

<p>If you want to read the beta update's full patch notes, then you can <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/975370/view/530961267633946651" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">do so here via Steam</a>. It's well worth checking them out if you want to see some of the super-granular changes Kitfox and Bay 12 have made to the game's beta branch.</p>




<p>If you're somehow not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Dwarf Fortress</em>, it's a colony management sim in which you must oversee a colony of dwarves attempting to survive in a hostile procedurally-generated world.</p>

<p>The game is well-known for its emergent gameplay; the procedural generation and multiple interlocking systems of&nbsp;<em>Dwarf Fortress&nbsp;</em>often allow amusing things to happen, many of which will be unique to each player's playthrough.</p>

<p>The original&nbsp;<em>Dwarf Fortress&nbsp;</em>was released all the way back in 2006, but the version being updated today is <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dwarf-fortress-steam-release-date-unleashes-chaos" rel="nofollow">the 2022 paid version</a>, which updates the game's presentation and makes various other quality-of-life improvements.</p>

<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Dwarf Fortress&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/975370/Dwarf_Fortress/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC via Steam</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>