<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 14:58:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gallipoli Is Isonzo and Verdun Dev BlackMill's Next WWI-Era Shooter]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gallipoli-wwi-shooter-verdun-isonzo</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gallipoli-is-isonzo-and-verdun-dev-blackmills-next-wwi-era-shooter.1272795/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Verdun&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Isonzo&nbsp;</em>developer BlackMill Games has announced&nbsp;<em>Gallipoli</em>, the next game in its series of World War I-set shooters, and it's promising "the most authentic WWI FPS battles yet".</p>

<p>As the name suggests,&nbsp;<em>Gallipoli&nbsp;</em>will shift the focus from the traditional European battlefields featured in <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tannenberg-holding-historical-wolf-truce-event" rel="nofollow">previous games</a> in the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/verdun-christmas-truce-dlc-supports-charity" rel="nofollow">franchise</a> to those of the Middle Eastern front. That means you can expect a healthy dose of desert warfare alongside the usual "beach landings, historical classes, and realistic weaponry".</p>

<p>In a Steam <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/3065940/view/834973992999715448" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">news post</a>, BlackMill says&nbsp;<em>Gallipoli&nbsp;</em>will come complete with its very own "signature game mode", and while the studio doesn't want to give too much away about that mode right now, it'll all revolve around momentum.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/gallipoli-wwi-shooter-explosive.jpg?itok=KaAK5DS9 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/gallipoli-wwi-shooter-explosive.jpg?itok=owOReAWI 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Gallipoli&nbsp;</em>will continue its predecessors' focus on WWI-era realism.</figcaption></figure><p>The mode will support 50 players and will split them into two teams. If you're on the attacking team, you'll need to try and complete your objectives as fast as you can, but the defending side will be trying to scupper you as you do so.</p>

<p>It sounds as though momentum will be incorporated as a gameplay mechanic rather than just a vague sense of initiative; BlackMill is promising opportunities to regain lost momentum other than completing objectives.</p>

<p>You can also look forward to improved gameplay and visuals in&nbsp;<em>Gallipoli&nbsp;</em>compared to previous installments; the studio says it's "gone to great lengths to faithfully recreate" Middle Eastern front weaponry, which it says was "usually quite obsolete, weird, or both".</p>

<p>BlackMill is also promising "major improvements to progression, loadouts, cosmetics, and the health system", but you'll have to wait for future updates in order to learn specifics about how all of those things are being improved.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/gallipoli-wwi-shooter-crouching.jpg?itok=QHbOtTL- 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/gallipoli-wwi-shooter-crouching.jpg?itok=LD4xPdxg 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>You can expect plenty of improvements in&nbsp;<em>Gallipoli</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>We don't have a release date for&nbsp;<em>Gallipoli&nbsp;</em>yet, but when it lands, you can expect to play it on PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X|S. Stay tuned for more on this one.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gallipoli-wwi-shooter-verdun-isonzo]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[StarRupture Early Access Release Date Revealed for January]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/starrupture-early-access-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/starrupture-early-access-release-date-revealed-for-january.1272792/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer and publisher Creepy Jar has announced the Early Access release date for its open-world survival-crafter&nbsp;<em>StarRupture</em>, and it's set to launch on PC early next year.</p>

<p>As revealed in a Steam <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1631270/view/597409112655921163" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">news post</a>,&nbsp;<em>StarRupture&nbsp;</em>will be coming to Steam Early Access on January 6th. Creepy Jar says it knows "you will need to wait a little bit longer than you originally anticipated" for the game's launch, but that the delay will mean "more polish [and] more improvements".</p>

<p>If you're unfamiliar with&nbsp;<em>StarRupture</em>, it's an open-world survival-crafter game with base-building elements that was first revealed as part of the PC Gaming Show <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/green-hell-dev-starrupture" rel="nofollow">all the way back in 2023</a>. The name is a reference to the star at the heart of the game's solar system, which creates "extreme living conditions" for those residing on the planet nearby.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/starrupture-early-access-release-date-horde.jpg?itok=Aaxun9oo 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/starrupture-early-access-release-date-horde.jpg?itok=h8uBugG8 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>StarRupture&nbsp;</em>is finally coming to Early Access next year.</figcaption></figure><p>Creepy Jar describes its game as a "first-person open world base-building game with advanced combat and tons of exploration" in which you can either play on your own or as part of a group.</p>

<p>You'll explore an "ever-changing open world" in which you'll have to construct a "complex industrial system" in order to "extract resources, produce goods and expand your base", in a similar fashion to titles like&nbsp;<em>Factorio&nbsp;</em>or&nbsp;<em>Satisfactory</em><em>.</em></p>

<p>Once the base is built, you'll also have to make sure you're defending it from the "hordes of alien monsters" that will lay siege to it, as well as the constantly-changing conditions of the planet on which you find yourself.</p>

<p>You can check out the Early Access release date trailer for&nbsp;<em>StarRupture</em>, which also gives a pretty good sense of what you can expect from Creepy Jar's game, right here.</p>




<p><em>StarRupture&nbsp;</em>is set to land on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1631270/StarRupture/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC via Steam Early Access</a> on January 6th. You can read our very own Ashley's preview of the spacefaring base-builder <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/starrupture-preview" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">right here</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/starrupture-early-access-release-date]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shenmue III Enhanced Wants to Be the Definitive Shenmue III Experience]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/shenmue-iii-enhanced-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shenmue-iii-enhanced-wants-to-be-the-definitive-shenmue-iii-experience.1272726/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Shenmue&nbsp;</em>auteur Yu Suzuki and his studio Ys Net have announced&nbsp;<em>Shenmue III Enhanced</em>, a...well...enhanced re-release of&nbsp;<em>Shenmue III&nbsp;</em>that brings visual and gameplay improvements aplenty.</p>

<p>As spotted by <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/shenmue-iii-enhanced-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-nintendo-and-pc" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Gematsu</a>,&nbsp;<em>Shenmue III Enhanced&nbsp;</em>is slated for release on PC, PS5, Xbox Series X|S, and "Nintendo" at some point in the future. No release date was revealed, and it's not specified whether "Nintendo" refers to both Switch 2 and the original Switch or just one of the two.</p>

<p>In any case,&nbsp;<em>Shenmue III Enhanced&nbsp;</em>will bring improved visuals and performance, complete with 4K textures, support for DLSS and FSR on PC, and increased NPC density to help Niaowu feel "more alive with more characters populating the streets".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/shenmue-iii-enhanced-edition-landscape.jpg?itok=UUdDARBq 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/shenmue-iii-enhanced-edition-landscape.jpg?itok=g0Xn-Hev 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Shenmue III&nbsp;</em>is getting a re-release in future, and it'll bring improvements galore.</figcaption></figure><p>It's not just the visuals getting some love, though. Ys Net is also promising gameplay tweaks, including a new "classic" camera mode that brings&nbsp;<em>Shenmue III</em>'s gameplay perspective closer to that of its predecessors.</p>

<p>You can also look forward to stamina system adjustments, Ryo's health being restored before fights, and "reduced money barriers for smoother progression", as well as the opportunity to skip certain cutscenes and conversations.</p>

<p>All of the gameplay improvements promised by&nbsp;<em>Shenmue III&nbsp;</em>can be switched off if you want the original gameplay experience, though, so if you just want to enjoy the game with its new and improved visuals, you can do that as well.</p>

<p>If you missed out on&nbsp;<em>Shenmue III&nbsp;</em>the first time, it's the long-awaited sequel to 2001's&nbsp;<em>Shenmue II</em>. Launching <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/shenmue-iii-release-date-delayed-three-months-to-november" rel="nofollow">eighteen years after that game</a>, it continues the story of protagonist Ryo Hazuki, who's on the hunt for his father's murderer.</p>




<p>Many of&nbsp;<em>Shenmue III Enhanced</em>'s additions have seemingly been introduced to combat much of the criticism of the original game, including its slow pace, gated money grinds, and frustrating combat.</p>

<p>If you want to check out&nbsp;<em>Shenmue III&nbsp;</em>before the enhanced version launches, you can do so right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/878670/Shenmue_III/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>&nbsp;and <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP2047-CUSA12289_00-SHENMUEIII0000US" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 4</a>. You can remind yourself of what we thought of the game <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/shenmue-3-review" rel="nofollow">right here</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/shenmue-iii-enhanced-announced]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>