<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 14:32:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Doloc Town Is a Pixel Art Farming Sim With a Platforming Twist]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/doloc-town-farming-sim-bullet-hell</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/doloc-town-is-a-pixel-art-farming-sim-with-a-platforming-twist.1021971/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/doloc-town-farming-sim-bullet-hell<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer RedSaw Games and publisher Logoi have announced&nbsp;<em>Doloc Town</em>, a cozy pixel art farming sim with a spicy bullet hell and platforming twist, and you can check it out on Steam now.</p>

<p>In a press release, RedSaw and Logoi say&nbsp;<em>Doloc Town&nbsp;</em>takes place "amidst the remnants of civilization", not unlike Pathea's&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/my-time-at-evershine-skipping-early-access"><em>My Time&nbsp;</em>series</a>, although it's fair to say&nbsp;<em>Doloc Town&nbsp;</em>is decidedly less idyllic than those games are.</p>

<p>You'll get the chance to build up "automated production systems" on a farm where you can cultivate crops and build facilities, all while you're contending with post-apocalyptic weather conditions like acid rain.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/doloc-town-farming-sim-platformer-rainy-forest.jpg?itok=EwApMZJ4 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/doloc-town-farming-sim-platformer-rainy-forest.jpg?itok=5f92FLkN 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Doloc Town&nbsp;</em>looks to be a moody yet cozy post-apocalyptic farming sim.</figcaption></figure><p>If you're wondering what makes&nbsp;<em>Doloc Town&nbsp;</em>stand out amongst a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/fields-of-mistria-roadmap">bevy</a> of <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tales-of-shire-release-date">other</a> cozy <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/my-time-at-sandrock">farming sims</a> on the market right now (or about to be on the market, anyway), the answer could well lie in the game's combat systems.</p>

<p>Rather uniquely,&nbsp;<em>Doloc Town</em>'s combat takes influence from platformers and bullet hell shooters. RedSaw says you'll be able to use "guns and...auxiliary combat drones" to help you battle "dangerous creatures".</p>

<p>Don't worry if you're not much of a bullet hell fiend, though; RedSaw says that the game's customization will allow "flexible combat styles", so you shouldn't need to fret about not having perfect reflexes.</p>

<p>You can check out the debut announcement trailer for&nbsp;<em>Doloc Town</em>, which also gives a sense of the game's&nbsp;very&nbsp;<em>Cave Story</em>-esque pixel art aesthetic, right here.</p>




<p>If your interest has been piqued by&nbsp;<em>Doloc Town&nbsp;</em>and you'd like to check it out, then you're in luck; a demo of the game is available right now via Steam, so you can give it a go and see whether it's for you or not.</p>

<p><em>Doloc Town&nbsp;</em>doesn't have a release date yet, but when it does land, it'll arrive <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2285550/Doloc_Town/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="noopener" target="_blank">on PC via Steam</a>. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ex-Bloodborne and Final Fantasy 16 Designer Opens New Studio Velux]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ex-bloodborne-and-final-fantasy-16-designer-velux</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ex-bloodborne-and-final-fantasy-16-designer-opens-new-studio-velux.1021911/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ex-bloodborne-and-final-fantasy-16-designer-velux<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A designer who worked on&nbsp;FromSoftware's&nbsp;<em>Bloodborne&nbsp;</em>and Square Enix's&nbsp;<em>Final Fantasy 16&nbsp;</em>has opened up his own studio by the name of Velux.</p>

<p>Per <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/former-fromsoftware-and-square-enix-game-designer-establishes-new-game-company-to-make-games-for-game-lovers/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Automaton Media</a> (which, in turn, cites a Japanese <a href="https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000001.000151924.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank">press release</a>), designer Sho Igarashi will serve as the newly-created Velux Studio's CEO. He's worked not only with FromSoftware and Square Enix, but also with&nbsp;<em>Granblue&nbsp;</em>studio Cygames and&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/forspoken">Forspoken</a>&nbsp;</em>developer Luminous Productions.</p>

<p>According to Automaton's translation of the press release, Igarashi's "expertise lies in battle production" (that's Automaton's wording, not the press release's), although it's not clear whether he definitely worked on combat design for the aforementioned games.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/bloodborne-velux-studio-sho-igarashi.jpg?itok=ReVpqYIb 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/bloodborne-velux-studio-sho-igarashi.jpg?itok=FeE0XH2q 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Sho Igarashi's credits include&nbsp;<em>Bloodborne</em>,&nbsp;<em>Final Fantasy 16</em>, and more.</figcaption></figure><p>We don't know much about Velux Studio, except that per Automaton, the company will be making games across PC, consoles, and mobile devices, and it'll include both "high-end" and "casual" titles in its remit (again, that's Automaton's wording).</p>

<p>The goal here is to "make games for game lovers", or so the press release says, and the studio will be working with Unreal Engine 5 in-house, so it sounds like nothing will be outsourced.</p>

<p>Right now, we don't know exactly what Velux is working on, although if a couple of preview images released on the studio's new <a href="https://velux-studio.co.jp/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">official website</a> are anything to go by, it looks like the debut game will have a sci-fi flavor to it.</p>

<p>Velux also has an <a href="https://x.com/VELUX_STUDIO" rel="noopener" target="_blank">X (formerly Twitter) account</a>, although naturally, since the studio is new, there isn't much on there yet. Still, you know who to follow if you want up-to-the-minute news about this new company.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/velux-studio-unreal-engine-5-project.jpg?itok=9NnXjUh- 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/velux-studio-unreal-engine-5-project.jpg?itok=_WYjiVYZ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Velux Studio is currently hard at work on...whatever this is.</figcaption></figure><p>Igarashi is far from the only decorated designer to be starting up his own studio. In recent years, we've seen studios started up by <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ex-disco-elysium-devs-new-studios-spiritual-successors">several ex-<em>Disco Elysium&nbsp;</em>developers</a>, as well as staffers from big companies like&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ex-bethesda-bioware-naughty-dog-near-studios-hawthorn">Bethesda</a>, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ex-ea-staffers-three-thousands-studio">EA</a>, and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ex-capcom-staffers-birdkin-hideaki-saori-utsumi">Capcom</a>, among others.</p>

<p>It remains to be seen what Velux Studio will reveal as its debut title, but let's hope we find out sooner rather than later. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Koei Tecmo to Release "Several Unannounced Titles" Before April 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/koei-tecmo-unannounced-games-fy-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/koei-tecmo-to-release-several-unannounced-titles-before-april-2025.1021860/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/koei-tecmo-unannounced-games-fy-2024<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Dynasty Warriors&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Rise of the Ronin&nbsp;</em>studio Koei Tecmo has revealed that it has several unannounced projects set to release before the end of the fiscal year in March.</p>

<p>According to the company's latest financial presentation, "several unannounced titles (up to mid-tier)" are set to launch before the beginning of April 2025, although of course, Koei Tecmo doesn't reveal exactly what they are.</p>

<p>That's in addition to the games already in the pipeline for Koei Tecmo, which include the upcoming&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/romance-of-three-kingdoms-8-remake-release-date"><em>Romance of the Three Kingdoms 8&nbsp;</em>remake</a>,&nbsp;<em>Dynasty Warriors: Origins</em>, and two&nbsp;different&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/atelier-resleriana-red-alchemist-and-white-guardian"><em>Atelier&nbsp;</em>RPGs</a>, as well as manga and anime adaptation&nbsp;<em>Fairy Tail 2</em>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dynasty-warriors-origins-koei-tecmo.jpg?itok=5fhKKIZm 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dynasty-warriors-origins-koei-tecmo.jpg?itok=C7LF7FQP 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Koei Tecmo's upcoming slate includes&nbsp;<em>Dynasty Warriors: Origins</em>, plus several unannounced games.</figcaption></figure><p>News of Koei Tecmo's unannounced projects comes alongside a look at the company's financial performance for the first half of 2024, and sales are down by 11.4% compared to the previous year, although Koei Tecmo says this is because the PC and console areas of the business were "focused on back catalog".</p>

<p>Similarly, Koei Tecmo's financials are lower than the company initially forecasted for this first half of the year, thanks to a "decrease in sales from console/PC and online/mobile".</p>

<p>However, it's noteworthy that unlike major Western studios (the likes of <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/bungie-layoffs-200-employees">Bungie</a> and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/microsoft-gaming-layoffs-september">Microsoft</a> spring to mind), Koei Tecmo hasn't laid any employees off this year; rather, its headcount has actually increased since the first half of last year.</p>

<p>It's true that Koei Tecmo hasn't increased its salaries across the board like <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/fromsoftware-raises-base-salaries">some</a> of its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/konami-salary-increase">compatriots</a>, but it's still nice to see a company responding to slightly lower sales not by firing employees by the hundreds, but by standing firm.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/koei-tecmo-atelier-yumia.jpg?itok=daFw0PA2 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/koei-tecmo-atelier-yumia.jpg?itok=HcuNlrTJ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Two new&nbsp;<em>Atelier&nbsp;</em>games are also in the works at Koei Tecmo.</figcaption></figure><p>Impressively, Koei Tecmo says it plans to maintain its current pace with regards to hiring new employees. The studio says it's on target to hire 200 new employees across the 2024-25 fiscal year, with a focus mainly on new graduates.</p>

<p>Other initiatives in place for Koei Tecmo's future include improving its internal tech, utilizing AI, and expanding its global publishing structure in the long-term. You can check out the <a href="https://www.koeitecmo.co.jp/e/ir/docs/ir3_20241028_e.pdf" rel="noopener" target="_blank">full financial results presentation here</a> if you want to get stuck into the stats.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arkham Horror The Roleplaying Game Core Rulebook Review - This Is Halloween!]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/arkham-horror-roleplaying-game-core-rulebook-review-this-is-halloween</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arkham-horror-the-roleplaying-game-core-rulebook-review-this-is-halloween.1021809/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/arkham-horror-roleplaying-game-core-rulebook-review-this-is-halloween<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>It was only three months ago that I was praising Arkham Horror: The Roleplaying Game Hungering Abyss for its ability to teach the game, supply players with everything they'd need for a multiple-hour experience, and create an entertaining and tense spooky experience. The one major downside I had was how it really was only suited for that one experience, now with the release of the Arkham Horror: The Roleplaying Game Core Rulebook in under a month we know what it will be like to create a story from scratch.</p>

<h2>Intuitive Layout</h2>

<p>Before I get into the contents of the book itself I need to highlight how incredibly well formatted the Core Rulebook is. From the moment I opened the book I could tell the time and effort that had gone into the layout. Starting with what Arkham Horror is, information about the setting of the game, and a very clear section disowning Lovecraft's beliefs, you launch into relevant information for the player.</p>

<p>You'll learn about the city of Arkham, where players might base their character, but also learn about how the game doesn't need to be restricted to Massachusetts. Examples of mysteries in Cairo or Europe, or even beyond the veil immediately start prodding at the mind of DM and player alike.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/arkham-horror-rpg-core-rulebook-the-world.jpg?itok=soqQ6YNz 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/arkham-horror-rpg-core-rulebook-the-world.jpg?itok=fkjBAbUI 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>From there you get all the required information on the rules of the game, neatly together for easy referencing, character creation, and information for DMs.</p>

<p>If you plan to keep the book on hand while playing it should be a breeze to locate what information you're after in a pinch. On top of that, inside the cover is a code from Drivethrurpg for a PDF of the Rulebook.</p>

<h2>Rules Glossary</h2>

<p>The first major section you'll reach is the Rules Glossary. This will cover how the Dynamic Pool system works, the different types of scenes that you'll encounter and how to take actions and consequences.</p>

<p>The approach to this is bite-sized information that can continue to be built upon starting with that important Dynamic Pool. In Arkham Horror: The Roleplaying Game the Dynamic Pool is every, it will determine how much you can do as you investigate a location to how you can move and act in combat.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/arkham-horror-rpg-core-rulebook-arkham-map.jpg?itok=wrHusmwq 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/arkham-horror-rpg-core-rulebook-arkham-map.jpg?itok=G9BRvTnL 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Players have a dice pool of six dice. As they take damage they can end up with fewer dice, hence fewer actions to make, or if they experience horrors those dice can turn against you inflicting horrors if they land with a certain face.</p>

<p>Going into the Core Rulebook with an understanding of the dice pool and how it functions after my time with Hungering Abyss the system made sense. For a player coming into this system new I do think it's a bit tough to understand initially. Like with a lot of TTRPGs there's a lot that you can read but doing the thing will normally help you understand much faster.</p>

<p>It's in this way that the introduction to the Dynamic Pool, scenes, and actions is actually better got across by Hungering Abyss in the way that the game only introduces concepts to you as they become relevant.</p>

<p>From there the bite-sized information continues and is effective in creating a glossary that is easy to reference and quick to check with clearly labeled sections and sub-sections alongside well-laid-out descriptions and even some examples for the harder-to-understand concepts.</p>

<h2>Bringing a character to life in the world of Arkham Horror</h2>

<p>There's a funny line at the beginning of the character creation that I believe sets up the world you're about to step into with Arkham Horror: The Roleplaying Game.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>"Most of the people in Arkham, Massachusetts and around the globe spend their time dealing with the simple routines of their daily lives. [...] Your characters aren't so lucky"</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Players will take on the roles of those unfortunate enough to find themselves tied to a dark and mysterious fate. These characters, dubbed investigators, might have been raised in this world or is about to get pulled from their comfy life but there's no turning back.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/arkham-horror-rpg-core-rulebook-hunter-class.jpg?itok=Rz4XUiD7 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/arkham-horror-rpg-core-rulebook-hunter-class.jpg?itok=8Jp0DkOh 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>A character is made up of a few key components; Background, Personality Trait, Archetype, Skills, and their starting equipment and advancements. In the back of the book is a blank character sheet that you can use to fill out as you go through the process of building your character up.</p>

<p>Interestingly this character sheet wasn't mentioned at the start of the character creation process, or in the table of contents.</p>

<p>A lot of these aspects aren't hard rules but instead prompts, for discovering your characters backgrounds you'll get prompted with questions like "What is your family like?" and "How does your character make a Living?" etc…</p>

<p>These questions then get paired with what differences there might be between a Poor upbringing and that of a Prosperous lifestyle.</p>

<p>Personality and Archetype are more set in the rules. There are eleven Personalities and eight Archetypes. You can mix and match these to finetune your character and allow for differences among characters to develop immediately.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/arkham-horror-rpg-core-rulebook-character-class.jpg?itok=E3B9_BH5 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/arkham-horror-rpg-core-rulebook-character-class.jpg?itok=7L8i2HWA 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2>Diversify The Party</h2>

<p>As a 'Outgoing' Personality you might have the chance to perform an action with your Presence stat, but it could also negatively impact you causing Disadvantage against rolls with allies. This could be combined with a Guardian archetype to create a mayoral character who is good at communicating with their peers.</p>

<p>That same Outgoing Personality could create a vastly different character if applied to a Seeker like a private detective, or a Mystic who is able to manifest supernatural abilities.</p>

<p>Characters will progress by earning experience in sequences. This experience isn't something to fill up a meter for, but instead, it can be spent on gaining abilities. It's not as much "leveling up" but skill points to be spent on a tree.</p>

<p>A major benefit of this is that players will be able to tweak a lot more, and faster. It's not a matter of multiple sessions before you can make skill checks easier or pick up a new ability, you might be able to pick something small up at the end of an encounter or save up for something bigger.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/arkham-horror-rpg-core-rulebook-stat-block.jpg?itok=gD4jdwuH 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/arkham-horror-rpg-core-rulebook-stat-block.jpg?itok=zIvhswi- 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2>Strapped Up</h2>

<p>The list of interesting equipment, mundane or otherwise, is like stepping into a candy store. Players will be able to obtain different armors, melee and ranged weaponry, single-use items, and even ancient tomes filled with spells.</p>

<p>Each section is filled with relevant information like gameplay mechanics, prices, and more again assisting the DM in creating a very seamless experience.</p>

<p>Mechanically I was extremely interested in the Tomes section. Unlike a Wizards book that could hold any spell the Tomes here are very specific with what information they contain, the checks that a character would need to complete to have read and understood them, and what spells can be cast with them.</p>

<p>These are definitely the rarest of the rare items for your party to come across but who wouldn't like to happen across the De Vermis Mysteriis, allowing you to enchant weapons or armor, or get your hands on the Necronomicon?</p>

<h2>The Role of the GM and Worldbuilding</h2>

<p>Moving further away from the information that the players need to know we reach the chapters with information for the Game Master. Here we have detailed information about Arkham, including the different regions of the town, important locations within them, and even a visitor-style map.</p>

<p>The section on running the game provides a variety of helpful tips and information including how to create a story, how to run the different scenes, and additional information on the tones and themes of the game.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/arkham-horror-rpg-core-rulebook-included-adventure-character.jpg?itok=A6K7F45x 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/arkham-horror-rpg-core-rulebook-included-adventure-character.jpg?itok=fdl5qQre 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>For a horror game I'm extremely glad to see a section on safety rules. Not just the guidelines on how to creat lines and veils, known as Pillars and Borders in Arkham Horror, but also to omit all Xenophobia and Marginalization.</p>

<h2>What Lurks Beyond The Veil</h2>

<p>Two of the final chapters are dedicated to the different Allies and NPCs you'll be able to inject into your games, including stat blocks for all monsters. For your world building the chapter, The Ancient Ones, is your one-stop shop to understand the kinds of eldritch creatures that Lovecraft came up with.</p>

<p>Here you'll find multi-paged dossier entries on some of the big and small players of the Mythos including Cthulhu, Nyarlathotep, Crothhoaka, and more. Each section does an impressive job of distilling all of the information surrounding these creatures into well-formatted sections. Reading each you'll understand what they are and where their domain is, what effect they have, what their lair is like, and what kinds of allies or factions may be supporting them.</p>

<p>What I really appreciate about the introduction of what are meant to be all-powerful Old Ones is that while there's a lot of context and understanding there isn't anything mechanical to them. Sure the Star Spawn might have a reference to their power from Cthulhu but no player character would truly be able to face an Old One. Their presence helps to inform the actions of cults and other factions, instead of being the Big Bad themselves.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/arkham-horror-rpg-core-rulebook-old-ones.jpg?itok=6NIHXB6J 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/arkham-horror-rpg-core-rulebook-old-ones.jpg?itok=vySbj8zP 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2>Time To Play</h2>

<p>Finally, the last section of the book holds with it an adventure to play. While I do still believe for new players the Hungering Abyss starter set is going to be your best 'first experience' playing, if you've already completed that and are ready for a new challenge then it's excellent to have this Core Rulebook be a one-stop-shop to your first time playing the game too.</p>



<p>I was incredibly impressed reading through the Arkham Horror Rulebook. The content of it all was extremely easy to understand and efficient, teaching you to the game quickly but also makes referencing rules while playing extremely efficient.</p>

<p>While the character sheet is tucked away the options will provide players a wide variety of options to take through their spooky adventure, and the DM is more than adequately equipped to channel a creepy vibe from beyond the veil.</p>

<p>If you're an absolutely new group to playing I would still recommend the starter set, as it comes with so many tokens, handouts, and a 'learn as you go' style rulebook but if you're a fan and you're ready to dive into your own adventures then this is an excellent Rulebook to do so.</p>

<hr><p><em>The copy of the</em>&nbsp;<strong>Arkham Horror: The Roleplaying Game Core Rulebook</strong>&nbsp;<em>used to produce this review was provided by the publisher.</em></p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>