<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 17:00:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Terminator: Survivors Delayed Indefinitely, Multiplayer Canceled]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/terminator-survivors-delayed-multiplayer-canceled</link>
            <guid>1386133</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer and publisher Nacon has revealed that post-apocalyptic survival game <em>Terminator: Survivors </em>has been delayed beyond its initial 2025 release window, and that a key feature has been canceled as well.</p><p>In a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2617340/view/624439505179377725" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">news post</a> on Steam, Nacon says <em>Terminator: Survivors</em>, which was originally due to launch in Early Access sometime this year (having <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/terminator-survivors-early-access-release" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="59cf7b33-22f3-452a-868e-dc0d1af2d92f" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">already been delayed once</a>), "won't be launching in 2025", and that the studio doesn't have a new release date "locked in" yet either.</p><p>However, there is a small (potential) silver lining to this news; Nacon says that it's adjusting its release plans because it no longer wants to launch <em>Terminator: Survivors </em>in Early Access, so when the game does arrive, it'll be a "complete and polished experience", per the studio.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption><em>Terminator: Survivors </em>isn't coming out in 2025, unfortunately.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Additionally, Nacon says it's canning the co-op multiplayer aspect of <em>Terminator: Survivors</em>, having come to the conclusion that a single-player title would be better for delivering an "authentic <em>Terminator </em>experience".</p><p>Nacon says that although <em>Terminator: Survivors </em>won't be launching in 2025, the studio will be holding a number of closed playtests under a non-disclosure agreement (NDA) "as the launch window gets closer". If you want to sign up for those tests, you can <a href="https://my.nacongaming.com/en-GB/playtests" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">do so here</a>.</p><p>If you're unfamiliar with <em>Terminator: Survivors</em>, it is, as the name suggests, a survival game based on the <em>Terminator </em>series of movies (and ancillary media, of course).</p><p>Originally <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/terminator-survivors-and-more-unveiled-at-nacon-connect" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="dc6ce4d7-d291-4d5c-8751-0809354ad4e9" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">revealed last year</a>, <em>Terminator: Survivors </em>takes place four years after Judgment Day, the event that devastated humanity and saw the machines rising up to rule the world. You'll need to battle Skynet's prototypes and help the Resistance claim a new future for mankind.</p>
<p>We no longer know exactly when to expect <em>Terminator: Survivors</em>, but if you want to keep up with Nacon's progress on the game, then you can <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2617340/Terminator_Survivors/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">wishlist it on PC via Steam right here</a>.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/terminator-survivors-delayed-multiplayer-canceled]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[November US Sales Data Shows Call of Duty Still Riding High]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/circana-november-2025-call-of-duty</link>
            <guid>1386127</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Reports of <em>Call of Duty</em>'s demise are greatly exaggerated, at least if Circana's latest US gaming sales data roundup is to be believed; the latest game in the long-running shooter series still reigns supreme.</p><p>According to the firm's <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3ma6t4njxoc2w" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">ever-reliable Mat Piscatella</a>, <em>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 </em>still managed to top the all-format premium sales chart for November, beating out rivals like <em>Battlefield 6</em>, <em>Pokemon Legends: Z-A</em>, and <em>Ghost of Yotei </em>(all of which, admittedly, originally <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/battlefield-6-october-best-selling-circana" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="15da8cce-653d-4fe6-aa54-3cae8b3a0758" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">launched in October</a>).</p><p><em>Battlefield 6 </em>is in second place for the month, with annual sports releases <em>NBA 2K26</em>, <em>Madden NFL 26</em>, and <em>EA Sports FC 26 </em>taking up third, fourth, and fifth place respectively. <em>Pokemon </em>and <em>Ghost of Yotei </em>are in sixth and seventh before another sports game, <em>EA Sports College Football 26</em>, snags eighth.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption><em>EA Sports College Football 26 </em>is one of November's best-selling games in the US.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Rounding out the top ten for the month are <em>Minecraft</em>, which can always be seen pretty close to the top few places in the chart, and <em>Kirby Air Riders</em>.</p><p>Despite <em>Black Ops 7</em>'s strong performance in November's chart, it hasn't managed to topple <em>Battlefield 6 </em>in the <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3ma6t4pndwc2w" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">year-to-date</a> stakes; in fact, it's currently sitting at a rather measly seventh on that chart, having been beaten out by the likes of <em>Monster Hunter Wilds </em>and <em>NBA 2K26</em>.</p><p>It's worth saying that <em>Black Ops 7 </em>is at something of a disadvantage here given that all of its rivals have had several months to rack up sales, but given that <em>Call of Duty </em>is usually a sales behemoth, this probably won't be particularly encouraging for Activision.</p><p>Indeed, the publisher recently revealed that back-to-back yearly releases of <em>Modern Warfare </em>and <em>Black Ops </em>games <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/call-of-duty-black-ops-modern-warfare-activision" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="1b6f0e4f-b66c-47da-8092-f3d497caf8fe" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">will end</a>, presumably paving the way for another sub-series to break up the repetition a little.</p>
<p>It's well worth taking a look at Piscatella's <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3ma6t4juhvs2w" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">full thread</a> for some more nerdy statistical breakdowns of how the gaming industry did sales-wise in November. Stay tuned for December's figures!</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/circana-november-2025-call-of-duty]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dispatch Apparently Coming to Switch 2 and Switch in January]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dispatch-switch-2-switch-eshop-listing</link>
            <guid>1386124</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A listing for adventure game-slash-management sim <em>Dispatch </em>has been spotted on the Nintendo eShop, suggesting that the game may be coming to both Switch 2 and Switch next month.</p><p>As spotted by <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/dispatch-coming-to-switch-2-switch-on-january-29-2026" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">Gematsu</a>, an Australian eShop <a href="https://ec.nintendo.com/AU/en/titles/70010000105332" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">listing</a> for <em>Dispatch </em>appears to point to a release date of January 29th for the game on both of Nintendo's consoles. It'll have an install size of 13.6GB on both machines and will also offer a free Switch 2 upgrade path for original Switch owners.</p><p>It is, of course, possible that the January 29th date is a placeholder, but it's an oddly specific one if so, given that the date in question is only just over a month away. I'd say it's a safe bet AdHoc Studio's game will be arriving on Switch 2 and Switch soon.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption><em>Dispatch </em>is probably making its way to Switch 2 and Switch soon.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>If you're not familiar with <em>Dispatch</em>, it's an adventure game created by AdHoc Studio, a developer that boasts <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ex-telltale-employees-go-on-to-form-adhoc-studio" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="ebf6f25a-7f8d-4c5f-bcf6-4525c284b84e" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">several ex-Telltale staffers</a> among its ranks.</p><p>As you might expect from folks who worked on Telltale's games, <em>Dispatch </em>is primarily an episodic choice-based adventure in which you'll make a series of decisions that will impact the game's narrative as it progresses.</p><p>However, the game also features a management element in which you must serve as a dispatcher, sending heroes to tackle crimes across the city. The decisions you make during the narrative segments may also end up impacting what you can do while you're dispatching.</p><p>Released earlier this year, <em>Dispatch </em>managed to cross a million sales <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dispatch-sales-1m-10-days" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="fdb19357-4765-4684-bf2c-7f64112fcdbd" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">in just ten days</a>, going on to pass the two million mark <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dispatch-sales-2m" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">less than two weeks later</a>. It's safe to say there's a voracious appetite for this one.</p>
<p><em>Dispatch </em>is available right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2592160/Dispatch/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">PC</a> and <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/dispatch/" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">PlayStation 5</a>, and if this report is correct, then it's due to launch on Switch 2 and Switch in January as well. Stay tuned for more.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dispatch-switch-2-switch-eshop-listing]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Forza Motorsport Updates to End as Focus Shifts to Forza Horizon 6]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/forza-motorsport-updates-ending</link>
            <guid>1386118</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer Turn 10 Studios has announced that regular <em>Forza Motorsport </em>updates will end as the team's focus shifts towards the upcoming <em>Forza Horizon 6</em>.</p><p>In a <a href="https://forza.net/news/forza-year-in-review-2025#fm" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">blog post</a> on the official <em>Forza </em>website, Turn 10 says that as it prepares for the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/forza-horizon-6-revealed-ps5" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="7ede297d-3bdf-4de5-b00a-3479b4a33aab" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">new installment in the simcade racing sub-series</a>, which is due to land next year, it does not "plan to introduce new cars, tracks, features, or regular bug fixes for <em>Forza Motorsport</em>" anymore.</p><p>Despite this, the servers for <em>Forza Motorsport </em>will remain active, and Turn 10 will continue to host "special events and competitions" within the game, as well as "reintroducing previously released Featured Tours and reward cars on a monthly basis". If you're hoping for anything more substantial than that, though, you're out of luck.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption><em>Forza Motorsport </em>isn't getting any more big updates.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>While <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/forza-horizon-4" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="af018315-c510-4f32-b4cf-4d2ff92152f1" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">previous games</a> in the <em>Forza Horizon </em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/forza-horizon-5" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="e06c8c57-82df-4c87-8f75-29496a5cf5fd" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">series</a> have been developed by Playground Games, <em>Forza Horizon 6 </em>will be a co-production between that studio and Turn 10, which is presumably why the latter can't give any more attention to <em>Forza Motorsport</em>.</p><p>If you need a reminder, the latest <em>Forza Motorsport </em>game, which simply bears the name of its series and no accompanying number, was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/new-forza-motorsport-announced" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="3c361157-11a9-43bf-8118-dd83a79d4a5d" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">first revealed back in 2020</a>.</p><p>Unlike <em>Forza Horizon</em>, the <em>Motorsport </em>series (from which <em>Horizon </em>is a spinoff) emphasizes elements like customization and realism; it places a much heavier emphasis on the "simulation" part of the series' equation.</p><p>The latest game was released in 2023 to a generally positive reception, although our own reviewer Blair was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/forza-motorsport-review-heavy-metal-mercy" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="b9ebd97c-f17b-4342-8d00-b0440ff15730" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">decidedly more lukewarm towards it</a>, criticizing its lack of aesthetic sensibilities and its "uninvolving" and "uncreative" gameplay.</p>
<p>As part of a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/latest-microsoft-layoff-wave-king-zenimax" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="56028754-47c9-4b65-ac22-8847d892a2d8" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">sweeping wave of layoffs at Microsoft</a> earlier this year, a number of Turn 10 Studios employees were reportedly let go, so it's also possible that the developer simply doesn't have the staff count to support <em>Forza Motorsport </em>anymore.</p><p>At any rate, although updates will no longer be released for <em>Forza Motorsport</em>, you can grab the game right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2440510/Forza_Motorsport/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">PC</a> and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/forza-motorsport/9P0TRPTHG7VF" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">Xbox Series X|S</a> if you'd like.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/forza-motorsport-updates-ending]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>