<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 14:54:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Take-Two Sells Indie Label Private Division to Undisclosed Buyer]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/take-two-private-division-sale</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/take-two-sells-indie-label-private-division-to-undisclosed-buyer.1029750/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/take-two-private-division-sale<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Take-Two has sold off its indie label Private Division to an unknown buyer, citing a need to "focus [its] resources on growing [its] core and mobile businesses for the long-term".</p>

<p>In a set of <a href="https://ir.take2games.com/static-files/e938f73a-cfd7-46ac-b308-3f5b55acaeb7" rel="noopener" target="_blank">prepared remarks</a> accompanying Take-Two's latest financial results, company president Karl Slatoff says that the transaction involved the mystery buyer "purchas[ing Take-Two's] rights to substantially all of Private Division's live and unreleased titles".</p>

<p>It looks like Early Access action RPG&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/no-rest-for-the-wicked">No Rest for the Wicked</a></em>, which was released back in April,&nbsp;wasn't included in that transaction, though, because Slatoff says that Take-Two "will continue to support" the game. He concludes by thanking Private Division for its "contributions" to Take-Two.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/no-rest-for-the-wicked-take-two-private-division.jpg?itok=WqMTJJ-U 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/no-rest-for-the-wicked-take-two-private-division.jpg?itok=C1c891Eh 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Private Division has been sold, but it looks like&nbsp;<em>No Rest for the Wicked&nbsp;</em>hasn't.</figcaption></figure><p>Private Division's fate has been uncertain for some time. When Take-Two <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/take-two-interactive-layoffs">laid off 5% of its workforce</a> back in April, a <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-05-01/take-two-interactive-shuts-down-two-game-studios" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Bloomberg report</a> noted that many of the workers who would lose their jobs as part of that layoff wave were Private Division employees.</p>

<p>Later, in May, evidence began to pile up that Take-Two had <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/intercept-games-shut-down-kerbal-space-program-2">shuttered the developers</a> of&nbsp;<em>Kerbal Space Program 2&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Rollerdrome</em>, both of which were games published by Private Division. Take-Two itself, however, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/take-two-denies-roll7-intercept-closure">denied shutting down those studios</a>.</p>

<p>Towards the end of that same month,&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill 2&nbsp;</em>remake developer Bloober Team revealed that its partnership with Private Division for an upcoming new horror IP <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/bloober-team-private-division-end-partnership">had ended</a>, with Take-Two being the entity that terminated said partnership.</p>

<p>That game may well be new horror project&nbsp;<em>Cronos: The New Dawn</em>, which will now be self-published by Bloober Team. It's circumstantial, of course, but this could be more evidence that Private Division was in the process of being sold even then.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/private-division-take-two-kerbal-space-program.jpg?itok=O8GpP_LW 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/private-division-take-two-kerbal-space-program.jpg?itok=QA7WCtgc 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>You may also know Private Division's name from<em>&nbsp;Kerbal Space Program</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>News of Private Division's sale comes as part of Take-Two's Q2 financial report, in which the company announces that net bookings have risen by 6% overall compared to last year.</p>

<p>According to Take-Two, this financial performance was mainly driven by "strength in the&nbsp;<em>Grand Theft Auto&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Borderlands&nbsp;</em>franchises", and that's without the release of&nbsp;<em>Grand Theft Auto 6</em>, which is <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/grand-theft-auto-6-trailer-released-early-following-leak-coming-in-2025">due to arrive next year</a>.</p>

<p>You can see the rest of Take-Two's <a href="https://ir.take2games.com/static-files/ff9f9b55-43a5-4af5-ab54-13a77102d4b9" rel="noopener" target="_blank">financial report right here</a> if you're interested in the nerdy stats side of things. We don't yet know to whom Private Division was sold, but it's possible we'll find out in the coming weeks. Stay tuned.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sims-Like Life Sim inZoi Gets Early Access Release Date for Next Year]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/inzoi-release-date-delayed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sims-like-life-sim-inzoi-gets-early-access-release-date-for-next-year.1029681/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/inzoi-release-date-delayed<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Krafton has announced the Early Access release date for its upcoming life sim&nbsp;<em>inZoi</em>, but there's some bad news if you were hoping for the game to launch in 2024.</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1162040845181124618/1207578601008926791/1303969784550920273" rel="noopener" target="_blank">message on the game's official Discord server</a>, director Hyungjun Kim, also known as "Kjun", announces that the&nbsp;<em>inZoi&nbsp;</em>release date is March 28th. He then apologizes that the team wasn't able to "bring you the game sooner", but that the delay is necessary to give&nbsp;<em>inZoi&nbsp;</em>"the best possible start".</p>

<p>Kjun goes on to say that the response to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sims-like-inzoi-character-creator-tool">its character creator test</a>, as well as its trial of user-generated content platform Canvas, was "amazing", and that seeing "such engagement" led the team to realize the responsibility it has to "provide players with the most complete experience possible".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/inzoi-release-date-delay-parents.jpg?itok=8QxpY1-n 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/inzoi-release-date-delay-parents.jpg?itok=lswu4biy 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>inZoi&nbsp;</em>will be arriving in March next year.</figcaption></figure><p>Technically speaking, this announcement constitutes a delay; back in October, Kjun himself <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/life-sim/life-sim-inzoi-is-still-set-to-release-in-early-access-this-year-krafton-confirms/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">confirmed to PC Gamer</a> that&nbsp;<em>inZoi&nbsp;</em>was scheduled to launch sometime in 2024.</p>

<p>When it does arrive,&nbsp;<em>inZoi&nbsp;</em>will be one of a rapidly-dwindling handful of competitors to EA's titanic&nbsp;<em>The Sims</em>, which essentially currently stands unopposed in its niche (and which isn't going to be getting <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sims-like-inzoi-character-creator-tool">a new numbered mainline entry</a> any time soon).</p>

<p>Paradox was working on a&nbsp;<em>Sims</em>&nbsp;competitor by the name of&nbsp;<em>Life by You</em>, but the game was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/life-by-you-paradoxs-sims-competitor-has-been-cancelled">canceled back in June</a>, causing the studio's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/paradox-profits-life-by-you-canceled">profits to nosedive</a>&nbsp;as a result.</p>

<p>Perhaps the only other major rival to&nbsp;<em>The Sims&nbsp;</em>that's currently in development is&nbsp;<em>Paralives</em>, which is currently scheduled for an Early Access release sometime next year as well (assuming it doesn't get delayed, of course).</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/paralives-sims-competitor-inzoi.jpg?itok=AXlsPpfQ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/paralives-sims-competitor-inzoi.jpg?itok=udFgfEJV 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Paralives&nbsp;</em>is one of the only competitors to&nbsp;<em>The Sims</em>, and, indeed,&nbsp;<em>inZoi&nbsp;</em>as well.</figcaption></figure><p>As for&nbsp;<em>inZoi</em>, Krafton describes it as a "deep and detailed simulation" in which you can build houses, customize characters, and watch people live their lives according to your whims, just like in&nbsp;<em>The Sims</em>.</p>

<p><em>inZoi&nbsp;</em>is due to land on PC via Steam Early Access on March 28th. You can <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2456740/inZOI/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="noopener" target="_blank">wishlist it here</a> if you want to keep up with its progress.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>