<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 16:58:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Train 2 Brings More Deckbuilding Madness, Demo Available Now]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-train-2-announced-demo-now</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-train-2-brings-more-deckbuilding-madness-demo-available-now.1113363/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-train-2-announced-demo-now<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Big Fan Games and developer Shiny Shoe have announced&nbsp;<em>Monster Train 2</em>, a followup to the 2020 roguelike deckbuilder&nbsp;<em>Monster Train</em>, and you can try it out right now if you want to.</p>

<p>As <a href="https://x.com/BigFanPresents/status/1892227902936093175" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">revealed</a> by Big Fan over on X,&nbsp;<em>Monster Train 2&nbsp;</em>will boast "new clans, card types [and] gameplay twists", as well as new factions and challenges to take on. Of course, the core gameplay, in which you'll defend your Pyre across three vertical gameplay fields, remains intact.</p>

<p>This time around, the story revolves around Titans, powerful beings who have "seized control of Heaven". It's up to you to command the forces of angels and demons in order to fight back against the Titans and reclaim the heavens from their machinations.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/monster-train-2-announced-big-fan.jpg?itok=SWv412AE 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/monster-train-2-announced-big-fan.jpg?itok=t02F_REf 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Monster Train 2&nbsp;</em>brings more deckbuilding madness soon.</figcaption></figure><p>Developer Shiny Shoe is promising five new clans for&nbsp;<em>Monster Train 2</em>, each of which will bring its own unique strengths to the table.</p>

<p>You'll also be able to experiment with two new types of card in the form of Room and Equipment Cards. The former adds new boosts to your train, while the latter can be applied to units to help them (and you!) out in combat.</p>

<p>Much like in roguelites like&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/hades" rel="nofollow"><em>Hades</em></a>,&nbsp;<em>Monster Train 2&nbsp;</em>has a hub area to which you'll return after each run. The Covenant Outpost is where you'll customize your train, take on new challenges, and interact with the game's characters to move the story forward.</p>

<p>You can check out the announcement trailer for&nbsp;<em>Monster Train 2&nbsp;</em>right here.</p>




<p><em>Monster Train 2&nbsp;</em>will be published by Devolver Digital subsidiary Big Fan Games, which is <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/devolver-big-fan-games-licensed-indies" rel="nofollow">effectively the successor to Good Shepherd Games</a> (also a Devolver subsidiary and the publisher of the original&nbsp;<em>Monster Train</em>).</p>

<p>If you want to try the game out, you can do so <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2742830/Monster_Train_2/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">right now on Steam</a>, where a demo awaits you. It doesn't sound like that demo is available on other platforms, unfortunately. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>