<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 15:54:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bandai Namco Staff Count Quietly Falls by Over 100 in Less Than a Year]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/bandai-namco-staff-count-falls-by-100</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bandai-namco-staff-count-quietly-falls-by-over-100-in-less-than-a-year.1101951/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/bandai-namco-staff-count-falls-by-100<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The staff count at&nbsp;<em>Tekken 8&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Elden Ring&nbsp;</em>publisher Bandai Namco has fallen by over 100 in the last ten months, a new report has revealed.</p>

<p>According to <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/bandai-namco-studios-staff-silently-reduced-by-over-100-people-japan-pension-service-database-shows/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Automaton Media</a>, the Japanese online pension registry, which shows how many employees business have enrolled, shows a diminished number of staff in February when compared to April 2024.</p>

<p>Automaton says that the register showed Bandai Namco employed 1,294 people in April 2024, but that this number had fallen to 1,177 as of the last update, which took place on February 4th. That represents a drop of 117 people.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/bandai-namco-staff-count-falls-unknown-9-awakening.jpg?itok=5yVeWH-J 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/bandai-namco-staff-count-falls-unknown-9-awakening.jpg?itok=ogKop7Ra 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>It's fair to say not every recent Bandai Namco game has been a success.</figcaption></figure><p>Bandai Namco doesn't seem to have publicly announced these layoffs, although recently,&nbsp;<em>Unknown 9: Awakening&nbsp;</em>developer Reflector Entertainment, a subsidiary of Bandai Namco, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/unknown-9-awakening-layoffs-cancellation-reflector" rel="nofollow">revealed it would lay off</a> an unknown (no pun intended) number of staff.</p>

<p>As Automaton points out, a Bloomberg <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-10-15/bandai-namco-begins-to-cut-headcount-after-culling-game-titles" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">report</a>&nbsp;in October alleged that Bandai Namco staff were essentially being coerced to leave the company voluntarily through the use of "oidashi beya", or "banishment rooms".</p>

<p>Employees were allegedly placed in these rooms with no real tasks to complete, effectively pressuring them into leaving the company and circumventing what Bloomberg calls "some of the world's strictest labor protection laws".</p>

<p>Bandai Namco itself denied those reports, and the reduction in headcount at the studio naturally doesn't provide any kind of evidence that oidashi beya were being used, but it does look like the studio underwent a fairly significant staff drop between April and February.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/elden-ring-nightreign-bandai-namco.jpg?itok=CPbVS1Pf 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/elden-ring-nightreign-bandai-namco.jpg?itok=mYs-zAVA 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Bandai Namco is gearing up to release&nbsp;<em>Elden Ring Nightreign&nbsp;</em>this year.</figcaption></figure><p>It's also worth noting that since this staff reduction hasn't been officially announced, it might not even technically be correct to call them "layoffs", since some staff may have left voluntarily or retired.</p>

<p>This report also comes after Bandai Namco released its <a href="https://www.bandainamco.co.jp/files/ir/financialstatements/pdf/20250205_en_Result.pdf" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">financial statement</a> for the nine-month period between April and December 2024, which shows growth in both profit and sales for the company.</p>

<p>That boost is, according to Bandai Namco, attributable in part to things like the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-sales-5m" rel="nofollow">"massive success"</a> of&nbsp;<em>Dragon Ball: Sparking! Zero</em>, as well as strong sales for both&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/elden-ring-sales-25-million" rel="nofollow">Elden Ring</a>&nbsp;</em>and its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/elden-ring-shadow-of-erdtree-sales" rel="nofollow">DLC&nbsp;<em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em></a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bloodborne PSX Demake Taken Down by Sony DMCA]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/bloodborne-psx-demake-dmca-sony</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bloodborne-psx-demake-taken-down-by-sony-dmca.1101924/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/bloodborne-psx-demake-dmca-sony<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A fanmade&nbsp;<em>Bloodborne&nbsp;</em>demake that reimagined the PS4 action RPG as a PS1 game has been hit with a Sony DMCA notice, meaning it's no longer available for download.</p>

<p>The aptly-named&nbsp;<em>Bloodborne PSX&nbsp;</em>(using the console's early PlayStation X codename) was previously available on Itch.io, but a <a href="https://itch.io/takedowns/1370201" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">takedown</a>&nbsp;was issued by Sony yesterday, and the game's <a href="https://b0tster.itch.io/bbpsx" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">page</a> now simply leads to a single line of text stating its files have been "suspended for copyright or trademark claim".</p>

<p>This is the second&nbsp;<em>Bloodborne</em>-related DMCA notice Sony has issued in a week. Last Friday, modder Lance McDonald revealed he'd received a DMCA instructing him to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/bloodborne-60fps-patch-dmca" rel="nofollow">take down his 60fps patch</a> for the game, an instruction with which he quickly complied.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/bloodborne-psx-demake-dmca-lantern.jpg?itok=WgvfGR1F 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/bloodborne-psx-demake-dmca-lantern.jpg?itok=e4SISVv_ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Lilith Walther's&nbsp;<em>Bloodborne PSX&nbsp;</em>demake is no longer available to download thanks to a DMCA.</figcaption></figure><p>These DMCA notices have sparked speculation that Sony could be about to announce its own official&nbsp;<em>Bloodborne&nbsp;</em>remaster; after all, there's got to be a reason Sony is suddenly taking notice of&nbsp;<em>Bloodborne</em>-related fan projects online, right?</p>

<p>Well...not necessarily. This isn't the first time Walther has run afoul of Sony with regards to&nbsp;<em>Bloodborne&nbsp;</em>fan projects; last year, she was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nightmare-kart-bloodborne-kart-release-date" rel="nofollow">told by Sony</a> that she needed to scrub the&nbsp;<em>Bloodborne&nbsp;</em>branding from racer&nbsp;<em>Nightmare Kart&nbsp;</em>and release it as its own thing.</p>

<p>Of course, it's possible that was also part of Sony's plans to release a&nbsp;<em>Bloodborne&nbsp;</em>remaster, but many months have passed between then and now, and no&nbsp;remaster or remake of the game was revealed in the interim.</p>

<p>It's entirely possible that this DMCA, as well as the one aimed at McDonald, just represents Sony's lawyers suddenly waking up and realizing they need to look busy, but as a huge&nbsp;<em>Bloodborne&nbsp;</em>fan myself, I understand the need for hope.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/bloodborne-kart-nightmare-kart.jpg?itok=SQI8iow2 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/bloodborne-kart-nightmare-kart.jpg?itok=1dIYdGt1 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Nightmare Kart&nbsp;</em>was once known as&nbsp;<em>Bloodborne Kart&nbsp;</em>before Sony got involved.</figcaption></figure><p><em>Bloodborne</em>'s age and relatively poor performance on PS4 have resulted in repeated calls for a remaster or remake over the years, but Sony has yet to heed those calls.</p>

<p>However, a State of Play presentation is rumored to be landing next week, as <a href="https://x.com/NateTheHate2/status/1885748440132456877" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">hinted at</a> by Switch 2 date leaker NateTheHate. It's possible that Sony intends to reveal its own&nbsp;<em>Bloodborne&nbsp;</em>remaster during that presentation, and that that's the reason behind the increased DMCA frequency.</p>

<p>We'll have to wait and see. In the meantime, you can still check out the original&nbsp;<em>Bloodborne&nbsp;</em>on <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/bloodborne/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PS4</a> (and PS5 via backwards compatibility).</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wizkids Baldurs Gate III MIniature Review - There's Something Off About That Ox...]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/wizkids-baldurs-gate-iii-miniature-review-theres-something-off-about-that-ox</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wizkids-baldurs-gate-iii-miniature-review-theres-something-off-about-that-ox.1101903/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/wizkids-baldurs-gate-iii-miniature-review-theres-something-off-about-that-ox<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>After the incredible popularity of <em>Baldur's Gate III,</em> and with Wizkids returning to previous <em>D&amp;D 5e</em> expansions, it was only a matter of time until players could get their hands on a set of <em>Baldur's Gate</em> minis focusing on characters from the incredibly popular video game by Larian, as well as the <em>5e</em> adventure <em>Baldur's Gate: Descent Into Avernus.</em></p>

<p>I received the <em>Icons of the Realms: Baldur's Gate III</em> Characters, the iconic party that adventures with your Tav, as well as eight of the Blind Boxes containing a mix of miniatures based on creatures you might see around<em> Baldur's Gate</em>, be part of the Descent into Avernus Adventure, or be important characters from Baldur's Gate III (including a suspicious looking Ox…).</p>

<h2>Icons of the Realms: <em>Baldur's Gate 3</em> Characters</h2>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/wizkids-dd-baldurs-gate-iii-minis-bg3-party.jpg?itok=M7FEzcWS 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/wizkids-dd-baldurs-gate-iii-minis-bg3-party.jpg?itok=UcsL9NMU 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The <em>Baldur's Gate III </em>Characters box comes with seven pre-painted miniatures highlighting the different BG3 party members along with Withers.</p>

<p>Each member of the party is sporting their iconic weapons; the large battle axe Karlach is holding against her body, Lae'zel holds her sword high above her head ready to strike, Shadowheart holding Selune's Spear Of Night out from her, and Astorion holding out one hand as if to invite you towards him while brandishing a dagger in the other.</p>

<p>For fans of Wyll he holds his sword outstretched as if mid-duel and is sporting the horns he can obtain early on for breaking his pact with his patron.</p>

<p>The outfits each character wears aligns with their promotional artwork meaning that even from a distance each is immediately recognizable and whether you want to purchase these minis to display or to throw the <em>BG3 </em>party in for a crossover at your own table you wont be disappointed.</p>

<h2>Adventures From <em>Baldur's Gate</em> Miniatures</h2>

<p>As with all Wizkids miniatures each blindbox has with it three Medium or Smaller miniatures and one Large miniature. There will always be some good multi-purpose stuff, while also ensuring you're going to get an impressive miniature to throw down at your table.</p>

<p>As I go through the different minis that I unboxed I'll break them out into generic <em>Baldur's Gate</em> creatures or those specific to Descent Into Avernus and those that fans of <em>Baldur's Gate III</em> will recognize.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/wizkids-dd-baldurs-gate-iii-minis-bg-generic-small.jpg?itok=9wUflSGG 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/wizkids-dd-baldurs-gate-iii-minis-bg-generic-small.jpg?itok=NZp3WvAc 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h3><em>Baldur's Gate</em> Miniatures</h3>

<p>For the more generic <em>Baldur's Gate</em> miniatures in the Small and Medium variety I opened:</p>

<ul><li aria-level="1">Imp</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Intellect Devourer</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Goblin Novice and Goblin Sharpshooter</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Two Duergar</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Two Bugbear Assassins, and</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Doppelganger</li>
</ul><p>A thing I am always thankful for in the Blind Boxes are that there are a healthy number of standard enemies. Having a high-quality Wizkids miniature of a dragon is great for the few and far between times where that specific dragon will appear but the above listed minis could be used anywhere and everywhere.</p>

<p>The Goblins are of the yellow-skinned variety brandishing a club and a shortbow, allowing for visual differences (even if Novie and Sharpshooter don't exactly have a stat block outside of BG3).</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/wizkids-dd-baldurs-gate-iii-minis-bg-generic-large.jpg?itok=e921JNbP 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/wizkids-dd-baldurs-gate-iii-minis-bg-generic-large.jpg?itok=TondPapL 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The Large generic <em>Baldur's Gate</em> miniatures I opened include:</p>

<ul><li aria-level="1">Gnoll</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Warg</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Bear</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Minotaur</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Spectator, and</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Bulette</li>
</ul><p>Again a fantastic range of miniatures. Bears for a random forest encounter (maybe it's a Druid in disguise), Gnoll once the party has adventured a bit further, and then for some deadlier encounters you can break out the Spectator and Bulette.</p>

<p>The design of the Bulette is completely different from the once previously included in Sand and Stone. Unlike the previous one, which was partially exposing itself from the ground that it's burrowed into, the new Bulette miniature stands totally above ground, showing off it's metal top coat that glistens in the light. Underneath its fleshier stomach is exposed.</p>

<h3><em>Baldur's Gate III </em>Miniatures</h3>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/wizkids-dd-baldurs-gate-iii-minis-bg3-medium.jpg?itok=GAFTL6hq 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/wizkids-dd-baldurs-gate-iii-minis-bg3-medium.jpg?itok=fN9IjHHf 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Of the miniatures that I got that were explicitly flavors of <em>Baldur's Gate III </em>for the range of Tiny to Medium sized creatures I opened:</p>

<ul><li aria-level="1">Dark Justicar</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Fist of Bane</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Flaming Fist Soldier</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Githyanki</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Halsin</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Hollyphant</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Necromyte of Myrkul</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Omeluum</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Orin the Red</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Priestess Gut</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Reaper of Bhaal</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Sovreign Glut</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Zevlor</li>
</ul><p>For fans of the game there's plenty to be excited for from important named characters like Umeluum, Halsin, and Priestess Gut to the interesting enemies you'd encounter like the Flaming Fist Soldier.</p>

<p>I always enjoy when a character is posed in a way that allows you to understand who they are or what affinities they have. In this way Priestess Gut creating an arch of power over her head make it a really interesting piece for your table.</p>

<p>The Dark Justicar wears contrasting blacks with golden armor brandishing his sword and the Githyanki holds up a crossbow ready to strike. Putting so many of these characters together the theme of 'red' really does seem to show up a lot though.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/wizkids-dd-baldurs-gate-iii-minis-bg3-large.jpg?itok=kM-uNREE 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/wizkids-dd-baldurs-gate-iii-minis-bg3-large.jpg?itok=0-ykApNz 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The large <em>Baldur's Gate III </em>miniatures that I opened include:</p>

<ul><li aria-level="1">Lump The Enlightened</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Shambling Mound</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Slayer of Bhaal</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Strange Ox</li>
</ul><p>I love how much of a strange mix of miniatures this is. Lump is great as an Ogre miniature but manages to also bring a smile as you remember the strange circumstance of an Ogre swallowing a Headband of Intellect. Likewise having the Strange Ox, that for all intents and purposes could be a simple Ox miniature, present in this collection brings back fond memories of strange conversations.</p>

<p>Taking a turn for the terrifying the Shambling Mount miniature here, while described generically has the same blueish light emanating from within like that of the Shadow-Cursed Shambling Mound. For something that is meant to be glowing blue I do wish they used a blue transparent plastic instead of just painting those areas blue.</p>

<p>The last of the giant minis was the Slayer of Bhaal, or simply a Slayer in <em>Baldur's Gate III.</em> This is one of those excellent miniatures that can be used for anything that you want to scare your players with. It looks fast, it can slice and dice, and will be able to easily throw your players around. A very nice and precise touch on close inspection is the almost orange glow from the eyes.</p>

<h2>Wizkids <em>Baldur's Gate III</em> Miniatures Review | Final Thoughts</h2>

<p>While the blind boxes advertise both Adventures From <em>Baldur's Gate</em> and <em>Baldur's Gate III </em>this set is really there for the fans of <em>Baldur's Gate III.</em> Every miniature, even the generic ones, will be more aligned with the models that you'll be more than familiar with if you've played <em>Baldur's Gate III.</em></p>

<p>This sense of knowing is also extra fun when you'll pull these out in games to come and will get to be brought back to&nbsp;</p>

<hr><p><strong><em>This review was completed with miniatures provided to TechRaptor by Wizkids. All photos were taken by the reviewer.</em></strong></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Andrew has written Video Game and Entertainment news, reviews, and guides for 10+ years. As Senior Content Manager, he assists in creating and editing… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/andrew-stretch">More about Andrew</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Space Marine 2 6.0 Datavault Update Brings New Map, New Enemy, and More]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/space-marine-2-datavault-update</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/space-marine-2-6-0-datavault-update-brings-new-map-new-enemy-and-more.1101900/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/space-marine-2-datavault-update<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Saber Interactive and Focus Entertainment have released a brand new <i>Warhammer 40k: Space Marine 2&nbsp;</i>update, and it's bringing a new area on the Battle Barge, a new PvP map to fight on, and more.</p>

<p>First up, the Datavault is a new area on the Resilient. Completing in-game challenges will give you the chance to earn Research Data, which you can use to unlock information on elements of the game's world, as well as new cosmetics.</p>

<p>A new PvP map, Tomb, has also been introduced. The map is&nbsp;<em>Space Marine 2</em>'s smallest, but it utilizes "a different approach" to its brethren when it comes to design, so make sure to give it a look if you want a more unconventional PvP experience.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/space-marine-2-6.0-datavault-update-biovore.jpg?itok=c8fKQgTM 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/space-marine-2-6.0-datavault-update-biovore.jpg?itok=siVKkI1w 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The Biovore is here to ruin your day in&nbsp;<em>Space Marine 2</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>The Tyranids' ranks have grown with a new enemy in this&nbsp;<em>Space Marine 2&nbsp;</em>update, too. The Biovore is a new Extremis-class enemy that serves as long-distance artillery, but it can also defend itself by stabbing with its legs.</p>

<p>If you've been looking for ways to communicate with your fellow Ultramarines, but good old-fashioned conversation isn't doing it, then the new Emote system should do the trick. It allows you to perform "a pound to the chest, a battle cry, and even a stoic handshake", plus others.</p>

<p>What's more, if the base challenge of&nbsp;<em>Space Marine 2</em>'s PvE modes wasn't enough for you, a new Absolute difficulty mode has been introduced that features "new, more diverse enemy packs" and limited resources to contend with.</p>




<p>You can read the full Datavault update <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2183900/view/529837904419094594" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">patch notes right here</a> to see everything that's new. There are a ton of balance changes in the update, specifically pertaining to class perks, so make sure to read them all to stay in the know.</p>

<p><em>Warhammer 40k: Space Marine 2&nbsp;</em>is out right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2183900/Warhammer_40000_Space_Marine_2/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP4133-PPSA04452_00-SPACEMARINESII00" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/games/store/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2/9n9pczwhvp2l" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>. You can read my <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-review" rel="nofollow">review of the Ultramarines' latest excursion here</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Paradox to Buy Jagged Alliance 3 and Surviving Mars Dev Haemimont Games]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/paradox-haemimont-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/paradox-to-buy-jagged-alliance-3-and-surviving-mars-dev-haemimont-games.1101897/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/paradox-haemimont-games<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Cities: Skylines 2&nbsp;</em>publisher Paradox Interactive has announced that it will purchase&nbsp;<em>Jagged Alliance 3&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Surviving Mars&nbsp;</em>studio Haemimont Games.</p>

<p>In its <a href="https://www.paradoxinteractive.com/investors/financial-reports/year-end-report-january-december-2024" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">year-end financial report</a>, Paradox reveals it has "entered into an agreement to purchase 100% of the shares" in Haemimont. No change in management was announced, so it seems like Haemimont will continue doing its own thing under Paradox.</p>

<p>This isn't the first time Paradox and Haemimont will have crossed paths, either. The company served as the publisher for colony sim&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/surviving-mars" rel="nofollow">Surviving Mars</a>&nbsp;</em>in 2018, although Haemimont is perhaps better-known for working with THQ Nordic and Kalypso Media on the likes of&nbsp;<em>Tropico&nbsp;</em>and<i>&nbsp;</i><em>Grand Ages: Rome</em>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/paradox-haemimont-games-surviving-mars.jpg?itok=jjJeSDWm 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/paradox-haemimont-games-surviving-mars.jpg?itok=m7GcNdml 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Paradox has worked with Haemimont before, on colony sim&nbsp;<em>Surviving Mars</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>As for the financial report itself, Paradox says its revenue has fallen 17% when compared to last year, but that profit has increased by 10%.</p>

<p>As a reminder, major Paradox releases like&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/cities-skylines-ii-announced" rel="nofollow">Cities: Skylines 2</a>&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/age-of-wonders-4-announced-for-pc-ps5-xbox-with-release-date-details-gameplay" rel="nofollow">Age of Wonders 4</a>&nbsp;</em>took place in the previous financial year, so Paradox didn't really have a major tentpole title to base its finances around in 2024.</p>

<p>Additionally, hotly-anticipated projects like&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/vampire-masquerade-bloodlines-2-delayed-yet-again" rel="nofollow">Vampire: The Masquerade - Bloodlines 2</a>&nbsp;</em>and, er, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/cities-skylines-2-ps5-xbox-release-delayed-again" rel="nofollow">the console release of&nbsp;</a><em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/cities-skylines-2-ps5-xbox-release-delayed-again" rel="nofollow">Cities: Skylines 2</a>&nbsp;</em>are either slated for this year or don't have a release date yet, so the company is in a sort of limbo right now.</p>

<p>Paradox CEO Fredrik Wester says the studio closes its year with "a period of high revenue and good margins" and says that the studio's "persistent work over time" is more important than between-quarter variation.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-paradox.jpg?itok=A33m4Wqm 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-paradox.jpg?itok=fpnT516m 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Paradox's future includes big releases like&nbsp;<em>Vampire: The Masquerade - Bloodlines 2</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>Paradox's yearly financial assessment comes a few months after the company <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/life-by-you-paradoxs-sims-competitor-has-been-cancelled" rel="nofollow">announced the cancellation</a> of its&nbsp;<em>Sims</em>-style life sim&nbsp;<em>Life by You</em>, which caused its quarter-by-quarter profits to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/paradox-profits-life-by-you-canceled" rel="nofollow">plummet by 90% in July</a>.</p>

<p>According to the studio, however, that fall was factored into its yearly assessment; Paradox says write-downs of around 208 million kronor, or about $19 million, are included in its operating profit report.</p>

<p>We'll have to wait and see what kind of 2025 Paradox has, as well as whether or not its purchase of Haemimont affects that developer's day-to-day operations. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metal Gear Solid Delta Release Date Seemingly Leaked Via PlayStation Store]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/metal-gear-solid-delta-release-date-leak-playstation</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metal-gear-solid-delta-release-date-seemingly-leaked-via-playstation-store.1101852/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/metal-gear-solid-delta-release-date-leak-playstation<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear Solid Delta&nbsp;</em>release date appears to have been leaked via the game's PlayStation Store listing, and if the leak is correct, then the hotly-anticipated remake will be launching in summer.</p>

<p>As spotted by ResetEra user <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/metal-gear-solid-delta-releases-august-25th-2025-new-trailer-on-ps-store-snake-vs-monkey-teased.1101735/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">NateDog</a>, a new <a href="https://vulcan.dl.playstation.net/img/rnd/202502/0611/2c429928f5c5b20df3c78f5053ace69c011d4f391782ab47.mp4" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">trailer</a> has appeared on the PlayStation Store's backend that shows off some of the game's content, including various iconic scenes and boss battles from&nbsp;<em>Snake Eater</em>. The release date is then given as August 28th.</p>

<p>Perhaps most excitingly, the trailer also seems to confirm the release of the Snake vs. Monkey gameplay mode, which saw the worlds of&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Ape Escape&nbsp;</em>collide in an unlikely crossover.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/metal-gear-solid-delta-release-date-snake.jpg?itok=Aw9T2VUp 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/metal-gear-solid-delta-release-date-snake.jpg?itok=g0UYVW71 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Metal Gear Solid Delta&nbsp;</em>looks set for an August release.</figcaption></figure><p>If the Snake vs. Monkey minigame is indeed included, it could well mark the<em>&nbsp;Ape Escape</em>&nbsp;series' first appearance outside the PlayStation ecosystem, although there's also every chance that the minigame is PlayStation-exclusive.</p>

<p>A quick look at the current <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-gb/concept/10007293/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation Store page</a> for&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear Solid Delta&nbsp;</em>also shows the August 28th release date, so it's likely Konami will soon officially release the trailer and confirm the date.</p>

<p>According to leaker <a href="https://x.com/NateTheHate2/status/1885592410589110653" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">NateTheHate</a>, who accurately predicted the date on which the Nintendo Switch 2 would be revealed, a PlayStation State of Play showcase will air this month. He currently seems to be suggesting that it'll take place <a href="https://x.com/NateTheHate2/status/1885748440132456877" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">on Valentine's Day</a>.</p>

<p>If that is indeed the case, then I wouldn't be surprised if the&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear Solid Delta&nbsp;</em>release date trailer aired during that presentation, which would also probably be why the Snake vs. Monkey minigame is shown.</p>




<p>As for&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater&nbsp;</em>itself, it's a remake of the classic 2004 PS2 stealth-action game&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear Solid 3: Snake Eater</em>.</p>

<p>Announced <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/metal-gear-solid-3-remake-announced-at-state-of-play" rel="nofollow">during a PlayStation showcase in May 2023</a>, the remake will offer completely reworked visuals and gameplay, complete with a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/metal-gear-solid-d-snake-eater-remake-reveals-first-spectacular-gameplay-in-unreal" rel="nofollow">transition to Unreal Engine 5</a>. It will, however, retain the voice audio of the original game and won't recast any actors.</p>

<p>The game is also being developed without the involvement of series creator Hideo Kojima, who's currently <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/death-stranding-2-filming-and-recording-completed" rel="nofollow">hard at work on&nbsp;</a><em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/death-stranding-2-filming-and-recording-completed" rel="nofollow">Death Stranding 2</a>&nbsp;</em>(as well as a stealth action game of his own mysteriously codenamed&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hideo-kojima-announces-next-generation-espionage-action-game" rel="nofollow"><em>Physint</em></a>).</p>

<p>Assuming this leak is indeed correct,&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater&nbsp;</em>is due to launch for <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2417610/METAL_GEAR_SOLID_D_SNAKE_EATER/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-gb/concept/10007293/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/metal-gear-solid-d-snake-eater/9pjln214rtkq" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a> on August 28th. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>