<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 15:27:24 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin's Creed Shadows Debuts to Series' Highest Steam Player Count]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/assassins-creed-shadows-steam-player-count</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassins-creed-shadows-debuts-to-series-highest-steam-player-count.1143183/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/assassins-creed-shadows-steam-player-count<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Assassin's Creed Shadows</em>, the latest game in the long-running&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed&nbsp;</em>series of stealth action-adventure games, has launched to the franchise's highest Steam player count of all time.</p>

<p>As spotted by the folks at <a href="https://www.dexerto.com/assassins-creed/assassins-creed-shadows-sets-huge-franchise-record-with-growing-player-count-3168000/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Dexerto</a>,&nbsp;<em>Shadows</em>' peak player count on Steam <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/3159330/charts/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">hit 64,825</a> over the weekend. At time of writing, that's still the game's peak; 43,263 players are currently enjoying&nbsp;<em>Shadows</em>, which still isn't bad considering today is a Monday.</p>

<p>That figure puts&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed Shadows&nbsp;</em>slightly ahead of Greek epic&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed Odyssey</em>, which managed to achieve a peak player count of 62,069 around the time of its release. There's not much in it, but&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed Shadows&nbsp;</em>is officially the series' biggest Steam launch.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/assassins-creed-shadows-steam-player-count-sneaking.jpg?itok=4STrPyMk 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/assassins-creed-shadows-steam-player-count-sneaking.jpg?itok=kuspaO07 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Assassin's Creed Shadows&nbsp;</em>is officially the franchise's biggest Steam launch.</figcaption></figure><p>If you're wondering how the game stacks up against other Ubisoft releases, it still can't quite hold a candle to the publisher's biggest Steam launches ever, at least not according to <a href="https://steamdb.info/publisher/Ubisoft/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">SteamDB's numbers</a>.</p>

<p>Ubisoft's biggest Steam launch ever was the crunchy melee brawler&nbsp;<em>For Honor</em>, which achieved an impressive 225,831 peak player count in August 2018. It's followed by&nbsp;<em>Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six Siege</em>'s peak of 201,933, with&nbsp;<em>The Division</em>'s 114,228 (a very satisfying number) putting it in a comfortable third.</p>

<p>Despite the fact that&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed Shadows&nbsp;</em>can't reach those lofty heights, its success will doubtless come as a relief to Ubisoft, given that the game hasn't exactly had an easy time of it in recent months.</p>

<p>Announced last year,&nbsp;<em>Shadows&nbsp;</em>was originally set to launch in November, but was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/assassins-creed-shadows-delayed-february" rel="nofollow">subsequently delayed to February</a> as Ubisoft announced it would rethink some of its business practices (including releasing PC games on Steam on day one in future).</p>




<p>The game was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/assassins-creed-shadows-delayed-again-march" rel="nofollow">then delayed again</a>, with publisher Ubisoft <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/xdefiant-shutting-down-ubisoft-studios-closing" rel="nofollow">closing down</a> three of its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ubisoft-layoffs-leamington-closure" rel="nofollow">locations</a>&nbsp;and revealing its intention to pursue <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ubisoft-financials-cost-cutting-q3" rel="nofollow">further cost-cutting measures</a> after a pretty dire third-quarter performance.</p>

<p>It remains to be seen whether&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed Shadows&nbsp;</em>can single-handedly turn Ubisoft's fortunes around, but the game is available right now for <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3159330/Assassins_Creed_Shadows/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/assassins-creed-shadows/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-GB/games/assassins-creed-shadows" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>. You can read our Andrew's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/assassins-creed-shadows-story-attempting-to-hit-word-limit" rel="nofollow">review of the game here</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Winkeltje: The Little Shop Followup Faire Trade Announced for 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/winkeltje-little-shop-followup-faire-trade-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/winkeltje-the-little-shop-followup-faire-trade-announced-for-2025.1143075/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/winkeltje-little-shop-followup-faire-trade-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Cozy shop sim&nbsp;<em>Winkeltje: The Little Shop&nbsp;</em>is getting a followup by the name of&nbsp;<em>Faire Trade</em>, and developer and publisher Sassybot's new game is coming to PC via Steam Early Access sometime later this year.</p>

<p>Sassybot says that while&nbsp;<em>Faire Trade&nbsp;</em>may bear a new name, it will have the "same charm of <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/winkeltje-little-shop-10-update-finally-arrives" rel="nofollow">its predecessor</a>", as well as boasting "more depth and customisation options than ever before".</p>

<p>Just like in&nbsp;<em>Winkeltje</em>, you'll be running your own cozy little shop, and you'll grow it from humble beginnings into the lifeblood of a bustling fantasy town with plenty of repeat customers to get to know.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/faire-trade-winkeltje-followup-shop.jpg?itok=Sh5og0-D 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/faire-trade-winkeltje-followup-shop.jpg?itok=yICd1HQL 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Faire Trade&nbsp;</em>asks you to manage your very own bustling fantasy shop (or perhaps that should be "shoppe").</figcaption></figure><p>Your goal in&nbsp;<em>Faire Trade&nbsp;</em>is to "stay ahead in a shifting economy" by selling everything your customers might need, "from fresh goods to enchanted armor". If you can imagine a less anime-styled&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/recettear-hd-2025" rel="nofollow"><em>Recettear: An Item Shop's Tale</em></a>, then you're probably not a million miles away.</p>

<p>Sassybot is also promising plenty of "eccentric" characters to meet in&nbsp;<em>Faire Trade</em>, each of whom will have their own "secrets" to uncover. You'll get to know them across shifting seasons, which will bring new challenges and new opportunities for your shop.</p>

<p>You'll also be able to create many of the items you're looking to sell, from forging armor yourself through to growing and sourcing your own fresh produce.</p>

<p>Of course, since this is a shop sim, you'll also need to pay attention to your balance sheets; you'll need to hire employees, make sure you're paying them fairly, and "make tough business decisions" in order to ensure the smooth day-to-day running of your store.</p>




<p><em>Faire Trade&nbsp;</em>launches on PC via Steam Early Access sometime later this year. Sadly, we don't have a more specific release date for the game than that, but you can <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2526560/Faire_Trade?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">wishlist it on Steam here</a> if you want to keep up with its progress.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>