<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:34:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Riot Games Releases Riftbound: Spiritforged Preview, Confirming New Mechanics for League of Legends TCG]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/riot-games-releases-riftbound-spiritforged-preview-confirming-new-mechanics-for</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/riot-games-releases-riftbound-spiritforged-preview-confirming-new-mechanics-for-league-of-legends-tcg.1351846/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Riot Games has released a <em>Riftbound: Spiritforged</em> preview. The second set in the official <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/league-of-legends" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>League of Legends</em></a> TCG will introduce new cards, new gameplay mechanics, and feature certain Legends from across the popular franchise.</p>



<p>The <em>Riftbound: Spiritforged</em> preview shows off a small handful of cards, some new prebuilt champion decks, and three new mechanics coming to the game.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/riftbound-spiritforged-preview-card-artwork.jpg?itok=WRs6_P1y 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/riftbound-spiritforged-preview-card-artwork.jpg?itok=FAyIjFtp 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Equipment is a new card subtype. Equipment can be attached to to units to make them stronger. Interestingly, equipment sticks around even if even if the unit is killed. Gold is a new resource that you can "spend" to get a new resource called Power, which is a required cost for certain cards. Lastly, there is Repeat. A spell with this effect can be doubled if you pay the card's cost a second time.</p>

<p>Some of the cards in the <em>Riftbound: Spiritforged</em> preview showcase some of these new mechanics. These include new Equipment cards such as <em>Guardian Angel</em>, <em>Dorian's Shield</em>, and <em>Sterak's Gage</em>. In keeping with his character, the cards featuring the Legend, Draven involves gaining and using Gold.</p>

<p>Notably, the assets in the preview do confirm at least two new champion decks. One will feature the dangerous duelist, Fiora. The other showcases the genius tinkerer, Rumble. As for how those particular decks will play is anyone's guess.</p>

<p>Lastly, there are 12 new Spirit Blossum-themed Overnumbered cards in the set. These cards are tied thematically to the set, which involves the lifting of the veil between the mortal and spirit realms.</p>

<p>Riftbound launched last month and, despite <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/riot-games-addresses-launch-issues-with-riftbound-origins" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">some launch issues</a>, has found its audience. It has entered a crowded space of other competitive card games such as <em>Magic The Gathering</em>, <em>Disney Lorcana</em>, and the <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/games/pokemon-trading-card-game" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Pokemon TCG</em></a>. The Spiritforged set will launch in December 2025 in China, and in English-speaking regions February 2026.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/riot-games-releases-riftbound-spiritforged-preview-confirming-new-mechanics-for]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>