<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 18:59:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hyper Light Breaker Preview - A Journey Worth Taking]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/hyper-light-breaker-preview-journey-worth-taking</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hyper-light-breaker-preview-a-journey-worth-taking.1080969/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/hyper-light-breaker-preview-journey-worth-taking<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer Heart Machine gained worldwide fame for its stellar debut title, <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/hyper-light-drifter" rel="nofollow"><em>Hyper Light Drifter</em></a>. Its mysterious world filled with vibrant ruins and dangerous foes is making the transition to 3D in the upcoming follow-up, <a href="https://techraptor.net/companies/heart-machine" rel="nofollow"><em>Hyper Light Breaker</em></a>.</p>

<p>I had a chance to play <em>Hyper Light Breaker</em> at Summer Game Fest Play Days <a rel="nofollow">earlier this year</a>, and I called it your "next roguelite addiction." I still agree with that sentiment, perhaps even more so now that I had a chance to try out a co-op session with two other players.</p>



<h2>Lootin', Shootin', and Slashin' in Hyper Light Breaker</h2>

<p>So I don't end up retreading old territory, be sure to check out <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/hyper-light-breaker-preview-your-next-roguelite-addiction" rel="nofollow">my preview</a> from June. I'll give the basics of <em>Hyper Lift Breaker</em>'s gameplay before I dive into some new thoughts from my cooperative session. It is, of course, <a href="https://techraptor.net/genre/roguelite" rel="nofollow">a roguelite</a>, so all the mechanics we expect from such a genre (metaprogression, random generation, tough difficulty, etc..) are there.</p>

<p>With a range of melee weaponry from swift striking claws to a one-handed sword, and guns from an electric shotgun to a large beam cannon, playstyles will differ vastly based on your kit. There's a lot of different weapons and I didn't have nearly enough time to try them out, but there's sure to be a great deal of variety for players.</p>

<p>The fact that <em>Hyper Light Breaker</em> drops in Early Access means there's going to be even more weapons, upgrades, and characters to play, so we're only seeing the beginning of things. Right now, players will be satisfied with the loot they might come across as they explore the large, randomly generated environments.</p>



<h2>Scouring the Ruins <em>of Hyper Light Breaker</em></h2>

<p>Speaking of environments, this is where <em>Hyper Light Breaker</em> shines. The world I explored during this demo was different than the one I played earlier this year. With two experienced co-op buddies tagging along, I got a better idea of where to look for loot.</p>

<p>There's a large amount of verticality in <em>Hyper Light Breaker</em>. In this vast, open map, ruins are scattered all over the environment and tower above the player. These ruins are massive, and a series of jump pads help players get to the top. My co-op partners explored every inch of these towers and we found loot tucked away, meaning a keen eye goes a long way.</p>



<p>It's quite marvelous to see just how high you can climb these ruins. At one point, we reached the top of a tower. There wasn't any loot, but I thought the scenery from being all the way at the top of the world was worth it. You could see various stunning landmarks, like a giant sword jutting out of the earth in the distance.</p>

<p>With a handy map, we chose our next destination and jumped off the tower. Like <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/legend-of-zelda-breath-of-wild-review-switching-things-up" rel="nofollow"><em>Breath of the Wild</em></a>, you can use a glider to slow your descent and prevent fall damage. Indeed, it feels like <em>Hyper Light Breaker</em> takes great inspiration from <em>Breath of the Wild</em>, with its open, almost directionless exploration and stamina meters.</p>



<h2><em>Hyper Light Breaker</em> Preview | Final Thoughts</h2>

<p>And again, fun is multiplied when friends are along for the ride. I can just imagine myself and some buddies checking out our map, charting where we want to go next. Taking on a bunch of foes is also a bit less daunting when you have two other players by your side.</p>

<p>We collected some keys scattered around this large map and unlocked a boss fight. Teleporting into an arena, this fearsome boss spawned a bunch of minions and a frantic fight to the death ensued. Whether you're in <em>Hyper Light Breaker</em> for its fast-paced, snappy combat or its grand exploration, you're bound to have fun.</p>

<p><em>Hyper Light Breaker</em> received a delay earlier this year, which was sad to see. Nonetheless, developers don't delay a game lightly and I'm sure <em>Hyper Light Breaker</em> is much better for it. Everything felt more polished from my first demo. Heart Machine is cooking up something special, and you won't have to wait long to play: <em>Hyper Light Breaker </em>launches in Early Access on January 14, 2025.</p>

<hr><p><em><strong>Hyper Light Breaker </strong>was previewed during an hour long play session on PC with a key provided by the publisher. All screenshots were provided by the publisher.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Austin cut his teeth writing various&nbsp; fan-fiction stories on the RuneScape forums when he was in elementary school. Later on, he developed a deep love for… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/austin-suther">More about Austin</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wizards Of The Coast VP Reveals Dungeons & Dragons 2024 Sales and Digital Usage]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/wizards-of-coast-vp-reveals-dungeons-dragons-2024-sales-and-digital-usage</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wizards-of-the-coast-vp-reveals-dungeons-dragons-2024-sales-and-digital-usage.1080963/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/wizards-of-coast-vp-reveals-dungeons-dragons-2024-sales-and-digital-usage<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Last week we got to hear from Jeremy Crawford and Wes Schneider, Co-Leads for the 2024 <em>Monster Manual</em>, about what we can expect when the third part of the 2024 Core Rulebooks release in a little over a month. Before that though Jess Lanzillo, VP of Franchise and Product for <em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em>, walked us through 2024 as a year for <em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em> including some interesting comparisons to the 2014 5th Edition release.</p>

<h2><em>D&amp;D</em> and D&amp;DBeyond in 2024</h2>

<p>Lanzillo began by discussing the way Wizards of the Coast have been tracking the sales for the 2024 Core Rulebooks released so far; the <em>Player's Handbook</em> in September 2024 and the <em>Dungeon Master's Guide</em> in November 2024. In the past four months these two books have already sold as many copies as it took the 2014 edition three years to meet including all language versions.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dd-2024-core-rulebooks.jpg?itok=OwOpkzsT 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dd-2024-core-rulebooks.jpg?itok=VyrHyN9d 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>This is an impressive amount of growth, but also not an incredibly surprising number considering the monumental boom that Dungeons &amp; Dragons has had in popularity over the past 10 years including the popularity of Actual Plays like <em><a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="a9a9913f-42e9-4189-bbde-08061c01a7e8" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/matthew-mercer-interview" rel="nofollow">Critical Role</a>, <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="55a80c6c-ea7c-4151-9523-d332db6f6cd5" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/interviews/how-brennan-lee-mulligan-created-never-stop-blowing-up-love-letter-to-80s" rel="nofollow">Dimension 20</a>, </em>and<em> <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="19bf4cd8-4ab1-421c-9264-de00ad57fcc0" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/discussing-start-of-acquisitions-incorporated-first-actual-play-with-jerry" rel="nofollow">Acquisitions Incorporated</a>,</em> the increase in play seen over the pandemic and past that, and even the releases of a movie and popular video games like Baldurs Gate III.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>You can check out our reviews for the <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="ed2ad5c2-7b7b-4a5a-84ff-eb15f1121885" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/dungeons-dragons-5e-2024-player-handbook-review-mixed-messaging-around-strong" rel="nofollow"><em>Player's Handboo</em></a>k and <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="56eebec3-a321-4403-b71c-54e4edf91d0c" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/dungeons-dragons-5e-2024-dungeon-masters-guide-review-true-dms-best-friend" rel="nofollow"><em>Dungeon Master's Guide</em></a>, and be sure to look out for a review of the Monster Manual before too long.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Lanzillo expressed that now that the final Core Book is almost released they're looking forward to 'finally beginning'.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>"We're going to have this really nice base of what's going to be setting up <em>D&amp;D</em> for the future. [...] It's going to be a springboard for all of the exciting stuff that we are going to be doing in the future."</p>
</blockquote>

<p>After discussing that Wizards of the Coast was happy with the engagement in the new Core Rulebooks Lanzillo discussed some other milestones that they were seeing across other D&amp;D related platforms.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ddbeyond-vtt.jpg?itok=_cTYeCIf 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ddbeyond-vtt.jpg?itok=85vBlW6B 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>For D&amp;DBeyond she was able to reveal that over 3.6 million characters have been made on D&amp;DBeyond with the 2024 ruleset, there are over 19 million registered users on D&amp;DBeyond, and that 1.3 million maps have been used in the D&amp;DBeyond VTT (This is not including the new 3D VTT that we know is on the way).</p>

<p>Lanzillo bookmarked all of the statements about <em>D&amp;D</em> and D&amp;DBeyond by mentioning that all of these milestones also don't include all of those who are playing the game completely physically.</p>

<h2>The Greater <em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em> Brand</h2>

<p>Talking about <em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em> outside of the Tabletop experience Lanzillo brought up the continued success of <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="2158b818-8ae7-45f2-997e-44a5977e48f4" href="https://techraptor.net/games/baldurs-gate-3" rel="nofollow"><em>Baldurs Gate III</em></a> which continues to be in the top 10 most played games on Steam and regularly breaks into 100K+ concurrent players. There was also mention of continued support from Larian into 2025 with new sub-class options.</p>

<p>Finally to wrap up the discussion on the D&amp;D Brand Lanzillo was able to reveal that in 2024 around 85 million fans have engaged in D&amp;D across movies, video games, merchandise purchases, or just by playing the game.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Andrew has written Video Game and Entertainment news, reviews, and guides for 10+ years. As Senior Content Manager, he assists in creating and editing… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/andrew-stretch">More about Andrew</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>