<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 23:30:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Clue: Peanuts Brings Childhood Charm to Classic Mystery Board Game]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/clue-peanuts-brings-childhood-charm-to-classic-mystery-board-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/clue-peanuts-brings-childhood-charm-to-classic-mystery-board-game.1121136/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/clue-peanuts-brings-childhood-charm-to-classic-mystery-board-game<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A new version of the iconic Clue board game is coming based on the world of Peanuts. The aptly named <em>Clue: Peanuts</em> reimagines the classic whodunnit mystery board game with the characters and iconography of the comic strip created by Charles Schulz.</p>

<h2>The <em>Clue: Peanuts</em> Announcement</h2>

<p>According to an official press release, the <em>Clue: Peanuts</em> board game is being developed by The Op under license of toy company giant <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/hasbro-unveils-new-playing-to-win-strategy-expanding-their-reach-to-more-players" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Hasbro</a>. The mystery at the heart of the game isn't a murder, but the disappearance of Linus' blanket. Players will step into the shoes of Snoopy, Charlie Brown, Lucy, and more to solve the classic Clue questions of Who, Where, and with What.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/clue-peanuts-game-board.jpg?itok=ezG2B3Hw 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/clue-peanuts-game-board.jpg?itok=qvw8MFI_ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The use of the <em>Peanuts'</em> license extends to the locations as well. Players will explore Lucy's psychiatric booth, the pumpkin patch, and Snoopy's doghouse to find clues, interrogate various supporting characters, and piece together the greater puzzle. The game is designed for 2-6 players ages 8 and up.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>“At The Op Games we believe happiness is…playing board games with friends and family,” said Dane Chapin, CEO of The Op Games. “We’re excited to add CLUE: PEANUTS Edition to our growing line of PEANUTS titles in this special anniversary year, and fans can look forward to more of Charlie Brown, Lucy, and Snoopy just around the corner.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Peanuts is a syndicated Sunday comic strip written and illustrated by Charles Schulz. It debuted in 1950 and continued until Schulz died in 2000. By that time the comic had circulated in thousands of magazines across 75 countries. It is considered one of the most influential comic strips in history for it cementing the four-panel gag comic format, alongside philosophically and psychologically complex humor.</p>

<p>The last major project featuring the Peanuts gang was an animated movie in 2015 developed by Blue Sky Studios. It received positive reviews and was the 7th highest grossing animated film of that year.</p>

<p><em>Clue: Peanuts</em> is available now at physical and online retailers. It is being sold at an MSRP of $44.99.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>