<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 17:51:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[High on Life 2 Preview – Squanch Games Faux Skater]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/high-on-life-2-preview-squanch-games-faux-skater</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/high-on-life-2-preview-%E2%80%93-squanch-games-faux-skater.1297191/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/high-on-life-review" rel="nofollow"><em>High on Life</em></a> seemingly had one guiding question that fueled every design decision: What's the funniest thing we can do here? It's the kind of over-the-top, wildly left-field humor that's in line with <em>Rick &amp; Morty</em>, as you'd expect, and <em>High on Life 2</em> takes those ideas to new heights.&nbsp;</p>

<p>I played it a few weeks ago at a Microsoft event during PAX West weekend, where we also chatted with Squanch Games COO Matty Studivan about this sequel that takes things to more radical places (in more ways than one).&nbsp;</p>

<p>In <em>High on Life 2</em>, you must use your intergalactic hitman abilities to take down a sci-fi-comedy metaphor for big pharma. The talking weapons from the first game return, though some new ones have joined the fray. Most interestingly, however, is that you can't sprint in this game. Instead, you skate.</p>



<h2>High on Laughs</h2>

<p>If you played the first game or have watched <em>Rick &amp; Morty</em>, you'll know exactly what to expect with <em>High on Life 2 </em>in terms of its narrative and character moments. A prime example from the demo I played is when I was infiltrating an area to assassinate my target.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Of course, the front door was guarded, so I had to sneak in through some other means. In most other games, you'd find that vent or elevator shaft and simply use it. Congratulations, you reached the next checkpoint.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In <em>High on Life 2</em>, I just went slightly to the right and found an elevator being worked on by maintenance. I approached the worker, heard a little of his spiel, and then walked past him to get in the elevator, which immediately broke.&nbsp;</p>

<p>From there, he asked if I could help him fix the elevator by hitting some buttons inside. At some point, he asks me to hold one button for 20 seconds, then while holding it, hit another button. Astute gamers might realize that there's only, in fact, one interact button.</p>

<p>So even if you follow the charade of counting to 20, you can't do it. And the worker says something that points out that you don't really have the capacity to hit two interact buttons.</p>



<p>In other words, it's meta comedy all the way down. That meta humor comes into play during a boss fight in the demo. I won't spoil it too much, but let's just say that it surpassed my expectations in terms of just how much Squanch Games is dedicated to obliterating the fourth wall. If this wouldn't risk legal trouble, I'm sure they would joke about deleting system32 to solve a puzzle.</p>

<p>Even the premise of <em>High on Life 2</em> lives on the line between absurd and ridiculous. My mission was to hunt down a fictional senator named Muppy Doo, who was giving a speech at a convention. So I had to go to the Convention Planet and go through Parking Con and Con Con (again, meta) to get to his convention. Of course, it was impossible to find parking at Parking Con.</p>



<h2>Love It or Skate It</h2>

<p>This kind of humor can be pretty polarizing; often it's either incredibly your thing or absolutely not your thing. Regardless, what's hard to deny is that the core gameplay itself is fun, amid all the jokes and jabs.</p>

<p>This first-person shooter feels more energetic and frantic than its prequel, and what really contributes to the frenetic pace is the new sprint mechanic. Instead of running, your character whips out a skateboard, immediately changing the trajectory of how you move.</p>

<p>It takes a bit to get used to just because it really does feel like riding a skateboard instead of sprinting in something like <em>Call of Duty</em>. Once you get the hang of it though, you can also leap onto walls and ride them for a bit. Rails can be grinded on, adding another option for cruising around an arena.</p>

<p>The talking weapons make a return here, as expected. They're arguably the heart and core of <em>High on Life</em>, providing both comedic relief and narrative advancement. Each has an alternate fire mode as well, which can doubly be used to solve certain puzzles in the environment.</p>

<p>The new weapon I found in the demo was a three-shot burst rifle named Sheath, and he's voiced by the buttery-brutal tones of Ralph Ineson. His alternate fire shoots out a giant spike, and you can chain it to multiple enemies to make them all collide into each other. It adds a nice amount of crowd control that comes in handy, especially when you get a little overwhelmed.</p>



<h2><em>High on Life 2</em> Preview | Final Thoughts</h2>

<p>At the end of the day, I think a lot of people interested in <em>High on Life 2 </em>already know exactly what they're signing up for. This is a comedy game first and foremost, which is both its greatest strength and greatest weakness. If you like quirky meta humor, you'll like this, but the equal and opposite is also true. At the very least, the tone seems consistent in the demo, and it will always stand out from the pack regarding all the first-person shooters out there.</p>

<p>Over the long term, I'm curious how well the narrative will land. Joking the entire time can potentially get old, and I personally ran out of steam partway through the first game. But with more exciting gameplay, maybe <em>High on Life 2</em> will have enough juice to keep things radical all the way to the end.&nbsp;</p>

<hr><p><em><strong>High on Life 2</strong> was previewed at an Xbox event in Redmond, WA, courtesy of Microsoft.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Robert Scarpinito is the Features Editor of TechRaptor. With a Bachelor of Arts in Journalism from the Ohio State University, sharing compelling stories is… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/robert-scarpinito">More about Robert</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/high-on-life-2-preview-squanch-games-faux-skater]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valor Mortis Preview – Bloodborne But Make It French]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/valor-mortis-preview-bloodborne-but-make-it-french</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valor-mortis-preview-%E2%80%93-bloodborne-but-make-it-french.1297170/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Polish studio One More Level made a good name for itself with <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/ghostrunner-2-review-run-ghost-run" rel="nofollow">the <em>Ghostrunner </em>franchise</a>, and now it's taking a stab at the ever-popular soulslike formula with its own twist. Enter <em>Valor Mortis</em>, which was revealed just weeks ago at Gamescom.</p>

<p>This upcoming game keeps the first-person perspective that One More Level is known for, but it swaps out the cyberpunk-ninja aesthetic for something a little more 19th century. You play as an English soldier in the French military (for story reasons), but there's some supernatural, bloodcurdling spooky stuff going on.</p>

<p>The combat feels intense and enjoyable, and the world presents this intriguing mystery that I want to learn more about when <em>Valor Mortis</em> releases in 2026.</p>



<h2>Shoot, Slice, Spark</h2>

<p>A majority of soulslikes, as you probably know, are in a third-person perspective, to account for the rapid movements of certain enemies and the endless dodge rolls you'll be doing. They can be frantic at times, so I was a little worried about how it'd feel in first person.</p>

<p><em>Valor Mortis</em>, however, threads the needle perfectly. Motions are clear, and I found a lot of clarity in the hitboxes between me and the enemies. Swinging the sword feels great, and the visual and audio feedback when you land a hit or parry is satisfying.</p>

<p>This game goes for the dual-wielding approach to combat, where your right hand is your sword while your left hand deals ranged attacks. I got a flintlock pistol early in the demo, but later, I found a power up that let me shoot magical fire. In some screenshots, I saw a full-on rifle too that requires two hands to wield.</p>



<p>If you keep up the pressure, you can break an enemy's stance, though parries do more damage to their stance meter. Once they're broken, you can do a critical hit that does massive damage, similar to other soulslikes.</p>

<p>I found that the dodge feels great, as well. It reminded me of the quick dash in <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/doom-eternal" rel="nofollow"><em>Doom Eternal</em></a>, and it was easy to position myself to wherever I needed around the enemies.</p>

<p>Otherwise, you've got all the usual soulslikes trappings here, too. There are totally-not-flasks to heal you, and they get replenished at totally-not-bonfires that also respawn all the enemies.</p>



<p>At the lamps, which are <em>Valor Mortis</em>'s bonfires, I could also upgrade my stats using a currency that enemies dropped. Most of them seemed a little boring at first, with basic upgrades like +6% endurance. I imagine in the long run, it'll add up nicely, but for a short 20-minute demo, there wasn't much to play with there.</p>

<p>The most exciting thing about the skill tree was that after you unlock a certain tier of it, you can equip something called an Amber into your tree. These can be found around the world, and they provide more powerful passive upgrades. I get the sense that in the full game, these will play a core part in crafting a build.</p>



<h2>Alt-History Europe That Isn't World War 2</h2>

<p>Aesthetically, <em>Valor Mortis</em> combines the grotesque body horror of <em>Bloodborne </em>with 19th-century French military garb. In fact, this game takes a stab an alternate history, but instead of tackling the trodden paths of World War 2, it looks at the Napoleonic Wars.</p>

<p>In this universe, Napoleon clinched the victory at Waterloo, continuing his conquest across Europe. Of course, there's more going on here—your character seems to have some sort of telepathic link to Napoleon, implying all sorts of supernatural spooky vibes. It's an intriguing story setup that makes me curious about the ramifications of a magical super Napoleon.</p>



<p>Where it really came together for me was when I ran into the first boss in the demo. It was a giant, fleshy mass of a formerly human soldier—or really, more like a group of soldiers mushed together.</p>

<p>It had three arms on its one shoulder, like a twisted pauldron. Each hand had a flintlock pistol, giving it a ranged attack, while its main arms twirled and thrusted a giant spear. In the second phase, it swapped the spear for a giant claw. In terms of design, it felt like the perfect mix of a From Software boss with the world that One More Level has crafted.</p>



<h2><em>Valor Mortis</em> Preview | Final Thoughts</h2>

<p><em>Valor Mortis</em> brings a unique premise to the well-worn soulslike formula, both in terms of gameplay and narrative. The moment-to-moment combat feels good, with just enough challenge to keep you on your toes.</p>

<p>The addition of magical powers and supernatural vibes adds a level of intrigue here, as well. It's not a straightforward alt-history romp. Instead, there's something more insidious at play here, and we'll learn more when <em>Valor Mortis</em> releases some time next year on PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X|S.</p>

<hr><p><em><strong>Valor Mortis</strong> was previewed on a PC at PAX West courtesy of the developers.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Robert Scarpinito is the Features Editor of TechRaptor. With a Bachelor of Arts in Journalism from the Ohio State University, sharing compelling stories is… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/robert-scarpinito">More about Robert</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/valor-mortis-preview-bloodborne-but-make-it-french]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Age of Sigmar Helsmiths of Hashut Army Set Review - Let Fire The Duardin Of War]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/age-of-sigmar-helsmiths-of-hashut-army-set-review-let-fire-duardin-of-war</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/age-of-sigmar-helsmiths-of-hashut-army-set-review-let-fire-the-duardin-of-war.1297128/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The Helsmiths of Hashut, the Chaos Duardin, have brooded for centuries on the wrongs done to them, but with the Hour of Ruin, they have emerged to claim back what's rightfully theirs, and they consider everything rightfully theirs.&nbsp; In this article, we check out the first <em>Age of Sigmar</em> release for the spiritual cousins of <em>Warhammer's</em> Chaos Dwarfs, the Helsmiths of Hashut Army Set.</p>

<p>We've been covering <i>Age of Sigmar </i>for a while on the site, and you can check out our review of the <em>Age of Sigmar</em> 4th Edition launch box <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/warhammer-age-of-sigmar-skaventide-review-perfect-starter-set" rel="nofollow">here</a>, and as the Helsmiths of Hashut Army Set also functions as their Spearhead force, you can check out our getting started with the Spearhead style of gaming <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/how-to-get-started-with-age-of-sigmar-4th-edition-with-spearhead" rel="nofollow">here</a>.</p>




<h2>What's In the Box</h2>

<p>The Helsmiths of Hashut Army Set acts as the perfect introductory set for the new faction, and contains all the rules for the full planned release of miniatures, along with containing a complete Spearhead force that can be used straight away while you flesh out your full&nbsp;<em>Age of Sigmar</em> army.</p>

<p>The full box contents are:</p>

<ul><li>Helsmiths of Hashut Battletome</li>
	<li>32 Helsmiths of Hashut Warscroll Cards</li>
	<li>Helsmiths of Hashut Transfer Sheet</li>
	<li>14 miniatures (War Despot, Dominator Engine, Tormentor Bombard, and 11 Infernal Cohort)</li>
</ul><figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/age-of-sigmar-helsmiths-of-hashut-army-set-2.jpg?itok=W2KgM3gL 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/age-of-sigmar-helsmiths-of-hashut-army-set-2.jpg?itok=1tnXRb-A 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The <em>Age of Sigmar</em> Helsmiths of Hashut Army Set includes a full Battletome, Warscrolls and Spearhead Force.</figcaption></figure><h2>The Tip Of The Glaive</h2>

<p>The Helsmiths of Hashut Spearhead force is a complete force for the Spearhead <em>Age of Sigmar</em> game type. This force can be used against any other <em>AoS</em> Spearhead box using the unique warscrolls for it.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Helsmiths' Spearhead force is led by a War Despot who boosts nearby units' ability to capture objectives. They're armed with a Daemonflame Glaive, with 5 attacks that hit and wound on a 3+. They're backed up by 2x 5 warrior units of sturdy Infernal Cohorts, one of which also has a Gong Carrier who can be removed to return D3 slain units to the battlefield, further adding to their resilience.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/age-of-sigmar-helsmiths-of-hashut-army-set-3.jpg?itok=rtbcYkSE 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/age-of-sigmar-helsmiths-of-hashut-army-set-3.jpg?itok=PHCbP7dp 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The<em> Age of Sigmar</em> Helsmiths of Hashut Army Set is led by a War Despot, backup by 2, 5 warrior Infernal Cohort units.</figcaption></figure><p>The real power of the force is the towering Dominator Engine and the Tormentor Bombard artillery piece. The Dominator is the fastest unit in this force, and its movement and attacks can also be boosted with demonic power points, which your force gains a growing number of each turn. It's immolation cannons start off with 5 attacks, each dealing D3 wounds. The Bombard has a range of 30 inches, but its attacks are also boosted for larger enemy units more than 12 inches away. It can also be used to reduce the control score of enemy units by allocating demonic power points to the Bombard, to stop them from scoring objectives.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/age-of-sigmar-helsmiths-of-hashut-army-set-4.jpg?itok=4CV0G8VA 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/age-of-sigmar-helsmiths-of-hashut-army-set-4.jpg?itok=ZLhk7kte 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The&nbsp;<em>Age of Sigmar</em> Helsmiths of Hashut Army Set Tormentor Bombard and Dominator engine give your force a huge punch.</figcaption></figure><h2>Thick Beards, Horns And Tusks</h2>

<p>On top of those in the Spearhead force, their Battletime details a number of durable and devastating units with which to grind their enemies down. Our favorites are the Infernal Razers, armed with Flamehurlers or Blunderbusses. The flamehurlers have a shorter range, but more attacks, and the blunderbusses have a slightly longer range, but are easier to wound and deal 2 damage each.</p>

<p>The Helsmiths also have Bull Centaurs, who, along with looking awesome, really capture the Helsmiths' cavalry aesthetic. They add 1 to their charge rolls for each demonic power point they have, and can also inflict extra mortal wounds by rolling a 6+ for each model in the charged unit, with the roll also boosted by the number of their demonic power points.</p>

<p>There's also an option for a different flavor of Dominator Engine, armed with Bane Maces for an entirely close combat experience of smashing your enemies into the ground, and for those who prefer range, the Deathshrikeker Rocket Battery adds another artillery option with 3 attacks dealing D3+2 wounds, with their Watch Them Burn reaction able to deal maximum damage to monsters or war machines.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/age-of-sigmar-helsmiths-of-hashut-army-set-5.jpg?itok=Ru3NZ1gm 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/age-of-sigmar-helsmiths-of-hashut-army-set-5.jpg?itok=ArUU7JwX 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Outside of the&nbsp;<em>Age of Sigmar</em> Helsmiths of Hashut Army Set, the Bull Centaurs offer a devastaing cavalry charge ahead of the duable infacntry units.</figcaption></figure><h2>Age of Sigmar Helsmiths of Hashut Final Thoughts?</h2>

<p>The Helsmiths of Hashut Army Set is a great start for the Chaos Duardin, and the Spearhead force it contains offers a great insight into their larger game. The Infernal Cohorts stand firm on objectives while the War Despot supports them, and then the Dominator Engine wreaks havoc, as the Tormentor Bombard rains down fire on units that look like they might score other objectives.&nbsp;The miniatures across the range really capture the feel of the Chaos Dwarves of old. Thick black beards and tusks standing proud, and the demonic weapons they carry add an eerie feel to them.&nbsp;</p>

<hr><p><em>The copy of the</em> <strong>Helsmiths of Hashut Army Set</strong>&nbsp;<em>used to produce this review was provided by Games Workshop.</em></p>


</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Adam is a Tabletop Specialist for TechRaptor. He started writing for TechRaptor in 2017 and took over as Tabletop Editor in 2019 and has since stood down… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/adam-potts">More about Adam</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/age-of-sigmar-helsmiths-of-hashut-army-set-review-let-fire-duardin-of-war]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>