<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 00:48:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dungeons of Drakkenheim: Daggerheart Triumphs on Kickstarter, Hitting Funding Goal in 13 Minutes]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/dungeons-of-drakkenheim-daggerheart-triumphs-on-kickstarter-hitting-funding-goal-in</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dungeons-of-drakkenheim-daggerheart-triumphs-on-kickstarter-hitting-funding-goal-in-13-minutes.1343905/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="page-content">
  
          
      
<article role="article">

  
    

  
  <div>
      
  
  
  <div>
      <div><p>The newest crowdfunding campaign by the <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="6d78830c-46d2-4911-8370-fd1532625bb8" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/dungeon-dudes-talk-dungeons-of-drakkenheim-on-dd-beyond-what-to-expect-and" rel="nofollow">Dungeon Dudes</a> has gone live. The aptly named <em>Dungeons of Drakkenheim: Daggerheart</em> aims to adapt the award-winning campaign to Darrington Press' fantasy TTRPG. It was fully funded in just 13 minutes.</p>

<h2>The <em>Dungeons of Drakkenheim: Daggerheart</em> Campaign</h2>

<p>According to the official campaign page, <em>Dungeons of Drakkenheim: Daggerheart</em> will bring every faction, intrigue, and horror of the original campaign to Darrington Press' <em>Daggerheart</em> system.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dungeons-of-drakkenheim-daggerheart-contaminated-cards.jpg?itok=Hf9NT5Fq 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dungeons-of-drakkenheim-daggerheart-contaminated-cards.jpg?itok=mPt53uEy 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>This will not be a simple conversion. Joining the Dungeon Dudes' team on this project is <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/daggerheart-review-narrative-forward-yes-and-ttrpg-that-is-force-to-be-reckoned" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Daggerheart</em></a> designer, Mike Underwood. This is to ensure this adaptation is built from the ground up to retain the excitement and intensity of the original <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/dungeons-of-drakkenheim-now-available-on-dd-beyond" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Dungeons of Drakkenheim</em></a> experience. Said experience is a sandbox-style campaign designed for characters at levels 1-10.</p>

<p>For enterprising GMs, the <em>Dungeons of Drakkenheim: Daggerheart</em> campaign will include official mechanics for the game's contaminations, mutations, and anomalies. This is because the titular Drakkenheim setting is a wasteland ravaged by an eldritch storm of otherworldly magic. These can be used as intended in this campaign, or can be adapted into your own home game of <em>Daggerheart</em>.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>To learn more about <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="6d78830c-46d2-4911-8370-fd1532625bb8" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/dungeon-dudes-talk-dungeons-of-drakkenheim-on-dd-beyond-what-to-expect-and" rel="nofollow">Dungeons of Drakkenheim check out our interview with the Dungeon Dudes</a> from last year.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>One of these mechanics is the new Contaminated Domain cards. As your characters' contamination rises, they lose equal levels of Hope, a vital resource in <em>Daggerheart</em>. The trade-off is access to new card abilities, which you must give the GM Fear to use. Fear a GM can use to make the next challenge more harrowing.</p>

<p>The pledge tiers for <em>Dungeons of Drakkenheim: Daggerheart</em> are as follows:</p>

<ul><li><strong>Digital for $30:</strong> A PDF of the campaign guide, character sheets, and a set of miniature STLs</li>
	<li><strong>Core Book for $60:</strong> Everything in the Digital tier, a physical campaign book, a poster set, and a set of resin miniatures</li>
	<li><strong>Digital Deluxe for $70:</strong> Everything from the Digital tier, digital card deck, digital GM cheat sheets, and VTT access on Demiplane and Roll20</li>
	<li><strong>Core Set for $170:</strong> Everything from the Core Book and Digital Deluxe tier, a physical GM Screen, a set of resin dice, a card deck, and an STL file for a Fear Tracker</li>
	<li><strong>Deluxe Set for $295:</strong> Everything from the Core Set tier, a physical Special Edition campaign book, a premium dice tray, and a unique set of gemstone dice</li>
</ul><p>At the time of writing, the <em>Dungeons of Drakkenheim: Daggerheart</em> campaign has raised&nbsp;<span><span>$123,612, more than six times its initial funding goal. The campaign ends on November 28..</span></span></p>
</div>


<div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div>

    </div>
  
  
  
  <div>
  <ul>
    <p>Additional topics:</p>
          <p>
        <li><a href="https://techraptor.net/topic/announcement" hreflang="en">Announcement</a></li>
      </p>
          <p>
        <li><a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/rpg-0" hreflang="en">RPG</a></li>
      </p>
      </ul>
</div>
  

  </div>

</article>

  </div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/dungeons-of-drakkenheim-daggerheart-triumphs-on-kickstarter-hitting-funding-goal-in]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>