<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 13:40:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Broken Arrow Release Date Finally Revealed After Four Years]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/broken-arrow-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/broken-arrow-release-date-finally-revealed-after-four-years.1176246/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/broken-arrow-release-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer Steel Balalaika and publisher Slitherine Games have announced the&nbsp;<em>Broken Arrow&nbsp;</em>release date, just about four years after the fast-paced tactical RTS was initially announced.</p>

<p>As revealed in a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1604270/view/537726178354528747" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">post</a> on Steam,&nbsp;<em>Broken Arrow</em>, described by the two studios as "the most wishlisted strategy game on Steam" (although its wishlists do still pale in comparison to the likes of the <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/hollow-knight-silksong" rel="nofollow">still-absent&nbsp;<em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em></a>), launches on June 19th.</p>

<p>The game, which was originally revealed all the way back in May 2021, will set you back $49.99 when it's released, but it won't be an Early Access release, unusually; it'll be arriving fully formed.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/broken-arrow-release-date-tank.jpg?itok=aiOoSwq- 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/broken-arrow-release-date-tank.jpg?itok=RCCWdcFb 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Fast-paced tactical RTS&nbsp;<em>Broken Arrow&nbsp;</em>is finally arriving this June.</figcaption></figure><p>As well as revealing the release date, Slitherine and Steel Balalaika have also unveiled a new edition of&nbsp;<em>Broken Arrow&nbsp;</em>for which pre-orders are now open.</p>

<p>The Vanguard Edition will set you back $10 extra, and it packs in that now-common three-day early access (as opposed to Early Access) period, allowing you to play&nbsp;<em>Broken Arrow&nbsp;</em>three days ahead of everyone else.</p>

<p>You'll also get a digital soundtrack comprising 41 "intense and energetic bangers", as well as nine "beautiful" digital wallpapers representing&nbsp;<em>Broken Arrow</em>'s "specialization decks". On top of that, you'll get exclusive vehicle skins too.</p>

<p>If you want to know more about&nbsp;<em>Broken Arrow</em>, you can tune into Slitherine's <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/slitherinetv/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Twitch channel</a> tomorrow at 10am Eastern, where the studio will be showcasing a "never-shown-before mission" in the form of Kaliningrad.</p>




<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Broken Arrow</em>, its developers describe it as a "large-scale real-time modern warfare tactics game" that features "a unique army building system and deep unit customization tools".</p>

<p>The game will feature two major factions, the Americans and the Russians, as well as a full-scale campaign. You'll even be able to use the same scenario editor used to create the campaign's missions to make your own scenarios.</p>

<p><em>Broken Arrow&nbsp;</em>launches on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1604270/Broken_Arrow/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC via Steam</a> on June 19th.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wuchang: Fallen Feathers Release Date Set for July]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/wuchang-fallen-feathers-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wuchang-fallen-feathers-release-date-set-for-july.1176198/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/wuchang-fallen-feathers-release-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer Leenzee and publisher 505 Games have announced the release date for upcoming China-set Soulslike&nbsp;<em>Wuchang: Fallen Feathers</em>, and it's adding to what will already be a pretty stacked summer.</p>

<p>Per a Steam <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2277560/view/498319683381887449" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">post</a>, the game will be launching on July 24th across PC and current-gen consoles. It joins the likes of shooter&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/robocop-rogue-city-unfinished-business-release-date" rel="nofollow">RoboCop: Rogue City - Unfinished Business</a>&nbsp;</em>and cozy hobbit life sim&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tales-of-shire-delayed-july" rel="nofollow"><em>Tales of the Shire</em></a>.</p>

<p>As is customary for modern games, pre-ordering&nbsp;<em>Wuchang: Fallen Feathers&nbsp;</em>will also get you some extra goodies. You'll receive two outfits, a new weapon, and a Glistening Mercury upgrade item if you place your order before the game's launch.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/wuchang-fallen-feathers-release-date-combat.jpg?itok=NnNL2VC0 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/wuchang-fallen-feathers-release-date-combat.jpg?itok=SwuDFnk9 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Wuchang: Fallen Feathers&nbsp;</em>lands in July. This guy, on the other hand, looks like he's landing a lot sooner than that.</figcaption></figure><p>A Deluxe Edition of&nbsp;<em>Wuchang: Fallen Feathers&nbsp;</em>will also be available, and it'll net you four more outfits and four weapons, as well as a Blood of Changhong skill upgrade item. Of course, you'll be able to obtain plenty of those items throughout your journey, but it's nice to have a headstart.</p>

<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Wuchang: Fallen Feathers</em>, it's a Soulslike action RPG set in the Shu kingdom during the late Ming dynasty. You'll play as the titular Wuchang, a pirate "struck by amnesia" who must contend both with her uncertain past and a horrific disease known as the Feathering.</p>

<p>Along the way, you'll face "grotesque abominations", explore "forgotten temples" and "overgrown ruins", and "piece together Wuchang's lost memories". It all sounds pretty much par for the course when it comes to Soulslikes.</p>

<p>You can check out a new trailer for&nbsp;<em>Wuchang: Fallen Feathers</em>, which shows off a rather unsettling boss by the name of the Perfect Bride, right here.</p>




<p><em>Wuchang: Fallen Feathers&nbsp;</em>launches across <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2277560/WUCHANG_Fallen_Feathers/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/concept/10005853" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/wuchang-fallen-feathers/9nprhd8gqkqs" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a> on July 24th. It'll also be available as part of a Game Pass subscription if you're signed up to the PC or Ultimate tiers.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>