<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 15:40:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mafia: The Old Country Release Date Confirmed for August]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/mafia-old-country-release-date-confirmed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mafia-the-old-country-release-date-confirmed-for-august.1184397/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/mafia-old-country-release-date-confirmed<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>2K and Hangar 13 have revealed the&nbsp;<em>Mafia: The Old Country&nbsp;</em>release date, and just as we suspected, the latest entry in the long-running crime drama saga will be arriving in summer.</p>

<p>Per a new trailer,&nbsp;<em>Mafia: The Old Country&nbsp;</em>arrives on August 8th, which is the release date that was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/mafia-old-country-release-date-seemingly-leaked" rel="nofollow">mistakenly leaked via Steam</a> back in April before being hastily removed from the page. Who'd have thunk it would turn out to be real?</p>

<p>In any case, the release date was revealed alongside a brand new gameplay trailer, and...well, yep,&nbsp;<em>Mafia: The Old Country&nbsp;</em>sure does look like a&nbsp;<em>Mafia&nbsp;</em>game, so you probably already know whether you'll like it or not.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/mafia-the-old-country-release-date-driving.jpg?itok=yVeTyffj 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/mafia-the-old-country-release-date-driving.jpg?itok=E5nul8aN 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Mafia: The Old Country&nbsp;</em>has plenty of activities that you'll be familiar with if you're a series fan.</figcaption></figure><p>Over the course of the trailer (which, disappointingly, does feature people speaking in thick Italian-accented English rather than Italian), we see plenty of the usual action-adventure staples; stealth, driving sequences, shootouts, and, of course, squeezing through narrow passageways.</p>

<p>We also see the player engaging in a knife fight with an opponent, as well as riding on horseback, so it looks like you won't just be traversing the Sicilian countryside in your ye olde 1900s car.</p>

<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Mafia: The Old Country</em>, it's a prequel to the first three&nbsp;<em>Mafia&nbsp;</em>games. Taking place in 1900s Sicily, it sees you playing as Enzo Favara, a man looking to make good with the Torrisi crime family after "a brutal childhood of forced labor".</p>

<p>Like previous&nbsp;<em>Mafia&nbsp;</em>games, it looks like&nbsp;<em>The Old Country&nbsp;</em>is emphasizing its cinematic credentials, so don't expect any&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/second-grand-theft-auto-vi-trailer" rel="nofollow"><em>GTA</em>-style</a> emergent open-world shenanigans here. In fact, this one <a href="https://mafia.2k.com/the-old-country/faq/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">won't be open-world</a> like previous games in the series.</p>




<p><em>Mafia: The Old Country&nbsp;</em>launches on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1941540/Mafia_The_Old_Country/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/mafia-the-old-country/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/mafia-the-old-country/9P834N9S4LL0" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a> on August 8th. Stay tuned for more on this one.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Expects to Sell 15m Switch 2 Units in First Year]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-15m-switch-2-first-year</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-expects-to-sell-15m-switch-2-units-in-first-year.1184340/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-15m-switch-2-first-year<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Nintendo has revealed the number of Switch 2 consoles it expects to sell within the machine's first year on sale, and it's safe to say the Japanese gaming giant isn't underselling its newest hardware.</p>

<p>In the company's financial summary for the 2024-25 fiscal year, Nintendo reveals that it expects to shift a staggering 15 million Switch 2 units before April next year, which gives the console around nine months to achieve that figure.</p>

<p>Software-wise, Nintendo says it expects to sell around 45 million software units in that time as well. It's worth noting that this figure doesn't include original Switch games; Nintendo is expecting to sell a staggering 105 million of those before April.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/nintendo-switch-2-first-year-15m-docked.jpg?itok=ZbR9Ycrd 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/nintendo-switch-2-first-year-15m-docked.jpg?itok=ndeuZnOP 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Nintendo is expecting to sell a heck of a lot of Switch 2 units.</figcaption></figure><p>Nintendo's prediction is in line with a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-switch-2-20m-shipments-report" rel="nofollow">Bloomberg report</a> earlier this year, which stated that the company was preparing to ship "more than 20 million units" in the console's first year. That would give the Switch 2 an additional three months to reach the 20 million figure, which sounds about right.</p>

<p>Interestingly enough, Nintendo also says it expects to sell about 4.5 million original Switch consoles this financial year. I suppose not everyone is going to flock to buy the newest machine, and there are still a few people left in the world who don't own a Switch.</p>

<p>Nintendo will no doubt be hoping that its predictions about the Switch 2 are correct, because sales aren't looking great. They're down 30% on last year, with profit falling 43% as well.</p>

<p>It is, of course, worth noting that the last twelve months haven't exactly seen a slew of high-profile first-party Nintendo releases to bolster sales, although&nbsp;<em>Super Mario Party Jamboree&nbsp;</em>and<i>&nbsp;The Legend of Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom&nbsp;</i>have <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/zelda-echoes-of-wisdom-sales-nintendo-financials" rel="nofollow">certainly attempted to pull their weight</a> in this regard.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/zelda-echoes-of-wisdom-switch-2-15m-units.jpg?itok=IHVDvREQ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/zelda-echoes-of-wisdom-switch-2-15m-units.jpg?itok=N-w02qgM 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>The Legend of Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom&nbsp;</em>wasn't able to save Nintendo from falling sales this year.</figcaption></figure><p>Since Nintendo is at the end of a console's life cycle, a drop in sales is also to be expected, and I'm sure the company isn't exactly quaking in its boots when the Switch 2's launch is just around the corner.</p>

<p>You can check out Nintendo's <a href="https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/pdf/2025/250508_4e.pdf" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">full financial summary for the year here</a> if you want to see some more numbers. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>