<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 16:07:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ZeniMax QA Union Goes on Strike Over Outsourcing and Remote Work]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/zenimax-qa-union-strike</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zenimax-qa-union-goes-on-strike-over-outsourcing-and-remote-work.1034748/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/zenimax-qa-union-strike<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>ZeniMax Workers United, a gaming union consisting of quality assurance workers from across the studios of Bethesda's parent company, is going on strike today over what it alleges to be excessive outsourcing of QA on parent company Microsoft's part.</p>

<p>As revealed in <a href="https://x.com/ZeniMaxWorkers/status/1856714377992278336" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">a post on X (formerly Twitter)</a>, the union wants Microsoft to "meet [it] at the bargaining table over key issues like remote work options and outsourcing", <a href="https://x.com/ZeniMaxWorkers/status/1856714480413003983" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">demanding</a> "job security and improved working conditions".</p>

<p>In an <a href="https://www.inverse.com/gaming/bethesda-strike-zenimax-xbox-microsoft" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Inverse report</a>, QA test lead Rhyanna Eichner says ZeniMax Workers United members are "all really looking forward to coming together and spending time together", and that "this is what needs to be done to move on".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/the-elder-scrolls-online-zenimax-workers-united-strike.jpg?itok=iLZ6m1w6 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/the-elder-scrolls-online-zenimax-workers-united-strike.jpg?itok=Dg4PltUN 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>ZeniMax Workers United comprises QA workers of all stripes from across Bethesda's offices.</figcaption></figure><p>Eichner also says that the union is striking over its parent company's remote work proposals, which she says are not good enough. She says Microsoft has "continually given us their first proposal again and again", and that it's obvious to her the union's "different mobilization tactics have not worked".</p>

<p>Senior QA tester Juniper Dowell adds that many employees would be forced to consider alternative employment if they were required to be at the office five days a week because they were hired under remote working conditions.</p>

<p>Dowell says that while striking "isn't fun or ideal", there's a "satisfaction in having a concrete physical action" to help the union and its members "fight for better work conditions". She's hoping that Microsoft and ZeniMax will "stop dragging their feet and meet us at the table".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/bethesda-zenimax-workers-united-strike-starfield.jpg?itok=mv-ewWrh 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/bethesda-zenimax-workers-united-strike-starfield.jpg?itok=OoFPjxfo 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>ZeniMax Workers United wants to negotiate for better remote working policies and less QA outsourcing.</figcaption></figure><p>ZeniMax's union isn't the only one to go on strike in recent months. Last week, employees at French studio Don't Nod <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dont-nod-employees-strike" rel="nofollow">went on strike</a> following the announcement that almost 70 jobs at their studio could be at risk, with remote working policies also on the list of issues employees raised.</p>

<p>Gaming giant Ubisoft also <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ubisoft-strike-investor-letter" rel="nofollow">faced a strike in October</a>, again in part over remote working policies, as well as what the employees involved perceived to be inadequate salaries.</p>

<p>ZeniMax Workers United's strike will last a single day, running between 10am and 6pm local time. We'll have to wait and see whether Microsoft and ZeniMax pay enough attention for negotiations to truly begin.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GOG Preservation Program Aims to Make Your Games "Live Forever"]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gog-preservation-program</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gog-preservation-program-aims-to-make-your-games-live-forever.1034688/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gog-preservation-program<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>GOG has announced the GOG Preservation Program, an initiative that aims to keep certain games playable forever no matter whether their developers are still supporting them or not.</p>

<p>Over on the official Preservation Program <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/gog-preservation-program" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">website</a>, the company warns that "time is erasing the games that shaped you", but that "we can fight back" through the program, which "ensures classic games remain playable on modern systems".</p>

<p>According to GOG, games that belong to the initiative will be DRM-free and eligible for "dedicated tech support", so even if something does go wrong, you'll be able to get help to fix it.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/gog-preservation-program-games.jpg?itok=8mrmRJ9h 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/gog-preservation-program-games.jpg?itok=jt7K9zVg 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The GOG Preservation Program currently covers 100 games, and more are coming.</figcaption></figure><p>In a <a href="https://x.com/GOGcom/status/1856698605563793789" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">followup thread on X</a> (formerly Twitter), GOG says that the initiative features "updated, improved, or quality-tested builds", and that if you see the Preservation Program stamp on a game's GOG page, that means you'll be able to enjoy it on your PC "hassle-free".</p>

<p>Games currently included in the program include the likes of the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/resident-evil-3-classic-gog-re-release" rel="nofollow">original three&nbsp;<em>Resident Evil&nbsp;</em>games</a>, the original&nbsp;<em>Diablo&nbsp;</em>and its&nbsp;<em>Hellfire&nbsp;</em>expansion, and&nbsp;<em>Heroes of Might and Magic 3</em>, as well as&nbsp;<em>Legacy of Kain: Defiance</em>,&nbsp;<em>Dragon Age: Origins</em>, and more.</p>

<p>GOG cites the Video Game History Foundation as saying that "87% of games created before 2010 are inaccessible today", a sobering statistic that demonstrates just how necessary an initiative like this really is.</p>




<p>You'll also find an FAQ on the Preservation Program's website that provides more information about the initiative. It includes info like what to do when a stamped game doesn't work, as well as whether classic GOG games are necessarily worse than those included in the Program (the answer being no, of course).</p>

<p>GOG says it wants "hundreds of games" to come with the GOG Preservation Program stamp by the end of 2025, so you can expect lots more games to be added to this initiative as time goes on. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Handheld Officially Confirmed by Phil Spencer, but It's Years Away]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/xbox-handheld-confirmed-but-years-away</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-handheld-officially-confirmed-by-phil-spencer-but-its-years-away.1034637/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/xbox-handheld-confirmed-but-years-away<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Xbox head Phil Spencer has officially confirmed that an Xbox handheld is in the works, although that announcement does, as you would expect, carry several pretty heavy caveats.</p>

<p>Speaking to <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-11-13/microsoft-s-gaming-chief-is-still-looking-for-acquisitions-sees-future-growth" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Bloomberg</a>, Spencer said that the "expectation" is that Xbox would create some kind of hardware in the handheld category. Bloomberg says that Xbox is "working on prototypes", but that the final release of any kind of Xbox handheld device is "a few years out".</p>

<p>An Xbox handheld (that is to say one created officially by Xbox, rather than one simply <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/logitech-and-tencent-cloud-gaming-handheld-images-possibly-leaked" rel="nofollow">designed to play</a> Xbox cloud games) has long been rumored, but this is the first official confirmation we've had from anyone on Xbox's side.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/asus-rog-ally-xbox-handheld.jpg?itok=qhbTOxyk 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/asus-rog-ally-xbox-handheld.jpg?itok=gnSjnz5M 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>There are handheld devices that play Xbox games on the market, but we now know that an official Xbox handheld is in the works.</figcaption></figure><p>Rather than focusing on the handheld, Xbox engineers will instead work to improve the Xbox app on existing devices. Spencer told Bloomberg there was room for improvement with regards to the Xbox app, and that any potential handheld needs to be "informed by learning and what's happening now".</p>

<p>Elsewhere in the interview, Spencer reveals a couple of other interesting tidbits regarding Xbox's strategy. He reiterates that there are no "red lines" dictating which games could or couldn't come to non-Xbox platforms, but says that it's too early to talk about whether&nbsp;<em>Halo&nbsp;</em>could go multiplatform.</p>

<p>Spencer also confirms that Microsoft and Xbox are still looking at more acquisitions, which puts recent <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/microsoft-ceo-payrise-layoffs" rel="nofollow">sweeping layoffs</a> and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/microsoft-arkane-austin-tango-gameworks-shutdown" rel="nofollow">studio closures</a> at Microsoft into somewhat stark relief if you ask me.</p>

<p>Then again, Xbox arguably has a history of saying seemingly contradictory things after making big decisions. Remember when Matt Booty said Xbox <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/xbox-smaller-games-comment-hi-fi-rush" rel="nofollow">needed "smaller games"</a> right after closing two studios that would have been ideally situated to make them? Me too.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/redfall-xbox-arkane-closure.jpg?itok=p9SgA1Jz 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/redfall-xbox-arkane-closure.jpg?itok=34aX7k45 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Even after closing two studios earlier this year, Microsoft still says it's considering more acquisitions.</figcaption></figure><p>Spencer also confirms in the Bloomberg interview that the planned Xbox mobile store, which was originally announced in May with a July release window, has been delayed.</p>

<p>He says that an approach in which Microsoft simply hopes that "if we build it, they will come" won't work, and so the challenge is trying to figure out how to get consumers to find the Xbox store amongst stiff competition.</p>

<p>It should be noted that this is distinct from Xbox allowing you to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/xbox-android-app-games" rel="nofollow">buy and play games via its own app</a>, a feature that Xbox president Sarah Bond announced would be implemented following <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/epic-google-victory-play-store" rel="nofollow">a ruling in an Epic-Google lawsuit</a> that also proved favorable to Microsoft.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Outlanders Is an Open-World Mobile RPG from Tencent and Capcom]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-outlanders-mobile-rpg</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-outlanders-is-an-open-world-mobile-rpg-from-tencent-and-capcom.1034622/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-outlanders-mobile-rpg<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Capcom and Tencent subsidiary TiMi Studio Group have announced&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Outlanders</em>, an open-world action RPG set to be released for mobile devices.</p>

<p>The two studios describe&nbsp;<em>Outlanders&nbsp;</em>as an "open-world survival game set in the&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter&nbsp;</em>universe", and you'll be able to do all of the things you'd expect from a&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter&nbsp;</em>game, including discovering ecosystems, crafting gear, and hunting alongside your friends.</p>

<p>We don't have a release date for&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Outlanders&nbsp;</em>yet, but TiMi and Capcom say they will be conducting "several play tests in advance", although those don't have dates yet either, unfortunately. The goal with the game is to create a mobile experience you can enjoy "with friends, anytime and anywhere".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/monster-hunter-outlanders-gliding.jpg?itok=CKAskoKS 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/monster-hunter-outlanders-gliding.jpg?itok=Q6GMqsIK 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Monster Hunter Outlanders&nbsp;</em>is an open-world mobile survival RPG from TiMi and Capcom.</figcaption></figure><p>The screenshots TiMi and Capcom have released so far show a game that looks...well, a lot like a traditional&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter&nbsp;</em>game. Expect open-ended areas to explore, monsters to take down, and lots of elaborate, ostentatious armor and weapons to build from monsters' remains.</p>

<p>The two studios are promising "natural environments [and] ecosystems" to discover, so like classic&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter</em>, you'll probably be able to observe monsters as they go about their daily lives before you start your hunt.</p>

<p>If you're interested in&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Outlanders</em>, you can sign up for email announcements via the <a href="https://monsterhunteroutlanders.com/en/index.html" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">newly-created official website</a>, which also displays some rather evocative concept art.</p>




<p>The reveal of&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Outlanders&nbsp;</em>comes as Capcom gets ready to release&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>, the next mainline entry in the franchise, which is scheduled to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-release-date" rel="nofollow">arrive across PC and consoles in February</a>.</p>

<p>It's shaping up to be a pretty big success already; an open beta was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta" rel="nofollow">held earlier this month</a>, and the beta alone <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta-steam-records" rel="nofollow">broke the series' Steam player count record</a> despite not being a full game.</p>

<p>We don't yet have an official release date or window for&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Outlanders</em>, so watch this space for more info as and when we get it.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>