<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 16:26:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Frosthaven Early Access Roadmap Promises New Heroes, Storylines, and More]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/frosthaven-early-access-roadmap</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/frosthaven-early-access-roadmap-promises-new-heroes-storylines-and-more.1290051/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer Snapshot Games and publisher Arc Games have revealed their&nbsp;<em>Frosthaven&nbsp;</em>Early Access roadmap, showing off what's coming to the turn-based tabletop adaptation over the next year or so.</p>

<p>The&nbsp;<em>Frosthaven&nbsp;</em>adaptation was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/frosthaven-video-game-adaptation-announced" rel="nofollow">first announced back in March</a>, then released in Early Access at the end of July. Now, Snapshot and Arc have unveiled what's coming to the game over the next few months, and you're getting new heroes, new storylines, and much more.</p>

<p>First up, in October, a major update will arrive that adds the game's Unfettered storyline, as well as new playable heroes, new summons, and new quests. You can also look forward to two new features in the form of Challenges and Job Postings.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/frosthaven-early-access-roadmap-full.jpg?itok=c7Pn9PLh 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/frosthaven-early-access-roadmap-full.jpg?itok=Sp3HzUHY 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Plenty is on the way to&nbsp;<em>Frosthaven&nbsp;</em>over the next few months.</figcaption></figure><p>Following that, another big update will be arriving in January, bringing yet more heroes, summons, and quests, as well as the Algox storyline for you to enjoy. You can also expect new bosses, new Challenges, and new environments.</p>

<p>April brings more heroes and quests, as well as new items and building upgrades. The Lurker storyline will also be added as part of this update. Finally (for this roadmap, at least), July will wrap up&nbsp;<em>Frosthaven</em>'s main story, as well as bringing lots more of the goodies other months have added to the game.</p>

<p><em>Frosthaven</em>'s Steam page proclaims that the game will remain in Early Access for "approximately one year", but that "this can change depending on player feedback". The current roadmap, however, would suggest that a July 2026 release date is on the cards for the game's 1.0 version.</p>




<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Frosthaven</em>, it's a video game adaptation of Isaac Childres' tabletop RPG&nbsp;<em>Frosthaven</em>, which itself serves as a sequel to&nbsp;<em>Gloomhaven</em>.</p>

<p>The original tabletop game proved phenomenally popular; it was, for a time, <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/frosthaven-kickstarter-is-most-funded-board-game-on-platform" rel="nofollow">Kickstarter's most-funded tabletop project</a>, before being surpassed by Brandon Sanderson's <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/brandon-sandersons-cosmere-rpg-kickstarter-raised-5-million-in-one-day" rel="nofollow">hugely successful&nbsp;<em>Cosmere&nbsp;RPG&nbsp;</em>campaign</a>.</p>

<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Frosthaven&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2347080/Frosthaven/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC via Steam Early Access</a>, and if you want to know whether it's worth your time, you can take a look at our very own Andrew Stretch's <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/previews/frosthavens-video-game-adaptation-creates-no-fuss-experience-at-sgf-2025" rel="nofollow">preview right here</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/frosthaven-early-access-roadmap]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>