<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:44:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Path of Exile 2 Update 0.1.1 Full Patch Notes Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/path-of-exile-2-update-011-full-patch-notes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/path-of-exile-2-update-0-1-1-full-patch-notes-revealed.1084038/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/path-of-exile-2-update-011-full-patch-notes<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Path of Exile 2&nbsp;</em>Update 0.1.1 lands tomorrow, and Grinding Gear Games has revealed the official full patch notes ahead of the update's release.</p>

<p>You can expect an update that's roughly on a similar scale to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/path-of-exile-2-update-010e" rel="nofollow">December's Update 0.1.0e</a>; while there's no single massive feature that will completely overhaul&nbsp;<em>Path of Exile 2</em>'s gameplay, there are tons of smaller changes that should result in a smoother experience.</p>

<p>Four new endgame tower map areas have been introduced in the form of Alpine Ridge, Bluff, Mesa, and Sinking Spire, and the Lost Towers map has been revamped in order to make it a little more interesting to explore.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/path-of-exile-2-update-0.1.1-tower.jpg?itok=tnyqoAUN 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/path-of-exile-2-update-0.1.1-tower.jpg?itok=EVJA7PK0 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Path of Exile 2&nbsp;</em>Update 0.1.1 brings changes to the endgame, plus lots more.</figcaption></figure><p>The Arbiter of Ash boss fight has also been redesigned so that you'll have more attempts; rather than only getting to try this boss once, you can now tackle it up to six times, with higher difficulties lowering the number of respawns you get.</p>

<p>Other changes have also been made to this boss fight; the falling flame seed skill can't be interrupted anymore, and the boss is now invulnerable for a longer duration after emerging.</p>

<p>As you might expect, the new&nbsp;<em>Path of Exile 2&nbsp;</em>update has an absolute ton of changes besides the ones I've listed here, so if you want to see the full changelog, you can check out the <a href="https://www.pathofexile.com/forum/view-thread/3695606" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">patch notes via the game's official forum</a>.</p>




<p><em>Path of Exile 2&nbsp;</em>is, believe it or not, the sequel to the original&nbsp;<em>Path of Exile</em>. Like its predecessor, the game is an action RPG, but unlike its predecessor, it's not free-to-play;&nbsp;<em>Path of Exile 2&nbsp;</em>started out as a massive update for the original game before its devs realized it was big enough to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/path-of-exile-2-will-be-standalone-game-closed-beta-date-gameplay-revealed" rel="nofollow">spin off into a separate title</a>.</p>

<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Path of Exile 2&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2694490/Path_of_Exile_2/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/path-of-exile-2/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/path-of-exile-2-game-preview/9ND8N4RW5GHX" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>, and Update 0.1.1 lands tomorrow. Make sure to take a look at our <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/path-of-exile-2-hands-on-preview-pax-east-2024" rel="nofollow">hands-on preview</a> to find out what we thought of this action RPG sequel.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024 TechRaptor Awards - Indie Game of the Year]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/2024-techraptor-awards-indie-game-of-year</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/2024-techraptor-awards-indie-game-of-the-year.1083954/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/2024-techraptor-awards-indie-game-of-year<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>AAA games feel like what we gravitate to when we want our mind blown or absolutely saturated in something, whether that's an insanely detailed world or crazy action. Indie games have a much wider variety, and because by necessity they have to have a great hook or idea to form a game around, those that usually see the most success are also the most interesting games of the year.</p>

<p>Here are the nominees for TechRaptor's 2024 Indie Game of the Year Award for outstanding creative and technical design from outside a large studio.</p>

<ul><li>1000xRESIST</li>
	<li>Animal Well</li>
	<li>Balatro</li>
	<li>Indika</li>
	<li>Lorelei and the Laser Eyes</li>
	<li>Manor Lords</li>
	<li>Neva</li>
	<li>The Plucky Squire</li>
	<li>The Rise of the Golden Idol</li>
	<li>UFO 50</li>
</ul><p><a href="https://techraptor.net/awards" rel="nofollow">Check out here</a>&nbsp;for our other award categories.</p>

<hr><h2>Fifth Place -&nbsp;The Rise of the Golden Idol</h2>



<p>Developer: Color Gray Games | Release Date: November 12th, 2024</p>

<p>Written by Andrew Otton</p>

<p><em>The Case of the Golden Idol</em> was easily one of my favorite games in recent years, and thankfully the sequel <em>The Rise of the Golden Idol </em>doesn't disappoint. An exercise in beautiful simplicity,<em> Rise of the Golden Idol </em>is amazing at making you feel like a genius (or idiot for an extended period) when something finally clicks.</p>

<p><em>Rise </em>brought with it some quality of life updates in this detective/investigation game in how information is organized and how you can quickly access it as you try to suss out exactly what happened in any one scene. There are bigger storylines connected in interesting ways, with plenty of callbacks to the original game as well.</p>

<p>If you like logic-based puzzles or really just want to figure out some mysteries, including some murder mysteries here and there, this game is a no brainer.&nbsp;</p>

<h2>Fourth Place - UFO 50</h2>



<p>Developer: Mossmouth, LLC | Release Date: September 18th, 2024</p>

<p>Written by Austin Suther</p>

<p>If you love the artform of video games, <em>UFO 50 </em>is the game for you. It’s a digital time capsule with 50 individual games, giving us a glimpse at how technology and gameplay evolved during the early years of the medium, warts and all.</p>

<p>There’s a fun little narrative behind the scenes, with this fake company called UFOsoft, running on fake hardware and a bunch of made-up employees in the credits. It’s fun to explore the history of UFOsoft, but the games themselves are, of course, the highlight.&nbsp;</p>

<p>We’d be here forever if I explained the ins-and-outs of every game within this collection, but just know these can range from quick, arcade-like experiences to full fledged RPGs. <em>UFO 50</em> is a remarkable achievement in game design.&nbsp;</p>

<h2>Third Place -&nbsp;1000xRESIST</h2>



<p>Developer: Sunset Visitor | Release Date: May 9th, 2024</p>

<p>Written by Tyler Chancey</p>

<p><em>1000xRESIST</em> is the kind of interactive experience that is few and far between -- a narrative experience that is equal parts strange and personal, profound and intimate.</p>

<p>Across 15 hours, it encompasses the complexities of high school drama, the anxiety of uncertainty in the face of a pandemic, the existential dread of an alien invasion, the hollow comforts of a religious cult, and the complex cracks in the system by revolution.</p>

<p>It is the kind of narrative that is dense with metaphor and layered meaning. The generational gaps of Watcher, All Mother, and Iris. The recursive nature of humanity throughout the centuries: oppression leading to revolution leading to oppression.</p>

<p>While its gameplay features are light, little more than dialogue options, the experience of <em>1000xRESIST</em> cannot be missed by those that love interactive narrative or thoughtful sci-fi.</p>

<h2>Second Place - Animal Well</h2>



<p>Developer: Shared Memory | Release Date: May 9th, 2024</p>

<p>Written by Andrew Stretch</p>

<p>This game caught my eye as soon as it was revealed -- a tease of puzzles within puzzles, upon release it absolutely delivered. With a core game experience presenting a tight, non-linear Metroidvania, you can enjoy the unsettling atmosphere as you hop through the world. For those who enjoy finding collectibles you'll be treated to unique puzzles and gameplay challenges.</p>

<p>If you scratch just a bit further below the surface, the experience is one that only a few games have managed to pull off so far. No matter what level of interest in this game, it's an entertaining and unique experience for every type of player.</p>

<h2>Winner - Balatro</h2>



<p>Developer: LocalThunk | Release Date: February 20th, 2024</p>

<p>Written by Blair Bishop</p>

<p>It was somewhat humorous to see the reaction to <em>Balatro </em>in the run-up to awards season. People simply couldn’t believe a game that looked like that could generate enough hype to last throughout the entire year. So they delved in and saw for themselves how this was possible, and they returned changed. Ashamed that they ever doubted that this was possible.</p>

<p>It’s a testament to how well-designed <em>Balatro </em>is. It’s easy to pick up and play, and it’s easier to find yourself lost in it. Striking the perfect balance between casual muckabouts and all-in numbers games, LocalThunk has created something which will be in the space for years to come.</p>

<p>And maybe even after that.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Andrew is the Editor in Chief at TechRaptor. Conned into a love of gaming by Nintendo at a young age, Andrew has been&nbsp;chasing the dragon spawned by Super… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/andrew-otton">More about Andrew</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>