<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:27:51 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Farming Simulator 25 Sales Cross 4m as Year 2 Pass Brings Yet More Content]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/farming-simulator-25-sales-4m</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/farming-simulator-25-sales-cross-4m-as-year-2-pass-brings-yet-more-content.1357129/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer and publisher Giants Software has revealed that&nbsp;<em>Farming Simulator 25&nbsp;</em>sales have reached a major milestone since the game launched just over a year ago.</p>

<p>Per a press release,&nbsp;<em>Farming Simulator 25&nbsp;</em>has hit four million sales across all platforms, which puts it ahead of fairly major hits like <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/silent-hill-2-remake-sales-2-5m-worldwide" rel="nofollow">Konami's&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill 2&nbsp;</em>remake</a>&nbsp;(although it's still trailing major breakout hit&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/clair-obscur-expedition-33-sales-5m-update" rel="nofollow"><em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em></a>).</p>

<p>Giants isn't slowing down with content for&nbsp;<em>Farming Simulator 25</em>, either; a second season pass has been released today, and it promises lots of new content throughout the rest of the year, including a brand new JCB tractor that's ready to claim right now if you own the pass.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/giants-software-farming-simulator-25-sales-4m.jpg?itok=tISs1FLc 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/giants-software-farming-simulator-25-sales-4m.jpg?itok=R8qqkj9F 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Oh, Giants Software. Never change.</figcaption></figure><p>As well as the aforementioned vehicle,&nbsp;<em>Farming Simulator 25</em>'s Year 2 Season Pass will also bring a major DLC pack somewhere between January and March, followed by another between April and June.</p>

<p>They'll be chased up by a major expansion that will launch between October and December this year, which will introduce a brand new map and more to the farming simulator. It sounds like there will be plenty of players waiting to greet that pack as well.</p>

<p>If you're unfamiliar with&nbsp;<em>Farming Simulator 25</em>, it's...well...it's a farming simulator, and it's this year's iteration of Giants Software's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/farming-simulator-22-sales-surpass-3-million-units-globally" rel="nofollow">successful</a> and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/farming-simulator-15-coming-consoles" rel="nofollow">long-running</a> series.</p>

<p>Released back in November last year, the game managed to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/farming-simulator-25-sales-2-million-one-week" rel="nofollow">rack up two million sales for itself</a> within its first week of launch, which means it's picked up another two million in the intervening year. That's not bad at all, especially for what remains an essentially niche title.</p>




<p>If you're interested in checking out&nbsp;<em>Farming Simulator 25</em>, you can pick it up right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2300320/Farming_Simulator_25/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/farming-simulator-25/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/farming-simulator-25/9NMCDQ6RCJKH" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>. Stay tuned for more on this and all other things&nbsp;<em>Farming Simulator</em>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/farming-simulator-25-sales-4m]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Interplay Co-Founder and Industry Legend Rebecca Heineman Dies Aged 62]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/rebecca-heineman-dies-62-interplay</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/interplay-co-founder-and-industry-legend-rebecca-heineman-dies-aged-62.1357126/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Rebecca Heineman, one of the co-founders of&nbsp;<em>Fallout&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Baldur's Gate&nbsp;</em>publisher Interplay, has passed away aged just 62.</p>

<p>As reported by <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/interplay-co-founder-rebecca-heineman-dies-from-cancer" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Rock Paper Shotgun</a>, Heineman's death was confirmed by close friend <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/hmcd.bsky.social/post/3m5u7i37gns2u" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Heidi McDonald</a> and former colleague <a href="https://x.com/BrianFargo/status/1990561629080277499" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Brian Fargo</a> on social media yesterday. McDonald described her as a "trailblazing game industry bad-ass", while Fargo called Heineman "one of the most brilliant programmers around".</p>

<p>Previously, Heineman had set up a <a href="https://www.gofundme.com/f/help-rebecca-ann-heineman-fight-aggressive-cancer" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">GoFundMe page</a> to help pay for treatment for her recently-diagnosed adenocarcinoma, but yesterday, she said further treatments would be "pointless" according to her doctors, urging donors to give so that her funeral can help her "make a worthy entrance for reuniting" with spouse Jennell Jaquays.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/fallout-interplay-rebecca-heineman-death.jpg?itok=lEs59mkZ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/fallout-interplay-rebecca-heineman-death.jpg?itok=E6cCc5e6 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Rebecca Heineman co-founded&nbsp;<em>Fallout&nbsp;</em>publisher Interplay.</figcaption></figure><p>Heineman was one of the first major video game championship winners, having bagged a prize for her performance during a&nbsp;<em>Space Invaders&nbsp;</em>tournament all the way back in 1980.</p>

<p>Following her victory during that tournament, she co-founded Interplay Productions, the studio that went on to publish iconic and influential games like survival horror classic&nbsp;<em>Alone in the Dark</em>, CRPGs&nbsp;<em>Baldur's Gate&nbsp;</em>and <em>Fallout</em>, and the European version of the original&nbsp;<em>Warcraft</em>.</p>

<p>As well as being a major industry figure, Heineman was also active as an LGBTQ+ campaigner. She won a Gayming Icon award from <a href="https://gaymingmag.com/awards/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Gayming Magazine</a> this year, with the publication commending her "advocacy for LGBTQ+ inclusion, accessibility, and diversity in tech".</p>

<p>In her later years, Heineman was also active on streaming and video platforms, showing off some of the curios she had gathered over her decades working in the gaming industry. It's no stretch to say that without Heineman, many of the most well-respected games of today simply wouldn't exist.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/alone-in-the-dark-interplay-rebecca-heineman.jpg?itok=q1zrRsev 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/alone-in-the-dark-interplay-rebecca-heineman.jpg?itok=ZbWcldqS 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Survival horror simply wouldn't be the same without Rebecca Heineman.</figcaption></figure><p>All of our condolences here at TechRaptor go out to Heineman's family and friends. Maybe go play a classic Interplay title as a tribute to her and all of the work she's done in the industry over the years.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/rebecca-heineman-dies-62-interplay]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hytale Rescued by Original Co-Founder Following Riot Shutdown]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hytale-rescued-early-access-soon</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hytale-rescued-by-original-co-founder-following-riot-shutdown.1357120/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Hytale co-founder and original developer Simon Collins-Laflamme has purchased the rights for the game back from <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/riot-games-hytale-acqusition-adds-blocky-adventure-to-roster" rel="nofollow">original owner Riot Games</a>, following the shutdown of the project earlier this year.</p>

<p>In a new <a href="https://hytale.com/news/2025/11/hytale-is-saved" rel="nofollow">blog post</a> entitled “Hytale Is Saved!”, Collins-Laflamme says the project has been acquired from Riot Games in its entirety, and the new team is “fully independent and personally committed to funding Hytale for the next ten years”, a commitment he says he’s making alongside fellow director Philippe Touchette.</p>

<p>As well as reviving the project, Collins-Laflamme and Touchette have hired “over 30 former developers” who were working on Hytale prior to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hytale-canceled-dev-shuts-down" rel="nofollow">its closure in June</a>, and the two say they will “continue to hire as the budget allows” and as the right candidates for the game are found.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/hytale-rescued-original-developer-farmer_0.jpg?itok=NRmg4qmZ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/hytale-rescued-original-developer-farmer_0.jpg?itok=SV0dvd94 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Hytale&nbsp;</em>is making a return, so rejoice.</figcaption></figure><p>The new Early Access date for the revived version of Hytale will be revealed in the coming days, Collins-Laflamme says, as will the game’s pricing.</p>

<p>You should, according to the developers, expect Hytale to be in a pretty rough state when it launches, with “bugs, rough edges, unbalanced content, and frequent updates that break things” being par for the course.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This is partly due to the abandonment of the so-called “Cross-Platform Engine”, which would have ensured Hytale’s compatibility with other platforms; instead of using that engine, the developers have returned to Hytale’s original “Legacy Engine”, which they say is “playable now” and which will allow them to “build a game rather than an engine”.</p>

<p>Despite being a big part of the original Hytale release, official minigames won’t be a part of this revived version of Hytale at Early Access launch, but a dedicated team will work on bringing them into the fold “once the core game is stable”.</p>




<p>In the coming days, you can expect to see new gameplay footage and screenshots for Hytale, as well as detailed patch notes for what the team has been working on recently.</p>

<p>In addition, you’ll get a roadmap post showing what’s coming to Hytale in the future, as well as the aforementioned pricing details, an Early Access release date, and “plenty of updates and communication”.</p>

<p>In case you’re unfamiliar with Hytale, it’s an ambitious RPG sandbox that pledges to offer “a procedurally generated world full of dungeons, secrets, and a variety of creatures” that you can “shape…block by block”. Whether that original vision changes with new ownership and a new direction remains to be seen.</p>

<p>If you’d like to keep up with Hytale’s progress, you can do so via the <a href="https://discord.gg/hytale" rel="nofollow">new Discord server</a>, and you can keep an eye on the <a href="https://hytale.com/" rel="nofollow">official website</a> as well.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hytale-rescued-early-access-soon]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>