<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:36:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No, That Shenmue 4 Footage Isn't Real, Developer Ys Net Says]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/shenmue-4-footage-fake-ys-net</link>
            <guid>1376257</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Shenmue </em>studio Ys Net has taken to social media to debunk reports of a supposedly-leaked <em>Shenmue 4 </em>trailer, calling the footage's circulation a "serious issue".</p><p>Speaking <a href="https://x.com/YSNET_Inc/status/1997938996677394595" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">on X</a> (thanks, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/shenmue-4-video-has-absolutely-no-connection-to-developer-ys-net-and-now-the-studio-is-threatening-legal-action-as-the-footage-misleads-viewers-into-believing-such-content-is-official" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">IGN</a>), Ys Net said that the footage, which supposedly <a href="https://x.com/SuperSisi/status/1996855092734230658" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">shows</a> several scenes from a currently-in-development build of a fourth <em>Shenmue </em>game, has "absolutely no connection" to the studio.</p><p>Additionally, Ys Net says that it has "not released any trailers, footage, or other promotional materials related to <em>Shenmue 4</em>", and that the fact the footage uses the Ys Net logo "falsely giv[es] the impression that it is an official <em>Shenmue 4</em>-related video", which it is not.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption>Sorry, <em>Shenmue </em>fans, but <em>Shenmue 3 </em>is still the latest <em>Shenmue </em>game for now.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Ys Net goes on to say that the use of its logo, as well as the attempt to mislead viewers into thinking the footage is official, "constitutes a serious issue that may amount to trademark infringement and unfair competition".</p><p>As such, the developer says it's "currently working with relevant parties and preparing appropriate measures, including potential legal action". It sounds like whoever made that footage might be dealing with some uncomfortable queries soon.</p><p>Although some believed the <em>Shenmue 4 </em>footage to be real, others suggested it had been made with generative AI, pointing to certain animations and the slightly-too-reverent story content in the trailer as proof.</p><p>Of course, being made with generative AI doesn't mean the trailer isn't real by itself; many studios, including <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ea-hopes-to-use-generative-ai-to-drive-more-monetization-and-make-development-30-more" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="746600ea-ef36-4d95-b141-ab37281d9e3e" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">EA</a>, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/netflix-generative-ai-vp" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="affdbbdc-41b9-4313-aacc-396adb4aed5a" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">Netflix</a>, and, indeed, <em>Shenmue </em>owner <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sega-acknowledges-strong-resistance-as-it-turns-to-ai-but-says-itll-use-technology-appropriately" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">Sega</a>, have embraced the technology in one form or another. Still, this particular <em>Shenmue 4 </em>balloon has been thoroughly popped, I'm afraid.</p>
<p>The <em>Shenmue 4 </em>footage doing the rounds might not be real, but that doesn't mean the franchise has no future.&nbsp;</p><p>Back in August, Ys Net <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/shenmue-iii-enhanced-announced" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="ba817600-c94e-4669-a165-612cf6c34c02" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">announced an enhanced version</a> of <em>Shenmue 3 </em>for modern platforms, bringing improvements like camera tweaks, stamina adjustments, and skippable cutscenes.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/shenmue-4-footage-fake-ys-net]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Nightreign's Forsaken Hollows DLC Has Already Sold 2m Copies]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/elden-ring-nightreign-forsaken-hollows-dlc-sales</link>
            <guid>1376254</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Bandai Namco and developer FromSoftware have revealed that <em>Elden Ring Nightreign</em>'s <em>The Forsaken Hollows </em>DLC has already crossed a major sales milestone.</p><p>On the official <em>Elden Ring </em><a href="https://x.com/ELDENRING/status/1997093633401430482" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">X page</a>, the two studios announced on Saturday that <em>The Forsaken Hollows </em>has sold two million copies across all platforms since <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/elden-ring-nightreign-forsaken-hollows-dlc" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="47dc4e8d-fb03-4c1b-b622-97743b09da55" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">its release last week</a>.</p><p>At last count, <em>Elden Ring Nightreign </em>itself had <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/elden-ring-shadow-of-erdtree-nightreign-sales" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="69736224-ca37-469c-8a4b-6afcb8284048" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">sold around five million copies</a>, so if that figure still stands, then that means more than a third of the game's players have picked up its DLC. Still, it's entirely possible the base game has racked up more sales for itself since July as well.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption><em>Elden Ring Nightreign</em>'s <em>The Forsaken Hollows </em>DLC has already sold two million copies.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>If you're not familiar with <em>The Forsaken Hollows</em>, it's the first big DLC expansion for <em>Elden Ring Nightreign</em>, and it introduces two brand new Nightlord bosses to take on, including the fearsome Dreglord.</p><p>As well as the two extra bosses, <em>The Forsaken Hollows </em>adds a new map (although it's technically just a Shifting Earth condition) to explore, plus new bosses from <em>Souls </em>series history, new enemies, and plenty more.</p><p>You can also play as two brand new characters in <em>The Forsaken Hollows</em>, namely the Scholar and the Undertaker, who bring disparate play styles to make your expeditions into the parallel land of Limveld more exciting.</p>
<p>As for the base game itself, <em>Elden Ring Nightreign </em>is an experimental spinoff of the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/elden-ring-sales-30m" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="6919a2a8-7d6a-4b7b-ba51-02f9b15b7407" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">multi-million-selling open-world Soulslike</a>, one which mixes elements of games like <em>Fortnite </em>and extraction shooters into FromSoftware's signature blend of exploration and combat.</p><p>The game sees teams of up to three players heading into a constantly-changing map in order to scavenge gear, battle enemies and bosses to level up, and take on an especially powerful bespoke encounter at the conclusion of each three-day run.</p><p>You can check out <em>Elden Ring Nightreign </em>and its <em>Forsaken Hollows </em>DLC on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2622380/ELDEN_RING_NIGHTREIGN/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/elden-ring-nightreign/" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">PlayStation</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/elden-ring-nightreign/9PJ22QNVCZ3G" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">Xbox</a> right now, and you can read <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/elden-ring-nightreign-review-fort-night" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="d6d6f261-ff0a-4fbc-9eea-253dd2d55ca7" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">my review of the base game here</a>.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/elden-ring-nightreign-forsaken-hollows-dlc-sales]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tekken Legend Katsuhiro Harada to Leave Bandai Namco]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/katsuhiro-harada-tekken-leaving-bandai-namco</link>
            <guid>1376251</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Tekken </em>director and industry icon Katsuhiro Harada has announced that he will leave Bandai Namco later this year.</p><p>In a <a href="https://x.com/Harada_TEKKEN/status/1997952347709034747" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">message</a> on social media, Harada says that while his experiences working on <em>Tekken </em>have "remained at the center of [his] identity", he's been thinking about "the time [he has] left as a creator".</p><p>These reflections were prompted by the loss of "several close friends" in Harada's personal life, as well as "the retirement or passing" of several colleagues whom Harada says he "deeply respect[s]".</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption>Longtime <em>Tekken </em>director Katsuhiro Harada is leaving Bandai Namco at the end of this year.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Harada goes on to say that he's spent the last "four to five years" handing off responsibilities for <em>Tekken </em>to the franchise's development team, including the "stories and worldbuilding [he] oversaw", so his departure shouldn't come as too much of a shock for <em>Tekken</em>.</p><p>As for what's next for Harada, he says he'll "share more about [his] next steps at a later date". Could he be on his way to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/netease-launches-new-studio-pincool-led-by-former-dragon-quest-producer-will-work-on" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="1814b13d-5295-44d3-918a-0431453d10ed" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">starting up his own studio</a>, perhaps with <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ex-capcom-producer-founds-new-studio-at-netease" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="872fe8bd-eb94-4ab0-bdbb-86eb30e948c8" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">NetEase funding</a>? Recent <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/rich-vogel-t-minus-zero-entertainment-netease-shut-down" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="ceba73e9-0d31-4194-b075-665cc4485263" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">developments</a> may make that possibility <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/bad-brain-game-studios-netease-shut-down" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="2a158319-1876-4d94-9ee6-92c96cbe7255" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">a little more complicated</a> than it might have been a year or two ago.</p><p>You haven't quite heard the last of Harada with regards to <em>Tekken</em>, though. He says that he will be attending the Tekken World Tour finals in January, albeit "as a guest", so you'll see him there if you check out that event.</p><p>Additionally, to say goodbye to <em>Tekken</em>, Harada has created a "DJ-style nonstop mix" of music from the franchise that he "personally edited". You can listen to it <a href="https://soundcloud.com/katsuhiro-harada-1/tekken-a-30-year-journey-haradas-final-mix" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">right here</a>.</p>
<p>For its part, the <em>Tekken </em>team responded to Harada's departure <a href="https://x.com/TEKKEN/status/1997954347347620178/" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">on social media</a>, expressing its "deepest gratitude" to him for his "vision", as well as the "<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tekken-8-sales-2-million" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="887e97a6-22ea-4a2f-addf-6530f0ed9912" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">continued success</a>" of <em>Tekken </em>over the years.</p><p>It sounds as though <em>Tekken </em>will continue without Harada; the team says it's "fully committed to future development and content plans" for the latest game in the series. Stay tuned for more.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/katsuhiro-harada-tekken-leaving-bandai-namco]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>