<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 13:42:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anthem to Shut Down Permanently in January 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/anthem-shutdown-january-2026</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/anthem-to-shut-down-permanently-in-january-2026.1237203/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Publisher EA and developer BioWare have announced that ill-fated live-service looter-shooter (boy, that's a lot of hyphens)&nbsp;<em>Anthem&nbsp;</em>will be shut down early next year.</p>

<p>In an <a href="https://www.ea.com/en-gb/games/anthem/news/anthem-game-update" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">FAQ</a> on the publisher's official website, the two studios confirm that&nbsp;<em>Anthem&nbsp;</em>will cease operations on January 12th, at which point "the game will no longer be playable". There won't be any kind of single-player mode, EA and BioWare say, because&nbsp;<em>Anthem&nbsp;</em>was "designed to be an online-only title".</p>

<p>If you've previously purchased&nbsp;<em>Anthem&nbsp;</em>and haven't installed it for a while, you'll still be able to do so right up until January 12th, but this really is the end for the game; after that date, you can't download it or play it anymore.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/anthem-shutdown-january-2026-suits.jpg?itok=KdD0z_Wa 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/anthem-shutdown-january-2026-suits.jpg?itok=-KX-2qPW 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Anthem&nbsp;</em>won't be around for much longer, EA and BioWare say.</figcaption></figure><p>Naturally, it's no longer possible to purchase&nbsp;<em>Anthem&nbsp;</em>from digital storefronts, although it will remain on the EA Play subscription service (which is also included with certain tiers of Xbox Game Pass) until August 15th.</p>

<p>Additionally, you can still spend any in-game currency you might have left over until January 12th, so if there's anything in&nbsp;<em>Anthem</em>'s shop you've had your eye on, you might want to pick it up before it's too late.</p>

<p>EA says that <i>Anthem</i>'s shutdown "has not led to any layoffs", although given that the studio appears to have just <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/respawn-layoffs-ea-cuts-titanfall-game" rel="nofollow">emerged from a fresh layoff wave</a>, that might not be the case for long. Then again, the writing's been on the wall for&nbsp;<em>Anthem&nbsp;</em>for some time, so it's not like its shutdown has come as a surprise.</p>




<p><em>Anthem&nbsp;</em>was released in early 2019 to divided opinion. Some praised its mech combat, while others lamented its weak story and lack of content. Incidentally, our very own Sam did both of these things <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/anthem-review-biowares-b-side" rel="nofollow">when he reviewed it at launch</a>.</p>

<p>Player response was equally mixed, and while a major update known as&nbsp;<em>Anthem Next&nbsp;</em>was planned to revitalize the flagging shooter, the update was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/anthem-next-has-reportedly-been-canceled" rel="nofollow">eventually canceled in early 2021</a>, and&nbsp;<em>Anthem&nbsp;</em>has flagged ever since.</p>

<p>If you want to check out&nbsp;<em>Anthem&nbsp;</em>before its shutdown in January, you can do so with an EA Play membership. It's not available separately via any other digital platforms.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/anthem-shutdown-january-2026]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>