<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 12:55:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Tabletop Accessories and Gifts For Board Gamers]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/best-tabletop-accessories-and-gifts-for-board-gamers</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/best-tabletop-accessories-and-gifts-for-board-gamers.1060683/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/best-tabletop-accessories-and-gifts-for-board-gamers<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>What do you get for the board gamer who has everything? Don’t risk getting them a game or expansion they already have, follow our regularly updated Best Tabletop Accessories and Gifts&nbsp; guide for the best everyone on your list.</p>

<h2><b>Pathfinder Spell Cards and Flip-mats</b></h2>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tabletop-accessories-pathfinder-spell-cards.jpg?itok=Fu617YgC 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tabletop-accessories-pathfinder-spell-cards.jpg?itok=QbgvQ-06 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Pathfinder Spell Cards help organize a complicated system.</figcaption></figure><p><i>Pathfinder</i> is one of the most popular tabletop RPG’s in the world, and if you’ve got friends’ who are into the game, there’s a whole host of incredible accessories to go along with the game.</p>

<p>We recommend two products in particular. First, check out <a href="https://paizo.com/store/pathfinder/accessories/cards" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><i>Pathfinder Spell Cards</i></a>, which take all the cards in a school of magic and print them out in easy-to-use, organized cards! There are cards for all of the different schools of magic, and make a complicated process of managing spells just that much easier.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tabletop-accessories-pathfinder-flipmat.jpg?itok=Oqcb5SM8 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tabletop-accessories-pathfinder-flipmat.jpg?itok=P8BKyw7z 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Pathfinder Flip-Mats are super versatile.</figcaption></figure><p>Next up are the incredible <a href="https://paizo.com/store/pathfinder/accessories/maps/flipmats" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><i>Pathfinder Flip-Mats</i></a>, which are good for any Tabletop RPG that uses a grid-based map system! Come to think of it, if you ignore the grid of squares, these maps can be used for any game - RPG or wargame - that cares about the kind of terrain you're moving through.</p>

<p>Beautifully detailed, with a map on each side, these are even dry and wet-erase compatible. There are hundreds of map packs out now, for both&nbsp;<em>Pathfinder</em>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<em>Starfinder</em>.</p>

<h2><b>Wingspan Fan Art Pack</b></h2>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tabletop-accessories-wingspan-fan-art-pack.jpeg?itok=74KLmPbJ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tabletop-accessories-wingspan-fan-art-pack.jpeg?itok=-qn9G8Yw 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The&nbsp;<em>Wingspan</em>&nbsp;Fan Art Pack celebrates the creativity of the community.</figcaption></figure><p>When <i>Wingspan </i>first hit the gaming market, it took the community by storm with its clever game design, incredible theme (it’s just about birds!), and charming artwork. But if you’ve got a <i>Wingspan</i> lover in your house, they’re likely to own all the main expansions.</p>

<p>But with the <a href="https://store.stonemaiergames.com/products/wingspan-fan-art-cards" rel="nofollow"><i>Wingspan Fan Art Pack</i></a>, you can help them add a ton of personality to their game! Made up of 255 illustrations from fans all over the world, this pack of bird cards are mechanically identical to their counterparts in Wingspan and the Europe, Oceania, and Asia expansions.</p>

<h2><b>Epic Encounters: Local Legends Tavern Kit</b></h2>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tabletop-accessories-tavern-kit.jpg?itok=YZW5Ji3u 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tabletop-accessories-tavern-kit.jpg?itok=HvtC3vME 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The Tavern Kit makes quick work of fleshing out an RPG campaign</figcaption></figure><p>Does the Tavern in your Tabletop RPG feel a little dull? Get new inspiration with the incredible <a href="https://steamforged.com/products/local-legends-tavern-kit?srsltid=AfmBOoo_F7m_3N1m3MyMjvCCFTACpIz9H_C5kYhhKNnsjXUMTK3RfpaS" rel="nofollow">Tavern Kit from Steamforged Games</a>. We loved it when <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/epic-encounters-local-legends-review-legendary-bar-stories" rel="nofollow">we reviewed the Tavern Kit</a>, and for good reason! It includes an "Inncounter" book, featuring a complete guide to running epic tavern inncounters, a book describing 10 unique fantasy taverns and their various engaging plot hooks, an NPC book&nbsp;and&nbsp;cards&nbsp;featuring&nbsp;60 fully-statted NPC’s, detailed tavern maps, and 10 illustrated play mats&nbsp;for when the inevitable tavern brawl breaks out.</p>

<h2><b>Dungeons &amp; Dragons Book Tabs</b></h2>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tabletop-accessories-dnd-book-tabs.jpg?itok=OPbdU4kv 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tabletop-accessories-dnd-book-tabs.jpg?itok=6qfJeN7G 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>I can't express how helpful this simple little product is for a busy GM like myself!</figcaption></figure><p>Here’s a brilliant idea we can’t believe no one thought of until WizKids brought it to market a few years back - <a href="https://wizkids.com/dd-book-tabs/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">acrylic tabs to help you navigate your core <i>D&amp;D</i> rulebooks</a>! With tabs for both larger chapters and smaller sub-sections across each book, these tabs are a lifesaver. This makes an especially good gift if you’re the kind of player who’s always asking your poor beleaguered DM nitty gritty questions that sends them flipping through rulebooks.</p>

<h2><b>RollaCrit Accessories</b></h2>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tabletop-accessories-bag-of-holding.jpeg?itok=HflvU3dW 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tabletop-accessories-bag-of-holding.jpeg?itok=K_gUqyfF 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The Bag of Holding, true to its name, can hold a nice stack of games.</figcaption></figure><p>What’s the hardest part about being a diehard tabletop gamer? Lugging around all your stuff! With the help of <a href="https://www.rollacrit.com/products/rollacrit-messenger-bag-of-holding" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">RollaCrit’s Bag of Holding</a>, gamers can take those worries off their shoulders (by slinging this incredible bag <i>over</i> their shoulder). With pockets upon pockets, the bag can store a healthy amount of games, has a slot for laptops, reinforced straps and zippers, and a sleek, functional, and minimal design.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tabletop-accessories-dry-erase-mug.jpeg?itok=dgknFdCv 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tabletop-accessories-dry-erase-mug.jpeg?itok=H5uqfxLg 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>This RollaCrit mug makes a perfect gift or stocking stuffer!</figcaption></figure><p>We also got a chance to see a few brand new products from RollaCrit on the floor of PAX Unplugged, including an incredible-looking <a href="https://www.rollacrit.com/products/character-creation-coffee-mug-bundle?_pos=1&amp;_sid=c56e24740&amp;_ss=r" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">dry-erase mug designed to look like a character sheet</a>. Simply add your character’s most important stats to the mug, and then sip away while you delve into the dungeon.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tabletop-accessories-rollacrit-bag.jpeg?itok=1SrJzTdK 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tabletop-accessories-rollacrit-bag.jpeg?itok=R142fHsM 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Only '90s kids will remember...</figcaption></figure><p>But one of my favorite RollaCrit items I saw on display was <a href="https://www.rollacrit.com/products/royal-crit-mimic-dice-bag" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">a dice bag</a> designed to look like - what for many of us slightly older gamers - would have been our first dice bags we ever used: a purple felt Crown Royal bag! Embroidered with the RollaCrit logo on the front and with an inside lining that flips to reveal you’ve been using a Mimic all along (!!), this shows off RollaCrit’s clever, tongue-in-cheek humor the company’s famous for.</p>

<h2><b>Gamegenic Storage Solutions</b></h2>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tabletop-accessories-gamegenic-deck-boxes.jpg?itok=UZRAQr7p 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tabletop-accessories-gamegenic-deck-boxes.jpg?itok=NqUbUu1W 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The high production quality truly sets Gamegenic apart from the crowd!</figcaption></figure><p>We’ve previously covered just how much we love <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/gamegenic-deck-and-game-boxes-review" rel="nofollow">Gamegenic’s line of incredible storage solutions</a>, and they remain the best in the biz for all your TCG needs. With massive, well-constructed deck boxes like the <a href="https://www.gamegenic.com/product/sidekick-pro-100xl/?attribute_pa_color=blue" rel="nofollow">Sidekick Pro</a>, and impressive card storage solutions like the <a href="https://www.gamegenic.com/product/cards-lair-pro/?attribute_pa_color=gray-red" rel="nofollow">Cards’ Lair Pro</a>, there’s a useful, magnetically sealed product for every card gamer. I personally use the Watchtower 100+ XL Pro to keep my precious Group Hug EDH deck safe, tucking my goofy commander Gluntch, The Bestower safely away after each game I inevitably lose.</p>

<h2><b>The Hobby Holder</b></h2>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tabletop-accessories-hobby-holder.jpeg?itok=R7rH9U1U 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tabletop-accessories-hobby-holder.jpeg?itok=vVlWZAcA 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Painting even the trickiest parts of a Space Marine is a snap with the Hobby Holder!</figcaption></figure><p>Designed by Game Envy, the <a href="https://gameenvy.net/product/the-hobby-holder-painting-handle/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Hobby Holder</a> is here to solve all your miniature painting needs. Simply secure your miniature into the holder, and then enjoy multiple ways to hold your mini to get into those hard to reach spots. Simple design, great functionality, and made from quality material, this is an easy gift to give to the miniature artists in your life.</p>

<p>Which of these Tabletop Accessories are the right fit for the gamers on your list? What's your go-to Tabletop Accessory that you think deserves to be shouted from the rooftops? Let us know in the comments and we'll add our favorites to this ever-growing list!</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Giaco Furino joined the TechRaptor team as a Staff Writer in 2019 after searching for a dedicated place to write and talk about Tabletop Games. In 2020, he… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/giaco-furino">More about Giaco</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>