<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 01:01:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ninja Gaiden 4 Review - Blackened Rain Beckons]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/ninja-gaiden-4-review-blackened-rain-beckons</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ninja-gaiden-4-review-blackened-rain-beckons.1330003/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>What a year it has been for <a href="https://techraptor.net/series/ninja-gaiden" rel="nofollow"><em>Ninja Gaiden</em></a>, one of the most beloved franchises in the action genre.&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ninja-gaiden-2-black-update-new-game-plus" rel="nofollow">Ninja Gaiden 2 Black</a>&nbsp;</em>was released in January and served as a gripping remaster for a beloved game. This summer saw the release of&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/ninja-gaiden-ragebound-review-razor-sharp-retro-platformer" rel="nofollow"><em>Ninja Gaiden: Ragebound</em></a>, an outstanding homage to the franchise's roots. With&nbsp;<em>Ninja Gaiden 4</em>, this marks the finale of the Year of the Ninja.</p>

<p>With <a href="https://techraptor.net/companies/platinum-games" rel="nofollow">PlatinumGames</a> at the helm in collaboration with <a href="https://techraptor.net/companies/team-ninja" rel="nofollow">Team Ninja</a> and <a href="https://techraptor.net/companies/koei-tecmo" rel="nofollow">Koei Tecmo</a>,&nbsp;<em>Ninja Gaiden 4&nbsp;</em>is a bombastic gorefest. The action is more visceral than ever as you slash through armored warriors, vicious demons, and terrible fiends in a relentless fury. <em>Ninja Gaiden 4</em> is a shot of adrenaline, and I can't get enough of it.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ninja-gaiden-4-yakumo.jpg?itok=2buy8Pzk 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ninja-gaiden-4-yakumo.jpg?itok=ezV7fQ47 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Get ready to get bloody.</figcaption></figure><h2><em>Ninja Gaiden 4</em> is Action In Its Purest Form</h2>

<p>I'll just get to the point, because&nbsp;<em>Ninja Gaiden 4</em>&nbsp;doesn't hold back from throwing players right into the fray. The gameplay is electric. It's fast-paced, unrelenting, and is exactly the evolution fans of the series yearned for.</p>

<blockquote>
<p><em>Ninja Gaiden 4</em> is a shot of adrenaline, and I can't get enough of it.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><em>Ninja Gaiden 4&nbsp;</em>is an action game through and through, focusing almost purely on the minute-by-minute gameplay of racking up combos, slashing through foes with sick moves, and dominating the battlefield (or dying despite your best efforts).&nbsp;</p>

<p>You play as Yakumo of the Raven Clan, an expert fighter, and the main character of this entry. Ryu takes a bit of a backseat; though, we'll talk about him in a bit. Yakumo starts with the Takeminakata, duel katanas that cut swiftly and severely into his foes. This is your starter weapon, but as you progress, several more weapons unlock.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ninja-gaiden-4-fighting.jpg?itok=-6h9Hg9d 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ninja-gaiden-4-fighting.jpg?itok=tGOo4TMe 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Sick flip, Yakumo.</figcaption></figure><p>Additional weapons in the roster include the Yatousen, a speedy, rapier-like lance; Magatsuhi, a swift and sweeping staff perfect for taking out groups of enemies; and Kage-Hiruko, a box that contains a menagerie of iconic ninja tools.</p>

<p>This weapon roster might seem smaller compared to&nbsp;<em>Ninja Gaiden 2</em>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<em>Ninja Gaiden 3</em>, but each of these four weapons feels diverse and has a complexity that requires mastering to tap into their full potential.</p>

<p>You'll also unlock new abilities for each weapon that use simple inputs, like flicking the joystick in a circle and pressing light or heavy attack. Weapon XP is accrued as you fight through encounters and complete missions, so there's a nice feeling of progression both in your own skill with these weapons and through the unlocking of these new moves.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ninja-gaiden-4-new-weapon.jpg?itok=HwUCU6m5 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ninja-gaiden-4-new-weapon.jpg?itok=_ATShw3g 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>New weapon, who dis?</figcaption></figure><p>Enemies in&nbsp;<em>Ninja Gaiden 4</em>&nbsp;are pretty bulky despite the feeling of power behind every move, so you're encouraged to lean into these abilities and string together combos without getting hit. Yakumo, in the hands of a dedicated player, is an unrelenting stream of savage blows in between dodges and flips.</p>

<p>The sheer brutality of combat is emphasized by the dismemberment of enemies. Often, cutting off a limb doesn't mean they're down and out, so you can use Obliteration technique with the touch of a button to execute them. Combine that with the series' iconic Ultimate Technique (an overwhelmingly powerful flurry of blows used by charging heavy attack), and I couldn't get enough of slicing through foes.</p>

<p>Of course, being a master ninja is easier said than done. Most enemies are capable foes, even the weaker ones, if you're not careful, and <em>especially </em>when they come in droves. Each weapon is more than sufficient to use on its own, but switching between them in the heat of battle is seamless and often the difference between life and death.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/blood-raven-form-lance-ninja-gaiden-4.jpg?itok=lMerWFsP 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/blood-raven-form-lance-ninja-gaiden-4.jpg?itok=uZwaDSOW 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>This drill sure makes a bloody mess.</figcaption></figure><p>Being able to switch weapons on the fly is a wonderful feature and adds a whole new complexity to the gameplay. Add in Bloodraven Form, and things get even more interesting. See, Yakumo, as a Raven Clan ninja, can transform his weapons with Bloodraven Form, so in fact,&nbsp;<em>Ninja Gaiden 4</em>&nbsp;ends up having something like eight weapons.</p>

<p>Using Bloodraven Form transforms your current weapon into a wholly new one. Holding down the left trigger allows you to enter this state and utilizes a finite resource that accrues as you fight. Thus, each move in the Bloodraven Form requires some of that resource but is more powerful than your average attack.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Being able to switch weapons on the fly is a wonderful feature and adds a whole new complexity to the gameplay.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>A lot of enemies in&nbsp;<em>Ninja Gaiden 4</em>&nbsp;utilize guards, and the only way to penetrate through that armor is with a powerful attack. A normal attack from any of your weapons will bounce off guarding enemies and make you vulnerable, so using the Bloodraven Form is the solution that breaks through that tough armor.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ninja-gaiden-4-ninja-bombs1.jpg?itok=z0Mtd64j 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ninja-gaiden-4-ninja-bombs1.jpg?itok=pGRbEWhW 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Ninja bombs? Why not!</figcaption></figure><p>As for the weapons' new transformations, our duel swords become one single, sweeping katana that can take out groups of enemies in a wide area. The rapier turns into a drill that, when holding down attacks, allows you to spin it and rearrange enemies' guts, no matter how powerful they might be. The Kage-Hiruko, that box of ninja tools, throws empowered katanas with its light attack and uses even more powerful ninja tools with the heavy ones that can be strengthened by releasing your inputs at the right time.&nbsp;</p>

<p>My personal favorite is the staff, the Magatsuhi. This turns into a giant hammer and really emphasized the depth of&nbsp;<em>Ninja Gaiden 4</em>'s gameplay when it comes to its weapons. The hammer is slow but powerful, and similar to the Kage-Hiruko, releasing the input at certain moments in your combos allows it to explode and deal even more damage.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ninja-gaiden-4-staff.jpg?itok=nqubykZx 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ninja-gaiden-4-staff.jpg?itok=YWwY9Sqt 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Overwhelm the enemy with furious attacks.</figcaption></figure><h2>A Martial Master</h2>

<p>Mastering&nbsp;<em>Ninja Gaiden 4</em>'s weapons was a gratifying experience, but I'm not going to claim I'm an expert with them. It's just getting the timing down for the hammer was a bit weird at first, but once it clicked, it was an extremely potent tool in my arsenal and absolutely tore up the battlefield.</p>

<p>I can just imagine someone more skillful than me going ham with the different weapons, switching between them in the midst of combat to formulate unstoppable combos. The Bloodraven Form of these weapons adds so much to the gameplay, so it's such a blast to use them.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Bloodraven Form really is just the tip of the iceberg for&nbsp;<em>Ninja Gaiden</em>&nbsp;<em>4</em>'s combat. There are so many techniques and moves to purchase through your NinjaCoins to enhance your moveset even further. Parries, perfect dodges, the Izuna freakin' Drop, and more are unlockable as techniques, much to the delight of action fans.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ninja-gaiden-4-hammer.jpg?itok=sqcaxX1U 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ninja-gaiden-4-hammer.jpg?itok=8ab0HLaN 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The coolest screenshot you'll see all week. You're welcome.</figcaption></figure><p>There's even a Berserk State that uses a separate resource, which, when used, makes your Bloodraven form even&nbsp;<em>more&nbsp;</em>powerful by causing explosive attacks. While in this state, you can unleash one giant attack that takes out large groups of enemies in a single hit.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Trust me, you're going to need every single tool to win in&nbsp;<em>Ninja Gaiden 4</em>. The difficulty on Normal felt just right to start that steadily ramps up as it throws more enemies and challenges your way. Moving on to the new hardest difficulty made me appreciate how far my skills have come, though I'm still not ready for Master Ninja just yet.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ryu_ninja-gaiden-4.jpg?itok=_yYLEgUd 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ryu_ninja-gaiden-4.jpg?itok=msxyYJPS 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>He's too cool, I can hardly stand it.</figcaption></figure><h2>Ryu Returns</h2>

<p>It's not a spoiler to say you also play as Ryu in&nbsp;<em>Ninja Gaiden 4</em>&nbsp;-- it's in the marketing material. Though, don't go expecting him to be the main character here, that's Yakumo. Ryu is playable for several chapters, however, and it's nice to step into the shoes of the genre's greatest hero.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ryu has his own moves and skills separate from Yakumo, so both play and feel distinct. Ryu's moveset operates more like the traditional&nbsp;<em>Ninja Gaiden&nbsp;</em>we know and love; it's hard to describe how, exactly, but playing as him felt closer to <em>Ninja Gaiden 2</em>&nbsp;than Yakumo, no doubt. In this case, he uses just one weapon, but has four different Ninpo spells fans should recognize, including but not limited to a powerful fire attack that targets multiple enemies.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ryu_ninja-gaiden-4-2.jpg?itok=QbLQWCgA 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ryu_ninja-gaiden-4-2.jpg?itok=-xP-2SB8 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>A master ninja doing what a master ninja does.</figcaption></figure><p>Ryu doesn't use Bloodraven form, but he still has a resource that allows him to tap into other attacks. This is called Gleam Form, allowing Ryu to unleash these kinetic, super-fast slashes that break through armor and deal tons of damage.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Your time as Ryu is brief, and it's probably best that way. He plays fine enough, it's just that the segments featuring Ryu retread previous levels you played as Yakumo. You even fight the same bosses, and they're not even different than the first time you fought them. These levels could have used more variation, but it almost comes across as padding the game's length.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ninja-gaiden-4-big-enemy.jpg?itok=sS3ClGbC 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ninja-gaiden-4-big-enemy.jpg?itok=ypgUwx9p 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>A big boy like him stands no chance against Yakumo.</figcaption></figure><h2>Fighting Against Insurmountable Odds</h2>

<p>Before I dive deeper into bosses, I want to commend&nbsp;<em>Ninja Gaiden 4</em>&nbsp;for its enemy variety.&nbsp;I like dealing with a diverse roster of baddies to cut through since it requires me to adapt on the fly, and facing off against humans, demons, and fiends means each encounter has something new.</p>

<p>This variety also means&nbsp;<em>Ninja Gaiden 4</em>&nbsp;has a few annoying, pesky enemies that break up the flow.&nbsp;Mainly, it's these flying lanterns that lob ranged attacks at you. Before they die, they charge into you and try to explode. When you're dealing with multiple of these, it's just a huge nuisance.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/boss-ninja-gaiden-41.jpg?itok=nfFrCpXx 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/boss-ninja-gaiden-41.jpg?itok=xiD2meGD 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Ah hell, what in tarnation am I about to fight.&nbsp;</figcaption></figure><p>There are a couple more enemies like this, and most of them use range-based attacks. I suppose the solution to this is to "git gud," but compared to the rest of the enemy roster, they're more infuriating than intimidating.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Boss fights are, similarly, a hit or miss. Some of these bosses are just tanky as all hell and feel like&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/series/dark-souls" rel="nofollow">Dark Souls</a>&nbsp;</em>bosses, with these wide, sweeping attacks that, like those lanterns, are more annoying than difficult to deal with.&nbsp;The smaller bosses -- and I really do mean more human-sized -- are much more fun and exciting to fight.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/seori-ng4.jpg?itok=xoLjhSoW 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/seori-ng4.jpg?itok=q7vyGVgV 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Priestess doing priestess things.</figcaption></figure><h2>The Dark Dragon Dilemma</h2>

<p>Tokyo rains blood. The Dark Dragon's corpse bleeds a toxic rain over Tokyo, leading the once prosperous metropolis into disarray. The only way to save this city is to revive the Dark Dragon and slay it once more; though, as prophesied, only a Raven Clan ninja can purge this monstrosity for good.</p>

<p>Thus, our hero Yakumo sets out to unseal the Dark Dragon, revive it, and fulfill his destiny. The Divine Dragon Order (DDO), a paramilitary group of "peacekeepers," stands in his way, as does Ryu Hayabusa and a number of fiends and demons. With the help of his clan, as well as a priestess named Seori, perhaps Tokyo can be saved.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ninja-gaiden-4-seori.jpg?itok=cOJlAJyS 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ninja-gaiden-4-seori.jpg?itok=LW-Z81ah 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Poison rain sounds like quite the dilemma.&nbsp;</figcaption></figure><p>The story is serviceable, but it's by no means the highlight of&nbsp;<em>Ninja Gaiden 4</em>. The story acts more as a vessel to throw players into cool situations against the DDO, demons, fiends, and the like. Really, what&nbsp;the story lacks is strong characters. Yakumo, despite being our protagonist, is monotone.</p>

<p>Yakumo's a badass ninja, don't get me wrong, but he's too one-note. He doesn't really have a personality, or at least there isn't enough time for the story to develop one. He has an affinity for priestesses, though I'm not sure why, since there aren't many face-to-face interactions with them together. With just a few other side characters, I didn't feel any connection for Yakumo, his clan members, or Seori. It was nice to see Ryu because that's Ryu freakin' Hayabusa, but he's not the main focus here anyway.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tokyo-ninja-gaiden-4.jpg?itok=gMjftgLq 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tokyo-ninja-gaiden-4.jpg?itok=3phVFdvH 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Tokyo transit is looking a little different these days.</figcaption></figure><h2><em>Ninja Gaiden 4&nbsp;</em>| Final Thoughts</h2>

<p>The whole time I was playing&nbsp;<em>Ninja Gaiden 4</em>, I couldn't get over how&nbsp;<em>awesome</em>&nbsp;the soundtrack was. Having a good track to go along with your fight is essential in an action game, and few do it as good as&nbsp;<em>Ninja Gaiden 4</em>. Thinking about my favorite boss fights, I get chills, and part of that is because of the music. A lot of the OST has this hard rock or post-metal feel, and when the vocals start playing, I&nbsp;<em>locked in</em>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>I found myself going back to these fights just to hear the music, and thankfully, it's quite easy to fight previous bosses. Post-game&nbsp;<em>Ninja Gaiden 4</em>&nbsp;offers a hefty amount of content, like replaying bosses and levels on higher difficulties to get a high score.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Having a good track to go along with your fight is essential in an action game, and few do it as good as&nbsp;<em>Ninja Gaiden 4</em>.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The post-game Trials will put your skills to the test as it throws you into unique scenarios as either Yakumo or Ryu. Trials might, for instance, restrict the use of Bloodraven form or Gleam, while others might mean one hit from an enemy, and you're dead. Even though it's a single-player game, I feel compelled to get better, hone my skills, and complete these trials just to prove something to myself.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ninja-gaiden-4-jump.jpg?itok=mL6zVYaf 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ninja-gaiden-4-jump.jpg?itok=QNxtEX7z 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Raven Clan ninjas can't fly, but that doesn't stop them from trying.</figcaption></figure><p>The last time I felt this excited about an action game was&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/stellar-blade-review-mother-sphere-knows-best" rel="nofollow"><em>Stellar Blade</em></a>, and my enthusiasm was not unfounded.&nbsp;<em>Ninja Gaiden 4</em>&nbsp;is an exhilarating ride from start to finish, with combat that's sure to please even the most battle-tested veterans of the genre. Thus, the Year of the Ninja comes to a close, and what a way to end with a bang.&nbsp;</p>

<hr><p><em><strong>Ninja Gaiden 4&nbsp;</strong>was reviewed on PS5 with a copy provided by the publisher over the course of 25 hours of gameplay - all screenshots were taken during the process of review. </em>&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>
</div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/ninja-gaiden-4-review-blackened-rain-beckons]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Over 500 Steam Next Fest Demos Disclosed Generative AI Usage]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/over-500-steam-next-demos-disclosed-generative-ai-usage</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/over-500-steam-next-fest-demos-disclosed-generative-ai-usage.1329943/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The October Steam Next Fest ends today, and we decided to look into how many upcoming games claim they are using generative AI. Many of these games release in the next few months, which gives us a good current snapshot of where small to mid-size game development is at when it comes to generative AI.</p>

<p>By pulling the information from Steam about which Next Fest titles had enabled the AI Generated Content Disclosure, we discovered that over 500 demos disclosed using AI. The data here is necessarily imperfect, as it only counts the games that have disclosed AI Usage.</p>

<p>As we saw with games like&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/the-alters-possible-generative-ai" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="The Alters Players Reckon They've Spotted Some Undisclosed Generative AI Work"><em>The Alters</em></a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2286600/view/503963131223999762" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Statement on AI use in Hotel Barcelona"><em>Hotel Barcelona</em></a>, some games will not disclose it on the Steam page but do use or had used generative AI. In the case of <em>The Alters</em>, their Steam page doesn't disclose that the game previously had generative AI content used in development.</p>

<p>The exact total of games disclosing generative AI was 507 games out of the total 2960 titles in Steam Next Fest. By briefly examining their AI Generated Content Disclosure, we found out that three of them had situations that made us believe they may not have qualified as using generative AI in the making or marketing of their game, giving us a new total of 504 games.</p>

<p>This gave us a percentage of 17.03%, which is close to 1 in 5 games. As mentioned above, this is only a baseline figure, with more games potentially making use of it either in early stages of production or in areas that aren't seen (such as code) and not disclosing it.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/packmates.jpg?itok=fv-_4QV1 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/packmates.jpg?itok=c6TuNcGI 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3171540/Packmates/" rel="nofollow"><em>Packmates</em>&nbsp;</a>used the AI Generated Content Disclosure spot to write "No generative AI content."</figcaption></figure><h2>What Was Generative AI Used For in Steam Next Fest Demos?</h2>

<p>Games had a variety of uses for generative AI in their disclosures, which we haven't yet fully reviewed, but we saw several major areas of use emerge:</p>

<ul><li>Marketing and Steam Store Page Assets&nbsp;</li>
	<li>Art assets in-game (from concept art, to placeholders, to all of the art in a game)</li>
	<li>Audio assets (music, sound effects, voice over)</li>
	<li>Translation</li>
	<li>Coding</li>
	<li>Writing</li>
	<li>Ideation</li>
	<li>In-Game Live Calls</li>
</ul><p>Those are roughly in the order of frequency of usage we saw in the 100 games we examined. There will be a more in-depth report on more games in a future report. There were also a number of games that used AI for creating Steam capsule images, store page pictures, or for translating their store page with no other use of generative AI.</p>

<h2>What Was the Most Popular Demo with Generative AI In Steam Next Fest?</h2>

<p>The most popular game that had an AI generated content disclosure was <em>Cloudheim </em>by Noodle Cat Games. It broke into the top 50 of Steam Next Fest October 2025 most played demos and had a max concurrent user count of 667. Here is what their AI Content disclosure said:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Our primary use of generative AI is for internal communication: we made a bot called InfoSage which helps us search our documentation, notify others of interesting discussions, and look through recent changes to pinpoint when bugs occurred.</p>

<p>Our developers can choose to use generative AI as part of an iterative exploratory process, but the decision of how and when is left up to individuals, and the final product always reflects the creativity and expression of our own development team.</p>

<p>No people have been replaced by AI. This includes artists and engineers on our team, voice actors, localization, or other roles.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/cloudheim.jpg?itok=loR65jZo 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/cloudheim.jpg?itok=RcZsMIWF 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>In the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/10-steam-next-fest-demos-you-need-to-try-june-2025" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title=" 10 Steam Next Fest Demos You Need To Try - June 2025">June Steam Next Fest</a>, we also saw that <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1757300/Jump_Space/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Jump Space"><em>Jump Space</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>made use of generative AI content and was a quick seller on release in September, with over 100k copies sold in the first 24 hours.</p>

<p>How generative AI will shape our hobby and industry going forward is something that is yet to be determined, and what players are willing to accept will play a huge role in how it is used as well. Keep an eye out for a more in-depth report of AI usage on Steam Next Fest games.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>A longtime lover of speculative fiction, in almost all its forms, Don joined TechRaptor in 2014 on a whim sending in an application as he was looking for… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/don-parsons">More about Don</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/over-500-steam-next-demos-disclosed-generative-ai-usage]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>