<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 15:36:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monaco 2 Release Date Brings Sneaky Heists to PC and Consoles Next Month]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monaco-2-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monaco-2-release-date-brings-sneaky-heists-to-pc-and-consoles-next-month.1136682/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monaco-2-release-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer Pocketwatch Games and publisher Humble Games have announced the release date for upcoming sneaky heist sim&nbsp;<em>Monaco 2</em>.</p>

<p>Per a new release date trailer,&nbsp;<em>Monaco 2&nbsp;</em>will launch across PC and current-gen consoles on April 10th. It is, as you've probably already surmised, the sequel to the amusingly-named 2013 stealth game&nbsp;<em>Monaco: What's Yours Is Mine</em>.</p>

<p>The sequel trades the original game's top-down 2D art style for a new isometric 3D look, but it's still very much all about finding the perfect route in and out of a series of well-guarded locations to steal valuable loot.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/monaco-2-release-date-heist.jpg?itok=Uf2mkBtf 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/monaco-2-release-date-heist.jpg?itok=FZ8qwHYM 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Monaco 2&nbsp;</em>sneaks onto the scene in April.</figcaption></figure><p>Like its predecessor,&nbsp;<em>Monaco 2&nbsp;</em>is focused on co-op multiplayer; you can play by yourself, but you can also team up with up to three friends in either online or local co-op play.</p>

<p>The game will boast eight playable characters, each of whom has their own strengths and weaknesses. You can also switch your character partway through a run if you need to utilize a different skillset.</p>

<p><em>Monaco 2</em>'s levels are procedurally generated, and you'll be able to see each of them before you delve into the heist thanks to the game's Blueprint Mode, which allows you to do what any good thief would do and case the joint before you break in.</p>

<p>You can check out the&nbsp;<em>Monaco 2&nbsp;</em>release date announcement trailer right here. It gives a good sense of what you can expect from the game in terms of art style and gameplay.</p>




<p><em>Monaco 2&nbsp;</em>will be published by Humble Games, which remains an operational outfit despite large-scale layoffs and restructuring efforts <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/humble-games-lays-off-over-30-employees-as-it-restructures" rel="nofollow">back in July last year</a>. The game will serve as developer Pocketwatch's fifth effort, as well as its first since the 2017 RTS&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/tooth-and-tail-review-fur-and-loathing" rel="nofollow"><em>Tooth and Tail</em></a>.</p>

<p>You'll be able to check out&nbsp;<em>Monaco 2&nbsp;</em>when it launches for <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1063030/Monaco_2/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S on April 10th.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ex-Disco Elysium Devs Launch Kickstarter for "Psychogeographic RPG" Hopetown]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/longdue-hopetown-kickstarter-disco-elysium</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ex-disco-elysium-devs-launch-kickstarter-for-psychogeographic-rpg-hopetown.1136652/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/longdue-hopetown-kickstarter-disco-elysium<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Longdue, a studio made up in part of former&nbsp;<em>Disco Elysium&nbsp;</em>developers and creative personnel, has launched a Kickstarter crowdfunding campaign for its debut project&nbsp;<em>Hopetown</em>.</p>

<p>The studio describes&nbsp;<em>Hopetown&nbsp;</em>as a "psychogeographic RPG" that casts you as an ex-journalist looking to investigate "a town above, the world below, and the depths of your own psyche". So far, so very&nbsp;<em>Disco Elysium</em>.</p>

<p>As with&nbsp;<em>Disco Elysium</em>, you'll have the chance to play as you see fit; you can "spark chaos as a gonzo journalist" or "twist events as a conspiracist", sure, but if you prefer to do things in a more straightforward way, you can also "reveal brutal truths as a calculated investigator".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/disco-elysium-longdue-hopetown.jpg?itok=bp8U2d4_ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/disco-elysium-longdue-hopetown.jpg?itok=cG-UqkJJ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Hopetown&nbsp;</em>is the very&nbsp;<em>Disco Elsyium</em>-esque debut game from Longdue Games.</figcaption></figure><p>True to Longdue's legacy, the studio promises that&nbsp;<em>Hopetown</em>'s "psychogeography system" will replace traditional puzzles and keys with "emotions, memories, and conversations". It sounds rather like if you love&nbsp;<em>Disco Elysium</em>, you'll want to keep an eye on this as well.</p>

<p>The Kickstarter campaign for&nbsp;<em>Hopetown&nbsp;</em>is live now, and at time of writing, it had raised £19,967 of its £25,000 goal (apologies for using UK currency, but I'm a Brit, so it comes with the territory). It's looking fairly likely the game will hit its goal by the end of the day.</p>

<p>Longdue is one of <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ex-disco-elysium-devs-new-studios-spiritual-successors" rel="nofollow">a number of studios</a> that formed after original publisher ZA/UM effectively imploded following&nbsp;<em>Disco Elysium</em>'s release. The studio boasts the involvement of ZA/UM co-founder Martin Luiga, who also wrote "seven characters in&nbsp;<em>Disco Elysium</em>", according to the studio's website.</p>

<p><em>Kentucky Route Zero&nbsp;</em>co-creator Ben Babbitt and&nbsp;<em>The Witcher 3&nbsp;</em>composer Pawel Blaszczak have also joined the team, so it's fair to say Longdue is shaping up to be a real supergroup of developers at this stage.</p>




<p>Although many of ZA/UM's principal creatives have left the studio, the company is still soldiering on. Just last week, it <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/zaum-project-c4-disco-elysium" rel="nofollow">announced&nbsp;<em>Project C4</em></a>, which it describes as a new "genre-defining" RPG.</p>

<p>ZA/UM also <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/disco-elysium-mobile-version-tiktok-user" rel="nofollow">unveiled a&nbsp;<em>Disco Elysium&nbsp;</em>mobile port</a> last week, which studio head Denis Havel says is aimed at "captivating the TikTok user" with shorter blasts of narrative and gameplay.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Undertale Steam Player Count Hits New Record Almost Ten Years After Release]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/undertale-steam-player-count-new-record</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/undertale-steam-player-count-hits-new-record-almost-ten-years-after-release.1136562/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/undertale-steam-player-count-new-record<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Toby Fox's classic RPG&nbsp;<em>Undertale&nbsp;</em>has reached a new Steam player count record almost ten years after its initial release, and it's probably all down to a remarkable Steam sale discount.</p>

<p>As spotted by <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/undertale-sets-new-concurrent-player-record-almost-10-years-after-its-initial-release/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Automaton Media</a>,&nbsp;<em>Undertale&nbsp;</em>reached a 24-hour player peak of 11,071 yesterday, which is also the game's <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/391540/charts/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">all-time record</a>&nbsp;on the platform. Prior to the Steam Spring Sale's commencement,&nbsp;<em>Undertale&nbsp;</em>was averaging around 1000-1500 players per day.</p>

<p>It's almost certainly no accident that&nbsp;<em>Undertale&nbsp;</em>is currently on sale at a 90% discount, which means you can pick up one of the most celebrated and influential games of the past decade for one single measly dollar. Trust me, if you haven't played this one already, it's worth it.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/undertale-steam-player-count-record-books.jpg?itok=5IM3UcsF 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/undertale-steam-player-count-record-books.jpg?itok=jtVRx5Mf 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Undertale&nbsp;</em>has hit a brand new Steam player count peak.</figcaption></figure><p>If you haven't yet picked up&nbsp;<em>Undertale&nbsp;</em>as part of the Steam sale, you've still got a few more days to do so, as noted by <a href="https://x.com/tobyfox/status/1901049377134907874" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">creator Toby Fox himself</a>. Even if you don't intend to play it for a while, it's probably going to be a long time before you can get&nbsp;<em>Undertale&nbsp;</em>this cheap again.</p>

<p>Just in case you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Undertale</em>, it's a turn-based RPG with bullet hell elements created by solo developer Toby Fox (who also handled the excellent soundtrack).</p>

<p>I don't want to give too much away in case you're not already spoiled, and&nbsp;<em>Undertale&nbsp;</em>is a game best experienced without knowing much about it when going in. Suffice it to say that there's more going on here than just a simple SNES-style&nbsp;<em>Earthbound</em>-influenced RPG.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/undertale-steam-player-count-record-deltarune.jpg?itok=B4adxtPx 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/undertale-steam-player-count-record-deltarune.jpg?itok=rSLJNJOs 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Toby Fox is currently working on an&nbsp;<em>Undertale&nbsp;</em>spiritual successor by the name of&nbsp;<em>Deltarune</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>Currently,&nbsp;<em>Undertale&nbsp;</em>creator Toby Fox is hard at work on&nbsp;<em>Undertale&nbsp;</em>spiritual successor&nbsp;<em>Deltarune</em>, the first two chapters of which are available to play for free right now.</p>

<p>Fox <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/deltarune-chapters-three-and-four-2025" rel="nofollow">has said</a>&nbsp;that the third and fourth chapters of the game will definitely be arriving sometime this year, and he's also <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/deltarune-update-promises-smoother-development" rel="nofollow">promised</a> that development will be "smoother" following a fairly long gestation period for the game.</p>

<p>In the meantime, you can check out&nbsp;<em>Undertale&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/391540/Undertale/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC via Steam</a>, as well as on <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/undertale/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PS4</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/undertale/9pjggx9xjxpb" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox One</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/undertale-switch/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Nintendo Switch</a> (and, of course, PS5 and Xbox Series X|S through backwards compatibility).</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>