<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 14:37:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rockstar to Buy LA Noire Director's Studio Video Games Deluxe]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/rockstar-video-games-deluxe-la-noire</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rockstar-to-buy-la-noire-directors-studio-video-games-deluxe.1123689/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/rockstar-video-games-deluxe-la-noire<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Grand Theft Auto&nbsp;</em>studio Rockstar has announced that it will acquire Video Games Deluxe, the studio founded by former Team Bondi head and&nbsp;<em>LA Noire&nbsp;</em>director Brendan McNamara.</p>

<p>In a press release, Rockstar confirms the acquisition and also announces that Video Games Deluxe will be renamed to Rockstar Australia. The two studios don't reveal what they'll be working on together.</p>

<p>For his part, McNamara says his studio is "thrilled" to be a part of Rockstar and that the newly-minted Australian wing will "continue [its] efforts to make the best games possible". Rockstar publishing head Jennifer Kolbe, meanwhile, says it's "exciting" to add Rockstar Australia to the studio's lineup.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/la-noire-vr-case-files-video-games-deluxe-rockstar.jpg?itok=-xRtN_zF 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/la-noire-vr-case-files-video-games-deluxe-rockstar.jpg?itok=fjH56qWv 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Rockstar is acquiring&nbsp;<em>LA Noire: The VR Case Files&nbsp;</em>developer Video Games Deluxe.</figcaption></figure><p>If you're wondering where you've heard Video Games Deluxe's name before, it's the studio responsible for the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/la-noire-remaster-releases-on-consoles-and-vive-in-november" rel="nofollow">2017 re-release of&nbsp;<em>LA Noire</em></a>, which saw the game ported to consoles complete with all of its previously-released DLC.</p>

<p>The studio is also responsible for creating that same year's&nbsp;<em>LA Noire: The VR Case Files</em>, which serves as a sort of remake-slash-reimagining of the original&nbsp;<em>LA Noire</em>. It follows the same story, but its cases are unique and built from the ground up for VR.</p>

<p>Along with its work on&nbsp;<em>LA Noire</em>, Video Games Deluxe also worked on the mobile versions of the ill-received&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/grand-theft-auto-trilogy-definitive-edition-announced-by-rockstar-games" rel="nofollow"><em>Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy - The Definitive Edition</em></a>, although it's not the developer originally responsible for creating those remasters.</p>

<p>Last we heard, Video Games Deluxe was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/la-noire-devs-working-with-rockstar-on-aaa-open-world-vr-game" rel="nofollow">working on an open-world game</a> for Rockstar, although we haven't heard much about that project since it was first unveiled back in 2020. It isn't mentioned in the press release, either, so presumably the two studios aren't ready to reveal it yet.</p>




<p>As for Rockstar, the studio is currently gearing up for the release of tentpole sandbox game&nbsp;<em>Grand Theft Auto 6</em>, which is <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gta-6-still-on-track-for-fall" rel="nofollow">currently expected to land in fall</a> (although no official release date has been given for the game yet).</p>

<p>The <em>GTA&nbsp;</em>publisher&nbsp;also recently <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gta-5-pc-update-ps5-xbox-series-xs" rel="nofollow">released a long-awaited update</a> for the PC version of&nbsp;<em>GTA 5</em>, adding previously console-exclusive features and technical improvements to the game.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam Passes 40m Concurrent Users for the First Time]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/steam-40m-concurrent-users</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steam-passes-40m-concurrent-users-for-the-first-time.1123644/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/steam-40m-concurrent-users<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>PC gaming platform Steam has broken another major concurrent player milestone, and this one's a big one, likely driven by the success of games like the recently-released&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>.</p>

<p>As spotted by the ever-reliable <a href="https://x.com/SteamDB/status/1896195019419111562" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">SteamDB</a>, Steam passed 40 million concurrent players over the weekend, with 40,017,061 players being logged into the platform at one point yesterday. That, naturally, is an all-time record.</p>

<p>Back in August, the release of Soulslike action game&nbsp;<em>Black Myth: Wukong&nbsp;</em>helped Steam <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/steam-37m-user-milestone-wukong" rel="nofollow">break the 37 million concurrent user barrier</a>, so it's impressive that this weekend's total represents a three million increase on that, especially given&nbsp;<em>Black Myth: Wukong</em>'s <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/black-myth-wukong-expansion-sales-18m" rel="nofollow">popularity</a>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/steam-40m-players-monster-hunter-wilds.jpg?itok=KWdMFCbL 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/steam-40m-players-monster-hunter-wilds.jpg?itok=Zqr7iyME 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</em>has proven a big success story on Steam.</figcaption></figure><p>As SteamDB points out, 12.6 million of those players were currently playing games at the time the site logged the new concurrent player record, which means around 27.4 million were either enjoying other features or idling.</p>

<p>Still, 12.6 million people playing games on Steam at the same time is pretty impressive, and I'm sure Valve will be happy that its digital distribution platform still doesn't really seem threatened by its increasing number of rivals.</p>

<p>So, what games helped Steam reach the 40 million count? Perhaps one of the biggest contributors is Capcom's&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>, which <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-steam-player-record" rel="nofollow">attracted over a million players</a> at its peak, going on to become the game with the fifth-highest player peak in Steam's history.</p>

<p>Others include many of the usual suspects;&nbsp;<em>Counter-Strike 2 </em>has enjoyed 1.75 million players over the last 24 hours, and other big hitters like&nbsp;<em>PUBG: Battlegrounds</em>,&nbsp;<em>Dota 2</em>, and&nbsp;<em>Naraka: Bladepoint&nbsp;</em>all hit peak player counts in the hundreds of thousands.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/counter-strike-2-steam-40m-players.jpg?itok=F7GXgCeB 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/counter-strike-2-steam-40m-players.jpg?itok=4ziorc4F 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Counter-Strike 2&nbsp;</em>has a pretty respectable 24-hour player peak on Steam.</figcaption></figure><p>In other recent Steam news, Valve has <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/steam-early-access-update-warning-feature" rel="nofollow">implemented a new feature</a> that informs you if it's been a while since an Early Access game received an update, although the feature seems a little temperamental at the moment.</p>

<p>The latest Steam Next Fest is also underway, and our own Don has <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/10-steam-next-fest-best-demos-february-2025" rel="nofollow">compiled a list of some of the best demos</a> the event has to offer.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Visions of Mana Director Reveals New Studio Sasanqua]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/visions-of-mana-director-kenji-ozawa-sasanqua</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/visions-of-mana-director-reveals-new-studio-sasanqua.1123599/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/visions-of-mana-director-kenji-ozawa-sasanqua<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Visions of Mana&nbsp;</em>director Kenji Ozawa has announced that he's founded his own studio by the name of Studio Sasanqua.</p>

<p>As spotted by <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/former-dev-from-netease-games-ouka-studio-establishes-his-own-company-that-wont-push-the-responsibility-of-management-onto-developers/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Automaton Media</a>, the website for Studio Sasanqua went live yesterday, along with a teaser trailer (which is entirely in Japanese) announcing the studio and its name. The studio will apparently begin by working on smaller-scale projects before transitioning to larger games.</p>

<p>In case you need a reminder, Ozawa <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/visions-of-mana-director-quits-ouka-joins-square-enix" rel="nofollow">left his previous employer</a>,&nbsp;<em>Visions of Mana&nbsp;</em>developer Ouka Studios, back in December. His departure came after the studio reportedly <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/visions-of-mana-layoffs-netease-report" rel="nofollow">laid off a large amount of its employees</a> on the day of the game's release.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/visions-of-mana-director-new-studio-kenji-ozawa-sasanqua.jpg?itok=Zt_82rBS 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/visions-of-mana-director-new-studio-kenji-ozawa-sasanqua.jpg?itok=SdUr78gS 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Visions of Mana&nbsp;</em>director Kenji Ozawa has founded his own studio.</figcaption></figure><p>Speaking to Automaton, Ozawa said that he was moved to start Studio Sasanqua because he frequently saw managers not taking responsibility for failed projects. Ozawa believes that "management needs to protect creators", and that seems to be what he's intending to do with Studio Sasanqua.</p>

<p>According to Automaton, Ozawa will begin by developing small-scale games in Unreal Engine, but eventually, the goal is to transition to "full-blown, original PC/console games" (that's Automaton's wording, not Ozawa's).</p>

<p>You can check out the brief teaser trailer for Studio Sasanqua right here. Again, be aware that the whole trailer is in Japanese, and there aren't any English subtitles, so you might have to do a little interpretation if you don't speak the language.</p>




<p>Ozawa's previous employer Ouka is just one NetEase-funded studio to be hit with layoffs, project cancellations, or outright closures in recent months.</p>

<p>Others include <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/worlds-untold-netease-pause-shutdown" rel="nofollow">Worlds Untold</a>, the studio run by BioWare veteran Mac Walters, as well as&nbsp;<em>Just Cause&nbsp;</em>creator Christofer Sundberg's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/liquid-swords-layoffs-just-cause-creator" rel="nofollow">Liquid Swords</a>. Neither studio has released, or even properly announced, its first game yet.</p>

<p>NetEase also recently <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/marvel-rivals-studio-shockingly-closed-by-netease-laying-off-everyone" rel="nofollow">closed down the Seattle studio</a> responsible for working on<i>&nbsp;</i><em>Marvel Rivals</em>, despite the fact that the game has attracted 40 million registered users since launching in December. Sadly, it seems NetEase isn't quite the industry veteran haven it seemed a year or two ago.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>