<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 14:09:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gylt and Rime Developer Tequila Works Files for Insolvency]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tequila-works-insolvency</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gylt-and-rime-developer-tequila-works-files-for-insolvency.1034556/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tequila-works-insolvency<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Gylt&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>The Sexy Brutale&nbsp;</em>developer Tequila Works has filed for insolvency, with newly-appointed general manager&nbsp;Térence Mosca citing "prolonged market conditions" as the reason for the studio's predicament.</p>

<p>According to a GamesIndustry.biz <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/rime-developer-tequila-works-files-for-insolvency" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">report</a>, Mosca says he's proud of what his team "has accomplished together", but that the aforementioned market conditions gave his studio no choice other than filing for insolvency.</p>

<p>As a reminder, Tequila Works <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tequila-works-rime-sexy-brutale-layoffs" rel="nofollow">canceled an unannounced project</a> and laid off an unspecified number of staff back in October, calling the current moment in the gaming industry an "incredibly difficult time". Evidently, those layoffs and that cancellation weren't enough to save the studio.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tequila-works-insolvency-rime.jpg?itok=9k1Rc0Q0 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tequila-works-insolvency-rime.jpg?itok=LjOf2zZz 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Tequila Works is responsible for games like&nbsp;<em>Rime</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>It's worth noting that insolvency isn't necessarily the same thing as a studio shutdown; essentially, insolvency means an entity isn't able to pay the debts it's incurred, which means Tequila is functionally out of money but not necessarily defunct yet.</p>

<p>As such, the studio could undergo a reorganization under Mosca, although it looks like it might take a pretty mighty reorganization effort in order to save a studio that seems to have been struggling for quite some time.</p>

<p>In the statement provided by GI.biz, Mosca says that the studio is doing everything it can to "provide support and guidance to our teams", an assurance that was also made when the studio laid off staff and canceled its project last month.</p>

<p>The statement notably doesn't say that Tequila has canceled its remaining project or laid off the remainder of its staff, so it's possible we may see Tequila rising from the ashes at some point in the future.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/the-sexy-brutale-tequila-works-church.jpg?itok=LSlQWP4B 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/the-sexy-brutale-tequila-works-church.jpg?itok=cuhNEQBm 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Previous games by Tequila Works include time-loop puzzler&nbsp;<em>The Sexy Brutale</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>Tequila Works was founded in 2009 and released its first game, cinematic zombie platformer&nbsp;<em>Deadlight</em>, in 2012. That game was followed by titles like&nbsp;<em>The Sexy Brutale</em>,&nbsp;<em>Rime</em>, and&nbsp;<em>Gylt</em>, as well as last year's&nbsp;<em>League of Legends&nbsp;</em>spinoff&nbsp;<em>Song of Nunu</em>.</p>

<p>It remains to be seen what lies in Tequila Works' future, but don't be surprised if we don't hear from the studio for some time. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lego Horizon Adventures Review - A Lego Icon]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/lego-horizon-adventures-review-a-lego-icon</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lego-horizon-adventures-review-a-lego-icon.1034439/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/lego-horizon-adventures-review-a-lego-icon<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Lego has been a staple of gaming for as long as I can remember. From the early days on the PC with games like <em>Lego Island</em>, to the more modernized takes we see today based on popular franchise IPs such as <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/lego-star-wars-skywalker-saga" rel="nofollow"><em>Lego Star Wars: The Skywalker Saga</em></a>, there’s no doubt Lego continues to thrive.</p>

<p>Their latest adventure cozies up to Sony’s own <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/horizon-zero-dawn-review-merging-past-future-into-great-present" rel="nofollow"><em>Horizon Zero Dawn</em></a>, focusing on a video game story rather than an existing movie or TV show. We know that the idea first came from Lego’s people, so it’s interesting to see that they were the ones who wanted to explore doing something with Horizon beyond its own game and existing Lego sets.</p>

<p>Thus, we have <em>Lego Horizon Adventures</em>, developed in partnership by both Guerrilla and Studio Gobo.</p>

<p>When I first saw this game, I couldn’t help but ask myself: just who is this for? Is it for fans of Lego? Is it for fans of <em>Horizon</em>? After getting a chance to play it, I’d say the answer is something more in between.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/lego-horizon-adventures-01.jpg?itok=pGOUVv5a 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/lego-horizon-adventures-01.jpg?itok=rrsqcW9g 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Similar to <em>Horizon Zero Dawn</em>, <em>Lego Horizon Adventures</em> tells the story of a machine hunter named Aloy, who has to set out, gather a crew of characters, and discover her past. All of this is framed by a world settled in the far future – and most importantly, Lego bricks.</p>

<p><em>Lego Horizon Adventures</em> is at its core a new spin on the existing story we know from <em>Horizon Zero Dawn</em>, but truncated and retold with Lego’s typical sarcastic and oftentimes whimsical humor. Whether or not that works for you is going to depend a lot on how much you connect to Aloy and her friends, and want to see them in a more humorous environment.</p>

<p>On my end, I thought it was a cute way to get those who have played the original <em>Horizon</em> up to speed, but also fun to see these characters break out of their more serious setting. While Aloy and friends lean into a lot of jokes, the antagonist has also been exaggerated to a comical degree, which is to be expected from Lego's usual brand of humor. My only gripe is that they did cut out a lot along the way of adapting the story for a different format. Perhaps that won't be too much of an issue for newcomers.</p>

<p>As for how everything else works out, <em>Lego Horizon Adventures</em> sheds the original game’s open world, and in its place is a series of linear levels that must be completed to advance the story.</p>

<p>Each level consists of a different type of environment, such as mountains, a desert, or the jungle, and Aloy, or one of her companions selected at the beginning of each mission, will be allowed to explore it. You can even hook up another controller and play on-screen co-op, which allows more than just a single character to interact with the set pieces.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/lego-horizon-adventures-02.jpg?itok=Oox1KaxX 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/lego-horizon-adventures-02.jpg?itok=6HokTK8D 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>These linear levels are structured so that the characters can platform through them – climbing up bricks, destroying objects to collect a currency known as studs, and building structures such as ziplines or the iconic <em>Horizon</em> towers.</p>

<p>Scattered throughout each level, Aloy will come across various enemies, and these all have their own special gimmick to them. With a variety of weapons and gadgets at her disposal, highlighted weak spots on each enemy in yellow will help Aloy take them down quickly.</p>

<p>There’s actually a good amount of variety here, which surprised me. This isn’t like <em>Lego Star Wars</em> where you spent most of the time slapping someone with a lightsaber. In <em>Lego Horizon Adventures</em>, there are a lot of different weapons you can play with, and those playstyles extend to the other characters as well. For example, Aloy can equip a flame bow that causes elemental damage, or a bow that fires multiple arrows. The variety helps mix things up when different enemies are about.</p>

<p>While I found myself using Aloy often for her witty banter and access to ranged items, Varl’s ability to use spears was fun for a pure melee approach. It helps break up some of the monotony too, because largely, the linear level approach remains the same throughout.</p>

<p>Aside from that, <em>Lego Horizon Adventures</em> features the Mother’s Heart location from the Horizon games as a sort of hub. Here, you can regroup after each level, and purchase items using the stud currency to build and customize what a lot of this area looks like. The neat thing here is you can purchase classic Lego items too from Ninjago and Lego City, just to name a few.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/lego-horizon-adventures-03.jpg?itok=-8KxwVeC 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/lego-horizon-adventures-03.jpg?itok=rpuqcQTG 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>There are also smaller quests here on a notice board Aloy can pick up, which amount to things like killing so many of a type of enemy, defeating them using elemental abilities, and more. They’re just little extra tasks that can earn more currency, which Aloy will get in loads anyway from simply playing the game.</p>

<p>Additionally, Aloy can take on Apex Machines – further side quests that involve powerful enemies and help break up the pacing of the story. These quests are still available after completing the main quest, so there’s no real pressure to collect everything at once.</p>

<p>I think what impressed me the most with <em>Lego Horizon Adventures</em>, was the presentation. This is far and away the best Lego has looked to date, with plenty of colors, and the material of the characters and environments looks exactly how you expect Lego to look in real life. Everything is voiced with many of the voice actors returning - it's a solid effort.</p>

<p>It’s clear the development team put a lot of thought into how everything should look, and much of what people loved about <em>Horizon</em> is recreated here seamlessly. The machines are probably my favorite part – what with real kits for some of them already out there. It’s pretty easy to see why this game got the greenlight.</p>

<p>Whether you're a big <em>Horizon</em> fan or not, <em>Lego Horizon Adventures</em> can at least provide some entertainment for both crowds. It's a different way to get into the series for sure, but if you're already a big fan, there's a lot to be had with these characters and the Lego brand of humor. If anything, they've certainly provided a strong template for future Lego games, <em>Horizon</em> or otherwise.</p>

<hr><p><em>TechRaptor reviewed <strong>Lego Horizon Adventures</strong> on PlayStation 5 with a code provided by the developer over roughly 8 hours of gameplay - all screenshots were taken during the process of review.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Erren is a staff writer for TechRaptor whose writing experience stems from years of helming Nova Crystallis – a website dedicated to everything Square Enix… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/erren-van-duine">More about Erren</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>