<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:17:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hytale Pre-Purchases Have Already Covered Two Years of Development]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hytale-pre-purchases-two-years-development</link>
            <guid>1403542</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Hytale </em>developer Hypixel Studios has announced that pre-purchases of the upcoming voxel-based sandbox RPG have already covered two years of the game's development, so it looks like the future is bright for the once-ill-fated project.</p><p>In a <a href="https://x.com/Simon_Hypixel/status/2010691717637222614" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">message on X</a>, Hypixel's Simon Collins-Laflamme says the studio has "officially secured the next two years of development costs through pre-purchases", so even if nobody else were to buy <em>Hytale </em>now, it would be supported for at least that long.</p><p>Additionally, Collins-Laflamme says he's committed to supporting and working on <em>Hytale </em>for ten years as a "personal commitment", closing by saying his studio and the game are "looking very strong for the future".</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption><em>Hytale </em>is covered for at least the next two years.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>In case you need a reminder, <em>Hytale </em>is a sandbox RPG that began life as a specialized <em>Minecraft </em>server run by Collins-Laflamme and his fellow Hypixel staffers before being spun off into its own (rather ambitious!) project in 2018.</p><p>In 2020, Riot Games <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/riot-games-hytale-acqusition-adds-blocky-adventure-to-roster" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="cce18a43-847f-48af-84f2-b986b2f91e4f" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">purchased Hypixel</a> and the rights to <em>Hytale</em>, but in June last year, the <em>League of Legends </em>and <em>Valorant </em>developer <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hytale-canceled-dev-shuts-down" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="d7a83480-b8b4-4d84-9282-580c367fefa6" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">announced that it was shutting Hypixel down</a> and canceling <em>Hytale</em>'s development.</p><p>Initially, that seemed like the end of the story, but in November, Collins-Laflamme and some of the original Hypixel staffers <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hytale-rescued-early-access-soon" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="067e1363-c5fc-4311-97f7-059f8a0d8810" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">announced that they had revived the studio</a> and were back working on <em>Hytale </em>again.</p><p>Following that, <em>Hytale </em>received an <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hytale-early-access-release-date" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="6a5ca1af-847d-401f-92a0-bf49ffc1da92" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">Early Access release date of January 13th</a>, so it's less than a day until you can check it out for yourself and see what the game's epic struggle has wrought.</p>
<p>Given how many people have already pre-purchased <em>Hytale</em>, I'd imagine things can only get better for Hypixel from here on out, especially if the Early Access release is well-received (although the studio has attempted to <a href="https://hytale.com/news/2025/11/hytale-early-access-january-13-2026" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">set expectations</a> on this front accordingly).</p><p>If you'd like to join in the fun, you can pre-purchase <em>Hytale </em><a href="https://hytale.com/" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">right here</a> (or just wait until tomorrow, when it officially launches in Early Access). Stay tuned for more.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hytale-pre-purchases-two-years-development]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lego Pokemon Sets Officially Revealed with Five Fan Favorite Pokemon]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/lego-pokemon-fan-favorites-revealed</link>
            <guid>1403413</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Lego and The Pokemon Company have revealed a first look at the Lego <em>Pokemon </em>sets due to arrive next month, and the five 'mons featured in the sets are firm fan favorites.</p><p>In an <a href="https://www.lego.com/en-us/aboutus/news/2026/january/lego-pokemon-product-announcement" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">announcement</a> on the official Lego website, the two companies reveal that the first three Lego Pokemon sets, which are launching on February 27th, will include the following critters: Pikachu, Eevee, Venusaur, Blastoise, and Charizard.</p><p>First up, the Lego Pikachu set allows you to build a scene of Pikachu leaping out of a Poke Ball. It's got 2,050 pieces and some fun details, like electrical energy between Pikachu and the Poke Ball, as well as a "25" on its base to signify the iconic mouse's Pokedex number.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption>Lego <em>Pokemon</em>'s Pikachu set has some fun hidden details to spot.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The next major set incorporates Venusaur, Charizard, and Blastoise as part of a single group, and you can build them either to stand alone or to take their place on an "action base". Lego and The Pokemon Company say the base will have Easter eggs for you to discover as well.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption>These three iconic starters could be yours if you pick up their Lego <em>Pokemon </em>set.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Finally, the third set revolves around a 587-piece set of everyone's favorite...err...mammal Eevee, which boasts an "expressive face", as well as a "movable tail, head, and limbs". You can see the set here.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption>N'awww. Rather pretty backdrop not included.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>These Lego <em>Pokemon</em> sets were <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/lego-pokemon-announced-2026" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="061837bc-dce4-4048-9a56-e120cf284470" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">first announced in March last year</a>, but this is the first chance we've had to get a good look at what you'll get if you decide to pick them up.</p><p>They join the likes of <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/first-ever-lego-mario-kart-sets" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="d55c03af-b288-4bcc-a242-7dec1b9f0687" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Mario Kart</em></a>, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/lego-animal-crossing" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="25704771-aecd-4ebf-b2a8-3f90af39a5ca" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Animal Crossing</em></a>, and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/new-lego-horizon-adventures-playset" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="ab63eaa9-833d-4722-8604-5d043d22d543" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">Sony's <em>Horizon </em>series</a> in the video-game-to-Lego-adaptation stakes, although I have a feeling the <em>Pokemon </em>set is about to clean house.</p><p>The five aforementioned Lego <em>Pokemon </em>sets are up for <a href="https://www.lego.com/en-us/themes/pokemon/about" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">pre-order starting from today</a> over on the official Lego website. Pick a set up between February 27th and March 6th and you'll get a rather lovely-looking Kanto badge collection into the bargain, too.</p><p>Here's how much each set will cost you:</p><ul><li>Lego Pikachu: $199.99 / €199.99 / £179.99</li><li>Lego Eevee: $59.99 / €59.99 / £54.99</li><li>Lego Venusaur, Charizard, and Blastoise: $649.99 / €649.99 / £579.99</li></ul><p>Stay tuned for more on this and all other things <em>Pokemon</em>!</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/lego-pokemon-fan-favorites-revealed]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Planetary Survival Game Icarus Clocks Up Nearly 1m Sales During Steam Winter Sale]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/icarus-sales-1m-steam-winter-sale</link>
            <guid>1403410</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Icarus </em>creator Dean Hall has revealed that his game, which was released four years ago, received a huge sales boost from the recent Steam Winter Sale, and for that matter, so did its DLC.</p><p>Speaking on social media platform <a href="https://x.com/rocket2guns/status/2010559063088934997" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">X</a>, Hall revealed earlier today that <em>Icarus </em>clocked up just shy of a million base game sales during the Steam sale, and that RocketWerkz also managed to sell just under a quarter of a million "DLC units".</p><p>As a quick reminder, <em>Icarus </em>was on offer at a pretty hefty discount during the sale; while the game would usually set you back $35 (as, indeed, it would if you picked it up now), buying it during the Steam winter sale would have cost you just $3.50.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption><em>Icarus </em>racked up a pretty healthy sales total during the Steam winter sale.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>There are several DLC packs available for <em>Icarus</em>, including three major expansions and a number of smaller additions to the game. Hall doesn't break down which of the packs were most popular during the sale, unfortunately.</p><p>Still, given the fact that <em>Icarus </em>is <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/icarus-release-date-takes-flight-this-december" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="f3f90dad-acfd-4ecf-81f3-78c72b65f1bb" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">entering its fifth year</a>, getting a million-sale boost, however deep the discount may be, is a pretty impressive feat. There's clearly still an appetite for Hall's particular brand of session-based survival.</p><p>If you're not familiar with <em>Icarus</em>, it's a survival game that shares some of its DNA with extraction shooters. You can either choose to take on timed missions to complete objectives under pressure or simply explore <em>Icarus</em>' hostile terraformed environment at your own pace.</p><p><em>Icarus</em>' popularity has almost certainly been aided by the pedigree of its creator; Dean Hall is also one of the people responsible for perennially popular zombie survival game <em>DayZ</em>, so his name lends gravitas and credence to this title as well.</p>
<p>Right now, <em>Icarus </em>is only available on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1149460/ICARUS/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">PC via Steam</a>, but it's coming to PS5 and Xbox Series X|S sometime this year as well. Stay tuned for more.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/icarus-sales-1m-steam-winter-sale]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>