<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 22:54:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wizards of the Coast Closes Doors on Sigil, the D&D Beyond 3D VTT]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/wizards-of-coast-closes-doors-on-sigil-dd-beyond-vtt</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wizards-of-the-coast-closes-doors-on-sigil-the-d-d-beyond-3d-vtt.1334431/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Wizards of the Coast has ceased development on Sigil. The tabletop publisher's dedicated, Unreal-powered 3D VTT is being shelved, leaving all material on the program inaccessible to users. The silver lining is that some compensation is being planned for dedicated players.</p>

<h2>The D&amp;D Beyond Sigil Cancellation</h2>

<p>In an official D&amp;D Beyond <a href="https://www.dndbeyond.com/posts/2086-closing-the-chapter-on-sigil-and-thanking-the" rel="nofollow">blog post</a>, Wizards of the Coast explained the reasons behind the closure of the Sigil VTT. The long and short of it is, despite the service giving players the means to create fully 3D miniatures, maps, and environments for their games, the studio could not sustain the level of ongoing development to support the service.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/sigil-vtt-zombie-graveyard-screenshot.jpg?itok=zK_NDXpa 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/sigil-vtt-zombie-graveyard-screenshot.jpg?itok=eIgwcWn0 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>For a vocal part of the <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/dungeons-dragons" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em></a> community, the cancellation of this service was inevitable. This announcement comes seven months after a <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/wizards-of-coast-lays-off-90-of-project-sigil-staff" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">series of reports</a> confirmed 90% of the Sigil VTT's development staff were laid off. This was done because the scale of the project at the time was deemed untenable.</p>

<p>If you used this VTT service, Wizards of the Coast has provided a roadmap and some compensation for its removal. If you have a D&amp;D Beyond Master Tier subscription and used Sigil at any point between March 1 and October 23, 2025, you will receive a six month Master Tier credit on your account. The credit will appear on your account on November 7.</p>

<p>If you are still running your games in the Sigil VTT, you have a few short days to migrate your game. By the end of October, the servers will shut down and all material will be inaccessible. This is a shame, but the online space is rife with other VTT platforms on which to play such as Roll20, Foundry, <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/interviews/alchemy-rpg-vtts-and-focus-on-roleplaying" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Alchemy RPG</a>, and D&amp;DBeyond's 2D Maps system.</p>

<p>Lastly, certain digital pre-order bonuses tied to the platform will have alternatives. If you bought the 2024 Digital and Physical Core Rulebook Bundle, the exclusive Gold Dragon Sigil miniature will be swapped out for a new digital dice set on D&amp;D Beyond.&nbsp;</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/wizards-of-coast-closes-doors-on-sigil-dd-beyond-vtt]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>