<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 15:20:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 Steam Next Fest Demos You Need To Try - February 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/10-steam-next-fest-best-demos-february-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/10-steam-next-fest-demos-you-need-to-try-february-2025.1121805/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/10-steam-next-fest-best-demos-february-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Every few months we see a bunch of upcoming games come and take to the walkway to strut their stuff and showcase what might be releasing in the next few months, this time in the&nbsp;Steam Next Fest for&nbsp;Winter 2025. What started as a COVID-era replacement of opportunity for events like PAX has become a consistent discovery point for many developers, with Next Fests now reliably having over 1,000 games in them.</p>

<p>No one could try them all, but with some time to play a number, and my own feelings on games, I can tell you 10 Steam Next Fest Demos you should get out and try, or at least keep your eyes on these games if they sound at all interesting to you.</p>

<h2><em><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3445320/Tower_of_Babel_Survivors_of_Chaos_Demo/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Tower of Babel Survivors of Chaos">Tower of Babel: Survivors of Chaos</a></em></h2>



<p>Take the <em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/vampire-survivors" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Vampire Survivors">Vampire Survivors</a> </em>Bullet Heaven formula, toss it in a blender with <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/diablo-2" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Diablo 2"><em>Diablo 2</em></a>, and after a few checks you may find that you come out with <em>Tower of Babel: Survivors of Chaos</em>. Beyond the equipment being very <em>Diablo-</em>esque, you’ll also notice that many of the abilities seem like they came right out of <em>Diablo 2</em>. Hammer of Might made me think of Hammerdins,&nbsp;while Ice Orbs felt like my favorite<i> </i>build, a Glacial Orb Sorceress.</p>

<h2><em><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2911500/Yes_Your_Grace_Snowfall_Demo/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Yes, Your Grace: Snowfall">Yes, Your Grace: Snowfall</a></em></h2>



<p>The sequel to the exquisite <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/yes-your-grace" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Yes, Your Grace"><em>Yes, Your Grace</em></a> in 2020, <em>Yes, Your Grace: Snowfall</em> brings takes it to the next level with the same focus on narrative and strategic choices to be made, while adding new wrinkles and levels of options in what you can do. You can play this without having played the first, but you’ll have the story of the first game revealed as it sets up what the world state is at the start of <em>Yes, Your Grace: Snowfall</em>.</p>

<h2><em><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3475100/Void_War_Demo/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Void War ">Void War</a></em></h2>



<p>What if <em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/review/ftl-advanced-edition-review" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title=" FTL Advanced Edition Review">FTL</a></em> was built around the <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/games/warhammer-40000" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Warhammer 40k"><em>Warhammer 40k</em></a>&nbsp;license? Well, if they failed to get the negotiations over and had to slightly scrub off references, you’d end up with <em>Void War</em>. It adds a few wrinkles to the <em>FTL </em>formula, but it is very similar&nbsp;and features similarly snappy play and roguelite decision making.</p>

<h2><em><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2585830/Promise_Mascot_Agency/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Promise Mascot Agency ">Promise Mascot Agency</a></em></h2>



<p>From the creators of <em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/paradise-killer" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Paradise Killer">Paradise Killer</a> </em>comes a really out-there game – a world where mascots have abilities and are real beings in the same world with us.</p>

<p>You play as a disgraced Yakuza member (<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/like-dragon-gaiden-man-who-erased-his-name-review-yakuza-greatest-hits" rel="nofollow">voiced by none other than the voice of Kazuma Kiryu himself</a>) in a run-down cursed Japanese town having to rebuild a failed mascot agency by recruiting quirky and abandoned mascots and doing a variety of jobs around town. Expect to be driving a lot and doing silly things all over while the cast takes it deadly serious in a wonderfully campy and fun video game.</p>

<h2><em><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3448280/Gothic_1_Remake__Demo_Nyras_Prologue/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Gothic 1 Remake">Gothic 1 Remake</a></em></h2>



<p>The <em>Gothic 1 Remake </em>captures the classic <em>Gothic </em>feel in the prequel demo with that beginning of powerlessness in an open world that the Gothic series was known for in its heyday. You can feel yourself improving as you learn things, and the game looks beautiful.</p>

<p>There's some jank to be worked out for sure, but so far it looks like a worthy revival of a storied RPG franchise. Just give it some patience, and be willing to meet it part way as its world operates on a different sense than most modern open-world RPGs<em>,</em> and when the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gothic-1-remake-2025-release-window" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title=" Gothic 1 Remake Will Launch in 2025, Developer Says"><em>Gothic 1 Remake</em> releases</a> later this year you'll have a good time.</p>

<h2><em><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3218530/Best_Served_Cold/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Best Served Cold">Best Served Cold</a></em></h2>



<p>If you played one of 2016’s best games,&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/va-11-hall" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title=" VA-11 HALL-A"><em>VA-11 Hall-A</em></a>, you might have been looking for other games in that vein ever since. The newest contender on the block is <em>Best Served Cold</em>, which ditches the dystopic cyberpunk bar for a 1920s-era speakeasy, and adds in a murder mystery. Some strong storytelling and setup here make this a game I want to see more of when it comes out.</p>

<h2><em><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3482820/Crystal_Rail_Demo/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Crystal Rail">Crystal Rail</a></em></h2>



<p><em>Crystal Rail</em> is an innovative digital board game that also takes inspiration from roguelites. It brings to mind strategy games and trading games, both digitally and tabletop. It particularly brings to mind <em>Gazillionaire </em>for me, and the times playing that with my family in my younger days (back when games had play-by-email options).</p>

<p>My only complaint after playing it really is that it doesn't seem likely to have multiplayer in the future, so I can't plan to play it together with friends.</p>

<h2><em><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3112480/Drop_Duchy_Demo/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Drop Duchy Demo">Drop Duchy</a></em></h2>



<p><em>Drop Duchy </em>is an interesting play on the <em>Tetris</em>-styled puzzle formula by turning the blocks into pieces of a roguelite building game, and you arrange them to gather resources and/or build an army to take on opposition. It plays slickly, intelligently, and has that addictive one-more-try type feel that many of the best roguelites have.</p>

<h2><em><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2975950/Solasta_II/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Solasta 2">Solasta 2</a></em></h2>



<p><em>Solasta 2 </em>looks and plays great as an adaptation of <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/dungeons-dragons" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Dungeons and Dragons">5th edition <em>Dungeons and Dragons</em></a>&nbsp;that aims to add more story and character to the series, building on what <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/solasta-crown-of-magister-review" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title=" Solasta: Crown of the Magister Review"><em>Solasta: Crown of the Magister</em></a> laid down. While it doesn't quite have all the bells and whistles of<em> <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/baldurs-gate-3" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Baldur's Gate 3">Baldur's Gate 3</a></em>, it is a lot of fun and it feels like playing a published campaign in many ways.</p>

<p>One small grace note for those looking to learn 5e from the video game is that they note when something is a house rule adaptation done to help bridge the gap between tabletop and digital roleplaying, so you'll know when a certain mechanic isn't quite the same as on tabletop.</p>

<h2><em><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2742830/Monster_Train_2/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Monster Train 2">Monster Train 2</a></em></h2>



<p>Did you enjoy <em>Monster Train</em>? Do you enjoy roguelite deckbuilders? If you answered yes to either, you should go and play the recently <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-train-2-announced-demo-now" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title=" Monster Train 2 Brings More Deckbuilding Madness, Demo Available Now">announced <em>Monster Train 2</em></a><i>&nbsp;</i>demo right after reading this article, as it is more <em>Monster Train</em>. An iterative, rather than innovative, sequel, it builds upon the first game by offering more of the same with new content and a few twists.</p>

<hr><p>That’s 10 games for you to try this weekend, among the many other games that are out there for the Winter Steam Next Fest 2025. If you’ve tried one and want to recommend it, let us know!</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>A longtime lover of speculative fiction, in almost all its forms, Don joined TechRaptor in 2014 on a whim sending in an application as he was looking for… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/don-parsons">More about Don</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Hits 1.2m Steam Players at Launch, Breaking Capcom Records]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-steam-player-record</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-hits-1-2m-steam-players-at-launch-breaking-capcom-records.1121802/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-steam-player-record<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</em>has debuted to record Steam player numbers, shattering previous records for both the&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter&nbsp;</em>franchise and Capcom as a whole on the platform.</p>

<p>Per <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/2246340/charts/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">SteamDB</a>, the game currently has 1,267,944 concurrent players, and that number is rapidly climbing, too. I wouldn't be surprised if <i>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</i>broke the 1.5 million mark later in the day, when people start coming home from work, school, and their various other obligations.</p>

<p>It probably goes without saying that this represents an absolutely colossal leap up from&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter</em>'s previous Steam record, which was achieved by&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter World</em>'s 334,684 peak player count back in 2018. (Incidentally,&nbsp;<em>World&nbsp;</em>still has 34,745 players on Steam at time of writing.)</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/monster-hunter-wilds-steam-player-count-1.2m-flying.jpg?itok=8O_-eGPm 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/monster-hunter-wilds-steam-player-count-1.2m-flying.jpg?itok=YWpKHTJb 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</em>has hit an impressive Steam player count on the day of its launch.</figcaption></figure><p>Of course, we're not counting the players who flocked to the first&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</em>open beta, which was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta" rel="nofollow">held back in November</a> and which also <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta-steam-records" rel="nofollow">achieved a higher peak player count</a> than&nbsp;<em>World&nbsp;</em>did. Still, that was essentially a demo, and this is the real thing.</p>

<p>Not only has&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</em>broken records for its franchise on Steam, but it's also shattered previous records for Capcom as a whole. The game has shot to the top of Capcom's <a href="https://steamdb.info/developer/CAPCOM+Co.%2C+Ltd./" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Steam charts</a>, beating out both&nbsp;<em>Capcom Arcade Stadium&nbsp;</em>compilations, as well as games like&nbsp;<em>Dragon's Dogma 2&nbsp;</em>and the&nbsp;<em>Resident Evil 4&nbsp;</em>remake.</p>

<p>Capcom's new game is now the seventh most-played game <a href="https://steamdb.info/charts/?sort=peak" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">of all time</a> on Steam; it's still got a ways to go to catch up with games like&nbsp;<em>Palworld</em>,&nbsp;<em>Black Myth: Wukong</em>, and&nbsp;<em>PUBG: Battlegrounds</em>, but I honestly wouldn't be surprised to see it scale those lofty heights over the weekend.</p>

<p>With that said,&nbsp;<em>Palworld&nbsp;</em>might have&nbsp;<em>Wilds&nbsp;</em>beat for now, but developer Pocketpair knew how successful the game would be; yesterday, it <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/palworld-pocketpair-monster-hunter-wilds-day-off" rel="nofollow">announced it would give its staff the day off today</a> because it anticipated a lot of employees calling in sick (almost certainly to play&nbsp;<em>Wilds</em>).</p>




<p>It's worth noting that this Steam number naturally doesn't take into account console players. I really wouldn't be surprised if&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</em>turns out to have sold two or three million copies on launch day alone.</p>

<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2246340/Monster_Hunter_Wilds/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/monster-hunter-wilds/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PS5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-GB/games/store/monster-hunter-wilds/9p7pd6wp5ghx" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>. Make sure to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/monster-hunter-wilds-review-new-frontier" rel="nofollow">read our Tyler's review here</a> to see why it's worth the hype.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zenless Zone Zero Version 1.6 Brings New Agents and More in March]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/zenless-zone-zero-version-16-march</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zenless-zone-zero-version-1-6-brings-new-agents-and-more-in-march.1121769/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/zenless-zone-zero-version-16-march<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>HoYoverse has announced the&nbsp;<em>Zenless Zone Zero&nbsp;</em>Version 1.6 release date, with the latest update for the stylish hack-and-slash action RPG set to launch next month.</p>

<p>Following on from <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/zenless-zone-zero-version-1-5-release-date" rel="nofollow">January's Version 1.5</a>,&nbsp;<em>Zenless Zone Zero&nbsp;</em>Version 1.6, which bears the characteristically HoYoverse alternate title of "Among the Forgotten Ruins", will launch across all platforms on March 12th.</p>

<p>It'll bring with it a new chapter of the main story in which you must go up against the mysterious phantom thief syndicate known as Mockingbird, attempting to secure an artifact replete with secrets. Sounds like classic&nbsp;<em>Zenless Zone Zero&nbsp;</em>stuff to me.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/zenless-zone-zero-version-1.6-soldier-0-anby.jpg?itok=yw5J5rMM 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/zenless-zone-zero-version-1.6-soldier-0-anby.jpg?itok=oj4oOjs9 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Zenless Zone Zero&nbsp;</em>Version 1.6 brings new Agents and more in March.</figcaption></figure><p>As is usually the case with <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/genshin-impact-version-54-release-date" rel="nofollow">updates</a> for HoYoverse's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/honkai-star-rail-version-31-release-date" rel="nofollow">games</a>,&nbsp;<em>Zenless Zone Zero&nbsp;</em>Version 1.6 will also bring three new Agents with it. The first, Soldier 0 - Anby, is an S-rank Electric Attack Agent who can amplify crit damage for her allies.</p>

<p>Another S-rank Agent, Trigger, will also be joining the fray in this update. Like Soldier 0 - Anby, Trigger's element is Electric, but she's a Stun Agent who can easily dodge attacks using her Sniper Mode and boost damage from her teammates.</p>

<p>Lastly, Pulchra will be available as an A-rank Physical Stun Agent in Version 1.6, and reruns will be available for Fire Anomaly Agent Burnice and Ether Attack Agent Zhuyuan throughout the update's life cycle.</p>

<p>As well as all of the above, you'll also get the chance to fight a new boss, Geppetto, in Hollow Zero, and there are plenty of other new challenges to try out as well.&nbsp;<em>Zenless Zone Zero&nbsp;</em>Version 1.6 is a characteristically dense HoYoverse update, so make sure to add March 12th to your calendar if you're a fan.</p>




<p><em>Zenless Zone Zero&nbsp;</em>is the latest game to be released by&nbsp;<em>Genshin Impact&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Honkai: Star Rail&nbsp;</em>studio HoYoverse (<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/genshin-impact-developer-mihoyo-rebrands-as-hoyoverse" rel="nofollow">formerly known as miHoYo</a>).</p>

<p>Like its predecessors,&nbsp;<em>Zenless Zone Zero&nbsp;</em>is an action RPG, but its emphasis is far more on stylish hack-and-slash combat rather than the elemental experimentation of&nbsp;<em>Genshin&nbsp;</em>or the turn-based strategizing of&nbsp;<em>Honkai: Star Rail</em>.</p>

<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Zenless Zone Zero&nbsp;</em>right now for free on <a href="https://zenless.hoyoverse.com/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC, PlayStation 5, and mobile devices</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>