<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 14:54:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zenless Zone Zero Version 2.3 Brings Spooky Delights Next Month]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/zenless-zone-zero-version-23-october</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zenless-zone-zero-version-2-3-brings-spooky-delights-next-month.1311472/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>HoYoverse has announced the release date for the next major&nbsp;<em>Zenless Zone Zero&nbsp;</em>update, and since it'll arrive not long before the spookiest day of the year, you can expect lots of creepy treats to enjoy.</p>

<p>Per a press release, Version 2.3, which will, naturally, follow on from <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/zenless-zone-zero-version-22-release-date" rel="nofollow">September's Version 2.2</a>, will be arriving on October 15th, bringing three brand new Agents for your team, a new map to explore, and more.</p>

<p>First and foremost, you'll be exploring the brand new Timesworn Hills area, which, as HoYoverse says, is a place where "ghost stories echo through abandoned ruins". You'll be investigating the disappearance of miners in the region, which will lead to the discovery of "unsettling truths".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/zenless-zone-zero-version-2.3-release-date-spook-shack.jpg?itok=fgIjtAP4 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/zenless-zone-zero-version-2.3-release-date-spook-shack.jpg?itok=R4R73ypu 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Zenless Zone Zero&nbsp;</em>Version 2.3 will have you investigating miners' disappearances alongside the Spook Shack faction.</figcaption></figure><p>Naturally, you'll also be recruiting new Agents to your cause, starting with Lucia, an S-rank Ether Support Agent who can boost her allies' HP and damage, making her a valuable asset as you explore the Timesworn Hills.</p>

<p>She's joined by Yidhari, an S-Rank Ice Rupture Agent whose damage is boosted as her HP falls. You'll need to strike a balance between risk and safety if you want to maximize her damage potential.</p>

<p>Your final new Agent in&nbsp;<em>Zenless Zone Zero&nbsp;</em>Version 2.3 is Komano Manato, an A-Rank Fire Rupture Agent who gains damage as his HP scales. S-Rank Agents Vivian and Ju Fufu will also be available during this update as rerun banners.</p>

<p>You can also expect a new powered-up version of Soldier 0 - Anby, who first debuted during&nbsp;<em>Zenless Zone Zero&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/zenless-zone-zero-version-16-march" rel="nofollow">Version 1.6</a>, as well as a new turn-based combat challenge and the return of the Snap! Shining Strike photography event.</p>




<p>News of this latest&nbsp;<em>Zenless Zone Zero&nbsp;</em>update comes shortly after HoYoverse announced two brand new free-to-play games being added to its lineup, namely <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hoyoverse-honkai-nexus-anima" rel="nofollow">autochess creature-collector&nbsp;</a><em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hoyoverse-honkai-nexus-anima" rel="nofollow">Honkai: Nexus Anima</a>&nbsp;</em>and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hoyoverse-petit-planet-cozy-life-sim" rel="nofollow">cozy life sim&nbsp;<em>Petit Planet</em></a>.</p>

<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Zenless Zone Zero&nbsp;</em><a href="https://zenless.hoyoverse.com/en-us/main" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">for free right now</a> on PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X|S, as well as mobile devices. Version 2.3 launches on October 15th across all platforms.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/zenless-zone-zero-version-23-october]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[There Are No Ghosts at the Grand Preview - Fixer Upper]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/there-are-no-ghosts-at-grand-preview-fixer-upper</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/there-are-no-ghosts-at-the-grand-preview-fixer-upper.1311430/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>There Are No Ghosts at the Grand&nbsp;</em>was revealed during this year's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/xbox-games-showcase-2025-all-news-and-announcements" rel="nofollow">Xbox summer showcase</a>, and it was an instant highlight of the show for me. It's a mixture of reggae musical, renovation sim, and spooky mystery adventure game, and what's more, it's tiny UK studio Friday Sundae's first title.</p>

<p>I got a chance to sit down with a demo of the game, which showcases a slice of gameplay during which I (partially) renovated a hotel, sojourned down to a creepy abandoned island, and fought off monstrous chair-spider ghosts.</p>

<p>All of that might sound like tremendous fun, and I have faith that with a little extra time, it could be. Unfortunately, the demo I played is in serious need of some extra work before it's ready to open its doors to the public.</p>

<h2><em>There Are No Ghosts at the Grand&nbsp;</em>Is Ambitious as Heck</h2>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/there-are-no-ghosts-at-the-grand-preview-renovation.jpg?itok=9gMkHCD2 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/there-are-no-ghosts-at-the-grand-preview-renovation.jpg?itok=-kGJaHGy 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>There Are No Ghosts at the Grand</em>'s renovation mechanics are simple, but satisfying.</figcaption></figure><p>During my time with&nbsp;<em>There Are No Ghosts at the Grand</em>'s demo, which lasts around 30 minutes, I got to experience a tasting platter showing off all three of its core pillars. It's a pretty brief demo, and I don't think it necessarily does the full scope of&nbsp;<em>No Ghosts&nbsp;</em>justice.</p>

<p>The renovation mechanics on offer here are...fine. If you're expecting the depth of something like <em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/house-flipper" rel="nofollow">House Flipper</a>&nbsp;</em>or <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/powerwash-simulator" rel="nofollow"><em>PowerWash Simulator</em></a>, you're likely going to be disappointed; the systems are fairly surface-level, and they don't amount to much more than "point the right gun at the thing".</p>

<p>Still, the feelings of hoovering up loose debris or popping broken pieces of a boat back onto its hull are satisfying, and I can imagine that the areas you'll be expected to renovate will increase in complexity as you progress through the full game.</p>

<p>There's a fun little twist on the renovation mechanics whereby you need to use your house-flippin' tools to right the scenes of memories so they can progress, but again, they're not too much more than just following on-screen instructions.</p>

<p>During this demo, I didn't get much of a chance to explore <i>No Ghosts</i>' gorgeous English seaside setting, but I'm hoping that the full game will offer more incentive to wander the environs of the Grand and uncover hidden secrets. It's hard to say how well exploration and narrative will stack up since the demo is so short.</p>

<p>It's impressive that Friday Sundae is attempting to cram a reggae musical into&nbsp;<em>There Are No Ghosts at the Grand&nbsp;</em>as well, but I have to say I'm a little worried about how that element is going to pan out.</p>

<p>This demo offers one brief musical sequence, which admittedly isn't anywhere near enough to express a full opinion, but the character animation feels a little too stilted for singers to express the full range of the songs' emotions.</p>

<p>It remains to be seen whether Friday Sundae's game can capitalize fully on the immense potential of incorporating musical sequences into its exploration-renovation loop, but on the strength of the song snippet presented during this demo, I'm skeptical.</p>


<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/there-are-no-ghosts-at-the-grand-preview-memory.jpg?itok=s3PC3PDZ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/there-are-no-ghosts-at-the-grand-preview-memory.jpg?itok=UgQfltwr 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>I had to restart this section multiple times because of bugs.</figcaption></figure><p>Let's get one thing out of the way first: this is a demo, and it's an early one at that.&nbsp;<em>There Are No Ghosts at the Grand&nbsp;</em>is not due to launch until 2026, so Friday Sundae has plenty of time to rid itself of some of the more bothersome bedbugs in its hotel's rooms.</p>

<p>That's a good thing, too, because I encountered no shortage of bugs during my time with this demo. I had to restart chapters multiple times due to game-breaking (demo-breaking?) progress bugs, and the starting position for one chapter restart in particular is halfway through the floor.</p>

<p>Performance-wise, my rig struggled with&nbsp;<em>No Ghosts&nbsp;</em>as well. This is perhaps an even more subjective criticism than any other I've offered so far, but I'm running an RX 9070 XT and a Ryzen 7 9700X (plus 64GB of RAM), which is way above the game's minimum specs.</p>

<p>Despite that, performance was iffy, with lots of slowdown and chugging in scenes that weren't even particularly busy. Not only that, but some sections stuttered and froze up for several seconds, and while they always righted themselves in the end, I constantly worried each hitch would be the point at which the demo crashed.</p>

<p>I couldn't find a way to change the graphical options beyond resolution upscaling, and changing those options didn't seem to alter performance for me at all. Again, though, I should stress that there's every chance you won't experience these issues. We all know how mercurial PC gaming can be.</p>

<p>At the end of the demo, Friday Sundae sets up an exciting escape sequence, and my support character yelled at me that there was no way I could take all of the things chasing me, so I should just "leg it", in his words (a colloquialism I appreciated seeing as a Brit).</p>

<p>However, when I then dispatched every enemy chasing me with relative ease,&nbsp;<em>There Are No Ghosts at the Grand&nbsp;</em>didn't seem to know what to do, so it just kind of didn't do anything for a while before a title drop anticlimactically brought the demo to a close.</p>

<p>It was a funny moment, sure, but it also made me worried about <i>No Ghosts</i>' future. Yes, there's still lots of time for Friday Sundae to fix it, but I'm not sure this demo was ready for release, at least not in my eyes. This one's going to need a lot more time in the oven.</p>

<h2><em>There Are No Ghosts at the Grand&nbsp;</em>Preview | Final Thoughts</h2>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/there-are-no-ghosts-at-the-grand-preview-petting.jpg?itok=PQaRA2Oy 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/there-are-no-ghosts-at-the-grand-preview-petting.jpg?itok=--oLLint 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The cat is very, very cute.</figcaption></figure><p>I'm really rooting for Friday Sundae and&nbsp;<em>There Are No Ghosts at the Grand</em>. The genre mixture on offer here is so unique and so mad that I want nothing more than for this game to launch and blow me away.</p>

<p>Sadly, on the strength of this demo, I think it's got a very long way to go before it can achieve that. It's messy, janky, and glitchy, so it's safe to say that a lot of renovation is needed before this hotel is ready to admit guests, even for the demo itself.</p>

<hr><p><em><strong>There Are No Ghosts at the Grand</strong>&nbsp;was previewed on a PC using a demo build provided by the developers. All screenshots were taken during the preview process.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/there-are-no-ghosts-at-grand-preview-fixer-upper]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silent Hill f Sales Top 1m, Outpacing Silent Hill 2 Remake]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/silent-hill-f-sales-1m</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/silent-hill-f-sales-top-1m-outpacing-silent-hill-2-remake.1311427/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Konami has announced that&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill f</em>, the latest entry in the long-running&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill&nbsp;</em>survival horror franchise, has managed to hit a major sales milestone, and it's outpacing the last big release in the series as well.</p>

<p>Per a <a href="https://www.konami.com/games/corporate/ja/news/topics/20250929/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">press release</a> (for which we're using machine translation),&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill f&nbsp;</em>sales topped one million within a single day of the game's launch. Naturally, that figure includes both physical sales and digital shipments.</p>

<p>As Konami says in the press release,&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill 2&nbsp;</em>managed to rack up a million sales <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/silent-hill-2-remake-sales-1m" rel="nofollow">in its first week</a>, which means that&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill f</em>&nbsp;reached the same milestone significantly faster than its predecessor. Konami will doubtless take this as an encouraging sign for the franchise as a whole.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/silent-hill-f-sales-1m-kneeling.jpg?itok=KJEVVgw- 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/silent-hill-f-sales-1m-kneeling.jpg?itok=uklUoOrg 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The latest&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill&nbsp;</em>game,&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill f</em>, has reached a million sales already.</figcaption></figure><p><em>Silent Hill 2&nbsp;</em>went on to pass the two million sales mark <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/silent-hill-2-remake-sales-2m" rel="nofollow">in January this year</a>, and if&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill f&nbsp;</em>continues at its current pace, then it won't take the latest title in the series too long to pass its predecessor on that milestone as well.</p>

<p>If you're unfamiliar with&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill f</em>, it's the latest entry in the&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill&nbsp;</em>series, although it's technically a spinoff of the main games that doesn't require any prior knowledge to enjoy.</p>

<p>Developed by Hong Kong-based studio NeoBards, the game revolves around Hinako Shimizu, a high school student who must get to the bottom of why her sleepy town of Ebisugaoka has suddenly become wreathed in fog and populated by dangerous monsters.</p>

<p>Konami's goal with&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill f&nbsp;</em>was to return the franchise to its Japanese roots, hence the setting being a Japanese town rather than the more Westernized locales of prior titles.</p>




<p>News of&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill f</em>'s strong sales performance will likely come as a relief to Konami; the studio <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/konami-bloober-team-new-silent-hill" rel="nofollow">revealed back in June</a> that it's working on a remake of the original&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill&nbsp;</em>alongside&nbsp;<em>SH2&nbsp;</em>remake developer Bloober Team.</p>

<p>While we wait for more on that, you can check out&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill f&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2947440/SILENT_HILL_f/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/silent-hill-f/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/silent-hill-f/9n5nfrqv2hqq" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/silent-hill-f-sales-1m]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>