<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 16:19:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IGDA Calls for Greater Transparency Amid Adult Game Bans]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/igda-transparency-adult-game-bans</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/igda-calls-for-greater-transparency-amid-adult-game-bans.1256097/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The International Game Developers Association (IGDA) has issued a statement regarding recent adult game bans on platforms like Steam and Itch.io, calling for "greater transparency and fairness" in the matter.</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://igda.org/news-archive/press-release-statement-on-game-delistings/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">press release</a> on its website, the IGDA says it's "alarmed" by the way in which "legal, consensual, and ethically-developed games, especially from LGBTQ+ and marginalized creators", have been delisted and deplatformed by storefronts like the aforementioned two in recent weeks.</p>

<p>The association says that while it does not wish to engage in "the defense of harmful material", it does want to advocate for "reform, developer voice, and platform accountability", calling for developers' works to be assessed "fairly, transparently, and contextually".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/igda-statement-adult-game-bans-steam.jpg?itok=4TKURuPY 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/igda-statement-adult-game-bans-steam.jpg?itok=_5FVIrWG 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The IGDA says platforms like Steam aren't assessing adult games fairly or contextually.</figcaption></figure><p>The IGDA laments the sudden ways in which platforms like Steam and Itch.io are delisting and banning adult-oriented content, bemoaning the "lack of transparency around enforcement criteria, sudden shifts in policy, and...absence of appeal pathways" open to developers.</p>

<p>As the IGDA points out, these issues can lead to developers losing income, not to mention damage to their reputation; after all, some might be less likely to buy a developer's next game if they learn the previous effort was banned due to content Steam or Itch.io deem objectionable.</p>

<p>Not only that, but these policies can have a "disproportionate impact on marginalized voices", as the IGDA says. Censorship the association describes as "overreaching" may have a greater impact on "queer, trans, femme-identifying, and POC developers".</p>

<p>So, what does the IGDA recommend? The association is calling for clearer guidelines on what content is prohibited, as well as "timely communication" if action is taken. That's in addition to greater appeal pathways for developers, "advisory panels", and regular transparency reports.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/itch.io-adult-content-bans-igda.jpg?itok=3geS6vM7 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/itch.io-adult-content-bans-igda.jpg?itok=rYqnAEAx 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Itch.io has also been enacting adult content delistings in recent days.</figcaption></figure><p>This all began a couple of weeks ago, when a report by the activist group <a href="https://www.collectiveshout.org/open-letter-to-payment-processors" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Collective Shout</a> alleged that platforms like Steam and Itch.io were hosting content that glorified sexual abuse and contravened the guidelines of payment processors like PayPal, Visa, and Mastercard.</p>

<p>Following that campaign's commencement, both Steam <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/itch-io-deindexes-adult-pages" rel="nofollow">and Itch.io</a>&nbsp;began deindexing and delisting adult games from their platforms, the rationale being that if payment processors objected, then they may withdraw their services, leaving customers unable to pay for games.</p>

<p>However, this scorched-earth approach has already begun to affect creators it arguably shouldn't even go near.&nbsp;<em>Vile: Exhumed&nbsp;</em>creator Cara Cadaver, for instance, recently <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/vile-exhumed-steam-removed-sexual-content" rel="nofollow">reported that her game had been banned from Steam</a>, despite the fact it's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/vile-exhumed-review-dirty-computer" rel="nofollow">about as far from a glorification of sexual abuse or violence</a> as it's possible to get.</p>

<p>Let's hope the IGDA's statement stops this issue from getting too out of hand. It's all too easy to imagine a world where developers don't feel confident creating games with any adult themes in them at all for fear of upsetting nebulous organizations that have very little to do with the games they're causing to get banned.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/igda-transparency-adult-game-bans]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>