<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 06:46:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Greater Than Games Shuts Down in Response to Trade Tariffs]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/greater-than-games-shuts-down-in-response-to-trade-tariffs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/greater-than-games-shuts-down-in-response-to-trade-tariffs.1168236/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/greater-than-games-shuts-down-in-response-to-trade-tariffs<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Greater Than Games is shutting down. The tabletop publisher is reducing its staff and suspending all of its ongoing projects in response to the global economic volatility introduced by the US trade tariffs.</p>



<p>In an <a href="https://www.greaterthangames.com/blogs/news/greater-than-games-team-reduced-in-response-to-tariff-crisis" rel="nofollow">official post</a>, Greater Than Games announced that it would be scaling down its production of tabletop board games. The post is just three paragraphs, but is direct and succinct. Staff will be reduced and all new projects the studio was working on have been suspended. The reason for this scaling back is the trade crisis happening internationally caused by the US' trade tariffs.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/greater-than-games-sentinels-of-the-multiverse-box-art.jpg?itok=cVWXenpO 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/greater-than-games-sentinels-of-the-multiverse-box-art.jpg?itok=3roHNeUn 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>This closure is sad, but expected. As the <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/game-manufacturers-association-opposes-new-trade-tariffs" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Game Manufacturers Association</a> alluded to in their official statement opposing the tariffs, since the vast majority of board game development happens overseas, a lot of smaller tabletop studios may need to scale back production or shut down all together. Not every tabletop studio, even major ones like <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/hasbro-unveils-new-playing-to-win-strategy-expanding-their-reach-to-more-players" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Hasbro</a>, can justify a 145% price increase (at the time of writing).</p>

<p>Greater Than Games' post continues by stating their web store will remain operational. They will continue to sell product they have while supplies last. As for any pre-orders or fulfilled crowdfunding projects, they will be making an announcement addressing those projects at a later date.</p>

<p>Lastly, the post confirms that Greater Than Games' parent company, Flat River Group, will continue to support retail and distribution partners both through communication and fulfillment. Considering Flat River Group helps fulfill multiple studios in the tabletop industry, this is some peace of mine for ardent consumers.</p>

<p>Greater Than Games is most well known for <em>Sentinels of the Multiverse</em>, a comic book superhero co-op card game. This award-winning card game debuted in 2011 and has spawned countless expansions, a Definitive Edition rerelease, a series of comics, and an official TTRPG adaptation.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>