<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 02:22:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ares Games Announces English Localization of Several Italian TTRPGs]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/ares-games-announces-english-localization-of-several-italian-ttrpgs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ares-games-announces-english-localization-of-several-italian-ttrpgs.1024698/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/ares-games-announces-english-localization-of-several-italian-ttrpgs<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Ares Games will be distributing some Italian TTRPGs to English-speaking countries. The studio will be helping six unique, best-selling TTRPGs in the Italian market from two different publishing companies reach wider audiences worldwide.</p>

<h2>The Ares Games Italian RPG Distribution Announcement</h2>

<p>According to an official <a href="https://www.aresgames.eu/36303">Ares Games blog post</a>, the company will be distributing six "Made in Italy" TTRPGs and volumes in the English language. Three of these RPGs were produced by Italian publisher MS Edizioni, the others were made by indie studio Nigredo Press.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/five-days-promo-image.jpg?itok=5E8eBrwr 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/five-days-promo-image.jpg?itok=H5uGv1Vi 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The three MS Edizioni releases are described as light, self-contained, and highly innovative RPGs set in original settings. The first is Italian best-seller <em>Green Oaks</em>. It is a fast-paced narrative-driven RPG where players take on the rule of quirky elders staying at a haunted, rumor-filled retirement home.</p>

<p>The second RPG, <em>Five Days</em>, is a more somber one. Players play as a family member, either by blood or by experience, whose familial bond has been greatly damaged by past trauma. The game is an intense role-playing experience about navigating the raw pain of loss and fractured relationships but ultimately about coming to terms with tragedy.</p>

<p>The last MS Edizioni release being distributed by Ares Games is <em>Last Resort</em>. It is a cooperative RPG set on a tropical island during a zombie apocalypse. Players must work together if they want to stay alive at this resort.</p>

<p>The three RPGs produced by Nigredo Press are system-agnostic experiences aimed at enthusiasts with an emphasis on visual impact and novel gameplay ideas.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ares-games-flail-kult-artwork.jpg?itok=eDNlpYBT 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ares-games-flail-kult-artwork.jpg?itok=1MUNQeKL 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The first of these books is <em>Cthulhu Bay</em>. It is an investigative RPG packed with Lovecraftian horror and pulp-storytelling. It even allows players to create their own unique endings by piecing together Clues. In an industry packed with other Lovecraft RPGs like <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/call-of-cthulhu-arkham-review-supplemental-strangeness" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Call of Cthulhu</em></a> and the <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/arkham-horror-roleplaying-game-core-rulebook-review-this-is-halloween" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Arkham Horror RPG</em></a>, that novelty is notable..</p>

<p>The second book, <em>Flail Kult</em>, is an artbook featuring the work of Arcane Throne. It is a collection of black-and-white illustrations of brutal mythology with spiked weapons.and the endless cycle of time.</p>

<p>Last but not least is <em>Forsaken Scriptures</em>. It is a collection of minimalist word-maps designed for Mork Borg and other fantasy RPGs. It condenses the text visuals of whole dungeons into single images for easy no-prep adventures.</p>

<p>At time of writing, there is no concrete release date for these books.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>