<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 12:58:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ecco the Dolphin Remasters and Brand New Game On the Way]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ecco-dolphin-remasters-new-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ecco-the-dolphin-remasters-and-brand-new-game-on-the-way.1181898/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ecco-dolphin-remasters-new-game<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Ecco the Dolphin&nbsp;</em>creator Ed Annunziata has revealed that remasters of the first two games in the series are on the way, and that a brand new entry in the franchise is also in the works.</p>

<p>In an <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/05/05/xbox-asian-pacific-islander-heritage-month-2025/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">interview</a> as part of Xbox's Asian and Pacific Islander Heritage Month, Annunziata says that remasters of&nbsp;<em>Ecco the Dolphin&nbsp;</em>and its 1994 followup&nbsp;<em>Ecco the Dolphin: The Tides of Time&nbsp;</em>are on the cards, although it's not clear whether work on said remasters has begun yet.</p>

<p>He then says a "new, third game" that features "contemporary play and GPU sensibilities" will be made, although it's not clear whether he means a third modern project or a third&nbsp;<em>Ecco&nbsp;</em>game overall.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ecco-the-dolphin-remasters-new-game-website-countdown.jpg?itok=mKGlFMeC 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ecco-the-dolphin-remasters-new-game-website-countdown.jpg?itok=P3-AdhKD 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>At time of writing, this is what you see if you visit the&nbsp;<em>Ecco the Dolphin&nbsp;</em>website.</figcaption></figure><p>If it's the latter, then Annunziata is perhaps unfairly skipping over 1995's&nbsp;<em>Ecco Jr.</em>, its rather odd Sega Pico-only sequel, and 2000's Dreamcast game&nbsp;<em>Ecco the Dolphin: Defender of the Future</em>, which was due to get its own sequel before the Dreamcast's demise.</p>

<p>Either way, Annunziata says interested fans should keep an eye on the official&nbsp;<em>Ecco the Dolphin&nbsp;</em><a href="https://www.eccothedolphin.com/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">website</a>. At time of writing, said website shows only a counter that seems to promise some kind of announcement or reveal at the end of April next year, counting down around 8,500 hours to do so.</p>

<p>In the interview, Annunziata says he believes that "gamers possess a higher than average IQ" when compared to "the average human". This he puts down to gamers' "socially connected" nature, as well as the fact (as he says) that they're "frequently fully engaged and challenged mentally with real-time systems and information technology".</p>

<p>The&nbsp;<em>Ecco the Dolphin&nbsp;</em>revival will surely bring at least a modicum of joy to those who were hoping that&nbsp;<em>Dolphin Quest</em>, the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/intellivision-amico-reveals-new-game-from-ecco-dolphin-team" rel="nofollow">spiritual successor</a> originally touted for the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/leaked-intellivision-amico-documents-paint-grim-picture" rel="nofollow">ill-fated</a> Intellivision Amico, would come to fruition. There's a much better chance of&nbsp;<em>Ecco&nbsp;</em>happening than&nbsp;<em>Dolphin Quest</em>, that's for sure.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dolphin-quest-ecco-the-dolphin-team.jpg?itok=W_vhp-6T 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dolphin-quest-ecco-the-dolphin-team.jpg?itok=L9yoNdqR 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Dolphin Quest&nbsp;</em>probably isn't happening, is it?</figcaption></figure><p><em>Ecco the Dolphin&nbsp;</em>is just one of the many classic IPs Sega is currently in the process of reviving. Others include the likes of&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sega-new-virtua-fighter-game" rel="nofollow"><em>Virtua Fighter</em></a>, ninja platformer series&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/shinobi-movie-announced" rel="nofollow"><em>Shinobi</em></a>, and wacky arcade racer&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/crazy-taxi-reboot-open-world-mmo" rel="nofollow"><em>Crazy Taxi</em></a>.</p>

<p>It's likely we'll get to hear more about the&nbsp;<em>Ecco the Dolphin&nbsp;</em>revival in the coming months, although it's not clear whether the above timer is counting down to a release or just a reveal. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 Sales Top 2m in Less Than Two Weeks]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/clair-obscur-expedition-33-sales-2m</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/clair-obscur-expedition-33-sales-top-2m-in-less-than-two-weeks.1181856/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/clair-obscur-expedition-33-sales-2m<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer Sandfall Interactive and publisher Kepler Interactive have announced that JRPG-inspired adventure&nbsp;<em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33&nbsp;</em>has hit another big sales milestone less than two weeks after its initial release.</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://x.com/expedition33/status/1919701863491838316" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">post</a> on X, the two studios reveal that&nbsp;<em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33&nbsp;</em>has reached two million sales since its launch in late April. The figure means the game has picked up another million and a half sales since <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/clair-obscur-expedition-33-sales-500k" rel="nofollow">very quickly hitting 500,000</a>&nbsp;on launch day.</p>

<p>Sandfall says it's "watched in awe" as players flocked to&nbsp;<em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em>, "feeling every step, every emotion, every revelation" alongside those playing through the&nbsp;<em>Final Fantasy</em>-style RPG.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/clair-obscur-expedition-33-sales-2m-boss.jpg?itok=USkaGTri 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/clair-obscur-expedition-33-sales-2m-boss.jpg?itok=83SgQxfC 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Turn-based RPG&nbsp;<em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33&nbsp;</em>is selling pretty well.</figcaption></figure><p>As before, the two million figure is particularly impressive when considering that&nbsp;<em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33&nbsp;</em>is also available on Game Pass (as part of the PC and Ultimate tiers, at least), so two million people have bought it rather than opting to play it via the subscription service.</p>

<p>If you're unfamiliar with&nbsp;<em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em>, it's a turn-based RPG inspired by the&nbsp;<em>Final Fantasy&nbsp;</em>series, and it's also a pretty strong argument against&nbsp;<em>Final Fantasy&nbsp;</em>producer Naoki Yoshida's <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/final-fantasy-16-ditched-turn-based-combat-to-appeal-to-younger-generations-producer-says/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">assertions</a> that gamers don't want turn-based games anymore.</p>

<p>The game follows the titular Expedition 33 as it sets out to put an end to the Paintress, a solemn and terrifying figure who paints increasingly low numbers each year, with everyone of the equivalent age perishing as she paints.</p>

<p>It features staples of the JRPG genre like an overworld map with plenty of optional locations to explore, party members that can be swapped out on the fly, and turn-based battles (albeit with real-time elements and a parry system).</p>




<p>If you want to see what all the fuss is about, you can pick up&nbsp;<em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1903340/Clair_Obscur_Expedition_33/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/clair-obscur--expedition-33/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/clair-obscur-expedition-33/9ppt8k6gqhrz" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>. Be sure to read <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/clair-obscur-expedition-33-review-french-revolution" rel="nofollow">our Erren's review here</a> to see what she thought, too.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>