<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 12:36:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Nightreign Duo Expeditions Confirmed as Sales Top 3.5m]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/elden-ring-nightreign-duos-confirmed-sales</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-nightreign-duo-expeditions-confirmed-as-sales-top-3-5m.1205358/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/elden-ring-nightreign-duos-confirmed-sales<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer FromSoftware and publisher Bandai Namco have announced that one of&nbsp;<em>Elden Ring Nightreign</em>'s most-requested features will be coming to the game at a later date, and that a new sales milestone has been reached as well.</p>

<p>In <a href="https://x.com/ELDENRING/status/1929780347576750367" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">a post</a> on X, the two studios celebrate&nbsp;<em>Elden Ring Nightreign&nbsp;</em>reaching 3.5 million sales across both its physical and digital versions, which means it's amassed <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/elden-ring-nightreign-sales-2m" rel="nofollow">another 1.5m sales in the last few days</a>.</p>

<p>Perhaps more importantly, however, in a <a href="https://x.com/ELDENRING/status/1929780349380223096" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">followup message</a>, FromSoftware and Bandai Namco confirm that&nbsp;<em>Nightreign&nbsp;</em>will be getting duo expeditions at some point in the future. At the moment, it's only possible to play as a solo adventurer or in a group of three, unless one of your squad leaves partway through a run.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/elden-ring-nightreign-sales-3.5m-duos-roundtable-hold.jpg?itok=vm578ufc 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/elden-ring-nightreign-sales-3.5m-duos-roundtable-hold.jpg?itok=VibhdlM_ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Duos are finally on their way to&nbsp;<em>Elden Ring Nightreign</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>As well as duos, FromSoftware has also confirmed that future&nbsp;<em>Elden Ring Nightreign&nbsp;</em>updates will add "enhanced fights against existing Nightlords starting this month", although the studio doesn't explain exactly what that will entail.</p>

<p>Of course, the game will also be getting DLC "later this year", and although we're not sure what that will include either, I'd be surprised if it didn't add new minibosses, new map locations, and new Nightlords to take down at the very least.</p>

<p>If you're unfamiliar with&nbsp;<em>Elden Ring Nightreign</em>, it's a multiplayer spinoff of the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/elden-ring-sales-30m" rel="nofollow">wildly successful</a>&nbsp;<em>Elden Ring</em>. The game takes the core combat of its bigger sibling and transposes it into a roguelike environment, where the goal is to gear up, level up, and fight bosses before taking down a bigger boss at the end of each run.</p>




<p>Updates to improve&nbsp;<em>Nightreign</em>'s gameplay and infrastructure are already underway. Just yesterday, FromSoftware <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/elden-ring-nightreign-update-solo-revival" rel="nofollow">released an update for the game</a> that included the ability to revive during solo play, among other improvements.</p>

<p><em>Elden Ring Nightreign&nbsp;</em>is available right now for <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2622380/ELDEN_RING_NIGHTREIGN/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/elden-ring-nightreign/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/elden-ring-nightreign-deluxe-edition/9NDVX8HSXGLR" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox</a>. You can <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/elden-ring-nightreign-review-fort-night" rel="nofollow">check out my review of the game here</a> if you want to know my thoughts.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Everything We Learned About Riftbound At The Pre-Launch Summit]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/everything-we-learned-about-riftbound-league-of-legends-tcg-at-pre-launch-summit</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/everything-we-learned-about-riftbound-at-the-pre-launch-summit.1205310/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/everything-we-learned-about-riftbound-league-of-legends-tcg-at-pre-launch-summit<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Last Week, Techraptor was among a group of Media, TCG Influencers, and Riot Games influencers that were lucky enough to be invited to LA to visit the Riot Games headquarters and not only play <em>Riftbound</em>, the <em>League of Legends TCG</em>, but also hear all about the game's roadmap. We got to hear about <em>Riftbound's </em>release plans, organized play strategy, and design principles as the "physical fandom expression of <em>League of Legends</em> for all fans out there."</p>

<p>If you're interested in learning what we thought about the game be sure to <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="a63f9b90-cea7-4679-9c53-8cdd7c0159bd" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/previews/riftbound-league-of-legends-tcg-mixes-fast-gameplay-consistent-resource-system" rel="nofollow">check out our preview</a>, if you're interested in learning a bit more about Deckbuilding you can check out the rules and styles of decks that will be available as part of Set One, and if you're a collector wondering what cards you'll want to be looking for be sure to check out our guide on the rarity of cards and the incredibly exclusive Overnumbered cards.</p>

<p>If you're interested in learning about the release of Set One, Origins, what it will take to make it to <em>Riftbound Worlds</em>, or what kinds of steps were taken during the development process then continue below.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/riftbound-league-of-legends-tcg-chengran-chai-and-dave-guskin.jpg?itok=oP8oy54f 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/riftbound-league-of-legends-tcg-chengran-chai-and-dave-guskin.jpg?itok=E5eIrCiL 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Riftbound </em>Executive Producer Chengran Chai and Game Director Dave Guskin who walked us through everything <em>Riftbound</em></figcaption></figure><h2><em>Riftbound Set 1: Origins</em></h2>

<p>Set one of <em>Riftbound </em>will be called <em>Origins</em>, this set is being designed as a warm welcome not only to fans of <em>League of Legends</em> and it's spin-off games and media, but also an introduction to TCG players, featuring Legends with a wide variety of mechanics.</p>

<p>Dave Guskin, Game Director for <em>Riftbound</em>, explained that while future Sets may have more theming that Origins is meant to be "good honest <em>Riftbound</em>… whatever that means."</p>

<p>While we at the event got our hands on the four Trial Decks there is a lot planned for the release including Booster Packs and Sets, a Proving Grounds 'board-game-like' experience for 2-4 players with everything you need to play, and three Champion Decks (<em>Riftbound's </em>version of a pre-con) featuring Jinx, Victor, and Lee Sin.</p>

<h2>The Road To Release</h2>

<p>Talking more about where <em>Riftbound </em>came from it was explained that while investigating ways to bring Legends of Runeterra to China they discovered that while bringing in a Video Game was difficult, that a physical TCG would be a completely different story.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/riftbound-league-of-legends-tcg-conference-room.jpg?itok=-lD1m7Ep 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/riftbound-league-of-legends-tcg-conference-room.jpg?itok=emEjnVTY 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Once the basics of the gameplay had been ironed out it became very apparent, internally and externally, that <em>Riftbound </em>was a fun game that there was a desire to bring to a global audience. From there Riot Games was able to continue to develop <em>Riftbound </em>at a rapid pace, what helped even further was that they were able to leverage all of the art from Legends of Runeterra to feature on cards, allowing them to find a release pace that would be impossible otherwise.</p>

<p>While the core mechanics had been nailed down through pre-release events the team at Riot had continued to hear feedback that the art wasn't looking enough like something that shows off the flair of <em>Riftbound</em>.</p>

<p>With this feedback changes were implemented including a new design to make all of the cards look more recognizable from a distance and also add things like a border filigree that represents the rarity of a card or have artwork that 'breaks' out of the frame as they get rarer.</p>

<p>There was also an aim to appease to both Western and Eastern players where by "for the west [Riot] wanted everything to be clear, for the East [Riot] wanted to have full art and the flash."</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/riftbound-league-of-legends-tcg-cards-in-hand.jpg?itok=oetVocy6 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/riftbound-league-of-legends-tcg-cards-in-hand.jpg?itok=B8rVmRfh 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Looking forward as we get closer to the Summer China release of <em>Riftbound</em>, and the October Western release there are a number of places that interested players will get a chance to learn more about <em>Riftbound</em>:</p>

<ul><li aria-level="1">June 9th to July 18th - There will be a "spoiler season" where <em>Riftbound </em>cards will be getting slowly previewed</li>
	<li aria-level="1">June 27th to July 12th - <em>League of Legends Mid-Season Internationals</em>, taking place in Vancouver this year, will offer demos</li>
	<li aria-level="1">July 31st to August 3rd - GenGon</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Summer - China launch for <em>Riftbound</em></li>
	<li aria-level="1">October - English Release, including Organized Play</li>
	<li aria-level="1"><em>League of Legends World Championships</em> in China and the <em>TFT Paris Open</em> in France</li>
</ul><h2><em>Riftbound </em>Preview Season</h2>

<p>If you're wanting to learn more about the cards that will be accessible to you the Card Gallery will be getting updated with two to three cards every Monday, Wednesday, and Friday up until 2 weeks before the official Chinese launch of <em>Riftbound</em>. Once the card previews are over Riot Games will then start releasing Deckbuilding and Gameplay content to help you begin as a pro.</p>

<p>Each of these card groupings will have mechanics in common or be specifically shown off to get your TCG strategy brains working to try to come up with different strategies that you might want to implements in your own deck when <em>Riftbound </em>fully releases.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/riftbound-league-of-legends-tcg-activating-a-card.jpg?itok=p_2nYSyZ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/riftbound-league-of-legends-tcg-activating-a-card.jpg?itok=sZQApBq1 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Some cards won't just be released via the Card Gallery but will be revealed by Press, Influencers, and members of the community so be sure to also be following creators.</p>

<p><em>Riftbound: Origins</em> will release with an impressive 377 cards total.</p>

<h2><em>Riftbound Set 2</em> and Beyond</h2>

<p><em>Riftbound </em>plans to support continued sets with plans for a total of four sets a year and localization into new languages being explored. That being said the team is also very aware of not wanting to overload players or the market.</p>

<p>With each new set there plans to be new Champion decks (whether it's two or three with each new set is currently in flux, but there was a reinforcement that they always wanted a Champion Deck with every new Set release) and potentially new iterations of the beginner friendly 2-4 player Proving Grounds box set.</p>

<p>While the current plans are for the Chinese and English release of <em>Riftbound </em>to reach release parity by Set 3 there's always global events that can shift those plans. Riot Games has stated that they want to meet that parity ASAP.</p>

<h2><em>Riftbound </em>Organized Play</h2>

<p>There will be two levels of <em>Riftbound </em>Organized Play, the Local Play that occurs at your game shop, and Premier that starts with Regional Qualifiers and moves all the way up to the World Championship.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/riftbound-league-of-legends-tcg-influencers.jpg?itok=88yR2s4V 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/riftbound-league-of-legends-tcg-influencers.jpg?itok=zN5I_AXC 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>To support local playing there will be Release Events for each Set, Nexus Night (a weekly event) where participating players will get a three card booster pack, and Summoner Skirmish. Summoner Skirmish will take place at release, and then a month after and is focused at competitive play.</p>

<p>A unique approach to these Summoner Skirmishes is that you won't just be rewarded based on your final placing. But if you reach the Top 8, Top 4, etc you'll earn all of those rewards. That means if your deck is powerful enough to win you the Summoner Skirmish you'll walk away with a Participation Card, Top 8 Card, Top 4 Card, Finalist Card, Winner Card, and a Champion Playmat.</p>

<p>A key philosophy behind the Organized Play at the local level was also to give players a sense of momentum. Wins at the local level will offer you byes if you visit the Regional Qualifiers promoting your involvement in <em>Riftbound </em>at every level.</p>

<p>Regional Qualifiers are starting early in December. Based on how many participants attend a certain number of invites to Regional Championships will be distributed. An example given was that a Qualifier with 129 players might offer 4 players a spot in the Championship, but an event with 512 players might offer 16 invites.</p>

<p>This means that whether you're playing in a busy city with a bustling competitive scene or in a quieter area that there's a chance to earn that qualification.</p>

<p>There will be less Regional Championships for the first year; one in America and one in Europe. Past the first year they hope to reach two to three a year. You can attend the event as a participant, but for spectators they want to hold all kinds of other events.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/riftbound-league-of-legends-tcg-play-mats.jpg?itok=4jNqHjnZ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/riftbound-league-of-legends-tcg-play-mats.jpg?itok=67kD3wM5 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Prizes at the Regional Qualifiers include higher level promos, additional swap, cash prizing, and even 'Best of' prizing. This is intended to promote play that might be not the current optimal meta. If a player is using a Teemo deck, and is able to demonstrate skill at being the best Teemo and making it a long way even if they don't win, then there's opportunities for that player to be rewarded with swag themed for the Legend they're using.</p>

<h3>Organized Play Formats</h3>

<p>A number of Organized Play formats have been announced, those are:</p>

<ul><li aria-level="1">Constructed - This is the standard tournament format for all solo Premier events, set rotation is only planned to begin in 2028</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Teams - A tournament format for Duo Premier events and side events</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Sealed - A format for pre-release events and side events</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Multiplayer - For weekly events and will be a staple for side events</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Draft is currently still being worked on, but it will be intended for weekly events and side events</li>
</ul><p>While there's no timeline to any news on it at the Pre-Launch summit we also heard that there had been some testing internally about a PvE mode to allow players of different skill levels to participate together without fear of unfair competition.</p>

<p>Additional jokes were thrown around about a 5v5 format, consisting of two 2v2 battles and one 1v1 battle, where the aim is to "win two lanes."</p>



<p>While this is all we can currently discuss, expect to see additional images and updated articles from us on June 9th</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Andrew has written Video Game and Entertainment news, reviews, and guides for 10+ years. As Senior Content Manager, he assists in creating and editing… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/andrew-stretch">More about Andrew</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>