<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 13:18:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kill Team Blood and Zeal Review - All The Zealots]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/kill-team-blood-and-zeal-review-all-zealots</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kill-team-blood-and-zeal-review-all-the-zealots.1141971/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/kill-team-blood-and-zeal-review-all-zealots<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Kill Team</em> 2024 continues with the release of its second expansion set, Blood and Zeal. Following the same format as previous expansions, we're treated to 2 brand new kill teams, both sharing religious zealotry but to very different gods. In this article, we'll take a look at both kill teams and what else Blood and Zeal adds to your games.</p>

<p><em>Kill Team</em> is a skirmish wargame set in Games Workshop's larger <em>Warhammer 40,000</em> setting. As a skirmish game, <em>Kill Team</em> features a small number of elite troops, fighting special operations battles, rather than huge battles fought with entire armies. We've covered <em>Kill Team</em> in depth since the first edition, and you can read our review of the current <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/kill-team-starter-set-review" rel="nofollow">Starter Set</a> here.</p>




<h2>All The Fanatics All The Time</h2>

<p><em>Kill Team</em>&nbsp;Blood and Zeal, as with previous expansions, adds 2 brand new kill teams and some scenery that builds on that from the Hivestorm box, but rather than new missions, it has the Blood and Zeal mission pack to expand your games. The full box contents are:</p>

<ul><li><em>Kill Team</em>&nbsp;Blood and Zeal&nbsp;Dossier</li>
	<li>8x Goremongers</li>
	<li>11x Sanctifiers</li>
	<li>Datacards for both kill teams</li>
	<li>Tokens for both kill teams</li>
	<li>Blood and Zeal Mission Pack Card Set</li>
	<li>A large Shrine Statue scenery piece</li>
</ul><figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/kill-team-blood-and-zeal-4.jpg?itok=PD0g1vxH 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/kill-team-blood-and-zeal-4.jpg?itok=r57ShW_W 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Kill Team</em> Blood and Zeal includes a new style of mission pack with the Blood and Zeal card pack.</figcaption></figure><h2>Different Flavours Of Zeal</h2>

<p>Instead of the usual mission pack with linked scenarios,&nbsp;<em>Kill Team</em>&nbsp;Blood and Zeal adds a mission pack card deck to existing scenarios, putting the Shrine Statue in the centre of the board. The mission pack card deck has cards of 2 different types, and players can choose which deck to draw from. Cards are drawn at the start of each strategy phase, when your opponent scores a VP, or if you interact (praying or defiling) with the Shrine Statue.</p>

<p>Cards can then be played during the turn, with blood cards offering an offensive bonus like the Double Fight/Shoot card, which lets you immediately repeat a fight or shoot acction, and zeal cards offer a defensive bonus, like the Obscured card, which makes an operative targeted by a ranged attack more than 6 inches away obscured, reducing the hits by 1 and protecting them from critical hits.</p>

<p>At the end of the game, both players total up their used blood and zeal cards, and the player with the most of either, scores 1VP. The Blood and Zeal mission pack can put real pressure on during the game, as your opponent gains a card every time you score VP, giving them an edge as you never know what ability they've drawn, along with securing them a possible extra 2VP at the end if you've given them a lot of cards to use. It also draws combat to the Shrine Statue as both players try to control it to stop the other from drawing more cards.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/kill-team-blood-and-zeal-2.jpg?itok=nR4qSfOM 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/kill-team-blood-and-zeal-2.jpg?itok=-sDMkGWn 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2>Sanctifiers Are Us</h2>

<p>The Sanctifiers are ad-hoc units of zealots of the Imperial Creed, brought together by their faith, they join crusades with other forces of the Imperium or begin their own. The Sanctifiers have the Sermon special rule, that if played as a Strategic Gambit, one of their fighters gains the Orator keyword, which allows nearby units to benefit from the Sermon. Anyone benefiting from the Sermon takes 1 less damage from damage of 3 or more.</p>

<p>Each band is led by a Confessor, who, if is the Orator, can use the Lead the Procession special rule, which gives all nearby friendly units a free charge, fallback, or reposition action if the Confessor takes one of those actions, which can result in a particular devastating charge if you have a load of powerful units bunched up together.</p>

<p>The Confessors are backed up by Perscutors who wield oversized chainweapons, and Conflagrators, who dual-wield hand flamers. They can also deploy Miraculists, who have a single-use but very powerful Holy Light attack and can lay down psychic fire on nearby foes. To back them all up, you can take 2 Missionaries, who carry the heavy weapons like standard flamers, plasma and melta guns, but also have access to the Brazier of Holy Fire, which can be used as a short ranged, or melee weapon, and benefits from the Blaze special rule that sets targets on fire, dealing D3 damage whenever they activate until they put it out.</p>

<p>You can feel the fanatical zeal when using them. They're very close combat orientated, with short ranged weapons and melee armaments all round. They also mostly like to hang around in packs to benefit from the Sermon, except the Missionaries who's thematic 'Spread the word of the God-Emperor' ability gives their weapons severe if they're 6 inches away from other friendly operatives, and the Micaculists, who's Holy Light doesn't care who it burns.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/kill-team-blood-and-zeal-3.jpg?itok=8N3xrO0V 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/kill-team-blood-and-zeal-3.jpg?itok=ID17RwQA 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2>Goremongers Blood Drive</h2>

<p>The Goremongers are a different breed of fanatic. Like all followers of the Blood God, Khorne, they want to spill blood in his name. But these mortal followers are a further step into madness, having fought beside or seen the demonic followers of their god, and an obsession born of that experience pushes them further. Their cult starts with replacing their legs with bionic replacements and then installing tanks on their backs that carry a mix of blood and stimms that drive them and their augmetics.</p>

<p>These tanks give the Goremongers access to the Sanguavitae special rule, which lets them deplete their gore tank for special abilities. They have access to healing, increased action points, double fight actions, D3 extra damage on a charge, increased movement, and extra attacks. Tanks can carry a maximum of 2 uses and need to be topped up by taking out enemy fighters. This means that the Goremongers will do well against kill teams with lots of low wound fighters, but not so well against elites or durable fighters, and even worse against elite, durable kill teams like the Plague Marines.</p>

<p>As might be expected from a kill team that refills the blood tanks on their backs with their slain enemies, they like to get in close, which means most operatives are limited to wilding an autopistol (the Inciter wields 2!), but this is just to give you options, if you're shooting you're doing it wrong. The kill team is led by the Blood Herald, who can refill their gore tank for free if it's empty, thanks to their Khorne's Favour ability. They can also ignore the entirety of an attack once per battle.</p>

<p>The rest of the kill team is made up of an expected mix of bloodthirsty, melee-focused fighters. The Bloodtaker can fill their gore tank just by damaging enemies and can also transfer that blood to nearby friendly fighters' gore tanks. The Impaler is armed with a Fleshskewer that can drag enemies and choose not to inflict damage so that you can finish them off in combat, and the Inciter, who wields 2 autopistols, can also use them in close combat to make sure they're still taking the blood tithe.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/kill-team-blood-and-zeal-5.jpg?itok=fC2KlYaD 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/kill-team-blood-and-zeal-5.jpg?itok=kyYhUhXb 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The&nbsp;<em>Kill Team</em> Blood and Zeal Shrine Statue scenery piece is an awesome centre piece for your games.</figcaption></figure><h2>Kill Team Blood and Zeal Final Thoughts?</h2>

<p><em>Kill Team</em> Blood and Zeal is another great thematic box for <em>Kill Team</em>. The focus on getting up close and taking names works really well. The Blood and Zeal mission pack adds a new dynamic to the game, and while not balanced enough for competitive play, it gives a great narrative experience. The combination of Blood cards and the Goremongers Sanguavitae abilities can lead to some absolutely insane attacks. The Shrine Statue is an awesome scenery piece, and while it's nice to get functional scenery, having great-looking centerpieces is awesome too.</p>

<hr><p><em>The copy of</em> <strong>Kill Team Blood and Zeal</strong>&nbsp;<em>used to produce this review was provided by Games Workshop.</em></p>


</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Adam is a Tabletop Specialist for TechRaptor. He started writing for TechRaptor in 2017 and took over as Tabletop Editor in 2019 and has since stood down… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/adam-potts">More about Adam</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Upcoming Secret Lair Our Boss Is On Vacation Superdrop Brings Burst of Variety]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/upcoming-secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-superdrop-brings-burst-of-variety</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/upcoming-secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-superdrop-brings-burst-of-variety.1141746/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/upcoming-secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-superdrop-brings-burst-of-variety<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Wizards of the Coast has announced a Secret Lair superdrop for <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/magic-the-gathering" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Magic: The Gathering</em></a>. The lengthy Secret Lair Our Boss Is On Vacation superdrop will contain nine special drops for fans of the game to pick up, with a special promo card for those that go all in.</p>

<h2>The Secret Lair Our Boss Is On Vacation Superdrop Announcement</h2>

<p>In the official <a href="https://magic.wizards.com/en/news/announcements/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-superdrop" rel="nofollow">store page</a>, Wizards of the Coast outlines the cards in the Secret Lair Our Boss Is On Vacation superdrop. As the name implies, the cards in this superdrop are chaotic and sporadic. As if the person in charge wasn't around to approve them.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-spongebob-meme-cards.jpg?itok=AwPuvRi2 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-spongebob-meme-cards.jpg?itok=0buJQmb4 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The first three drops in the superdrop are the previously announced <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/spongebob-secret-lair-brings-iconic-cartoon-to-magic-gathering" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Spongebob Squarepants Secret Lairs</a>. Want to wield Mr. Krabs or Sandy Cheeks as Legendary Creatures or just cast meme-art versions of Counterspell and Force of Despair? These are the cards to pick up.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-dragonlord-card-artwork.jpg?itok=IxnkUZQ6 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-dragonlord-card-artwork.jpg?itok=bDcYs2ax 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The fourth drop in the Secret Lair Our Boss Is On Vacation superdrop is all about dragons. The <em>They Grow Up So Fast</em> drop showcases five different dragonlord cards. Each card is reversible. One side shows the dragon as a recently hatched wyrmling. the other shows them fully matured. This drop contains the following cards:</p>

<ul><li><em>Dragonlord Atarka</em></li>
	<li><em>Dragonlord Dromoka</em></li>
	<li><em>Dragonlord Kologhan</em></li>
	<li><em>Dragonlord Ojutai</em></li>
	<li><em>Dragonlord Silumgar</em></li>
</ul><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-garden-buds-card-artwork.jpg?itok=olZliX4E 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-garden-buds-card-artwork.jpg?itok=E8KJPcgo 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>For those with an eye for nature, the fifth drop is for you. The <em>Garden Buds</em> drop showcases nature or forest-dwelling cards in a trippy artstyle courtesy of Jordan Crane. The cards featured in this drop are as follows:</p>

<ul><li><em>Ashaya, Soul of the Wind</em></li>
	<li><em>Elvish Reclaimer</em></li>
	<li><em>Harrow</em></li>
	<li><em>World Shaper</em></li>
	<li><em>Horn of Greed</em></li>
</ul><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-tragic-romance-artwork.jpg?itok=Oh6dpFgv 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-tragic-romance-artwork.jpg?itok=-yv75yRj 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Drop six is for those that have indulged in a bit of fantasy romance. Aptly named <em>Tragic Romance</em>, this drop contains four cards with artwork straight out of a harlequin romance novel showcasing art by Abigail Larson. Those four cards are:</p>

<ul><li><em>Skithiryx, the Blight Dragon</em></li>
	<li><em>Kaalia of the Vast</em></li>
	<li><em>Angel of Despair</em></li>
	<li><em>Master of Cruelties</em></li>
</ul><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-twisted-toons-cards.jpg?itok=KxfwWXC4 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-twisted-toons-cards.jpg?itok=MbsPPp4y 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>In a complete pivot in tone is the seventh drop. The <em>Twisted Toons</em> drop sports an early 20th century cartoon look straight out of Fleisher Studios. If you like old-school Disney, or played a lot of Cuphead, these cards may catch your eye. Those cards are.</p>

<ul><li><em>Silence</em></li>
	<li><em>Winds of Abandon</em></li>
	<li><em>Culling of the Weak</em></li>
	<li><em>Fatal Push</em></li>
	<li><em>Young Wolf</em></li>
</ul><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-pick-em-and-stick-em-artwork.jpg?itok=FYlJGkfx 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-pick-em-and-stick-em-artwork.jpg?itok=nRujkfKD 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The eighth drop in the Secret Lair Our Boss Is On Vacation superdrop is yet another switch in tone. The <em>Pick 'Em and Stick 'Em</em> drop is a candy coated dose of bright, colorful fluff. It even has sheets of stickers to customize those cards further. The drop contains the following:</p>

<ul><li><em>Thalia, Heretic Cathar</em></li>
	<li><em>Clever Impersonator</em></li>
	<li><em>Hedron Crab</em></li>
	<li><em>Pitiless Plunderer</em></li>
	<li>Treasure Token</li>
</ul><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-class-of-87-artwork.jpg?itok=yjCvLUQE 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-class-of-87-artwork.jpg?itok=-edc-THw 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Last but not least is the S<em>ecret Lair: Class of '87</em> drop. As the name implies, this drop reimagines several cards as high school yearbook photos. The artwork by Stephen Andrade and Scott Okumura even goes that extra mile with era-specific stylized text. The cards in this drop are:</p>

<ul><li><em>Aesi, Tyrant of Gyre Strait</em></li>
	<li><em>Anje Falkenrath</em></li>
	<li><em>Chulane, Teller of Tales</em></li>
	<li><em>Radha, Heart of Keld</em></li>
</ul><p>All nine drops in the Secret Lair Our Boss Is On Vacation superdrop is available in both non-foil (MSRP $29.99) and foil (MSRP $39.99). In addition, if you spend more than $150 on a single order, you will receive a rainbow foil Deadeye Navigator promo card at no additional charge. The superdrop will be available March 24.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>