<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 17:20:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Cosmic Invasion Release Date Confirmed for December]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/marvel-cosmic-invasion-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-cosmic-invasion-release-date-confirmed-for-december.1331860/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Publisher Dotemu and developer Tribute Games have announced the release date for their upcoming star-studded superhero brawler&nbsp;<em>Marvel Cosmic Invasion</em>, and it won't be long before you get to check it out.</p>

<p>As revealed in a press release,&nbsp;<em>Marvel Cosmic Invasion</em>, which was first announced as part of a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-direct-march-2025-all-news-and-announcements" rel="nofollow">Nintendo Direct show earlier this year</a>, will be launching across PC and consoles on December 1st.</p>

<p>Not only that, but the two studios have also announced the two final characters to round out the game's 15-fighter-strong roster: Phoenix and Invincible Iron Man. They join a lineup that also includes iconic characters like Venom, Spider-Man, Storm, and Wolverine.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/marvel-cosmic-invasion-release-date-phoenix-iron-man.jpg?itok=Z3NcFVem 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/marvel-cosmic-invasion-release-date-phoenix-iron-man.jpg?itok=oH26KpMm 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Marvel Cosmic Invasion</em>'s two final fighters are Phoenix and Invincible Iron Man.</figcaption></figure><p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Marvel Cosmic Invasion</em>, it's a side-scrolling beat-'em-up developed by Tribute Games, the folks behind 2022's&nbsp;<em>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Shredder's Revenge</em>&nbsp;(of which our Alex <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/tmnt-shredders-revenge-review" rel="nofollow">was a big fan</a>).</p>

<p>Published by&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/absolum-200k-sales" rel="nofollow"><em>Absolum&nbsp;</em>outfit Dotemu</a>,&nbsp;<em>Marvel Cosmic Invasion&nbsp;</em>sees Marvel heroes banding together to fight the villainous Annihilus (the clue's in the name, I suppose), who's "launched an unprecedented attack across the galaxy".</p>

<p>You'll choose a team of two Marvel heroes, swapping between them as necessary and creating "unique team-ups" to deal "devastating damage" to your foes.</p>

<p><em>Marvel Cosmic Invasion&nbsp;</em>supports co-op play for up to four players, and you can play either locally or online. Drop-in-drop-out co-op is supported as well, so if you can't enjoy the entire adventure alongside the same people, it's no big deal.</p>




<p>Each player chooses their own team of two heroes, too, so you may well have up to eight heroes battling through the streets of New York towards the sinister-sounding Negative Zone to defeat Annihilus.</p>

<p><em>Marvel Cosmic Invasion&nbsp;</em>launches across <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2753970/MARVEL_Cosmic_Invasion/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10012545" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/marvel-cosmic-invasion/9n79tqtztqq4" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>, and Nintendo Switch (although not for Switch 2, it seems) on December 1st. Stay tuned for more on this one.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/marvel-cosmic-invasion-release-date]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PowerWash Simulator 2 Roadmap Promises New Crossover DLC and More]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/powerwash-simulator-2-roadmap</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/powerwash-simulator-2-roadmap-promises-new-crossover-dlc-and-more.1331857/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>FuturLab has revealed the first&nbsp;<em>PowerWash Simulator 2&nbsp;</em>roadmap, and if you're a fan of the franchise's crossover DLC, then you'll be pleased by what's in store for the next year or so.</p>

<p>As revealed in a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2968420/view/517476466977407328" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">news post</a> on Steam,&nbsp;<em>PowerWash Simulator 2&nbsp;</em>has three packs of "paid IP DLC" on the way, with one due to launch in each of the first three quarters of 2026.</p>

<p>It's not clear which IPs these DLCs will revolve around, but&nbsp;<em>PowerWash Simulator&nbsp;</em>has teamed up with some pretty big names in the past, including&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/powerwash-simulator-final-fantasy-vii-crossover-dlc-arrives-in-march" rel="nofollow"><em>Final Fantasy</em></a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/powerwash-simulator-warhammer-40k-dlc" rel="nofollow"><em>Warhammer 40,000</em></a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/powerwash-simulator-back-to-future-dlc" rel="nofollow"><em>Back to the Future</em></a>, plus more.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/powerwash-simulator-2-roadmap-40k-dlc-powerwash-1.jpg?itok=15E-Pn14 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/powerwash-simulator-2-roadmap-40k-dlc-powerwash-1.jpg?itok=GhDEZQ8N 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Will&nbsp;<em>PowerWash Simulator 2</em>'s "IP DLC" be as big as its&nbsp;<em>Warhammer 40k&nbsp;</em>collaboration?</figcaption></figure><p>The paid DLC packs will be arriving in conjunction with a host of free content, including three jobs forming part of the game's "Caldera Chronicles" series, as well as plenty of new features, bug fixes, and quality-of-life improvements.</p>

<p>FuturLab says that for the rest of the year, it's focusing on these fixes and QOL improvements, and that its top priority at the moment is to "get key bindings back into the game", so hopefully, your&nbsp;<em>PowerWash Simulator 2&nbsp;</em>experience should improve soon.</p>

<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>PowerWash Simulator 2</em>, it's the sequel to the original&nbsp;<em>PowerWash Simulator</em>, offering much the same gameplay experience as its predecessor (albeit with some extra bells and whistles to make things more exciting).</p>

<p>You'll once again be let loose on a variety of filthy environments and asked to clean them with your power washer, but you've also got access to new tools like an abseiling rig, a powerful new surface cleaner, and a cherry picker.</p>




<p><em>PowerWash Simulator 2&nbsp;</em>is available right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2968420/PowerWash_Simulator_2/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10011314" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/powerwash-simulator-2/9p45ggdtfnsm" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/powerwash-simulator-2-switch-2/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Nintendo Switch 2</a>. While you wait for the roadmap's content to be delivered, why not take a trip down memory lane and read our very own Blair's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/powerwash-simulator-review" rel="nofollow">review of the first game</a>?</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/powerwash-simulator-2-roadmap]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scarface: The World Is Yours Steam Release Canceled Over "Unexpected Complications"]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/scarface-world-is-yours-steam-port-taken-down</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/scarface-the-world-is-yours-steam-release-canceled-over-unexpected-complications.1331854/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A recent Steam port of 2006 action-adventure game&nbsp;<em>Scarface: The World Is Yours&nbsp;</em>has been taken down by publisher EC Digital owing to what the studio describes as "unexpected complications and concerns".</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/app/4113570/discussions/0/594037660640685944/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">news post</a>, EC Digital says that "certain builds" of the game were released on "other platforms", and that this release was "unintended", so the studio feels it's "necessary to pause and reevaluate" with regards to&nbsp;<em>Scarface: The World Is Yours</em>' re-release.</p>

<p>Apparently, the Steam page for the game was "initially intended as a placeholder" while EC Digital worked through what it calls "ongoing licensing and technical matters". The company also points to something it mysteriously calls "urgent discussions with multiple parties concerning the project's status".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/scarface-the-world-is-yours-steam-boat.jpg?itok=DsZhJVwa 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/scarface-the-world-is-yours-steam-boat.jpg?itok=c7TamcIB 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The recent Steam re-release of&nbsp;<em>Scarface: The World Is Yours&nbsp;</em>was an error, apparently.</figcaption></figure><p>Rather confusingly, the game remains available via the <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/scarface-the-world-is-yours-7c3e6f" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a>, which is presumably one of the "other platforms" on which its release caused this trouble in the first place. It's not clear why the game has been removed from Steam, but not from Epic.</p>

<p>As spotted by <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/action/19-years-later-scarface-game-mysteriously-resurfaces-on-steam-and-epic-but-not-for-long-weve-recently-entered-urgent-discussions-with-multiple-parties-concerning-the-projects-status/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">GamesRadar</a>, however, the re-release of&nbsp;<em>Scarface: The World Is Yours&nbsp;</em>contains two mods created by community members, both of which are intended to enhance the original Windows version and make it playable on modern systems.</p>

<p>One of the modders, Silent, who created the eponymous SilentPatch, <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:x6zaxkp46jrfqieaczwuc4il/post/3m3rcwjmhps2b" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">says</a> they weren't contacted about&nbsp;<em>Scarface: The World Is Yours</em>' re-release on PC.</p>

<p>The author of FusionFix, the other mod included in this re-release, <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/cookieplmonster.bsky.social/post/3m3rv3y5bqs2r" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">was contacted</a>, but&nbsp;Silent says it's unlikely the original&nbsp;<em>Scarface&nbsp;</em>IP holders are aware of this new version. In short, this seems like a pretty big mess, and I'd be amazed if the game re-appears on PC storefronts following this debacle.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/scarface-the-world-is-yours-steam-car.jpg?itok=LlSVbCTa 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/scarface-the-world-is-yours-steam-car.jpg?itok=QttEYXfq 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The new PC port of&nbsp;<em>Scarface: The World Is Yours&nbsp;</em>is suspicious, to say the least.</figcaption></figure><p>EC Digital doesn't appear to have any other games published under its name on Steam, so I think it's fair to say this re-release is suspect, to say the least. It sounds as though the publisher may not have acquired the appropriate licenses or talked to the right people before going ahead with this.</p>

<p>In any case, if you do want to check out this PC port of&nbsp;<em>Scarface: The World Is Yours</em>...well, it's technically available via the Epic Games Store, but I'd save my money and wait for more concrete confirmation of the port's legitimacy if I were you.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/scarface-world-is-yours-steam-port-taken-down]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>