<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 17:22:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PowerWash Simulator Wallace & Gromit DLC Takes You to West Wallaby Street]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/powerwash-simulator-wallace-gromit-dlc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/powerwash-simulator-wallace-gromit-dlc-takes-you-to-west-wallaby-street.1078089/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/powerwash-simulator-wallace-gromit-dlc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Square Enix and FuturLab have revealed a brand new&nbsp;<em>PowerWash Simulator&nbsp;</em>crossover DLC, and this time around, it's beloved Aardman animation&nbsp;<em>Wallace &amp; Gromit</em>'s time to shine.</p>

<p>As revealed in a brand new trailer, the<em>&nbsp;PowerWash Simulator Wallace &amp; Gromit&nbsp;</em>DLC will take you to the iconic 62 West Wallaby Street to clean some of the absent-minded inventor's most prized possessions, as well as the likes of Gromit's kennel and more.</p>

<p>The DLC's new Steam page promises to take you "from charming British suburbs to cheesy celestial bodies", so it sounds like you'll be able to visit the moon from the duo's inaugural adventure&nbsp;<em>A Grand Day Out</em>. Cracking!</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/wallace-gromit-dlc-powerwash-simulator-house.jpg?itok=Q-sh4sMw 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/wallace-gromit-dlc-powerwash-simulator-house.jpg?itok=7A4JOkqs 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>PowerWash Simulator&nbsp;</em>is getting&nbsp;<em>Wallace &amp; Gromit</em>-themed DLC soon.</figcaption></figure><p>We don't yet know how many locations will be featured in the DLC, but as with other&nbsp;<em>PowerWash Simulator&nbsp;</em>DLC packs, there will presumably be a number of different levels on offer.</p>

<p>It might stand a chance of being the strangest, but this <i>PowerWash Simulator Wallace &amp; Gromit&nbsp;</i>DLC is far from the game's first crossover.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It joins the likes of&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/powerwash-simulator-shrek-dlc-release-date" rel="nofollow"><em>Shrek</em></a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/powerwash-simulator-back-to-future-dlc" rel="nofollow"><em>Back to the Future</em></a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/powerwash-simulator-final-fantasy-vii-crossover-dlc-arrives-in-march" rel="nofollow"><em>Final Fantasy VII</em></a>, and, of course,&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/powerwash-simulator-warhammer-40k-dlc" rel="nofollow"><em>Warhammer 40k</em></a>, all of which have offered up their various vestiges and objects for&nbsp;<em>PowerWash Simulator</em>&nbsp;to hose down.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, we don't yet have a release date for the&nbsp;<em>Wallace &amp; Gromit&nbsp;</em>pack, but you can <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3077590/PowerWash_Simulator__Wallace__Gromit_Special_Pack/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">wishlist it on Steam here</a> if you want to keep up with it.</p>




<p>If you're unfamiliar with&nbsp;<em>PowerWash Simulator</em>, well, I'm sure you can guess what it is, but in case you need a refresher, it's a work sim-style game in which you must hose down various unclean locations and objects.</p>

<p>Playing either by yourself or alongside your friends, you can clean dirt from interiors and exteriors alike, taking satisfaction in a job well done. It's very much a relaxing, combat-free experience, unless you count the battle of water versus dirt as combat.</p>

<p><em>PowerWash Simulator&nbsp;</em>is available right now for <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1290000/PowerWash_Simulator/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/powerwash-simulator/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-GB/games/store/powerwash-simulator/9NHDJC0NW20M" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/powerwash-simulator-switch/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Nintendo Switch</a>. You can check out our very own Blair's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/powerwash-simulator-review" rel="nofollow">review of the game right here</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[V Rising Sales Top 5 Million as Stunlock Promises Major New Update]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/v-rising-sales-top-5-million</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/v-rising-sales-top-5-million-as-stunlock-promises-major-new-update.1078053/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/v-rising-sales-top-5-million<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>V Rising&nbsp;</em>has reached another major new sales milestone, according to developer Stunlock, and there's a big new update in the works for the game as well.</p>

<p>Per a press release,&nbsp;<em>V Rising&nbsp;</em>has officially crossed the 5 million sales milestone, which the developer says "cements the game's status as one of the most popular survival games of recent years". It's hard to disagree with that, especially in conjunction with that <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1604030/V_Rising/#app_reviews_hash" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Very Positive Steam rating</a>.</p>

<p>These sales numbers mean that&nbsp;<em>V Rising&nbsp;</em>has picked up another 2 million sales or so for itself since <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/v-rising-sales-cross-3-million-threshold" rel="nofollow">hitting the 3 million mark back in January 2023</a>. Given that the game's 1.0 release <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/v-rising-10-patch-notes" rel="nofollow">landed in May last year</a>&nbsp;and that it hit PS5 <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/v-rising-ps5-release-date" rel="nofollow">the following month</a>, that's perhaps to be expected.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/v-rising-sales-5m-castle.jpg?itok=jsVheeQi 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/v-rising-sales-5m-castle.jpg?itok=lqebCDjG 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>V Rising&nbsp;</em>has crossed another big sales threshold (presumably after being asked to do so).</figcaption></figure><p>If you've yet to check out&nbsp;<em>V Rising</em>, then perhaps the "big update" that's on its way to the game this year will convince you it's worth your time.</p>

<p>Stunlock says the update will bring a brand new biome that's "teeming with uncharted territories, a deadly new faction, and ancient technologies ready to be claimed".</p>

<p>In addition, you can look orward to revamped progression, a new Fusion Forge to help you craft "ultimate builds", and "risk-free PvP options" like the ability to duel other players, "customizable castle arenas", and more. All of this is on the way for free, too.</p>




<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>V Rising</em>, it's a sandbox survival game in which you play as a vampire lord attempting to build your very own vampiric empire in a hostile world.</p>

<p>You can construct your own castle, venture out into the world to find resources and battle enemies, and even team up with (or do battle with) other players.</p>

<p><em>V Rising&nbsp;</em>is available right now for <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1604030/V_Rising/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a> and <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/v-rising/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>. There's no word yet on whether it's coming to other platforms.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Developer Direct to Show Off Doom: The Dark Ages and More on January 23rd]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/xbox-developer-direct-january-2025-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-developer-direct-to-show-off-doom-the-dark-ages-and-more-on-january-23rd.1078020/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/xbox-developer-direct-january-2025-announced<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A new Xbox Developer Direct presentation has been announced for later this month, and it will feature updates on upcoming Xbox games, including&nbsp;<em>Doom: The Dark Ages&nbsp;</em>and more.</p>

<p>As revealed in a <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/01/09/xbox-developer-direct-2025/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">post</a> on the official Xbox Wire news site, the presentation will air on January 23rd. Just like <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/redfall-release-date-revealed-during-xbox-developer-direct" rel="nofollow">previous</a> Developer Direct <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/xbox-developer-direct-2024-recap-check-out-all-news-trailers-and-reveals" rel="nofollow">showcases</a>, it'll offer "an in-depth look at upcoming titles, how they're being created, and who's creating them".</p>

<p>The show will begin with a new look at Compulsion Games' action-adventure title&nbsp;<em>South of Midnight</em>, and it'll continue with a trip to France to check in with&nbsp;<em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33&nbsp;</em>developer Sandfall Interactive.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/xbox-developer-direct-january-2025-south-of-midnight.jpg?itok=N3pntcyK 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/xbox-developer-direct-january-2025-south-of-midnight.jpg?itok=c097vuwL 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>South of Midnight&nbsp;</em>is just one of the games that will be featured at this month's Xbox Developer Direct.</figcaption></figure><p>Following those two games, the presentation will switch focus to&nbsp;<em>Doom: The Dark Ages</em>, which is being developed by id Software over in Texas.</p>

<p>Perhaps most tantalizingly, though, Xbox says the showcase will end with a visit to a "surprise location" in order to see "another studio's brand new game". I wonder who that could be?</p>

<p>As ever with Developer Direct showcases, you probably shouldn't expect any extra reveals beyond what's been promised by Microsoft; outside of the "brand new game" that's being teased, it's likely the show will focus on the aforementioned three games.</p>

<p>As for what will be revealed regarding the three games outlined above, I'd be surprised if we didn't get a release date for&nbsp;<em>Doom: The Dark Ages&nbsp;</em>at the very least, since the game is currently penciled in for a 2025 launch.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/doom-the-dark-ages-xbox-developer-direct.jpg?itok=lg1cyQ6O 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/doom-the-dark-ages-xbox-developer-direct.jpg?itok=9rBDTFXN 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Will we get a&nbsp;<em>Doom: The Dark Ages&nbsp;</em>release date during this month's Xbox Developer Direct?</figcaption></figure><p>Xbox is promising a "full game reveal" for&nbsp;<em>The Dark Ages</em>, as well as a "deep dive" into&nbsp;<em>South of Midnight&nbsp;</em>and a behind-the-scenes look at&nbsp;<em>Clair Obscur</em>. Developer Direct shows are traditionally more focused on dev processes than sizzle reels, so expect some interesting insider tidbits.</p>

<p>At any rate, the next Xbox Developer Direct will air on January 23rd at 1pm Eastern (that's 10am Pacific). Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>