<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 03:22:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Critical Role Announces Campaign 4 Setting Through Community Solved ARG]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/critical-role-announces-campaign-4-setting-through-community-solved-arg</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/critical-role-announces-campaign-4-setting-through-community-solved-arg.1273362/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Earlier this month, <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/critical-role-announces-brennan-lee-mulligan-as-campaign-4-dm-release-date-in-october" rel="nofollow">Critical Role not only announced the release date of their hotly anticipated Campaign 4</a>, October 4th, but also that Matthew Mercer would be joining the table this time around as a player and not as the GM. The role of GM would go to <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="55a80c6c-ea7c-4151-9523-d332db6f6cd5" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/interviews/how-brennan-lee-mulligan-created-never-stop-blowing-up-love-letter-to-80s" rel="nofollow">Brennan Lee Mulligan</a>, and Campaign 4 would be set in a completely new setting.</p>



<p>Last Thursday at the bottom of the regular Beacon and Critical Role newsletter an interesting image was included of a five by five square of letters, clicking on which would lead you to join the Beacon Discord and access the #what-do-you-seek channel.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/critical-role-campaign-4-setting-5x5-letters.jpg?itok=Y4MBwSAS 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/critical-role-campaign-4-setting-5x5-letters.jpg?itok=aDrTvph2 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>This led puzzle hunters down the rabbit hole to share word of this ARG, hunt for any other clues, and ultimately the answer. This puzzle was solved earlier today and led to the discovery of a secret page on the Critical Role website that contained a password field, and the password itself.</p>

<p>Travelling to <a href="https://critrole.com/unseal" rel="nofollow">https://critrole.com/unseal</a> and entering the password ARAMAN (in all capital letters) eager fans can get access to a 20 second recording of Brennan Lee Mulligan setting the scene for Campaign 4. The audio is as follows:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>"Within the world of Araman, there exists a growing darkness in the shadow of revolution. Seventy years ago were the Shapers cut down, those seven lords of creation that saw fit to cast their children into ruin and shadown forever..."</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Accompanying this audio file is the date: <strong>August 21st, 2025 10am PT</strong></p>

<p>There are plenty of questions left to answer about Campaign 4 including who will be joining Matt and Brennan at the table, and what game system will be used. One or both of those might be answers on August 21st.</p>

<h2>The Critical Role ARG Solution</h2>

<p>If you're interested in learning what it took to solve the clues and reach this conclusion then be sure to <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1wXLH3dyDq0ApX8YQ8YSNMEDW8kZApomzRxeabTlKYqQ/edit?tab=t.0#heading=h.9j1gfaluj4mp" rel="nofollow">head over to the large Google Doc </a>that was used to collect all possible answers and crack the conundrum in under a week.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Andrew has written Video Game and Entertainment news, reviews, and guides for 10+ years. As Senior Content Manager, he assists in creating and editing… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/andrew-stretch">More about Andrew</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/critical-role-announces-campaign-4-setting-through-community-solved-arg]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer: The Horus Heresy Combat Forces Boxes Provides Reinforcements]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/warhammer-horus-heresy-combat-forces-boxes-provides-reinforcements</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-the-horus-heresy-combat-forces-boxes-provides-reinforcements.1273203/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Games Workshop has announced new miniature boxes for <em>Warhammer: The Horus Heresy</em>. The new <em>Warhammer: The Horus Heresy</em> Combat Forces sets are coming shortly after the <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/newest-edition-of-warhammer-horus-heresy-introduces-advanced-characteristics" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">latest edition's</a> release, providing new and veteran players a means of growing their army.</p>



<p>In an official <a href="https://www.warhammer-community.com/en-gb/articles/2yehwjta/begin-your-conquest-of-the-age-of-darkness-with-new-combat-forces/" rel="nofollow">Warhammer-Community post</a>, Games Workshop highlighted three <em>Warhammer: The Horus Heresy</em> Combat Forces boxes, providing different kinds of units to start or flesh out your army in this <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/games/warhammer-40000" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Warhammer 40,000</em></a> prequel. These units can be used in either Loyalist or Traitor armies.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/warhammer-the-horus-heresy-combat-forces-heavy-space-marine-miniatures.jpg?itok=6wyoe9pZ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/warhammer-the-horus-heresy-combat-forces-heavy-space-marine-miniatures.jpg?itok=Un3CgCDt 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The first of these boxes is the Astartes Legiones Combat Force box. This box contains 20 Legionaries in MkVI power armor. These units can be outfitted as either Tactical Legionaries with bolters or Heavy Support with missile launchers. In addition, the box contains two Tactical Marine sprues, providing parts for two Sergeants, vexillas, and vox units.</p>

<p>Finally, the Astartes Legiones Combat Force box contains a transport and a dreadnought. The Deimos pattern Rhino transport has twin-linked bolters and your choice of nine mounted weapons, a dozer blade, a hunter-killer missile, and towing hooks. As for the Leviathan Dreadnought, it comes with a choice of three arm-mounted weapons: A cyclonic melta gun, a grav-flux bombard, and a storm cannon, respectively.</p>

<p>The second Warhammer: The Horus Heresy Combat Forces box is called Mechanicum. As the name suggests, this box contains robotic and cyborg units, courtesy of the Tech Priests. The box contains six Thallax cyborg warriors alongside cosmetic options and different weapon kits, including photon thrusters, chain bayonets, and multi-meltas.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/warhammer-the-horus-heresy-combat-forces-castellax-miniatures.jpg?itok=Xb4VbPE7 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/warhammer-the-horus-heresy-combat-forces-castellax-miniatures.jpg?itok=gPO6EOoI 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Complementing the Thallax are two Castellax Battle-Automata units. This jumbo-sized mecha sport shock chargers and your choice of in-built bolters and flamers, and your choice of shoulder-mounted weapons like mauler bolt cannons, darkfire cannons, or multi-meltas.</p>

<p>Lastly, the Mechanicum box includes the Thanatar Cavas Siege-Automata. They are armed with a Heliax-pattern plasma mortar, shock chargers, and a wrist-mounted twin mauler bolt cannon.</p>

<p>The last Warhammer: The Horus Heresy Combat Forces box is the Solar Auxilia box. This box is packed with human infantry and support vehicles. The box contains 20 Solar Auxiliaries, complete with both weapon kit and cosmetic custom pieces. As for their COs, the box includes one Auxilia Captain and four Auxilia Companions.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/warhammer-the-horus-heresy-combat-forces-leman-russ-tank.jpg?itok=kZKkPISz 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/warhammer-the-horus-heresy-combat-forces-leman-russ-tank.jpg?itok=NkjkykSn 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>As for the support vehicles, the Solar Auxilia box contains two Hermes Sentinels and one Leman Russ battle tank. The Hermes Sentinels can be built as either Light Sentinels, or as Veletaris Sentinels. As for the Leman Russ, it can be built as either a Strike Tank or a Command Tank.</p>

<p>All three <em>Warhammer: The Horus Heresy</em> Combat Forces boxes will be available for pre-order soon.&nbsp;</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/warhammer-horus-heresy-combat-forces-boxes-provides-reinforcements]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>