<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:56:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Mandalorian Adventures - Clan of Two Expansion Preview]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/previews/mandalorian-adventures-clan-of-two-expansion-preview</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-mandalorian-adventures-clan-of-two-expansion-preview.1203249/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/previews/mandalorian-adventures-clan-of-two-expansion-preview<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>When we first reviewed&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/star-wars-mandalorian-adventures-review-is-this-way" rel="nofollow"><em>The Mandalorian Adventures</em></a> here on TechRaptor, we were truly impressed by the depth of the game and replay value contained within the core box. But every adventure, no matter how great, deserves a second season (or more)! Which is why we're thrilled to preview <em>The Mandalorian Adventures - Clan of Two</em>, which the fine folks at <a href="https://unexpectedgames.com/clanoftwo" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Unexpected Games</a> (via distributor <a href="https://store.asmodee.com/products/the-mandalorian-adventures-clan-of-two-expansion" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Asmodee USA</a>) sent along a copy of for us to check out!</p>



<p><em>The Mandalorian Adventures - Clan of Two</em>&nbsp;is an expansion to&nbsp;<em>The Mandalorian Adventures</em>, inspired by events taking place in the second season of&nbsp;<em>The Mandalorian</em>. With new heroes to play as and new missions to tackle, this great expands the base game - but, be warned,&nbsp;<strong>you need the base game to be able to play&nbsp;<em>The Mandalorian Adventures - Clan of Two</em>.</strong></p>

<p><strong>Box Contents Include:</strong></p>

<ul><li>1 Rulebook</li>
	<li>1 Mission Book</li>
	<li>95 Cards (Including 4 New Heroes)</li>
	<li>18 Mini Cards</li>
	<li>137 Tokens</li>
	<li>4 Standees</li>
	<li>2 Mercenary Mission Sheets (Double-Sided)</li>
</ul><h2>What New Heroes Are Included In&nbsp;<em>The Mandalorian Adventures - Clan of Two?</em></h2>

<p>There are four new heroes included in&nbsp;<em>The Mandalorian Adventures - Clan of Two&nbsp;</em>that you can play as with both these expansion missions and the missions included in the core game. These include: the exiled Jedi Ahsoka Tano, famed bounty hunter Boba Fett, Mandalorian heiress Bo-Katan Kryze, and master assassin and sharpshooter&nbsp;Fennec Shand.</p>

<p>Each of these characters also have new persistent character abilities, changing how they play and making them feel wholly unique compared to the characters contained in the core box. Let's take a look hero by hero and chat briefly about their abilities!</p>

<h3>Ahsoka Tano</h3>
<p>Ahsoka Tano's hero card may seem like it comes with a major drawback - she can only attack enemies within the same space as her? But along with it perfectly fitting her flavor (she is, after all, a lightsaber wielder), but with her "Shoto Lightsaber" card shown above (of which she has two in her deck), she could potentially dish out 6 damage!</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/the-mandalorian-adventures-clan-of-two-ahsoka-cards.jpg?itok=Q2W_Sk7R 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/the-mandalorian-adventures-clan-of-two-ahsoka-cards.jpg?itok=zK4iBW8Q 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Ahsoka's cards keep her very free-wheeling and float-y around the battlefield, just like a Jedi!</figcaption></figure><h3>Boba Fett</h3>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/the-mandalorian-adventures-clan-of-two-boba-fett.jpg?itok=HVgHcCQo 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/the-mandalorian-adventures-clan-of-two-boba-fett.jpg?itok=wqQ4FR6L 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Everyone's favorite bounty hunter Boba Fett blasts onto the scene with the persistent character ability you see above, allowing him to attack twice in a turn (as long as there aren't too many other cards in the action slot). Another great ability that gives you a huge benefit while also making you think carefully about how you play!</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/the-mandalorian-adventures-clan-of-two-boba-cards.jpg?itok=Ew8KNleG 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/the-mandalorian-adventures-clan-of-two-boba-cards.jpg?itok=qsEjwT9z 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Boba Fett is, as expected, extremely combat focused, with cards that help you mitigate his character ability's downside of strength restriction in action spaces.</figcaption></figure><h3>Bo-Katan</h3>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/the-mandalorian-adventures-clan-of-two-bo-katan.jpg?itok=C6SBbUou 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/the-mandalorian-adventures-clan-of-two-bo-katan.jpg?itok=zasn13Pp 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Bo-Katan is the most unique of any hero we've seen come to the game, as her persistent character ability says that she has to keep the top card of her skill deck faceup! This is a very fun mechanic, leading to a lot of shenanigans with trying to manipulate your skill deck to get the most out of her every turn, while giving you a bit of extra info you wouldn't normally know.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/the-mandalorian-adventures-clan-of-two-bo-katan-cards.jpg?itok=ma0w-DqC 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/the-mandalorian-adventures-clan-of-two-bo-katan-cards.jpg?itok=iycHl-mv 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Bo-Katan's cards truly focus on her ability to use and manipulate her skill deck, and is one of the trickier (but more satisfying) characters to play.</figcaption></figure><h3>Fennec Shand</h3>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/the-mandalorian-adventures-clan-of-two-fennec-shand.jpg?itok=zDQlndW2 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/the-mandalorian-adventures-clan-of-two-fennec-shand.jpg?itok=8fGyMqfS 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Fennec Shand is an unparalleled sniper in the&nbsp;<em>Star Wars</em>&nbsp;universe, and her ability to increase the range of her attack by one (at the cost of one strength) will make her close some pretty incredible distances in the game. Remember, three spaces can often feel like half the board when you're winding around the map!</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/the-mandalorian-adventures-clan-of-two-fennec-cards.jpg?itok=d3eYZN8o 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/the-mandalorian-adventures-clan-of-two-fennec-cards.jpg?itok=FoJzAakf 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Fennec is especially good at keeping enemy forces reined in and pinging out damage around the board.</figcaption></figure><h2>What Are The New Missions Like In&nbsp;<em>The Mandalorian Adventures - Clan of Two?</em></h2>

<p>The new missions in&nbsp;<em>The Mandalorian Adventures - Clan of Two</em>&nbsp;break the mold from the original game in fun and challenging ways, while providing a diverse set of challenges and maps that require different plans of attack! I don't want to spoil too much (that's part of the fun of playing&nbsp;<em>The Mandalorian Adventures</em>), so I'll stick with showing off and describing a bit about the first of the four missions in this expansion, which recreates the thrilling fight against the warlord Morgan Elsbeth on Calodan.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/the-mandalorian-adventures-clan-of-two-map-mission.jpg?itok=70oggOCw 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/the-mandalorian-adventures-clan-of-two-map-mission.jpg?itok=IWmXa5bM 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>This first mission really feels like a race against time, as each time you trigger the 6+ space you'll be advancing the power track - this increases the hit points on Morgan Elsbeth, who you'll need to flush out&nbsp;<em>after</em>&nbsp;saving three different prisoners. It's a tough one, right out the gate, and introduces enemies with new abilities.</p>

<p>Along with the four core missions, there are also two new mercenary missions included in this expansion - and it all goes together to form what seems to me to be an extremely strong expansion. It's more of what we loved about&nbsp;<em>The Mandalorian Adventures</em>, but the abilities on these four new heroes feel&nbsp;<em>extremely</em>&nbsp;different!</p>

<p>With an MSRP at $39.99, this feels like a perfect addition if you've played through and explored all that the original&nbsp;<em>Mandalorian Adventures</em>&nbsp;had to offer. Hitting shelves everywhere Friday, June 6th!</p>

<hr><p><em>The copy of&nbsp;</em>The Mandalorian Adventures - Clan of Two&nbsp;<em>used in the creation of this preview was provided to TechRaptor by Asmodee USA.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Giaco Furino joined the TechRaptor team as a Staff Writer in 2019 after searching for a dedicated place to write and talk about Tabletop Games. In 2020, he… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/giaco-furino">More about Giaco</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Disney Lorcana Fabled Preview Features Elsa Gift Box]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/disney-lorcana-fabled-preview-features-elsa-gift-box</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/disney-lorcana-fabled-preview-features-elsa-gift-box.1203192/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/disney-lorcana-fabled-preview-features-elsa-gift-box<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Ravensburger has released new information on the upcoming <em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/disney-lorcana" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Disney Lorcana</a> Fabled</em> set. The latest set of the trading card game based on iconic Disney characters will be getting a new format, new products, and a gift box featuring the ice queen, Elsa.</p>



<p>As part of their Weekly Lorecast on their official Twitch channel, Ravensburger showcased their <em>Disney Lorcana Fabled</em> preview. The preview centered on official products and accessories alongside the full <em>Fabled</em>&nbsp;lineup of booster packs, Illumineer's Troves, and starter decks.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/disney-lorcana-fabled-starter-deck-artwork.jpg?itok=jHy3WL1o 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/disney-lorcana-fabled-starter-deck-artwork.jpg?itok=VFwLfCB1 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>For those who want to get into <em>Disney Lorcana</em>, the two starter decks are a decent entry point.The first is an Emerald and Ruby deck sporting Max, Goofy, and Powerline from <em>A Goofy Movie</em>. The other deck, showcasing Ariel and Mulan, is an Amber and Sapphire deck. Both will be sold at an MSRP of $16.99 each.</p>

<p>The new products and accessories will portray other characters featured in the set. Those accessories are a pair of <em>Goofy Movie</em> and <em>Mulan</em>-themed card sleeve packs and deck cases. The card sleeves will be sold at an MSRP of $9.99, and the deck boxes will be sold at an MSRP of $5.99.</p>

<p>In addition, two playmats will be available. One spotlights Cinderella as she gets her gorgeous dress from her fairy godmother. The other showcases Mufasa, King of Pride Rock. Both playmats will be available at an MSRP of $19.99</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/disney-lorcana-fabled-cinderella-game-mat.jpg?itok=WQZIimeq 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/disney-lorcana-fabled-cinderella-game-mat.jpg?itok=BeieJ6rh 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>For <em>Frozen</em> fans, the <em>Disney Lorcana Fabled</em> preview contains a new gift box. The box will contain five booster packs, an Elsa-themed storage box, three punch-out dividers, and a glimmer foil promo card of <em>Elsa - The Fifth Spirit</em>. This Elsa Gift Box will be available this October at an MSRP of $29.99.</p>

<p>Lastly, the <em>Disney Lorcana Fabled</em> preview has confirmed the launch of two new formats. The first, Super Sealed, is a variation on a sealed draft. You get four boosters from each of the most recent sets. From there, you must make a three-ink color deck of 50 cards in under 60 minutes.</p>

<p>You are allowed to change cards between matches, but must revert back to the initial deck after each round and before the start of a new match.</p>

<p>The second format is called Triple Deck Constructed Format (Single Elimination). As the name implies, players create three decks, each covering all six ink colors. Players then play best-of-three against one another. You can even use an ink token to "bench" one of your opponents decks. The Grand Finals are determined in a best-of-five.</p>

<p><em>Disney Lorcana Fabled</em> will have a pre-release on August 29. The set's full release will be September 5.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>