<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 20:02:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Joe Allen's Top 5 Games of 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/opinions/joe-allen-top-games-2025</link>
            <guid>1401934</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I'm probably condemning myself to the Oubliette of Hot Takes with this statement (it's a real place and it's a nightmare), but for me, 2025 was a pretty weak year in terms of video games.</p><p>"How can you say that?" you explode. "This is the year of <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/clair-obscur-expedition-33-sales-5m-update" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="a11aa258-e2c1-48df-ac44-95f3a37e9c4a" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">our lord and savior</a> <em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em>! Surely it is the single greatest year in the history of interactive media, and thus are you branded a heretic for your divergence from scripture."</p><p>Reader, <em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 </em>left me not just cold, but frozen thanks to its ending, and while I'm sure I just didn't understand it because it was actually very clever and well-constructed, I have no interest in revisiting the game to confirm or deny that.</p><p>Thankfully, I managed to find five other games to keep me warm during that cold snap, so here, in tantalizingly reverse order, are my top 5 games of 2025!</p><h2>Honorable Mentions</h2><p>If I may, I'd like to start with a couple of games that just about didn't make the grade. I won't take much of your time with these, but I wanted to nod in their general direction without officially numbering them.</p><ul><li><em>Look Outside</em>. Very strong horror theming and non-linear exploration, but the combat's just a little too basic for my tastes.</li><li><em>Hades II</em>. The gameplay is complex and exciting, and there's loads to do, so it's a shame the story is terrible.</li><li><em>The Alters</em>. I found <em>The Alters</em>' core gameplay stressful and just a little dull, which is a shame because the story is superb. It's the inverse <em>Hades II </em>problem.</li></ul><p>Right, that's that out of the way. Here are the real heavy hitters!</p><h2>5. <em>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance</em></h2><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption><em>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance </em>impressed me this year.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Of the two ninja-themed side-scrolling retro platformers released this year, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-review-cutting-edge" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="8c06175e-1feb-4be2-ab4d-54d3796d631c" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance</em></a><em> </em>pips the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/ninja-gaiden-ragebound-review-razor-sharp-retro-platformer" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="1f5be4cb-8821-406e-ac38-384d019a3a18" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">also-excellent <em>Ninja Gaiden: Ragebound</em></a><em> </em>to the post for me.</p><p>Okay, so it's a Metroidvania where <em>Ragebound </em>is a much tighter and more focused linear affair, but it doesn't refuse to end properly after a single playthrough (spoilers, sorry), so it takes the title for me.</p><p><em>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance </em>has everything you could want from a platformer; it's got tight controls, finely tuned combat, a variety of interesting boss encounters, and well-crafted levels that never feel confusing or annoying to navigate.</p><p>The plot's a touch weak, but it does the job alright, and there are plenty of secrets to find by delving into <em>Art of Vengeance</em>'s levels after obtaining later upgrades, so it's got tons of longevity as well.</p><p>You won't find a reinvention of the wheel (or perhaps that should be the shuriken) here, but <em>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance </em>shows Sega is on the right track by reviving its old franchises. Well, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/shenmue-4-footage-fake-ys-net" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="e7156030-a639-47c2-8009-93c5c9789d71" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">except <em>Shenmue</em></a>.</p><h2>4. <em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em></h2><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption>Yeah, yeah, alright. It's good.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>It would be churlish not to acknowledge one of the biggest and most generous Metroidvania platformers ever created on this list, even if I do have some issues with wonky storytelling and some questionable difficulty choices.</p><p><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/hollow-knight-silksong" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="e6454f0b-6800-4e17-96eb-7c686c1e2c90" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em></a><em> </em>is, to put it simply, the platformer that keeps on giving. Like its predecessor, it keeps going when you think it surely must have run out of ideas, and then it tacks on entire extra areas and bosses after that as well.</p><p><em>Silksong </em>also represents a level up for Team Cherry's already drum skin-tight combat design; Hornet is an acrobatic protagonist, and she's an absolute thrill to control as she bounces and weaves her way through Pharloom's many and varied denizens.</p><p>Much like <em>Hades II</em>, however, things come apart for me in the story stakes. <em>Silksong</em>'s narrative is unfocused and sprawling, and it never quite coalesces around an identifiable goal, nor does it succeed in making Hornet feel like a genuine character for me.</p><p>I'm also not sure <em>Silksong </em>needed to be quite so frustrating. Some of its boss runs are <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/opinions/death-to-death-runs" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="bc88c70a-a511-49c5-9fc0-4b3f70907424" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">a little patience-testing</a>, and while its encounters feel perfectly tuned to me, one or two of its nastier surprises feel unfair rather than punishing.</p><p>With all that said, <em>Silksong </em>is a superb sequel to <em>Hollow Knight</em>, and I look forward to knitting my broken fingers back together to play its upcoming free expansion.</p><h2>3. <em>The Roottrees Are Dead</em></h2><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption>Do you like genealogy puzzlers? <em>The Roottrees Are Dead </em>is for you.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Representing an extremely strong start to the year, <em>The Roottrees Are Dead </em>is exactly what I think deductive puzzle games should be, which is to say it's inspired by <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/return-of-obra-dinn" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="cf4c55bd-209b-4472-8975-e018955d838d" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Return of the Obra Dinn</em></a>.</p><p>Tasking you with sorting through a tangled web of genealogy in order to uncover the secrets of a family of candy magnates, <em>The Roottrees Are Dead </em>isn't particularly flashy or sexy, but it is rich with puzzle goodness.</p><p>Discovering the identity of a particularly elusive family member by digging through periodicals and books might not sound like your idea of fun, but it's certainly mine, so I for one am grateful to Evil Trout.</p><p>In an era of AAA games treating players like complete morons (looking at you, <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/metroid-prime-4" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="c195faed-5d46-484c-bbea-f034fca5544b" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</em></a>), <em>The Roottrees Are Dead </em>represents a refreshing and exciting trend towards do-it-yourself puzzle-solving, and I'm very much here for it.</p><p>The art is a little uncanny at times, and it's true that there's no pulse-pounding action or multi-stage boss fight to captivate adrenaline junkies, but <em>The Roottrees Are Dead </em>thrilled me thoroughly, so onto the list it goes.</p><h2>2. <em>Donkey Kong Bananza</em></h2><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption><em>Donkey Kong Bananza </em>shows Nintendo's innovative spirit isn't dead.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Yes, yes, alright. I'm a Nintendo shill, I admit it. Still, there were very few games that matched <em>Donkey Kong Bananza</em>'s sheer joie de vivre and inventive spirit for me this year.</p><p>Okay, so DK's latest adventure can sometimes feel like <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/donkey-kong-bananza-super-mario-odyssey-team" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="95f40f3e-5162-45ed-8871-019d18466db6" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">a reskin (presumably a banana skin) of <em>Super Mario Odyssey</em></a>, and the dynamic between Donkey Kong and his young charge Pauline is odd, to say the least.</p><p>None of that changes the fact that Nintendo is still creating best-in-class platformers, and that <em>Donkey Kong Bananza </em>represents a thrilling demonstration of the legendary Japanese company's design chops.</p><p>Even without DK's ability to tunnel through levels, thus skipping entire platforming challenges and causing potentially devastating sequence breaks, <em>Bananza</em>'s many and varied challenges would be the cherry on top of the chef's kiss, as it were.</p><p>Taken with its innovative <em>Minecraft</em>-style digging systems, though, <em>Bananza</em>'s responsive platforming and wealth of diverse levels made it a joy to play through. I'm not collecting every banana, though. That way madness lies.</p><h2>1. <em>Blue Prince</em></h2><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption><em>Blue Prince </em>has its flaws, but it's just so gosh-darn interesting.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Dogubomb and Raw Fury released roguelite adventure puzzler <em>Blue Prince </em>in April, and not only was it easily the highlight of that month for me, it was also easily the year's best, with a couple of heavy caveats.</p><p>Let's get this one out of the way first: yes, the RNG is a problem. It's baked into <em>Blue Prince</em>'s design, so I can't think of a way to fix it, but having a puzzle most of the way solved only to repeatedly fail to get the room you need can be aggravating.</p><p>Despite that, though, <em>Blue Prince</em>'s mixture of randomized room-laying and puzzle-solving that stretches across multiple runs absolutely captivated me this year.</p><p>Between this and <em>Roottrees</em>, 2025 really was the year of retrieving an actual pen and notepad with which to make notes (I also thoroughly enjoyed <em>Lorelei and the Laser Eyes </em>this year, but I'm restricting myself to 2025 releases for this list).</p><p>As well as the wealth of puzzles to solve, <em>Blue Prince </em>also has a story to discover, and it's told out of order, so you'll need to be paying attention if you want to piece together what happened in this cozy but deceptively complex world.</p><p>I won't deny that <em>Blue Prince </em>frustrated me at times, but it's still my game of the year simply for its uniqueness and experimentation. I'd rather play a single <em>Blue Prince </em>than a thousand <em>Ghost of Yotei</em>s (<em>Ghosts of Yotei</em>?).</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/opinions/joe-allen-top-games-2025]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anson Chan's Top 5 Games of 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/opinions/anson-chan-top-games-2025</link>
            <guid>1401931</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>While 2025 was a relatively tame year when it came to AAA game releases, there were still plenty of standout titles if you knew where to look. <em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em> of course was the breakout hit of the year, definitively proving that you don't really need 20 different studios and billions of dollars to deliver a top-tier experience.&nbsp;</p><p>Naturally, the success of one game isn't indicative of an upheaval in the entire industry. However, between the apparent stagnation of old guard studios, the rapid maturation of Chinese gaming studios as a whole, and the proliferation of new software that enables smaller teams to pump out competitive titles, 2026 may be a very interesting year in terms of both individual games and the industry at large.</p><h2><em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em></h2><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/expedition-33-player-characters.jpg?itok=Nu8y_tmV 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/expedition-33-player-characters.jpg?itok=0vazjdJd 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><p>What else can be said about <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/clair-obscur-expedition-33-review-french-revolution" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow"><em>Expedition 33</em></a> that hasn't already been said by others? If you're a fan, or have even a passing interest in turn-based RPGs and you have the time to try the game, you should.&nbsp;</p><p>While the idea of implementing action-game mechanics into a turn-based RPG isn't new, <em>Expedition 33</em> does it so flawlessly that it sets a new standard for the genre. Throw in some excellent music and writing with some very creative world design and it's no surprise that it's one of the more undisputed Game of the Year contenders in recent memory.</p><p>On a small side note, I personally quite like the default skins of the playable characters. They all have similar uniforms with a very neat color scheme, but with just enough personalization that you can tell who is who with a mere glance. Given the context of the expeditions, it seems like a logical and practical choice, and it's a small deviation from the norm of every party member having completely different clothing and armor.</p><p>There are two small quibbles I have with <em>Expedition 33</em> though in that it seems like no matter what language you play on, the lip syncing seems to be just a little bit off. The second is that the jumping animation is a little stiff. Yet these are such a relatively minor issues in an otherwise excellent game.</p><h2><em>Doom: The Dark Ages</em></h2><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/doom-the-dark-ages-mech_0.jpg?itok=3FK3KbBh 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/doom-the-dark-ages-mech_0.jpg?itok=zgwYi9QC 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><p>Sequels to first-person shooters tend to be rather hit or miss in my experience and thankfully, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/doom-dark-ages-review" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="6c34b81d-7c3a-4488-97a7-1de8454240f4" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Doom: The Dark Ages</em></a> delivers more of the former than the latter. While the changes to <em>Doom's</em> core gameplay formula took a little bit to get used to, the shield and all of its abilities opens up so many more venues for violence that it's hard to see it as anything but an upgrade.</p><p>The shift from a sci-fi setting to a more fantasy-inspired backdrop was a great idea though. There have been a million and one interpretations of what humanity in space might look like, yet there are only so many games that take medieval design and decide to use that as a starting point for a sci-fi society.</p><p>Unfortunately, the new mech and dragon levels kind of just exist. They're a step up from those on-rails segments that were in every FPS decades ago, although in practice they're fundamentally identical. Simply put, if there was any real disappointment to be found in <em>Doom: The Dark Ages</em>, it's that the on-foot combat is somehow more visceral and more dynamic than flying a dragon with guns or piloting a huge mech.&nbsp;</p><h2><em>Ninja Gaiden 4</em></h2><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ninja-gaiden-4-tokyo.jpg?itok=-c_wKVfN 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ninja-gaiden-4-tokyo.jpg?itok=exjPZrGk 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><p>After so many years it's nice to see one of original "git gud" game franchises make a return in the modern era, and what a humbling return it is. The gameplay is ridiculously fast paced and the enemies aren't pulling their punches, even on normal difficulty. Miss a dodge and that random generic goon is taking off a big chunk of your health. Oh and there's usually several goons per encounter. The damage goes both ways though, and if you play correctly you can eviscerate bosses in mere minutes.&nbsp;</p><p>Admittedly, some of the difficulty comes from the camera and how it sometimes struggles to track enemies, but for the most part you really do have to just learn how to play. It's less "memorize these attack patterns and parry" and more "combo this guy out of existence before his friends spawn in," which I personally find to be more visually satisfying.&nbsp;</p><p>The injection of cyberpunk elements into the art direction of <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/ninja-gaiden-4-review-blackened-rain-beckons" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="cd1796d1-2f9f-45e0-9bc3-182e5870632c" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Ninja Gaiden 4</em></a> is quite neat too. There are chapters where you have a mix of contemporary, cyberpunk, and traditional/demonic themes playing off of each other and it's usually very well done.&nbsp;</p><h2><em>Where Winds Meet</em></h2><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/where-winds-meet-outpost.jpg?itok=uzmWUqAO 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/where-winds-meet-outpost.jpg?itok=Ko279QI3 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><p><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/where-winds-meet" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="09a36c6b-7807-494f-9194-2047bdcea2c4" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Where Winds Meet</em></a> is one of those rare games that I would recommend solely for the world design and art direction. While countless games draw from European fantasy for their setting, <em>Where Winds Meet</em> stands out because it quite obviously inspired by Chinese fantasy. The broad strokes of both genres are actually quite similar in concept, although the latter typically involves things like using martial arts to throw bears around or flying through the air with special sword moves and such.&nbsp;</p><p>Thankfully, such physics-defying tropes are used sparingly in the main quest and are seemingly there mostly for exploration purposes. <em>Where Winds Meet</em> plays like any other action game with parry and dodge mechanics otherwise.&nbsp;</p><p>Your arsenal is quite unique though. You have access to your standard array of swords, spears, and bows, but you also have more atypical options like umbrellas and fans. Similarly, your "magic" options are to get drunk and fist fight your enemies, throw geese at people, meditate really hard to get a damage reduction buff, and other similar moves that don't usually appear in games.&nbsp;</p><p>Again, this ties into the aspect that sets <em>Where Winds Meet</em> apart from its competitors. Without the strong adherence to the Chinese fantasy art direction, you're left with a mechanically sound yet somewhat mundane action game.&nbsp;</p><h2><em>Persona 5: The Phantom X</em></h2><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/persona5x-trial.jpg?itok=_jruadxn 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1200">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/persona5x-trial.jpg?itok=vMrYWdhm 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="750">
                  

  </picture><p>While it's certainly not ideal that the latest <em>Persona </em>game is a spin-off of <em>Persona 5</em> but with gacha mechanics, credit should be given to the developers of <em>Persona 5: The Phantom X</em> for implementing a lot of features that demonstrably improve the classic Persona experience. The most obvious addition would be the inclusion of multiple adult confidants and playable characters of various ages, ranging from college students and young adults to senior citizens.</p><p>Another neat change is the modernization of various core gameplay mechanics. For instance, party roles are more strictly defined, so you might have characters that are specialized buffers or tanks. Personas have similar niches, so while you do have the freedom to build a Persona however you want, you're still encouraged to pick certain Personas based on what your team needs. Navigators also play a more active role in combat, functioning as a kind of off-screen support.&nbsp;</p><p>The most controversial changes might be the removal of the calendar system and some of the writing. The mere notion that you might miss relevant story content in previous Persona games due to the calendar was like a specter that haunted every dialogue decision that you could make, so I certainly didn't miss its absence.</p><p>Unfortunately, most everyone can agree that <em>Persona 5: The Phantom X's</em> story has a very weak opening act. While I like the first two antagonists on a conceptual level, the execution of these concepts in terms of both writing and presentation left much to be desired.</p><p>The narrative only starts to shine at the third Palace, which is much better executed thus far. While it's not quite on the level of Dr. Maruki's arc in <em>Persona 5 Royal</em>, it has the potential for greatness, and its themes are quite contemporary too.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Anson is a Writer at TechRaptor and has been playing games for as long as he can remember. As far as he's concerned, games are one of the greatest forms of… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/anson-chan">More about Anson</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/opinions/anson-chan-top-games-2025]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dan Rockwood's Top 10 Games of 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/opinions/dan-rockwood-top-games-2025</link>
            <guid>1401925</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>As the midway point of the 2020s, the year 2025 has given us some excellent games. This was a pinnacle year, with a major console release from Nintendo and so many developers focusing exclusively on current-gen hardware. It was also an incredible year for indies, giving me such a diverse field of games to play through.</p><p>Here are my top 10 games I played in 2025.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ghost-of-yotei-deer.JPG?itok=PdKlAb54 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ghost-of-yotei-deer.JPG?itok=Th6Qq_Fl 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><h2>1. <em>Ghost of Yotei&nbsp;</em> &nbsp;</h2><p>Easily my most-anticipated title, having loved<em> </em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/ghost-of-tsushima" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow"><em>Ghost of Tsushima</em></a> and wanting to spend more time in that beautiful world,<em> Ghost of Yotei </em>delighted me in every way. I actually like it better than its predecessor, with Atsu's story and character being more compelling to me personally.</p><p>Taking full advantage of PlayStation 5, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/ghost-of-yotei-review-new-ghost-in-familiar-tale" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow"><em>Ghost of Yotei</em></a><em> </em>brought to life a vibrant world packed with wildlife, side quests, shrines and adventures around every region. Plus, Atsu was able to shred Jin's sense of honor that permeated the <em>Ghost of Tsushima</em> story so heavily, removing a lot of the guilt her predecessor felt about his actions. This is my top game of the year and one that I look forward to jump back into when<em> Legends</em> releases later this year.</p><h2>2. <em>Metroid Prime 4&nbsp;</em></h2><p>Eight years in the making and 18 years since <em>Metroid Prime 3</em>, <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/metroid-prime-4" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow"><em>Metroid Prime 4</em></a> finally launched this past December, and I loved almost every minute of it. It sounds contradictory, but my least favorite thing about Metroidvania games is the actual Metroidvania part, so a more straightforward action-adventure experience like <em>Metroid Prime 4 </em>was perfect for me.</p><p>It also motivated me to launch a spreadsheet to log powerups and secret locations, a tactic I'll bring forward to other games that I may have bounced off of because of their complexity. Incredible boss battles and gorgeous art direction (Sol Valley notwithstanding) all combine brilliantly to make this one of my favorite games of the year.</p><h2>3. <em>Donkey Kong Bananza</em></h2><p><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/donkey-kong-bananza-review-oohh-banana" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow"><em>Donkey Kong Bananza</em></a> is currently one of the best Nintendo Switch 2 exclusives, and it does a brilliant job of showcasing what the Switch 2 is capable of. I spent countless hours exploring the levels as DK with Pauline by my side, punching through dirt, gravel, and any other material I came across.</p><p>It reminded me of everything I love about <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/minecraft" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow"><em>Minecraft</em></a> while combining the smooth platforming of a <em>Super Mario</em> game. Knowing that<em> Donkey Kong Bananza </em>came from the <em>Mario </em>team at Nintendo, it sets up great possibilities for what the future of platformers looks like on Switch 2.</p><h2>4. <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em></h2><p><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/monster-hunter-wilds" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow"><em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em></a> switches up some of the core formula of the franchise that not all friends appreciated, but I did. SOS flares and AI companions meant I could take on some of the more difficult battles without waiting for friends to be online, and the responsive controls on PS5 made combat an incredibly satisfying experience.</p><p>The monster designs in this game were some of my favorite in the series, and I found myself replaying battles over and over just because of how cinematic they felt, dodging lightning strikes or navigating sandstorms. <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em> helped turn me into a full <em>Monster Hunter</em> fan, and I'll always appreciate it for that.</p><h2>5. <em>Blue Prince</em></h2><p><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/blue-prince" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow"><em>Blue Prince</em></a> was a delightful surprise on Game Pass this year (before I cancelled my account due to price increases, but <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/opinions/xbox-game-pass-ultimate-price-increase" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">that's another article</a>). I did not think that an indie game about exploring an estate room by room would have resonated with me as well as it did, but it pulled me in right away.</p><p>Solving the mysteries of the mansion only brings up more questions, and finding ways to navigate away from dead-ends and store important items for future runs only made this game more addicting.<em> Blue Prince</em> is a title I'll happily return to again and again to uncover more mysteries.</p><h2>6. <em>Split Fiction</em></h2><p>I had the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/split-fiction-review-everything-everywhere" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow"><em>Split Fiction</em></a> release date on my calendar for months, as my wife and I were so excited to play it together. When it launched in March, we had an incredible time working together to clear the puzzles and challenges of this game. Hazelight Studios deploys some of the best couch co-op experiences in gaming, and <em>Split Fiction </em>hits the mark just as well as its previous titles.</p><p>We found ourselves laughing and screaming in surprise as the many, many diverse gameplay vignettes played out during our time. I loved playing <em>Split Fiction</em> with my partner, and I have plans soon to start a new run-through with one of my best friends—I can't wait to experience this game again.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pokemon-legends-z-a.JPG?itok=rU_G5N2L 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1615" height="916">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pokemon-legends-z-a.JPG?itok=GfTPu2gg 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="681">
                  

  </picture><h2>7. <em>Pokémon Legends Z-A</em></h2><p>Is there a title this year that received more negative criticism than <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/pokemon-legends-za-review-mega-adventure" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow"><em>Pokémon Legends Z-A</em></a><em>? </em>The initial discourse made me avoid it for a few weeks, but the night before boarding a plane to Las Vegas I decided to download it and play it during my vacation, and I'm so happy I did.</p><p><em>Pokémon Legends Z-A </em>combines a beautiful world (yes, even with 2D balconies) with impressively smooth gameplay, giving longtime fans a <em>Pokémon </em>experience worthy of a mainline title. Lumiose City was so much fun to get lost in, and battling through the ranks and discovering new Pokémon in the Wild Zones never got boring. <em>Pokémon Legends Z-A</em> gives me great hope for what the future of the <em>Pokémon </em>franchise holds for Switch 2 players.&nbsp;</p><h2>8. <em>Arc Raiders</em></h2><p><em>Arc Raiders </em>dominated my fall by not just being a great game, but it was a phenomenal multiplayer experience that reconnected me with some friends as we went raiding together. The short mission structure and variety of weapon upgrades and crafting options made the hours in this game easily tick away.</p><p>I found myself up late many nights jumping into raid after raid, checking my notes to hunt specific enemies for parts and making split-second decisions to engage or run away when confronted with human fighters. <em>Arc Raiders</em> satisfies with a near-perfect gameplay and level-up system, solidifying it as a game that I'll love to play for a long time to come.</p><h2>9. <em>Marvel's Midnight Suns</em></h2><p>Not a 2025 release, but this was the year I dove back into <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/marvels-midnight-suns-review" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow"><em>Marvel's Midnight Suns</em></a>. I had played a bit of it when it first came out but decided to pick it back up on Steam Deck. I was pleased to see how well it performs on the portable PC, allowing me to chip away at battles and build relationships while on lunch breaks, traveling, and relaxing on the couch.</p><p>This has become my bedtime game, treating it like a comic book that I jump into each night to hang out with Blade, Captain Marvel, Spider-Man, and all the others. <em>Marvel's Midnight Suns</em> is a slow-burn for me, and the perfect pace for a game to play in-between the other heavy-hitting titles I pick up throughout the year.</p><h2>10. <em>Alan Wake 2</em></h2><p>I initially started <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/alan-wake-2-review-mesmerizing-murder-mystery" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow"><em>Alan Wake 2</em></a> this fall to coincide with the Halloween season, and it was the perfect spooky game to play late at night as the days got shorter.<em> Alan Wake 2</em> combines everything I love about survival horror and mystery, giving you a fun assortment of weapons and upgrades, as well as impressively designed locales to explore.</p><p>After about 20 years in games, I found myself turning down some of the jump-scare settings, an element I was pleased to be able to control as they were starting to hurt my experience. Saga is one of my favorite new characters I got to play as this year, and no game has accomplished flashlight-wielding and gunplay quite like <em>Alan Wake 2 </em>has—this game was definitely a major highlight of mine this year.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Dan is a Boston-based writer who has been with TechRaptor since the end of 2020. He has been working in the online writing, editing and SEO space for nearly… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/dan-rockwood">More about Dan</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/opinions/dan-rockwood-top-games-2025]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tyler Chancey's Top 10 Games of 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/opinions/tyler-chancey-top-games-2025</link>
            <guid>1401919</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Gaming in 2025 was arguably the most difficult it has ever been. Hardware and software prices are increasing due to illegal tariffs and unethical AI datacenters. High-profile releases appear to be charging more and providing less. Smaller studios that push the envelope struggle for the spotlight. This year, more than others, gaming was a struggle both as players and creators.</p><p>Yet, pleasant surprises did happen this year. Thoughtful, thematically rich, and downright delightful games broke through the haze of tumult, and I would like to share them here. These are my top 10 games of 2025.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/total-chaos-twisted-hallway-image.jpg?itok=EBqwzBk7 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1400" height="788">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/total-chaos-twisted-hallway-image.jpg?itok=I7kEKfDB 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><h2>10.<em> Total Chaos</em></h2><p><em>Total Chaos</em> is a standalone survival-horror game based on a <em>Doom II</em> total conversion mod created by the same guy behind <em>Turbo Overkill</em>. With that kind of dry description, it is easy to dismiss this late-in-the-year release.</p><p>But I cannot keep <em>Total Chaos</em> out of my mind. My journey through the island of Fort Oasis was one packed with memorable monster encounters, supremely timed scares, excellent sound design, haunting musical score, and challenging levels that pushed my survival-horror skills to the limit.</p><p>The narrative it tells, while opaque at times, is one packed with heavy subject matters: substance abuse, terminal illness, depression, and self-harm. Its gameplay loop is a satisfying mix of building makeshift melee weapons, scrambling against deranged monsters, and managing health.</p><p><em>Total Chaos</em> isn't higher on my list because some of its <em>Doom II</em> roots make it an acquired taste. The labyrinthine maps, manual save system, unforgiving resource management, and occasional jank can lead to a hostile player experience. Thankfully, I'm one of those sickos who completely clicked with this nasty surprise of a game.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/no-i-m-not-a-human-window-appearance.jpg?itok=7BpQ5FZB 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1400" height="788">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/no-i-m-not-a-human-window-appearance.jpg?itok=mM1PijOP 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><h2>9. <em>No, I'm Not a Human</em></h2><p>The second horror game on my list is from indie studio Trioskaz and from the same publisher as last year's <em>Mouthwashing</em>.</p><p><em>No, I'm Not a Human</em> truly feels like a game that came straight from a nightmare. You are trapped in your home during a calamity. At night, people come to your home seeking aid. There are human-looking Visitors that will kill you if you invite them in. Certain Visitors will break into your home and kill you if you're completely alone. Who do you let in? Who do you trust? It manages all of this in an experience you can easily finish in an afternoon.</p><p>Yet in just under three hours, N<em>o, I'm Not a Human</em> presents an excellent demonstration of social anxiety horror and pitch-dark human misery. For that particular consideration in design, it gets a place on my list.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/hades-ii-boss-fight-screenshot.jpg?itok=hH8YDQzM 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1400" height="758">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/hades-ii-boss-fight-screenshot.jpg?itok=4F8B-XIa 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="650">
                  

  </picture><h2>8. <em>Hades II</em></h2><p>Supergiant Games shocked fans this year with the first sequel in their development history. In addition, it is a sequel to one of their most critically acclaimed games.</p><p>The only real problem with <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/hades-2-review-new-standard-for-rougelites" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="ee979716-54c8-4f21-87b7-fe53a52b6c74" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Hades II</em></a> is that Melinoe's quest is a far more conventional fantasy narrative compared to the more nuanced family drama of the original.</p><p>But <em>Hades II</em> more than earns a spot on my list thanks to Supergiant packing this sequel with more of just about everything. Even if it isn't as ambitious the second time around, <em>Hades II</em> is still a fantastic accomplishment.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dispatch-moral-choice-screenshot.jpg?itok=DwbrzbcL 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1400" height="788">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dispatch-moral-choice-screenshot.jpg?itok=1Xx8wHsi 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><h2>7. <em>Dispatch</em></h2><p>AdHoc Studios' superhero workplace drama was one of 2025's greatest surprises. Playing <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/dispatch-is-episodic-workplace-comedy-first-iterating-where-telltale-refused-to" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="516f8eb5-9839-41ae-b120-63ed11a9fa86" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Dispatch</em></a> is like binging a season of prestige TV, one packed with strong character writing, entertaining dynamics, saucy romance, and imaginative superhero worldbuilding.</p><p>The writing is so impressive that it elevates <em>Dispatch's</em> otherwise light superhero management gameplay sections. But when you have well-rounded leads, hilarious interludes, and strong performances by some of the best actors in the business, it's hard to complain.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/silent-hill-f-boss-fight-screenshot.jpg?itok=1EjNn8sB 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1400" height="788">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/silent-hill-f-boss-fight-screenshot.jpg?itok=n0NCIlJe 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><h2>6. <em>Silent Hill f</em></h2><p>The <em>Silent Hill</em> series continues its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/opinions/silent-hill-2-remake-revives-classic" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">strong return</a> to the gaming space this year with <em>Silent Hill f</em>. Better still, developer Neobards Entertainment takes several creative risks in this spin-off that ultimately pay off.</p><p><em>Silent Hill f</em> moves away from the titular haunted town to a Japanese fishing village in the 1960s. The focus returns to a female protagonist for the first time since 2003. There is a strong emphasis on melee combat. Its disturbing Otherworld eschews the rusted liminal industrial aesthetic in favor of ethereal dark expanses, Shinto shrines, and torii gates. The story, courtesy of <em>Higurashi</em> creator Ryukishi07, is a layered, at times contradictory, folk tale of twisted rituals and the troubles of female adolescence.</p><p>These are all major swings in their own right. The fact that the final product is an engaging and terrifying horror experience is a miracle.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/the-alters-musical-number-screenshot.jpg?itok=3PR_PSkw 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1400" height="788">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/the-alters-musical-number-screenshot.jpg?itok=oWRinIAb 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><h2>5. <em>The Alters</em></h2><p>The developers of <em>Frostpunk</em> bring a welcome character focus to their newest game. <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/alters-review-narrative-driven-survival" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="10b01578-14f7-447d-af34-ca211101e179" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>The Alters</em></a> is a sci-fi survival story where protagonist Jan Dolski is trying to reconfigure a research station to escape a hostile alien world. His only allies are Alters: parallel versions of himself with different career skills and personalities. This narrative experience blends elements of films like <em>The Martian</em>, <em>Moon</em>, and a bit of <em>Everything, Everywhere, All at Once</em>.</p><p><em>The Alters</em> gets a spot on my list for two remarkable achievements. First, its complex, interlocking strategy, base management, and survival sim gameplay clicked with me (genres I personally find dry at best). Second, the experience is elevated by intelligent sci-fi worldbuilding and a strong central journey for the main character. Any narrative that can make you contemplate Albert Camus while facing serious ethical debates is one worthy of praise.</p><p>For that extra step beyond, 11-Bit Studios deserves all the praise.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/clair-obscur-expedition-33-verso-and-river-screenshot.jpg?itok=kclKokd9 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1400" height="788">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/clair-obscur-expedition-33-verso-and-river-screenshot.jpg?itok=ISt6GBVQ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><h2>4. <em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em></h2><p>For better and for worse, Sandfall Interactive's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/clair-obscur-expedition-33-review-french-revolution" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="07f3b1f2-234f-4782-8556-c21c1fb23302" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em></a> is a game that has critically dominated discussions this year.</p><p>It is praise well-deserved. <em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em> is a triumph of visual presentation and musical brilliance. The story it tells is an emotionally fraught journey of grief and the limitations of art as a means of coping with loss. The gameplay is a polished blend of other RPG contemporaries. The style and impact of <em>Persona</em>. The hybrid combat of the <em>Mario RPG</em> series. The obtuse yet rewarding progression system of early 2000s' <em>Final Fantasy</em>.</p><p>So why isn't it at the top of my list? Because, despite some measured explanations by Sandfall's CEO regarding their implementation, Sandfall Interactive utilized generative AI assets during development and failed to disclose it. While it is true these assets were ultimately used as placeholders and no longer exist in the game's current version, it is still a damper on an otherwise great title.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/absolum-frog-wizard-combat.jpg?itok=kQKfYSH7 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1400" height="788">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/absolum-frog-wizard-combat.jpg?itok=6Rb6vg3W 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><h2>3. <em>Absolum</em></h2><p><em>Absolum</em> is the kind of game I'm surprised didn't happen sooner: a roguelike beat-em-up in the vein of classic <em>Golden Axe</em> made by the same studio behind <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/streets-of-rage-4-review" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow"><em>Streets of Rage 4</em></a>.</p><p>As someone who has spent countless quarters in such button bashers, the core experience of <em>Absolum</em> is a fantastic blend of punchy hits, satisfying supers, and welcome modern flourishes. Combine this strong core loop with an exemplary spread of levels with branching paths and evolving storylines, and you have an endlessly replayable romp. A fun, addictive retro throwback with all of the right modern touches that earns its place among the year's best.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/split-fiction-dual-world-gameplay-screenshot.jpg?itok=79KLlsWC 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1400" height="788">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/split-fiction-dual-world-gameplay-screenshot.jpg?itok=qiZSSr8l 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><h2>2. <em>Split Fiction</em></h2><p>Hazelight Studio's latest co-op adventure doesn't make the best first impression. To be blunt, <em>Split Fiction's</em> narrative is barely above a boilerplate YA sci-fi story at best; its characters are thinly sketched, and its story beats are rote.</p><p>So why is <em>Split Fiction</em> so high on the list? Two words: Level design. Across its twelve-hour runtime, my co-op partner and I were consistently surprised and blown away by the game's relentlessly creative setpieces, vignettes, and boss fights. The finale alone has quickly risen to one of my favorite gaming moments ever. Take a bow, Hazelight development team and director Josef Fares, for this rollercoaster ride of a game.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/hollow-knight-silksong-citadel-screenshot.jpg?itok=_1-IhIEv 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1400" height="788">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/hollow-knight-silksong-citadel-screenshot.jpg?itok=gmE3AWEP 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><h2>1. <em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em></h2><p><em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em> was a game in an unenviable position. This long-awaited sequel to <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/hollow-knight" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow"><em>Hollow Knight</em></a> has been in development so long that fans descended into rabid speculation and delusion. It was the kind of self-sustaining hype only bolstered by <em>Hollow Knight's</em> already impressive reputation of being one of the best 2D action games of the past few years.</p><p>It's a narrative too familiar in this industry. Excellent debut title. Sky-high expectations for the follow-up. Inevitable disappointment when it fails to deliver, followed by backlash.</p><p>But something funny happened with <em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em>. It delivered. Hornet's journey to the land of Pharloom is an impressive Metroidvania adventure, one that explores and interrogates corrupt religious institutions and the importance of faith. The game's murderous, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/opinions/death-to-death-runs" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="bc88c70a-a511-49c5-9fc0-4b3f70907424" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">borderline unfair, difficulty curve</a>, and brutal in-game economy reinforce its cogent commentary.</p><p>On top of that, Team Cherry put multiple AAA publishers to shame by delivering this excellent title, not through crunch or by cutting corners, but by taking their time.</p><p>It is thanks to that perfect blend of development and result that secures <em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em> my top spot.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/opinions/tyler-chancey-top-games-2025]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parker Johnson's Top 10 Games of 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/opinions/parker-johnson-top-games-2025</link>
            <guid>1401916</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>2025 was a weird year! I don’t think anyone would disagree with that. For me personally, this was my first year post-college graduation, which I imagine is a weird time for everyone, but it feels especially weird in a post-COVID world.</p><p>There were a lot of times the world was confusing. I had to find out how insurance works! Buying a car is really expensive and complicated! But, while there weren’t any games that blew me away this year, I found a lot of comfort in games this year. Here were the ones that helped me most.</p><h2>10. <em>Monster Train 2</em></h2><p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/mt2keyart.jpg?itok=WlCxUrzD 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/mt2keyart.jpg?itok=UXImKCPM 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>You can read more of <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/monster-train-2-review-to-hell-and-back" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="3a2bd1e6-1b9d-413f-b649-92b14caafc0f" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">my <em>Monster Train 2</em> thoughts in my review,</a> but it’s great! In short, <em>Monster Train 2 </em>ended up my second favorite deckbuilder of the year, thanks to how many ways it gives you to play.</p><h2>9. <em>Ball X Pit</em></h2><p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ballxpit.jpg?itok=hoFcaKai 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ballxpit.jpg?itok=8JZGzF5r 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>The subgenre that <em>Vampire Survivors</em> spawned had some great entries this year, but for me, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/ball-x-pit-review-bubble-bobble-toil-and-trouble" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="bc62caf3-6a98-45be-907e-22ef807517ec" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Ball X Pit</em></a> is the one that takes the cake. As you descend into a pit, you upgrade your arsenal of balls, using characters with varied abilities to constantly put new twists on your run. After being a PC-heavy gamer this year, <em>Ball X Pit</em> has been the perfect “chill on the couch after work” game.</p><p>Where I thought it might lose me is the city building. I’ve never been enamored by games like <em>Stardew Valley</em>, and the mechanic in games like <em>Cult of the Lamb</em> has just never interested me. After getting a few hours into <em>Ball X Pit</em>, though, I had a great time developing the village. The loop of repositioning my buildings to try and send my villagers on the perfect harvest became really satisfying and, if nothing else, a very low-time investment way to build a city and get right back into the action.</p><h2>8. <em>Rematch</em></h2><p><em><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/rematch.jpg?itok=7qJJI4YS 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/rematch.jpg?itok=5hEQhNLm 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture></em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/rematch-review-near-pitch-perfect" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="8cc3450d-a90e-4f44-b1c6-792d4aae601f" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Rematch</em></a> probably isn’t the best multiplayer soccer game that you’ll play. <em>Rocket League</em> is right there, and it’s one of the most expressive multiplayer games out there. But, what <em>Rematch</em> lacks in a skill ceiling, it makes up for with a high skill floor.</p><p>Once you get the hang of the controls, pulling off cool stuff is pretty easy. Passing across the pitch to a teammate is one thing, sure. But, running down the field, slamming the ball against the wall to your teammate, who bicycle kicks it into the goal? Man, that feels good. Compared to <em>Rocket League</em>, <em>Rematch</em> is more of a battle of wits than a battle of execution, and it’s a ton of fun.</p><h2>7. <em>StarVaders</em></h2><p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/starvaders-key-art.jpg?itok=59E0TZWo 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/starvaders-key-art.jpg?itok=h2x_VuAC 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>Remember earlier when I said <em>Monster Train 2</em> was the second-best deckbuilder I’ve played this year? <em>StarVaders</em> is the one taking the number one spot.</p><p>Like <em>Slay the Spire</em> and <em>Space Invaders</em> had a baby bathed exclusively in Saturday morning cartoons, <em>StarVaders</em> is much more puzzle than traditional combat. Instead of being concerned with health, your job is to prevent Doom, generated when enemies reach a certain position on the board.&nbsp;</p><p>When you take damage, junk is temporarily added to your deck instead of losing HP. It’s a small change, but makes calculations so different from other deckbuilders. Should you take a hit to avoid generating Doom, but make your deck worse? It's a fun calculus to run, and while it hasn't eaten as many hours as other deckbuilders I've played, the hours I spent were memorable ones.</p><h2>6. <em>Ninja Gaiden: Ragebound</em></h2><p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ninjagaidenragebound.jpg?itok=jveMbm1X 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ninjagaidenragebound.jpg?itok=DgccQgWh 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>At the start of this year, I had never played a <em>Ninja Gaiden</em> game. I’m not a big <em>Souls</em> guy, and I don’t really seek out difficult games. But after seeing rave reviews, I gave <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/ninja-gaiden-ragebound-review-razor-sharp-retro-platformer" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="1f5be4cb-8821-406e-ac38-384d019a3a18" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Ragebound</em></a> a chance, and I’m really glad I did!</p><p>In the midst of a busy travel season in the spring and summer, I was playing a ton of this on flights. As I progressively got more frustrated, it made those eventual defeats all the more sweeter. I think I finally understand Soulslike gamers. I still won’t be one of them though!</p><h2>5. <em>PEAK</em></h2><p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/peakphotostrip.jpg?itok=qZoqK51F 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/peakphotostrip.jpg?itok=7h2in2Js 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>In one run, I saw a bbno$ concert, got eaten by my friend, and shot myself out of a cannon across a lava pit. There’s nothing quite like <em>PEAK</em>.</p><h2>4. <em>Rift of the NecroDancer</em></h2><p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/necrodancer.png?itok=X4oyuzDS 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/png" width="1885" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/necrodancer.png?itok=DlPMqrv1 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/png" width="1200" height="688">
                  

  </picture>I miss <em>Guitar Hero</em>, man. For a while, I thought there might not be anything that scratches a rhythm game itch like it ever again. Then, I played <em>Rift of the NecroDancer</em>.</p><p>Like <em>Guitar Hero</em>, notes come at you on a track, and you’ll need good reflexes and rhythm. Unlike <em>Guitar Hero</em>, these notes come in the forms of little guys, each of which will need different types of rhythm to defeat. Sure, skeletons and slimes just need to be hit on the beat once. But what about armadillos? They need to be hit in quick succession a la eighth notes in music. Enemies of different species and colors all have their own quirks that you need to be ready for.</p><p>And at first, it’s tough. It can be difficult to remember all of the traits that each creature has. But you get out of <em>Rift</em> what you put in. The more time you spend chasing high scores, the more fun you’ll have, and the more everything will start to connect. Not to mention, with DLC tracks from other games like <em>Shovel Knight</em> and <em>Everhood</em>, and even a pack of songs by Hatsune Miku, there’s always something new to play. <em>Rift of the NecroDancer</em> is one of my favorite rhythm games, and it just keeps getting better.</p><h2>3. <em>Hades II</em></h2><p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/hades2keyart.png?itok=XIMfsTo1 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/png" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/hades2keyart.png?itok=vHAGvxSZ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/png" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>Depending on the day, <em>Hades</em> is one of my all-time favorite games. The way it intertwines roguelike trappings with fantastic storytelling is still unmatched, including by its sequel.</p><p>In the moment-to-moment gameplay, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/hades-2-review-new-standard-for-rougelites" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="ee979716-54c8-4f21-87b7-fe53a52b6c74" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Hades II</em></a> blows its predecessor out of the water. The cast is far more effective than it is in <em>Hades</em>, and the new Boons and weapons are all fantastic. Runs to both the surface and underworld are varied, and runs all feel really distinct.</p><p>Where <em>Hades II</em> unfortunately lost me is the writing. The stories and characters I loved so much in the first game felt lacking in the sequel. When I want to go back for a story, I’ll probably go back to the original <em>Hades</em>. But, when I want to go back for one run, I’ll go back to <em>Hades II</em>.</p><h2>2. <em>Donkey Kong Bananza</em></h2><p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dkbananza.jpg?itok=j_osRw7G 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1200">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dkbananza.jpg?itok=XRWGDEBM 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="750">
                  

  </picture>After spending a much higher than I hoped amount on a Nintendo Switch 2, there weren’t a ton of games that were on my radar right away. Playing <em>Cyberpunk</em> on it has been great, sure, and <em>Mario Kart World</em> provided a few great nights of multiplayer fun, but nothing was a strict system seller for me. But, after picking up <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/donkey-kong-bananza-review-oohh-banana" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="1274fb40-6e8d-4703-bb0e-20669236af7b" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Donkey Kong Bananza</em></a>, I really am glad I waited outside Best Buy for that Switch 2.</p><p>Another Nintendo game, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/legend-of-zelda-tears-of-kingdom-review" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="90af5ca2-2e3e-472f-baf1-9df7fb10d3cc" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</em></a> is one of my favorite games of all time. The big thing it has in common with <em>Bananza</em>? Neither game should work, but they do. Both are massive technical achievements, and <em>Bananza</em>’s destructible environments are densely packed with things to do.&nbsp;</p><p>Most anywhere you dig will lead to something cool. And if it doesn’t? Who cares, dude? You just punched through a planet! That’s awesome! There’s some cracks that show in <em>Bananza</em> that aren’t in <em>Tears of the Kingdom</em>; in particular, I recall some frame rate dips in the middle of some tough boss battles. But moment-to-moment, <em>Donkey Kong Bananza</em> is just pure fun. What more can you ask for?</p><h2>1. <em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em></h2><p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/expedition33.jpg?itok=Iv91yaJQ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/expedition33.jpg?itok=_oT4zy4z 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>Put it in the history books, folks: another win for <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/clair-obscur-expedition-33-review-french-revolution" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="07f3b1f2-234f-4782-8556-c21c1fb23302" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em></a>. I’ve been wrestling with my feelings on the game for a while after feeling pretty conflicted, especially after the game was shown to have placeholder assets created by generative AI. But when I think about my experience playing <em>Expedition 33</em>, I think of two things that I feel are both head and shoulders above other games and undeniably human.</p><p>First is the music. I’ve been a big fan of video game music, and this soundtrack is an incredible achievement. The way Lorien Testard leaps between styles effortlessly is really something to behold, and Alice Duport-Percier’s vocals elevate the music to become something really special. I still listen to it quite often while I'm at work.</p><p>Second is the performances. Sure, the glitzy castings of Charlie Cox and Andy Serkis made a big splash, and they both give excellent performances. The real standouts, though, are Jennifer English and Ben Starr as Maelle and Verso. The final hours in particular feature some really great moments for both actors, and the facial animation is top-notch. I felt truly affected by the performances in <em>Expedition 33</em>, and I’m sure I’ll still be thinking about these performances and listening to this soundtrack for quite some time in 2026.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Parker is a freelance writer based in Iowa, and the co-founder and editor of gaming satire site Palette Swap. Before Palette Swap, he was an editor at Hard… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/parker-johnson">More about Parker</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/opinions/parker-johnson-top-games-2025]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Robert Scarpinito's Top 7 Games of 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/opinions/robert-scarpinito-top-games-2025</link>
            <guid>1401913</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>2025 is the year that broke me when it comes to video games. The years of a constant barrage of new AAA releases, almost all of which need to be 50+ hours, has worn me down, especially when juxtaposed with rampant layoffs, studio closures, and the general state of capitalism in the industry.</p><p>I've found some solace in the indie and AA space, however you want to define those terms. And there were still some interesting AAA games out there this year. <em>Donkey Kong Bananza</em> is a great adventure that's as fun as it is playful, and <em>Doom: The Dark Ages</em> turns the Doom Slayer into Captain America if he were bathed in hellfire.</p><p>In the not-so-AAA space, I loved playing <em>Peak </em>for a couple weekends. It's a fantastic way to kill time with friends. <em>Ball x Pit</em> is a genius mix of <em>Arkanoid</em>, city building, and roguelike elements that offers perfect bite-sized gaming sessions. And I found a new way to zone out with <em>PowerWash Simulator 2</em>, which adds just enough upgrades over the previous to make it easier but not too braindead.</p><p>But let's draw the arbitrary line in the sand here and start diving into my top 7 games of 2025, in some vibes-based order.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/top-games-2026-split-fiction.jpg?itok=OjGyXmXC 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/top-games-2026-split-fiction.jpg?itok=IfcjxEuH 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><h2><em>Split Fiction</em></h2><p>I played <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/split-fiction-review-everything-everywhere" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="97535e5a-e23e-4679-b20b-f4071ecead93" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Split Fiction</em></a> with my partner in the first half of 2025, and granted, partway through the game, we got a little bored. Every new set of powers and upgrades was novel and interesting, but the length of time with each mechanic dragged on just a tiny bit in some sections. It was like, "Okay, we get it."</p><p>But the final race to the finish line really stuck with us. It felt fresh, innovative, and chaotic, playing with the literal split fiction that the entire game sets up. Rushing between worlds and seeing things blend together felt like a fever dream.</p><p>Much like <em>Brothers: A Tale of Two Sons</em> or <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/way-out-review-cooperative-camp" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="0a8b056d-dfa1-4eb5-bf43-657d581fa8c1" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>A Way Out</em></a> before it, Josef Fares' team has one big, unique, genuinely cool idea at the end of <em>Split Fiction </em>that makes it<em> </em>worth the journey.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/top-games-2026-pirate-yakuza.jpg?itok=Et9za-0_ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/top-games-2026-pirate-yakuza.jpg?itok=99PEndEi 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><h2><em>Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii</em></h2><p>Can I defend <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/like-dragon-pirate-yakuza-in-hawaii-review-yarr-kuza" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="94818ce8-72d8-409e-b568-4f7ba9a213ad" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii</em></a> in a scholarly GOTY debate with fellow peers? Probably not. At this point, you're either super into <em>Like a Dragon</em> games, want to get into them, or absolutely don't get them. I fall in the first camp, and even though <em>Pirate Yakuza</em> isn't as good as some of the other recent games in the series, it's still a tonally unique and wild ride.</p><p>The protagonist, Goro Majima, gets amnesia, ends up on the shores of Hawaii, and becomes a pirate on a whim. His journey is kicked off by a campy musical number, and he plays a wonderful role model for a young boy, despite being rough around the edges.</p><p>With silly mini games, pirate ship death matches, and the ability to summon spectral monkeys, <em>Pirate Yakuza</em>—and the franchise at large—injects some levity into its unserious machismo. There really isn't anything like these games, and I'll always go out of my way to play the newest releases.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/top-games-2026-death-stranding-2.jpg?itok=0Hss-ZMT 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/top-games-2026-death-stranding-2.jpg?itok=bxqUzESL 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><h2><em>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</em></h2><p>Honestly, Kojima won me over with this one. I was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/death-stranding-review" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="ae097f31-89e8-48fb-a0e2-73ea8500c938" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Death Stranding's</em></a> biggest hater back in the day—I even argued against it being <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/every-game-techraptor-scored-10-10" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="98bd7345-b819-4204-99ab-eec184133f3b" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">one of our few 10/10 games</a>—but something about this sequel just hits perfectly. It streamlines some of the more tedious parts of the first game, and you get to the fun parts sooner.</p><p>It doesn't take long for you to build up a suite of tools and vehicles to optimize your routes. Doing side quests gets easier as the game goes on, and even the tedium of building roads and rails becomes easy, if not just a tiny bit tedious still. Even better, there's all sorts of silly and new ways to play the game. You can hurt people with pizza fu, ride a hoverboard, and jump off ramps with no consequence.</p><p>I think with <em>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</em>, I found a zen state that the gameplay was going for. Combat sequences are more straightforward too, making it easier to mode shift between delivery man and demolition man.</p><p>Of course, the story is still absolutely ridiculous. It's a world where the rule of cool is arguably more important than the substance, where it's more vibes-based than anything else. The game's most memorable moments come from when the game doesn't take itself that seriously, even when the dramatic tension soars.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/top-games-2026-dispatch.jpg?itok=fwx5i-r1 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/top-games-2026-dispatch.jpg?itok=RyfV1YWv 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><h2><em>Dispatch</em></h2><p><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/dispatch-is-episodic-workplace-comedy-first-iterating-where-telltale-refused-to" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="516f8eb5-9839-41ae-b120-63ed11a9fa86" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Dispatch</em></a> was a surprise late addition for me on this list. It takes everything I loved about the classic Telltale formula but streamlines it for the better. Episodes are tight and full of twists, making it an extremely lean package that trims out all the fat.</p><p>It pulls you into the narrative and gives you a front row seat to steer the story. Your choices truly feel like they matter, even when they ultimately don't. It's that belief and immersion that makes <em>Dispatch</em> work so well, especially for the big choices that change the overarching journey (like the one at the end of episode 3).</p><p>While the main characters are fine enough, the best people in <em>Dispatch</em> are the smaller side characters who all bring different levels of comedy relief. The scene of Phenomeman slowing highway traffic on the news while Waterboy disgustingly cleans the TV perfectly encapsulates the energy of <em>Dispatch</em>'s best moments. It concisely and effectively shows who both of these characters are right when you need to make a choice relevant to them. Plus, it's hilarious.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/top-games-2026-blue-prince.jpg?itok=TOqB1Gt_ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/top-games-2026-blue-prince.jpg?itok=W-XBLOym 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><h2><em>Blue Prince</em></h2><p><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/blue-prince-review-i-finished-game-50-hours-ago-and-theres-still-puzzles-to-solve" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="5246e141-1a34-45db-8967-3159c0562016" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Blue Prince</em></a> won our site's overall game of the year, and it's a well-deserved award for such an enthralling game. I played it with my partner this year, and it was so much fun figuring out its myriad secrets together. I distinctly remember the moment we had to pull out a notepad and pen together, realizing how deep the waters beneath us were.</p><p>Granted, the roguelike gameplay ultimately undermines and weakens the puzzle gameplay, weakening the overall package. Before the magic wore off though, <em>Blue Prince</em> was easily one of the most enthralling experiences I've had in 2025. Even when I wasn't playing it, I was thinking about all the different possible solutions.</p><p>Everything about this game is clever, even down to its name. I sometimes still mistype the game as "blue prints" because it feels like both names perfectly fit the game.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/top-games-2026-hades-ii.jpg?itok=IFOfY4ly 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/top-games-2026-hades-ii.jpg?itok=JcbMUlP8 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><h2><em>Hades II</em></h2><p><em>Hades</em> won our <a href="https://techraptor.net/blog/2020-techraptor-awards-game-of-year" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">Game of the Year Award in 2020</a>, so it's not surprising to see its sequel on my list. <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/hades-2-review-new-standard-for-rougelites" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="ee979716-54c8-4f21-87b7-fe53a52b6c74" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Hades II</em></a> really is just a bigger, better, bolder version of its older brother. It has twice as many levels, but it feels like quadruple the amount of content.</p><p>The action takes a slightly different approach considering Melinoe's slight aversion to close-ranged combat, but it's still a riveting, rewarding story full of intense combat, touching stories, and fleshed-out characters.</p><p>Her struggle to kill time is framed through a (somewhat) relatable family conflict, and with the post-release patch, the final parts of the story wrap up nicely. The excuse to continue doing runs in the post-game feels a little far fetched, but it works because the combat is ridiculously satisfying.</p><p>When a build works, it just hits so perfectly. Building around one mechanic, whether it's your cast or your omega special, simply feels so good. <em>Hades II</em> is more than everything I wanted in a sequel. The action, music, and narrative all hit just right.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/top-games-2026-clair-obscur.jpg?itok=KghlaFft 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/top-games-2026-clair-obscur.jpg?itok=-JlXtfs- 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><h2><em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em></h2><p>You might have missed this little-known gem, but <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/clair-obscur-expedition-33-review-french-revolution" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="07f3b1f2-234f-4782-8556-c21c1fb23302" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em></a> simply blew me away in 2025. It was unexpected and continues to surprise all the way through the final act. The hype for it is definitely overplayed and annoying, though the hatred for it is just as equally obnoxious. Regardless of where you fall on the fence, let's remember that other games besides the ones you like can be good to different people as well.</p><p>Unfortunately, yes, the use of generative AI in <em>Clair Obscur</em> isn't ideal—<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/interviews/witchfire-ceo-no-ai-larian" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="b6a9181d-93fd-4739-9598-8dc67ddaf53c" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">AI in general is a complicated topic in the industry.</a> I personally am not a fan of it being used in any game since it's such a creative field, and that includes with this game. But when you take the overall package for what it is, it's compelling and full of heart, tragedy, and twists.</p><p>The rock-solid turn-based gameplay feels so satisfying, especially when you set off a combo of effects. At some point though, it evolves into something that rewards you for breaking it. Sure, this makes the final couple hours stupidly easy, but by then, I was more invested in the story rather than the gameplay.</p><p>The narrative takes some big swings, deconstructing what you thought were the boundaries of this world for the sake of highlighting its characters and emotional struggles. It gets surreal, but in that space, <em>Clair Obscur</em> delivers a memorable story about the many ways people process grief—or put off processing it.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Robert Scarpinito is the Features Editor of TechRaptor. With a Bachelor of Arts in Journalism from the Ohio State University, sharing compelling stories is… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/robert-scarpinito">More about Robert</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/opinions/robert-scarpinito-top-games-2025]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>