<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 15:32:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Title Update 1 Release Date Revealed for Next Week]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-title-update-1-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-title-update-1-release-date-revealed-for-next-week.1144200/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-title-update-1-release-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Capcom has announced the release date for the upcoming&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</em>Title Update 1, which is set to introduce a new (or perhaps that should be returning) monster and more to the game next week.</p>

<p>Per a new&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter&nbsp;</em>showcase that aired earlier today,&nbsp;Title Update 1 will arrive on Friday, April 4th. The main attraction when it comes to this update is the introduction of Mizutsune, a water monster that made its first appearance in 2016's 3DS game&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Generations</em>.</p>

<p>You'll need to be High Rank level 21 or over to take on Mizutsune, and once you reach this level, you'll be able to grab an Extra Mission after speaking with Kanya in the Scarlet Forest. That's the mission in which Mizutsune waits for you.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/monster-hunter-wilds-title-update-1-mizutsune.jpg?itok=biImuV5Y 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/monster-hunter-wilds-title-update-1-mizutsune.jpg?itok=rfjIgQcj 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>' first title update is heading your way soon.</figcaption></figure><p>It's not just Mizutsune that's coming as part of this update, of course. You can also look forward to battling a new Arch-tempered version of new monster Rey Dau, which will be added to the game in a new quest "at a later date".</p>

<p>Zoh Shia, another new monster introduced in&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>, can now be fought as part of repeatable quests, although you will need to complete a new HR 50 mission in order to access it.</p>

<p>If you're looking for a new hangout spot for you and your fellow hunters, then you can head over to the new Grand Hub, which serves as a place "for hunters to gather and socialize", according to Capcom. There's also a fun new minigame to try out there.</p>

<p>You can check out all of the highlights of&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</em>Title Update 1 <a href="https://www.monsterhunter.com/wilds/en-us/update/ver_01_0/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">right here</a> courtesy of Capcom, and you can take a look at a brand new trailer for the update below.</p>




<p><em>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</em>is the latest game in Capcom's long-running&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter&nbsp;</em>series. It's proven to be the most popular game in the franchise by far, hitting <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-sales-8m" rel="nofollow">eight million sales in just three days</a>&nbsp;and breaking records both for the series and for Capcom as a whole <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-steam-player-record" rel="nofollow">on Steam</a>.</p>

<p>You can pick up&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2246340/Monster_Hunter_Wilds/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/monster-hunter-wilds/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/monster-hunter-wilds/9NMT6XFN0LVD" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>. If you want to know what our Tyler thought of the game, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/monster-hunter-wilds-review-new-frontier" rel="nofollow">you can see his review here</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>