<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 16:40:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hitman Developer Ends Conor McGregor Collab Following Trial]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/io-interactive-conor-mcgregor-collab-ended</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hitman-developer-ends-conor-mcgregor-collab-following-trial.1044624/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/io-interactive-conor-mcgregor-collab-ended<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Hitman&nbsp;</em>studio IO Interactive has announced that it's ending its collaboration with MMA fighter Conor McGregor following a court ruling which found that McGregor assaulted a woman.</p>

<p>In <a href="https://x.com/Hitman/status/1861049881160273921" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">a message on social media platform X</a>, IO said that its Conor McGregor collaboration was ending "effective immediately". The studio followed up by saying it takes the matter of McGregor's victim's assault "very seriously" and that it "cannot ignore [the matter's] implications".</p>

<p>As such, all content involving McGregor will be removed from&nbsp;<em>Hitman&nbsp;</em>"starting today". The developer hasn't explained what will happen if you already own&nbsp;<em>Hitman 3</em>'s Disruptor Pack, in which McGregor starred, but I'm assuming the content will be removed permanently from all storefronts.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/hitman-world-of-assassination-conor-mcgregor.jpg?itok=dPfziWlK 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/hitman-world-of-assassination-conor-mcgregor.jpg?itok=GOIOVEh_ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>All content involving Conor McGregor will be removed from IO Interactive's&nbsp;<em>Hitman World of Assassination&nbsp;</em>trilogy.</figcaption></figure><p>If you haven't been keeping up with McGregor's trial, a jury <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/clyrxl00151o" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">recently found him guilty</a> of assaulting a woman in a hotel in Dublin in 2018.</p>

<p>McGregor has been ordered to pay his victim Nikita Hand over&nbsp;€248,000 in damages, a result that Ms. Hand described as "a reminder that no matter how afraid you might be to speak up, you have a voice".</p>

<p>For his part, McGregor says he plans to appeal the verdict and that he's "focused on [his] future" for the time being.</p>

<p>The jury in McGregor's case heard a paramedic who examined Ms. Hand following the assault that they hadn't seen "someone so bruised" in a long time, while Ms. Hand herself said that she had spent over&nbsp;€4,000 on psychotherapy, pharmaceutical aid, and doctor's visits.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/hitman-world-of-assassination-conor-mcgregor-flames.jpg?itok=UafkeXqU 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/hitman-world-of-assassination-conor-mcgregor-flames.jpg?itok=0_0NiVGN 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Conor McGregor appeared as part of one of&nbsp;<em>Hitman 3</em>'s DLC packs.</figcaption></figure><p>Conor McGregor's appearance in the&nbsp;<em>Hitman&nbsp;</em>games came as part of&nbsp;<em>Hitman 3</em>'s&nbsp;<em>The Disruptor&nbsp;</em>DLC pack, which tasked Agent 47 with killing a martial arts fighter bearing McGregor's likeness.</p>

<p>Technically, the character in the game is never named as Conor McGregor, although he does clearly sport McGregor's face, as well as bearing a tattoo on his stomach that reads "McGregor".</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Penny Blood Director Sues Dangen Entertainment Over Unpaid Funds]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/penny-blood-director-dangen-entertainment-lawsuit</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/penny-blood-director-sues-dangen-entertainment-over-unpaid-funds.1044552/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/penny-blood-director-dangen-entertainment-lawsuit<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Penny Blood&nbsp;</em>director and Studio Wildrose CEO Matsuzo Machida has announced that he's filed a lawsuit against production company Dangen Entertainment and its former CEO Ben Judd over "unpaid production costs".</p>

<p>In <a href="https://www.studiowildrose.jp/post/%E8%A8%B4%E8%A8%9F%E6%8F%90%E8%B5%B7%E3%81%AE%E3%81%8A%E7%9F%A5%E3%82%89%E3%81%9B" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">an announcement</a> spotted by news platform <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/director-of-penny-blood-shadow-heartss-spiritual-successor-files-lawsuit-over-unpaid-funding-from-kickstarter-campaign/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Automaton Media</a>, Machida simply says that he's suing Judd and Dangen, naming Judd as a "producer" on&nbsp;<em>Penny Blood</em>'s Kickstarter and Dangen as part of the "campaign team".</p>

<p>Presumably, Dangen and Judd were supposed to help Studio Wildrose and Machida out with production costs on&nbsp;<em>Penny Blood</em>, but Machida seems to be alleging that this didn't happen. No further details about the lawsuit are provided in the announcement.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/penny-blood-lawsuit-dangen-entertainment-matthew.jpg?itok=d5BItrXp 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/penny-blood-lawsuit-dangen-entertainment-matthew.jpg?itok=OI6kh6ba 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Penny Blood</em>'s director is suing one of the companies involved in the game's Kickstarter campaign.</figcaption></figure><p>As a reminder,&nbsp;<em>Penny Blood&nbsp;</em>was one of two games that took part in a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/wild-arms-and-shadow-hearts-spiritual-successor-teaming-up-on-kickstarter" rel="nofollow">dual Kickstarter campaign back in 2022</a>, with the other being&nbsp;<em>Wild Arms&nbsp;</em>spiritual successor&nbsp;<em>Armed Fantasia</em>.</p>

<p>The campaign, which was launched by&nbsp;<em>Wild Arms&nbsp;</em>creator Akifumi Kaneko and&nbsp;<em>Shadow Hearts&nbsp;</em>lead Matsuzo Machida, aimed to get both games funded simultaneously, since the developers believed that it would be more difficult to fund them separately.</p>

<p><em>Penny Blood&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Armed Fantasia</em>'s dual Kickstarter asked for around $700,000 to bring both games to PC, and that goal was met within hours, with the campaign going on to <a href="https://www.siliconera.com/armed-fantasia-penny-blood-campaigns-close-successfully/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">make over $2.6 million</a> in total.</p>

<p>Despite this success, we still don't have release dates or specific release windows for either project. Notably, Kaneko and&nbsp;<em>Armed Fantasia&nbsp;</em>don't seem to have anything to do with the lawsuit brought against Dangen and Judd by Machida.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/armed-fantasia-kickstarter-penny-blood-lawsuit.jpg?itok=p2fGRf4C 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/armed-fantasia-kickstarter-penny-blood-lawsuit.jpg?itok=d-YnEypI 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Penny Blood</em>&nbsp;was Kickstarted alongside&nbsp;<em>Armed Fantasia</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>If you feel like you recognize Ben Judd and Dangen's name from somewhere, it may well be from <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dangen-entertainment-former-ceo-accused-preying-indie-developers" rel="nofollow">accusations leveled against Judd and Dangen back in 2019</a>, with Judd being accused of sexual misconduct and Dangen being accused of preying on indie studios.</p>

<p>Those allegations led to Judd being dismissed from his position with publishing firm Digital Development Management, as well as leading to his resignation from Japanese gaming festival BitSummit's board of directors.</p>

<p>All of this is to say that Machida's lawsuit isn't the first time Judd and Dangen have been accused of foul play when it comes to indie developers. We'll have to wait and see what, if anything, the lawsuit yields.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>