<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 04:22:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Catan Masterpiece Kickstarter Fully Funded Within An Hour, Promoting Bespoke Game Components]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/catan-masterpiece-kickstarter-fully-funded-within-hour-promoting-bespoke-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/catan-masterpiece-kickstarter-fully-funded-within-an-hour-promoting-bespoke-game-components.1117836/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/catan-masterpiece-kickstarter-fully-funded-within-hour-promoting-bespoke-game<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="page-content">
  
          
      
<article role="article">

  
    

  
  <div>
      <div><p>A new <em>Catan</em> Kickstarter campaign has gone live. Fanroll LLC's new <em>Catan Masterpiece</em> campaign isn't for a revised board game edition but for a series of artisanal, bespoke game components in the vein of <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/catan-3d-expansion-and-dawn-of-humankind-announced" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Catan 3D</em></a>. The campaign was fully funded in an hour.</p>

<h2>The Catan Masterpiece Kickstarter Campaign</h2>

<p>According to the Kickstarter page, the <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/ultimatecatan/catan-masterpiece-series/description" rel="nofollow"><em>Catan Masterpiece</em></a> campaign started as a premium dice set. This escalated to the studio wanting to reimagine every element of the beloved board game. Those reimagined elements include game pieces made of wood, metal, resin, and cut gemstones.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/catan-masterpiece-ancient-civilization-pieces.jpg?itok=bgJO1-GM 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/catan-masterpiece-ancient-civilization-pieces.jpg?itok=cQUfq52_ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>That is what you are backing with this Kickstarter. Not a premium version of the <em>Catan</em> board game, but individual components made with pristine materials. Backers have tons of options from resin or painted wooden dice to metallic or resin Robber pieces to gemstone hex tiles. There are even three sets of player pieces: Metal Classic, Plastic Civilizations, and Metal Civilizations.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>The CATAN Masterpiece Series is a tribute to the game that has brought joy and camaraderie to so many. It's a celebration of the countless memories made around the table, the friendships forged through friendly competition, and the sheer excitement of watching your settlements and cities come to life.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The different pledge tiers for the Catan Masterpiece series are as follows:</p>

<ul><li>Explorer for $25: Your choice of two plastic Ancient Civilization pieces and one of eight plastic pins</li>
	<li>Harbormaster for $69: Everything in the Explorer tier, a full set of nine Ports, a wooden dice set, and your choice of resin Robber and two of eight pins.</li>
	<li>Traditionalist for $99: Everything in the Harbormaster tier, a set of Classic Metal player pieces, a set of Sharp-edge Dice, your choice of Metal Robber, and three of eight pins</li>
	<li>Architect for $149: Your choice of four plastic Ancient Civilizations, one Metal Ancient Civilization, a set of Nine Ports, a set of Sharp-edge Dice, a Gemstone Robber, and four of eight pins</li>
	<li>Woodcutter for $299: A set of wood hexes, wood sea frames, Acryllic number discs, everything in Architect tier, and five of eight pins.</li>
	<li>Artisan for $499. A set of Sparkle Resin hexes, Sparkle Resin sea frames, metal number discs, everything in the Architect tier, and six of eight pins.</li>
	<li>Stonecutter for $749: A set of gemstone hexes, Sparkle Resin sea frames, metal number discs, everything in the Architect tier, and seven of eight pins.</li>
	<li>Noble for $999: a set of gemstone hexes, Sparkle Resin sea frames, metal number discs, all Ancient Civilizations, a set of Metal Classic Player Pieces, a set of Nine Ports, a set of Painted Wood and Sharp-edge dice, a Resin Robber, a Metal Robber, a Resin Robber, and all eight pins.</li>
</ul><p>For those wanting a more specialized bundle, the individual pieces can be purchased as separate add-ons once you have backed the project.</p>

<p>At time of writing the <em>Catan Masterpiece</em> Kickstarter has raised&nbsp;$286,318, more than five times its initial funding goal of $50,000. The campaign concludes on March 21.</p>
</div>


<div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div>

    </div>

</article>

  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>