<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 15:24:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tencent Added to US List of Companies Allegedly Aiding Chinese Military]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tencent-us-dod-list-chinese-military</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tencent-added-to-us-list-of-companies-allegedly-aiding-chinese-military.1076034/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tencent-us-dod-list-chinese-military<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The US Department of Defense has added Chinese gaming giant to a list of companies allegedly aiding the Chinese military, a decision that Tencent itself calls a "mistake".</p>

<p>According to a Reuters <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-adds-tencent-catl-list-chinese-firms-allegedly-aiding-beijings-military-2025-01-06/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">report</a>, Tencent was added to the DOD's list alongside battery manufacturer CATL, causing the shares of both companies to drop. Tencent's stocks fell by 7.3%, while CATL's dropped by just 2.8%.</p>

<p>The Reuters report goes on to say that Tencent responded to the DOD's decision by calling it a "mistake" and suggesting that its business would be unaffected by the move. The Chinese gaming giant also suggested it would begin legal proceedings if necessary.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tencent-us-list-chinese-military-epic.jpg?itok=k9rKb54p 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tencent-us-list-chinese-military-epic.jpg?itok=00MChtj- 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Tencent has its fingers in plenty of pies, including&nbsp;<em>Fortnite&nbsp;</em>studio Epic Games.</figcaption></figure><p>As Reuters points out, the list, which is officially known as the Section 1260H list, doesn't prohibit Tencent from doing business in the US, so it's unlikely to have any material impact on the company's dealings in the short term.</p>

<p>However, having a presence on the list can sometimes serve as a blow to a company's reputation in the US, which could prevent other companies from wanting to do business with Tencent.</p>

<p>Given just <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ubisoft-bosses-tencent-private-buyout-report" rel="nofollow">how many pies</a> Tencent has <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tencent-techland-majority-stakeholder" rel="nofollow">its fingers in</a> across <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tencent-and-sony-buy-over-30-shares-in-from-software" rel="nofollow">the gaming industry</a>, it's unlikely that there will be a mass exodus of studios breaking their agreements with the Chinese gaming giant, but this still likely won't come as pleasing news to the company.</p>

<p>As for what Tencent is up to outside of its addition to this list, the studio is busy working with developers both Western and non-Western on a number of different projects.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tencent-monster-hunter-outlanders.jpg?itok=RZb13lX1 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tencent-monster-hunter-outlanders.jpg?itok=6ZHFnuW8 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Tencent has plenty of projects on the go.</figcaption></figure><p>The gaming giant is currently working with Capcom on <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-outlanders-mobile-rpg" rel="nofollow">mobile RPG&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Outlanders</em></a>, and it's also behind the extremely&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/light-of-motiram-announced-tencent-horizon" rel="nofollow"><em>Horizon</em>-coded&nbsp;<em>Light of Motiram</em></a>, which was unveiled in full back in November.</p>

<p>Tencent is also attracting talent like&nbsp;<em>Dragon's Dogma 2&nbsp;</em>director Hideaki Itsuno, who <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hideaki-itsuno-lightspeed-studios" rel="nofollow">joined subsidiary LightSpeed Studios</a> recently (but not the branch that's currently working on&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/final-fantasy-xiv-mobile-revealed" rel="nofollow"><em>Final Fantasy XIV Mobile</em>, another Tencent project</a>).</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Announces Helldivers and Horizon Movies, Plus Ghost of Tsushima Anime]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sony-helldivers-horizon-movies-ghost-of-tsushima-anime</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-announces-helldivers-and-horizon-movies-plus-ghost-of-tsushima-anime.1075986/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sony-helldivers-horizon-movies-ghost-of-tsushima-anime<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Sony has revealed three major new visual media projects based on some of its most celebrated franchises, as well as a release window for the upcoming second season of&nbsp;<em>The Last of Us</em>.</p>

<p>During its CES 2025 presentation, Sony revealed that it's working on a live-action movie based on&nbsp;<em>Horizon Zero Dawn</em>, with PlayStation exec Asad Qizilbash confirming that the project is in its "early stages".</p>

<p>Additionally, we're also getting a live-action movie based on&nbsp;<em>Helldivers 2</em>, which will, of course, be created in conjunction with Sony Pictures. Let's hope this one doesn't <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/helldivers-2-pc-playstation-backtrack" rel="nofollow">require you to create a PlayStation ID</a> before you can watch it.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/helldivers-2-movie-sony.jpg?itok=VxpFye2T 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/helldivers-2-movie-sony.jpg?itok=JNXXhjJG 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Helldivers 2&nbsp;</em>is getting its own movie, as is Guerrilla's&nbsp;<em>Horizon Zero Dawn</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>It remains to be seen what creative direction these two movies will take; they're both likely fairly early on in production, so it might be a while before we hear from them again. Will&nbsp;<em>Helldivers 2&nbsp;</em>be more or less subtle than its obvious inspiration&nbsp;<em>Starship Troopers</em>? We'll have to wait and see.</p>

<p>It's not just those two that are getting adaptations, either. Sony has also revealed that an <a href="https://www.crunchyroll.com/news/announcements/2025/1/7/ghost-of-tsushima-legends-anime-series-2027-crunchyroll" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">anime adaptation</a> of&nbsp;<em>Ghost of Tsushima&nbsp;</em>is in production, with a tentative release window of 2027.</p>

<p>The anime is being developed in conjunction with Sony subsidiaries Aniplex and Crunchyroll, and it'll be directed by Takanobu Mizuno, perhaps best known for his work on the&nbsp;<em>Star Wars: Visions&nbsp;</em>short film "The Duel".</p>

<p>More specifically, the project will apparently adapt the&nbsp;<em>Ghost of Tsushima: Legends&nbsp;</em>multiplayer experience. It's not entirely clear how Sony and Crunchyroll are planning to go about doing this, though.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ghost-of-tsushima-legends-anime-sony.jpg?itok=YupKZCG0 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ghost-of-tsushima-legends-anime-sony.jpg?itok=sU1D6dFA 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Ghost of Tsushima: Legends&nbsp;</em>is getting its very own anime adaptation.</figcaption></figure><p>Additionally, the second season of Sony and HBO's&nbsp;<em>The Last of Us&nbsp;</em>adaptation will premiere in April, although Sony stopped short of revealing exactly what day we can expect the new season to drop.</p>

<p>Things aren't standing still in the worlds of the games these projects are based on, either. <i>Ghost of Tsushima&nbsp;</i>developer Sucker Punch recently announced a followup <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ghost-of-yotei-ghost-of-tsushima-followup-2025" rel="nofollow">by the name of&nbsp;<em>Ghost of Yotei</em></a>, and&nbsp;<em>The Last of Us&nbsp;</em>studio Naughty Dog <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/naughty-dog-intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet" rel="nofollow">unveiled its next game</a> during last year's Game Awards, too.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ballooning Call of Duty Budgets Revealed, Black Ops Cold War Cost $700m]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ballooning-call-of-duty-budgets</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ballooning-call-of-duty-budgets-revealed-black-ops-cold-war-cost-700m.1075950/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ballooning-call-of-duty-budgets<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A court document filed by&nbsp;<em>Call of Duty&nbsp;</em>publisher Activision has revealed just how astronomically huge the budgets for the first-person shooter franchise can get, with even games from a few years ago reaching hundreds of millions of dollars.</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/call-of-duty-budgets-development-costs-black-ops-modern-warfare" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">report</a> by Game File, Stephen Totilo points to a court filing in which Activision's Patrick Kelly outlines budget figures for three&nbsp;<em>Call of Duty&nbsp;</em>games, namely&nbsp;<em>Black Ops 3</em>, 2019's&nbsp;<em>Modern Warfare&nbsp;</em>reboot, and&nbsp;<em>Black Ops Cold War</em>.</p>

<p>According to those numbers,&nbsp;<em>Black Ops 3&nbsp;</em>cost Activision more than $450 million to make across its lifespan, while&nbsp;<em>Modern Warfare&nbsp;</em>cost $640 million and&nbsp;<em>Black Ops Cold War&nbsp;</em>set the company back a staggering $700 million.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/call-of-duty-budgets-modern-warfare.jpg?itok=PtzHJ9fM 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/call-of-duty-budgets-modern-warfare.jpg?itok=g-yjSCa- 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Call of Duty: Modern Warfare</em>'s budget broke the $600 million mark, and it's not even Activision's most expensive&nbsp;<em>Call of Duty&nbsp;</em>game.</figcaption></figure><p>It's worth bearing in mind that Kelly's figures refer to the development costs for these games' entire life cycles, not just the initial cost to make them.&nbsp;<em>Call of Duty&nbsp;</em>is, after all, a live-service franchise, and money must be spent to create content after the games are initially released.</p>

<p>Every&nbsp;<em>Call of Duty&nbsp;</em>game also sells tens of millions of copies, so it's very likely Activision is recouping its development budget and then some for each game.</p>

<p>In fact, Kelly points to sales figures for each of the games listed;&nbsp;<em>Black Ops 3&nbsp;</em>sold 43 million copies,&nbsp;<em>Modern Warfare&nbsp;</em>shifted 41 million, and&nbsp;<em>Black Ops Cold War&nbsp;</em>managed to sell 30 million units over its lifetime.</p>

<p>Obviously, Kelly's numbers don't include the most recent&nbsp;<em>Call of Duty&nbsp;</em>game,&nbsp;<em>Black Ops 6</em>, but we do know that it apparently&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/call-of-duty-series-sales-black-ops-6-launch" rel="nofollow">enjoyed the franchise's biggest launch yet</a>, so let's just say it's unlikely the budget is lower than&nbsp;<em>Black Ops Cold War</em>'s was.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/call-of-duty-budgets-black-ops-6.jpg?itok=ckIxWp3u 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/call-of-duty-budgets-black-ops-6.jpg?itok=YJzdA8-8 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</em>'s budget is likely to be even higher than its predecessors'.</figcaption></figure><p>Most major publishers and developers don't publicly reveal their budgets to this degree, so we don't have a lot of points of comparison. However, Totilo points to what he calls a "poorly redacted court filing" from 2023, which puts&nbsp;<em>The Last of Us Part 2</em>'s development cost at about $220 million.</p>

<p>Now, obviously,&nbsp;<em>The Last of Us Part 2&nbsp;</em>isn't a live-service game, so its budget will naturally be smaller. Still, this just goes to show the insane amounts of money&nbsp;Activision is spending on each&nbsp;<em>Call of Duty&nbsp;</em>game, especially compared to other industry tentpole releases.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>