<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 03:45:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Paizo Announces Pathfinder Lost Omens Shining Kingdoms and Treasure Vault: Remastered]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/paizo-announces-pathfinder-lost-omens-shining-kingdoms-and-treasure-vault-remastered</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/paizo-announces-pathfinder-lost-omens-shining-kingdoms-and-treasure-vault-remastered.1075359/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/paizo-announces-pathfinder-lost-omens-shining-kingdoms-and-treasure-vault-remastered<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Paizo is bringing two new sourcebooks to <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/games/pathfinder" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Pathfinder Second Edition</em></a>. The largest fantasy TTRPG competitor to <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/dungeons-dragons" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em></a> has two books arriving in the first half of 2025. One is a remaster of an older book. The second is a supplement: <em>Pathfinder Lost Omens Shining Kingdoms</em>.</p>

<h2>The <em>Pathfinder Lost Omens Shining Kingdoms</em> Announcement</h2>

<p>According to the <a href="https://paizo.com/products/btq08pw5/discuss?Pathfinder-Lost-Omens-Shining-Kingdoms#tabs" rel="nofollow">official store page</a>, <em>Pathfinder Lost Omens Shining Kingdoms</em> will focus on six key nations of the Inner Sea. The aptly named Shining Kingdoms are lands full of knightly orders, proud ancient cultures, and deadly court intrigue.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pathfinder-andoran-artwork.jpg?itok=IjOv9aKp 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pathfinder-andoran-artwork.jpg?itok=K170xqoC 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>This new supplement for <em>Pathfinder Second Edition</em> will delve into these six nations.</p>

<p>Andoran is the bastion of democratic freedom. Druma is the kingdom's trade hub. The Five Kings Mountains are the home of the fractured dwarven kingdoms. Galt is the land perpetually wracked with violent revolutions. Kyonin is the homeland of the elves cloaked in illusion. Last is Taldor, the ossified remnants of one of the Inner Sea's greatest empires.</p>

<p>Each region in <em>Pathfinder Lost Omens Shining Kingdoms</em> will present new player options. These include new archetypes, equipment, magic items, spells, and animal companions. Players can also learn more about each region's factions such as Andoran's Eagle Knights or the Shieldwrought Striders of the Five Kings Mountains.</p>

<p>For DMs, the supplement will include a bestiary of monsters and a fold-out poster map to serve as a centerpiece for a Shining Kingdoms campaign.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pathfinder-treasure-vault-remastered-book.jpg?itok=551JA1Pu 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pathfinder-treasure-vault-remastered-book.jpg?itok=A6hKkZmi 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The second supplement is <a href="https://paizo.com/products/btq08pvw?Pathfinder-Treasure-Vault" rel="nofollow"><em>Pathfinder Treasure Vault Remastered</em></a>. As the name implies, this is a reprinting of the Treasure Vault supplement with its terms and gameplay revised to align with <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/pathfinder-remaster-previewed-by-paizo-inc" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Pathfinder Second Edition Remastered</a>. If you already own the original version, it will remain compatible with this new version of the game. However, if you want the most up to date version, the option is here.</p>

<p>Both <em>Pathfinder Lost Omens Shining Kingdoms</em> and P<em>athfinder Treasure Vault Remastered</em> will release in June 2025. Shining Kingdoms is available at an MSRP of $59.99. Treasure Vault Remastered is available at an MSRP of $64.99.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>