<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:19:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MindsEye Will Reportedly Drop Publisher IO Interactive Soon]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/mindseye-dropping-io-interactive-report</link>
            <guid>1420837</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A new report has emerged which claims that poorly-received actioner <em>MindsEye </em>could be about to drop its publisher, <em>Hitman </em>studio IO Interactive, with publishing duties to be handled by developer Build a Rocket Boy in future.</p><p>That's according to Insider Gaming's <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/build-a-rocket-boy-io-interactive/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Tom Henderson</a>, who cites "sources close to the impending news" and says that the decision is Build a Rocket Boy's rather than IO Interactive's.</p><p>According to Henderson, Build a Rocket Boy wants to "gain more control over its future" and "bring its publishing in-house", as well as continuing to work on updates and patches for <em>MindsEye </em>to improve the player experience. Apparently, that's not something the developer wants IO Interactive to be involved in.</p><figure role="group">
<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/mindseye-dropping-io-interactive-publisher-shooting.jpg?itok=SHZ2yNHV 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/mindseye-dropping-io-interactive-publisher-shooting.jpg?itok=UeKOv7DX 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>
<figcaption><em>MindsEye </em>will reportedly drop IO Interactive as its publisher soon.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>As part of the impending publisher split (which, it's worth noting, still hasn't been officially confirmed yet), <em>MindsEye</em>'s upcoming <em>Hitman </em>crossover, which was revealed <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/summer-game-fest-2025-recap" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="45995c50-0a0e-42c9-88b2-fd8ecef35756" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">during last year's Summer Game Fest</a>, will apparently be canceled.</p><p>Even if the decision to split with IO Interactive isn't being driven by the <em>Hitman </em>studio, I can't imagine the Danish publisher is too cut up about it. Back in September, IO <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/io-interactive-mindseye-third-party-publishing" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="d1ad39f7-38ad-44f2-9a4e-5aff2e0ed71d" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">indicated it might be done with third-party publishing</a> after <em>MindsEye</em>, so this is probably a boon as far as IO is concerned.</p><p>In case you need a reminder, <em>MindsEye </em>launched back in June last year, and its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/mindseye-launch-messy" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="090d2e26-517c-4b1d-81d8-0c4c40228804" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">launch was chaotic, to say the least</a>. Players demanded refunds within hours of picking the game up, and sponsorships with streamers were pulled at the last second.</p><p>Developer Build a Rocket Boy subsequently <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/mindseye-build-a-rocket-boy-layoffs-report" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="cc20a09e-a602-4466-a53f-4fb3ccf68d58" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">laid off a wave of employees</a> just a few days after the game's release, and a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/mindseye-failure-new-report" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="59a77c58-1d39-4df1-bb46-f97e1f2b82f7" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">BBC report in October</a> saw former BARB staff accusing the developer of excessive crunch and having "no coherent direction" during development.</p>
<p><em>MindsEye </em>is available to check out right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3265250/MindsEye/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/mindseye/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-GB/games/store/mindseye/9PJ9WXK3V9FN" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Xbox Series X|S</a>, and you can read our review of the game from back at launch <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/mindseye-review-mideye" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="43daca71-9368-49cb-b5cd-71e0fd646ef8" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">right here</a>.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/mindseye-dropping-io-interactive-report]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zenless Zone Zero Version 2.6 Brings Two New Agents and More in February]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/zenless-zone-zero-version-2-6-release-date</link>
            <guid>1420801</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The release date for <em>Zenless Zone Zero </em>Version 2.6 has been officially revealed, and you can look forward to new Agents, an exciting new rhythm-based adventure, and much more.</p><p>Following on from <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/zenless-zone-zero-version-25-release-date" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="744db640-1a04-4b35-93b7-05bfbb2fae4f" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">December's Version 2.5</a>, <em>Zenless Zone Zero </em>Version 2.6 will arrive on February 6th, and it'll revolve around the in-game Angels of Delusion musical group, which is preparing for its first live performance "under the guidance of an enigmatic vocal coach".</p><p>You'll be helping the Angels of Delusion with their "training schedules and social media activities", participating in a new rhythm-driven gameplay mode as you work through the events of the so-called "A Harmony of Delusions" centerpiece.</p><figure role="group">
<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/zenless-zone-zero-version-2.6-release-date-angels-of-delusion.jpg?itok=HtpAB9zW 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/zenless-zone-zero-version-2.6-release-date-angels-of-delusion.jpg?itok=IPBC-Cwg 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>
<figcaption><em>Zenless Zone Zero </em>Version 2.6 will have you helping to manage the Angels of Delusion.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Two new Agents will make their debut in <em>Zenless Zone Zero </em>Version 2.6. The first, Sunna, is an S-Rank Physical Support Agent who can grant big buffs to party members and facilitate quicker switching of characters with her Ultimate.</p><p>She's joined by Aria, the lead vocalist of the Angels of Delusion, who's an Ether Anomaly Agent with two distinct forms. Unlike Sunna, Aria is all about dealing big damage, so if you like to tackle problems head-on, she's your fighter.</p><p>Reruns for Yixuan and Yuzuha will be appearing as part of this Version cycle's banners, and the Bangboo Biggest Fan will also be added to the game as part of this update, complete with an HP restoration ability and an attack boost around Angels of Delusion.</p><p>A number of other bonuses and activities, including a chance to earn Polychromes for logging in and completing daily challenges, will be introduced as part of Version 2.6 as well. Suffice it to say that it's all go in <em>Zenless Zone Zero </em>land.</p>
<p><em>Zenless Zone Zero </em>is available to <a href="https://zenless.hoyoverse.com/en-us/main" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">play right now for free</a> on PC, PS5, Xbox Series X|S, and mobile devices. Version 2.6, "Encore for an Old Dream", arrives on all platforms on February 6th.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/zenless-zone-zero-version-2-6-release-date]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>