<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 12:30:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Safe In Our World Launches Industry-First Gaming Mental Health Accreditation]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/safe-in-our-world-mental-health-star-accreditation</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/safe-in-our-world-launches-industry-first-gaming-mental-health-accreditation.1273554/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Gaming mental health charity Safe In Our World has launched the Mental Health Star Accreditation, an industry-first method to help gaming industry companies and studios shore up their efforts when it comes to employee mental health.</p>

<p>As revealed in a press release, the Mental Health Star Accreditation is "designed to provide companies with the opportunity to achieve a mark of excellence in workplace wellbeing", something that's sorely needed in today's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/spiders-layoffs" rel="nofollow">uncertain</a>, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/supermassive-games-layoffs-directive-8020-delayed" rel="nofollow">volatile</a>, and often <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/xbox-revenue-up-microsoft-2025" rel="nofollow">seemingly cruel</a> industry.</p>

<p>If a company chooses to undergo the process of accreditation, it will first be audited by Safe In Our World; the charity says it'll carry out a "company-wide audit of mental health policies, practices, culture, and sentiment".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/safe-in-our-world-mental-health-accreditation-star.jpg?itok=ymPCBpfD 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/safe-in-our-world-mental-health-accreditation-star.jpg?itok=ajXDgoBG 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Safe In Our World's new Mental Health Star accreditation aims to bolster companies' efforts to support mental health initiatives.</figcaption></figure><p>Using the data gathered from that audit, Safe In Our World then puts together a report that will tell a company what it's doing well to support its employees' mental health, as well as what could be done better.</p>

<p>If a company successfully completes the accreditation, they'll be awarded with one of three tiers: Dedicated, Accomplished, or Outstanding, depending on how satisfied Safe In Our World is with the company's performance.</p>

<p>Each accreditation lasts three years and comes complete with "annual check-ins and support" from the charity, as well as badges and other media assets for companies to display on their platforms to show off their achievement.</p>

<p>Companies that don't succeed in attaining the accreditation will be provided with a "thorough and detailed report" regarding why they didn't make the cut, as well as "practical advice and resources to aid improvement". They'll also be able to re-apply whenever they like.</p>




<p>Mental health remains a serious issue when it comes to the gaming industry, especially when <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/latest-microsoft-layoff-wave-king-zenimax" rel="nofollow">even employees of massive gaming corporations</a> could find themselves in the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/respawn-layoffs-ea-cuts-titanfall-game" rel="nofollow">layoff firing line</a> with very little warning.</p>

<p>We'll have to wait and see whether the Mental Health Star Accreditation is adopted en masse by the industry, but if you ask me, it's a much-needed step in the right direction for protecting employee mental health. Stay tuned for more.</p>

<div data-embed-button="embed_block" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:block_content.full" data-entity-type="block_content" data-entity-uuid="82abdc24-478f-4263-8533-238a8b6d536a" data-langcode="en"><hr><p><em>TechRaptor has partnered with Safe in Our World, a charity focused on mental health awareness in gaming. We joined their LevelUp program in order to offer more resources and support to all of our team members. <a href="https://techraptor.net/blog/mental-health-techraptor-safe-in-our-world" data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="3644af35-3b43-4c2d-ac27-006c405c94db" rel="nofollow">Visit our blog to learn more</a>, or <a href="https://safeinourworld.org/donate/" rel="nofollow">donate to their cause</a>.</em></p>

<hr></div>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/safe-in-our-world-mental-health-star-accreditation]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Critical Role Announces Campaign 4 Setting Through Community Solved ARG]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/critical-role-announces-campaign-4-setting-through-community-solved-arg</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/critical-role-announces-campaign-4-setting-through-community-solved-arg.1273362/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Earlier this month, <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/critical-role-announces-brennan-lee-mulligan-as-campaign-4-dm-release-date-in-october" rel="nofollow">Critical Role not only announced the release date of their hotly anticipated Campaign 4</a>, October 4th, but also that Matthew Mercer would be joining the table this time around as a player and not as the GM. The role of GM would go to <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="55a80c6c-ea7c-4151-9523-d332db6f6cd5" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/interviews/how-brennan-lee-mulligan-created-never-stop-blowing-up-love-letter-to-80s" rel="nofollow">Brennan Lee Mulligan</a>, and Campaign 4 would be set in a completely new setting.</p>



<p>Last Thursday at the bottom of the regular Beacon and Critical Role newsletter an interesting image was included of a five by five square of letters, clicking on which would lead you to join the Beacon Discord and access the #what-do-you-seek channel.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/critical-role-campaign-4-setting-5x5-letters.jpg?itok=Y4MBwSAS 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/critical-role-campaign-4-setting-5x5-letters.jpg?itok=aDrTvph2 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>This led puzzle hunters down the rabbit hole to share word of this ARG, hunt for any other clues, and ultimately the answer. This puzzle was solved earlier today and led to the discovery of a secret page on the Critical Role website that contained a password field, and the password itself.</p>

<p>Travelling to <a href="https://critrole.com/unseal" rel="nofollow">https://critrole.com/unseal</a> and entering the password ARAMAN (in all capital letters) eager fans can get access to a 20 second recording of Brennan Lee Mulligan setting the scene for Campaign 4. The audio is as follows:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>"Within the world of Araman, there exists a growing darkness in the shadow of revolution. Seventy years ago were the Shapers cut down, those seven lords of creation that saw fit to cast their children into ruin and shadown forever..."</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Accompanying this audio file is the date: <strong>August 21st, 2025 10am PT</strong></p>

<p>There are plenty of questions left to answer about Campaign 4 including who will be joining Matt and Brennan at the table, and what game system will be used. One or both of those might be answers on August 21st.</p>

<h2>The Critical Role ARG Solution</h2>

<p>If you're interested in learning what it took to solve the clues and reach this conclusion then be sure to <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1wXLH3dyDq0ApX8YQ8YSNMEDW8kZApomzRxeabTlKYqQ/edit?tab=t.0#heading=h.9j1gfaluj4mp" rel="nofollow">head over to the large Google Doc </a>that was used to collect all possible answers and crack the conundrum in under a week.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Andrew has written Video Game and Entertainment news, reviews, and guides for 10+ years. As Senior Content Manager, he assists in creating and editing… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/andrew-stretch">More about Andrew</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/critical-role-announces-campaign-4-setting-through-community-solved-arg]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>