<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 23:06:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DrivethruRPG AI-Content Filter Lets Users Curate Their Shopping Experience]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/drivethrurpg-ai-content-filter-lets-users-curate-their-shopping-experience</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/drivethrurpg-ai-content-filter-lets-users-curate-their-shopping-experience.1029216/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/drivethrurpg-ai-content-filter-lets-users-curate-their-shopping-experience<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A DrivethruRPG AI-Content filter has gone live. The world's largest digital TTRPG distribution has implemented a new browsing option, allowing consumers to search for games and supplements made by human hands.</p>

<h2>The DrivethruRPG AI-Content Filter Announcement</h2>

<p>According to an update on <a href="https://help.drivethrurpg.com/hc/en-us/articles/26794784634007-Customer-Experience-with-AI-Generated-Content-Within-Titles#h_01J97G88WDYDR5K4EXEH739R99" rel="nofollow">their official website</a>, the DrivethruRPG AI-Content filter lets users toggle how much content made by generative AI they see on the platform.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/drivethrurpg-ai-content-filter-screenshot.jpg?itok=oPGuF4nO 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/drivethrurpg-ai-content-filter-screenshot.jpg?itok=A0JdXQD9 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>In a User Account Settings under Additional Preferences, users can choose one of three options under "Creation Method." Handcrafted is for those who want games made by flesh and blood human beings. The worldbuilding, the text, the mechanics, and the artwork; all human-made.</p>

<p>Conversely, the Contains AI-Generated Content option is for those who are fine with products containing material made from generative AI programs. The product in question cannot be entirely AI-generated due to an official content policy by the platform. The third option, Creation Method Not Chosen, is the default.</p>

<p>If you are using the more recent version of DrivethruRPG, the AI-content filter is a simple on/off toggle alongside adult content.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/drivethrurpg-ai-content-filter-toggle-screenshot.jpg?itok=UBVkc0Ls 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/drivethrurpg-ai-content-filter-toggle-screenshot.jpg?itok=BJTaCeLX 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The use of generative AI content has been a highly controversial subject in all areas of the arts. This is due to its current use across multiple tech companies <a href="https://hbr.org/2023/04/generative-ai-has-an-intellectual-property-problem">actively stealing</a> work from users to train their programs.</p>

<p>This practice has also led to widespread energy usage and resource drainage. This is exemplified by Microsoft negotiating a deal to r<a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/09/20/nx-s1-5120581/three-mile-island-nuclear-power-plant-microsoft-ai">eopen Three Mile Island</a> in the US as a power source for their own cloud and AI power usage.</p>

<p>It is a subject that hasn't just lead to greater scrutiny of material used in large productions, and it has lead to several publishers and creatives to take stances on their use.</p>

<p><em>Tales of the Valiant</em> designer and publisher Kobold Press <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/kobold-press-ceo-says-no-to-generative-ai" rel="noopener" target="_blank">is proudly anti-AI</a>. Hasbro CEO Chris Cocks has <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/hasbro-ceo-chris-cocks-expresses-support-of-ai-in-dungeons-dragons" rel="noopener" target="_blank">vocalized support</a> of the use of AI in <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/dungeons-dragons" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em></a>, which lead to their communications director, Greg Tito, leaving the company. And recently the streaming service platform Netflix has announced they are <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/netflix-generative-ai-vp" rel="noopener" target="_blank">going all in</a> on generative AI for their gaming division.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>