<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 15:27:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 Sales Hit 5m, New Content on the Way]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/clair-obscur-expedition-33-sales-5m-update</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/clair-obscur-expedition-33-sales-hit-5m-new-content-on-the-way.1319818/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer Sandfall Interactive has announced a brand new sales milestone for turn-based indie RPG&nbsp;<em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em>, and there's a big new update in the works as well.</p>

<p>As revealed in a new <a href="https://www.expedition33.com/post/thank-you-from-sandfall-interactive" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">blog post</a>,&nbsp;<em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33&nbsp;</em>has hit five million sales since launching earlier this year. That means it's picked up another 1.7 million sales <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/clair-obscur-expedition-33-sales-3-3m-33-days" rel="nofollow">since May</a>, which is very impressive indeed for a game that doesn't have a huge studio backing it (no shade, Kepler).</p>

<p>In order to celebrate the new sales milestone, Sandfall says it's working on a huge new update that will bring lots of new content to the RPG, so if you've been hurting for stuff to do post-game, this might be the one for you.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/clair-obscur-expedition-33-sales-5m-maelle_0.jpg?itok=kMu-0r8e 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/clair-obscur-expedition-33-sales-5m-maelle_0.jpg?itok=b2Gs9-Ro 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33&nbsp;</em>has sold very well indeed.</figcaption></figure><p>The new update will, according to Sandfall, bring a brand new area in which you'll find "new enemy encounters and surprises to discover", as well as new challenging late-game bosses to battle.</p>

<p>You'll also find new costumes for each member of&nbsp;<em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em>, so you can finally take them out of those stereotypically French outfits from the base game (although if you don't, I won't blame you).</p>

<p>All of this is in addition to new localizations for the game, which will bring its total number of supported languages to 19, as well as "more to come", which is rather tantalizing.</p>

<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em>, it's a turn-based RPG developed by French indie studio Sandfall Interactive, and it revolves around the titular Expedition 33's attempt to defeat the Paintress in order to prevent the culling of everyone of a certain age each year.</p>




<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1903340/Clair_Obscur_Expedition_33/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/clair-obscur--expedition-33/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/clair-obscur-expedition-33/9PPT8K6GQHRZ/0010" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>, and you can read our very own Erren's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/clair-obscur-expedition-33-review-french-revolution" rel="nofollow">review of the game here</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/clair-obscur-expedition-33-sales-5m-update]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[System Shock 2 Set to Be Delisted from PC Storefronts This Week]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/system-shock-2-pc-delisting</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/system-shock-2-set-to-be-delisted-from-pc-storefronts-this-week.1319776/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Specialist retro gaming studio Nightdive has announced that the original PC version of&nbsp;<em>System Shock 2&nbsp;</em>will be delisted later this week, but it's not all bad news.</p>

<p>In <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/238210/view/503964319779651936" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">a post</a> on Steam, Nightdive says the original 1999 release will be delisted from PC storefronts on October 10th, and that's not just Steam, either; it's also GOG and anywhere else the original version of the game is available.</p>

<p>However, if you do want to play the 1999 version rather than Nightdive's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/system-shock-2-25th-anniversary-remaster-release-date" rel="nofollow">recent remaster</a>, all is not lost. If you pick up the remaster, you'll magically see the original appear in your library as well, and if you already own the remaster, you'll get a copy of the original version free of charge.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/system-shock-2-pc-delisting-citadel_5.jpg?itok=iJmmxeCl 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/system-shock-2-pc-delisting-citadel_5.jpg?itok=57KYOyky 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>System Shock 2&nbsp;</em>will be delisted from storefronts this week.</figcaption></figure><p>Of course, if you did buy the game before its delisting, you'll be able to continue downloading and playing it whenever you like, so if you do want to grab the original without picking up the remaster, you've still got a couple of days to do so.</p>

<p>If you've somehow made it this far without ever hearing about&nbsp;<em>System Shock 2</em>, it's a hugely influential first-person shooter released in 1999 by Ken Levine's Irrational Games alongside legendary immersive sim studio Looking Glass.</p>

<p>The game takes place on the Von Braun, where an unknown infection is ripping its way through the ship. Naturally, it's up to you to figure out where this infection is coming from and why it's happening.</p>

<p>Gameplay-wise,&nbsp;<em>System Shock 2</em>&nbsp;is an immersive sim-style RPG shooter in which you can specialize in various different disciplines to help you explore the Von Braun and battle its many hostile inhabitants. You can hack your way through problems, specialize in combat, or take any number of other approaches.</p>




<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>System Shock 2&nbsp;</em>right now on PC via both <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/238210/System_Shock_2_1999/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/system_shock_2" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">GOG</a>, and the remaster is also available across several platforms. You can check out our <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/system-shock-2-25th-anniversary-remaster-review-definitive-version-of-all-timer" rel="nofollow">review of the remaster right here</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/system-shock-2-pc-delisting]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>