<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 01:43:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Asmodee Acquires the Zombicide IP from Board Game Publisher CMON]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/asmodee-acquires-zombicide-ip-from-board-game-publisher-cmon</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/asmodee-acquires-the-zombicide-ip-from-board-game-publisher-cmon.1214970/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/asmodee-acquires-zombicide-ip-from-board-game-publisher-cmon<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Asmodee is buying the <em>Zombicide</em> IP. The <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/asmodee-rebrands-for-30th-anniversary-with-inspired-by-players-label" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">recently rebranded</a> tabletop publisher has initiated a new series of strategic acquisitions of prominent board game IPs and studios. Its first most recent purchase is of the co-op zombie game series owned by CMON.</p>



<p>According to a report from <a href="https://boardgamewire.com/index.php/2025/06/10/asmodee-buys-zombicide-ip-from-struggling-cmon-as-first-move-in-new-acquisition-spree/" rel="nofollow">Board Game Wire</a>, Asmodee has purchased the <em>Zombicide</em> IP from CMON for an undisclosed amount of money. This sale is, in part, connected to CMON's ongoing financial struggles. These troubles are substantive enough, the company is&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/cmon-reduces-staff-and-pauses-board-game-development-amid-us-trade-tariffs" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">scaling back production</a>&nbsp;due to the proposed <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/adjusted-us-trade-tariffs-to-china-still-poses-problems-to-board-game-industry" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">US trade tariffs</a>.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/zombicide-product-layout.jpg?itok=HZezlfEA 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/zombicide-product-layout.jpg?itok=4WjPbdH4 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><blockquote>
<p>Asmodee CEO Thomas Koegler said, “We are proud the iconic Zombicide IP further strengthens our tabletop games portfolio and allows us to reinforce our presence in key geographies. I can’t wait for the team to get to work at what’s coming next for this fantastic IP.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p><em>&nbsp;Zombicide</em> is one of the earliest success stories of tabletop Kickstarter campaigns. The first campaign was held in 2012 with the simple premise of you and your friends fighting through the zombie apocalypse. It was such a simple, cathartic premise, it spawned dozens of expansions and spin-offs.</p>

<p>Notable entries in the <em>Zombicide</em> franchise include&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/zombicide-dceased-brings-anti-life-to-table" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>DCeased</em></a>, where Superman and friends must fend off Anti-Life zombies, a crossover with the Winchester brothers with <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/cmon-games-announces-supernatural-zombicide-packs" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Zombicide: Supernatural</em></a>, a tabletop adaptation of the Zack Snyder film <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/cmon-announces-army-of-dead-board-game" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Army of the Dead</em></a>, and even a licensed spin-off featuring the art and mascot of heavy metal band, <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/iron-maiden-goes-plastic-with-zombicide-crossover" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Iron Maiden</a>.</p>

<p>Regardless of its monetary value, the sale of Zombicide is illustrative of CMON's ongoing financial struggles. In roughly the same time frame, the company sold five other board game IPs:&nbsp;<em>Blood Rage</em>, <em>Rising Sun</em>, <em>Ankh: Gods of Egypt</em>, <em>Arcadia Quest</em>, and <em>Starcadia Quest</em>, to Tabletop Tycoon.</p>

<p>At the time of writing, CMON is still selling what remains of their stock of other board game franchises they own. These include <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/cmon-summons-new-cthulhu-death-may-die-to-kickstarter" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Cthulhu: Death May Die</em></a>, <em>Rising Sun</em>, and <em>Marvel United.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>