<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 15:54:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sega Introduces New Unified Account System With Free Pirate Yakuza Skin]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sega-account-system-pirate-yakuza-skin</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sega-introduces-new-unified-account-system-with-free-pirate-yakuza-skin.1088745/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sega-account-system-pirate-yakuza-skin<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Sega has introduced a brand new unified account system that promises to give you access to rewards when playing either Sega or Atlus games, as well as "using their online services". The first of those bonuses is available to grab right now if you sign up.</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://sega-account.com/auth/content/notice/01JJ1QNG67ZW54BR35EAZRAJ7Y" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">notice</a> on its website, Sega says that signing up for an account will give you "the latest news" about Sega and Atlus games and promotions, and that it'll also grant you access to "exclusive bonuses", as well as "the ability to link accounts" across platforms.</p>

<p>Signing up before March 7th will give you access to a special&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/like-dragon-pirate-yakuza-in-hawaii-announced" rel="nofollow">Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii</a>&nbsp;</em>skin, which lets protagonist Goro Majima wear the iconic gray suit sported by longtime series main character Kazuma Kiryu (except in&nbsp;<em>Infinite Wealth</em>, of course).</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pirate-yakuza-in-hawaii-majima-sega-account.jpg?itok=txvBflv7 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pirate-yakuza-in-hawaii-majima-sega-account.jpg?itok=myRBjEN_ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>You can get yourself a free&nbsp;<em>Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii&nbsp;</em>skin if you sign up for a Sega account.</figcaption></figure><p>Of course, you won't be able to use the skin until the game itself comes out, and signing up for an account doesn't get you a copy of&nbsp;<em>Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii</em>, unfortunately. Still, if you're planning to play it anyway, signing up can't hurt, right?</p>

<p>If you want your free skin, you'll simply need to create a Sega account <a href="https://cp.sega-account.com/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">here</a>, then link it to a corresponding platform in order to redeem the skin on that platform. Obviously, you won't be able to redeem it on Switch, since&nbsp;<em>Pirate Yakuza&nbsp;</em>isn't coming out for that console.</p>

<p>Could the fact that Kiryu's iconic suit is appearing as a skin in the game perhaps portend further development of his story in&nbsp;<em>Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii</em>'s plot? I sure hope so, because&nbsp;<em>Infinite Wealth</em>'s ending left me desperate to know what happens to him next.</p>




<p>At the moment, there's no suggestion that the Sega account will become mandatory for playing Sega or Atlus' games, although I'm sure if that does happen, Sega and Atlus will know how their fans feel about it pretty quickly.</p>

<p>Sega has also <a href="https://sega-account.com/auth/content/notice/01JJ71YSH5ZR99A3GSYS1CMTTX" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">acknowledged</a> that some users are having trouble authenticating their accounts, promising to resolve the issue soon. Hang on in there if that's you.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mortal Kombat 1 Sales Have Passed 5m]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/mortal-kombat-1-sales</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mortal-kombat-1-sales-have-passed-5m.1088688/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/mortal-kombat-1-sales<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Mortal Kombat&nbsp;</em>co-creator Ed Boon has revealed the latest sales figures for&nbsp;<em>Mortal Kombat 1</em>, the most recent entry in the long-running fighting game franchise, and it turns out the game is doing about as well as a recent indie smash hit.</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://x.com/noobde/status/1881825218538467395" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">post</a> on social media platform X, Boon reveals that&nbsp;<em>Mortal Kombat 1&nbsp;</em>is currently sitting at five million sales, as well as the fact that it's still ranking in the top 15 most-played games on PlayStation 5 (according to data that looks suspiciously similar to Circana's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/us-sales-data-july-circana" rel="nofollow">usual roundup</a>).</p>

<p>That figure puts&nbsp;<em>Mortal Kombat 1</em>'s sales roughly on par with those of indie smash hit poker roguelike&nbsp;<em>Balatro</em>, which was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/balatro-sales-5m" rel="nofollow">revealed to have hit the same milestone yesterday</a>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/mortal-kombat-1-sales-fight.jpg?itok=IBARtKWX 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/mortal-kombat-1-sales-fight.jpg?itok=YG0Rx-Ir 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Mortal Kombat 1&nbsp;</em>has apparently reached five million sales.</figcaption></figure><p>Of course,&nbsp;<em>Mortal Kombat 1&nbsp;</em>belongs to one of the longest-running fighting game franchises in the world, and it was also released several months before&nbsp;<em>Balatro</em>, so its achievement is perhaps a little more humble in that light.</p>

<p>Back in November 2023, around two months after&nbsp;<em>Mortal Kombat 1</em>'s initial release, Warner Bros <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/warner-bros-eyes-more-live-services-as-mortal-kombat-1-sells-nearly-3-million-copies" rel="nofollow">revealed that the game had sold three million copies</a>. That means it's picked up another two million in just over a year.</p>

<p>Since launch,&nbsp;<em>Mortal Kombat 1&nbsp;</em>has enjoyed a slew of crossovers that have no doubt boosted its profile. These have included DLC fighters like <i>Invincible</i>'s <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/first-mortal-kombat-1-dlc-omni-man-gets-gameplay-reveal-november-release-window" rel="nofollow">Omni-Man</a>,&nbsp;<em>The Boys</em>' <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/mortal-kombat-1-homelander-first-look" rel="nofollow">Homelander</a>, and&nbsp;<em>Peacemaker</em>'s...uh...<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/mortal-kombat-1-peacemaker-gameplay" rel="nofollow">Peacemaker</a>.</p>

<p>The game's latest crossover DLC fighter is Conan the Barbarian, and believe it or not, he's never appeared in a&nbsp;<em>Mortal Kombat&nbsp;</em>game before, although another iconic Arnie character, the T-800 Terminator, was added to&nbsp;<em>Mortal Kombat 11&nbsp;</em>as post-launch DLC.</p>




<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Mortal Kombat 1</em>, it is, despite its name, the latest game in the&nbsp;<em>Mortal Kombat&nbsp;</em>series.</p>

<p>Released in September 2023, the game's story serves as another reboot, realigning some characters and reimagining others to create a new narrative continuity. It's still got plenty of the same blood-spattered fighting gameplay you know and love, though.</p>

<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Mortal Kombat 1&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1971870/Mortal_Kombat_1/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/mortal-kombat-1/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/mortal-kombat-1/9N7271QN4SGB" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/mortal-kombat-1-switch/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Nintendo Switch</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Doom: The Dark Ages Release Date Apparently Leaks Ahead of Developer Direct]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/doom-dark-ages-release-date-apparently-leaks</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/doom-the-dark-ages-release-date-apparently-leaks-ahead-of-developer-direct.1088655/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/doom-dark-ages-release-date-apparently-leaks<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The&nbsp;<em>Doom: The Dark Ages&nbsp;</em>release date may already have leaked ahead of the game's showing during tomorrow's Xbox Developer Direct presentation.</p>

<p>Earlier this month, Xbox <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/xbox-developer-direct-january-2025-announced" rel="nofollow">announced a Developer Direct</a> for January 23rd (that's tomorrow), during which the studio will be showing off&nbsp;<em>Doom: The Dark Ages</em>,&nbsp;<em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em>, and&nbsp;<em>South of Midnight</em>, as well as an as-yet unrevealed fourth game.</p>

<p>Getting a release date for one or all of those games would make sense during said presentation, but it looks like a French publication may accidentally have already leaked the release date for&nbsp;<em>Doom: The Dark Ages</em>, if a ResetEra user's sighting of an RSS feed listing is to be believed.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/doom-the-dark-ages-release-date-apparently-leaked-armor.jpg?itok=lkDB-wik 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/doom-the-dark-ages-release-date-apparently-leaked-armor.jpg?itok=ikweDE3y 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Doom: The Dark Ages</em>' release date may already have been leaked.</figcaption></figure><p>ResetEra user <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/doom-the-dark-ages-releasing-on-may-15-2025.1088169/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Alexzan</a> says they were browsing their RSS feeds (essentially feeds that display website updates and information) on RSS app Feedly when they noticed an entry from French publication <a href="https://www.gamekult.com/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Gamekult</a>.</p>

<p>The listing is, of course, in French. It reads as follows: "<em>Doom: The Dark Ages</em> décimera les légions infernales le 15 mai 2025".</p>

<p>You can probably work out roughly what that means on your own, but just in case, Alexzan helpfully provides a translation: "<em>Doom: The Dark Ages&nbsp;</em>will decimate the infernal legions on May 15th, 2025".</p>

<p>The article to which the listing should point is, of course, not currently available on Gamekult's website, but it would seem the publication has accidentally revealed a May 15th release date for the upcoming game. If it's legit, it was almost certainly published too early in error.</p>




<p>We'll almost certainly find out exactly when&nbsp;<em>Doom: The Dark Ages&nbsp;</em>is due to launch when the Developer Direct airs tomorrow. It's due to start at 1pm Eastern (which is 10am Pacific and about 6pm GMT).</p>

<p>When it does launch,&nbsp;<em>Doom: The Dark Ages&nbsp;</em>will arrive on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3017860/DOOM_The_Dark_Ages/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/doom-the-dark-ages/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-GB/games/doom-the-dark-ages" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>. As a first-party Xbox game, it'll also be available on Game Pass on day one, but only for certain tiers.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals Spring Festival Brings New Rocket League-Style Mode and More Tomorrow]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/marvel-rivals-spring-festival-rocket-league-mode</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-spring-festival-brings-new-rocket-league-style-mode-and-more-tomorrow.1088622/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/marvel-rivals-spring-festival-rocket-league-mode<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>NetEase Games has revealed a brand new event for hero shooter&nbsp;<em>Marvel Rivals</em>. The Spring Festival event arrives tomorrow, bringing with it a whole new game mode and some shiny new skins.</p>

<p>Kicking off on January 23rd at 9am UTC (that's 4am Eastern and 1am Pacific), the Spring Festival event's main draw is its Clash of Dancing Lions limited-time mode, which will look familiar to you if you've ever played&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/rocket-league" rel="nofollow"><em>Rocket League</em></a>.</p>

<p>Teams of three compete against one another on a dedicated map, with each team aiming to gain possession of a ball and make sure it enters the opposing team's scoring zone. Whoever reaches "a predetermined score" first will be declared the winner.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/marvel-rivals-spring-festival-new-mode-gameplay.jpg?itok=agXvRQcg 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/marvel-rivals-spring-festival-new-mode-gameplay.jpg?itok=TRUuuJux 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Marvel Rivals</em>' new mode will be familiar to you if you've played&nbsp;<em>Rocket League</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>The trailer for the event shows Star-Lord, Iron Fist, and Black Widow competing in the event, but it'll likely be open to all heroes; those are just the characters getting new skins as part of the Spring Festival.</p>

<p>Speaking of which, three Clashing Lions-themed skins have been introduced for those heroes. Star-Lord gets a fetching Lion's Mane costume, Black Widow gets a Lion's Heartbeat outfit, and Iron Fist gets a Lion's Gaze look.</p>

<p>They're all essentially themed around the same traditional Chinese lion dance motif, and they all look pretty excellent. At the very least, you'll be able to earn Star-Lord's outfit through "completing tasks", although it isn't clear whether you can earn the other two that way as well.</p>

<p>Additionally, since&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/marvels-spider-man-2" rel="nofollow">Marvel's Spider-Man 2</a>&nbsp;</em>is landing on PC soon, NetEase says a new&nbsp;<em>Spider-Man 2</em>-themed bundle will be available in&nbsp;<em>Marvel Rivals</em>' store, complete with a new outfit for Spidey, as well as a new nameplate and spray. Those are launching on January 30th.</p>




<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Marvel Rivals</em>, it's a free-to-play hero shooter developed and published by Chinese studio NetEase. Similar in many ways to&nbsp;<em>Overwatch</em>, the game pits Marvel heroes like Black Widow, Captain America, and Venom against one another in objective-based gameplay modes.</p>

<p>The game has proven popular among players, reaching a player count of <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/marvel-rivals-player-count-10m" rel="nofollow">10 million within a 72-hour period</a>. It's also attracted the attention of modders, who have already <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/marvel-rivals-modding-workaround" rel="nofollow">found a way around</a> an apparent <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/marvel-rivals-modding-clampdown" rel="nofollow">clampdown on skin modding</a> introduced alongside&nbsp;<em>Marvel Rivals</em>' first season.</p>

<p>You can play&nbsp;<em>Marvel Rivals&nbsp;</em>for free right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2767030/Marvel_Rivals/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/marvel-rivals/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/marvel-rivals/9n8pmw7qmd3d" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sonic the Hedgehog 4 Movie Set for March 2027 Release]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sonic-hedgehog-4-movie-march-2027</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sonic-the-hedgehog-4-movie-set-for-march-2027-release.1088598/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sonic-hedgehog-4-movie-march-2027<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Paramount has already announced a release date for the fourth&nbsp;<em>Sonic the Hedgehog&nbsp;</em>movie, despite the fact that the third movie was only made available to stream yesterday (and that it's still available to watch in some theaters).</p>

<p>Per <a href="https://variety.com/2025/film/news/sonic-4-release-date-march-2027-1236280697/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Variety</a>,&nbsp;<em>Sonic the Hedgehog 4&nbsp;</em>will be launching on March 19th, 2027. Obviously, that date is more than two years away, but hey, I suppose&nbsp;<em>Sonic&nbsp;</em>movie fans need something to look forward to.</p>

<p><em>Sonic the Hedgehog 4&nbsp;</em>won't necessarily be the movie's final title, but if it follows the naming conventions of its two predecessors, then it probably won't bear any kind of secondary name. Don't expect&nbsp;<em>Sonic 4: The Rise of Robotnik&nbsp;</em>or anything anytime soon.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/sonic-the-hedgehog-4-movie-release-date-sonic-3-shot.jpg?itok=XODQS-Vq 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/sonic-the-hedgehog-4-movie-release-date-sonic-3-shot.jpg?itok=NIohTK_b 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The fourth&nbsp;<em>Sonic&nbsp;</em>movie will be hitting theaters in March 2027.</figcaption></figure><p>A <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/fourth-sonic-hedgehog-movie-2027-report" rel="nofollow">report back in December</a> (also courtesy of Variety) already revealed that a fourth&nbsp;<em>Sonic&nbsp;</em>movie was confirmed before the proverbial ink on the third one was dry, but now we know exactly when we can expect it.</p>

<p>Of course, we still don't know what kind of story details we can expect from the movie, although the post-credits scenes included in the third installment are probably strong clues as to where it's headed.</p>

<p>The third movie's post-credits scenes (look away now if you don't want spoilers!) confirm that Shadow survived the events of the film, and they also tease the appearance of both Metal Sonic and Amy Rose in the next movie.</p>

<p>As such, we can probably expect&nbsp;<em>Sonic 4&nbsp;</em>to focus on both characters, and Keanu Reeves' Shadow the Hedgehog will probably be returning as well. Naturally, all of this is speculation until the movie is officially revealed.</p>




<p>The existence of a fourth&nbsp;<em>Sonic the Hedgehog&nbsp;</em>movie makes a lot of sense given how well the previous three have done in financial terms.</p>

<p>According to Paramount, between them, the three&nbsp;<em>Sonic&nbsp;</em>films have <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sonic-the-hedgehog-movies-1b-box-office" rel="nofollow">crossed $1 billion at the box office</a>, and since that report was released earlier this month, that number's likely to be higher by now as well.</p>

<p>In any case,&nbsp;<em>Sonic the Hedgehog 4&nbsp;</em>releases on March 19th, 2027. Don't expect to hear anything more about the movie for a while given how far off that date is.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>