<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 17:27:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mycopunk Preview - Mushrooms of Madness]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/mycopunk-preview</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mycopunk-preview-mushrooms-of-madness.1240539/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Co-op games are having a banner year so far in 2025. Games like <em>PEAK</em> and <em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/split-fiction-review-everything-everywhere" rel="nofollow">Split Fiction</a></em>&nbsp;have been topping the charts on Steam all year, and don’t show any signs of slowing down. <em>Mycopunk </em>is another co-op focused game dropping in Early Access, and the current build shows a really fun experience for friends, and a promising start for solo players as well.</p>

<h2>Mission Accomplished</h2>

<p><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/mycopunkhub.jpg?itok=e_0gzLCL 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/mycopunkhub.jpg?itok=SecSgOJ_ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture>Though it isn’t a roguelike, it’s hard for me to play <em>Mycopunk</em> without thinking of <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/risk-of-rain-2-is-lootin-shootin-good-time" rel="nofollow"><em>Risk of Rain 2</em></a>. The gameplay loop of accomplishing the mission, then getting the hell out of there, is simple but will get you hooked.</p>

<p>The major place <em>Mycopunk</em> diverges is the structure of missions. In <em>Risk of Rain 2</em>, the mission is the same: get to the teleporter and defeat the boss.</p>

<p><em>Mycopunk</em>, on the other hand, demands something a little different out of your squad every time. Sometimes you’re just defeating swarms, sure. Other times, you need to connect satellites to a power node, prepare a railgun to take out a rival spy, or clear an infection off a planet’s surface.</p>

<p>These missions help keep every adventure out into the wilderness feel different. If the missions don’t make things feel different enough, though, your own equipment you deploy with will.</p>

<h2>Employee of the Month</h2>

<p><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/mycopunkemployees.jpg?itok=9ZwT1qek 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/mycopunkemployees.jpg?itok=fGLA0gZu 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture>At the launch of Early Access, <em>Mycopunk</em>&nbsp;includes 4 “employees” for you to choose from. I really enjoyed how the game divided the strengths of each character: they all have different mobility abilities, but weapons aren’t tied to any single character.</p>

<p>These movement abilities are all really varied, and while some feel clunky, there are more good than bad. I felt like the Scrapper’s Jetpack and Wrangler’s Rocket Lasso just didn’t click for me, but the highlights were the Glider’s Wingsuit and Scrapper’s Grapple Pole, which felt excellent to use.</p>

<p>One of the lacking features in the movement was momentum. While I could really get going with the Grapple Pole and Wingsuit, it felt like the moment I hit the ground, I was back to square one.</p>

<p>I have much fewer complaints, however, about the gunplay. Every weapon I tried felt pretty satisfying to use and offered unique ways to play with each character.</p>

<p>In particular, I love how ammo works. You will likely run out of ammo at some point, and when you do, to get it back, you must use your secondary weapon. It’s a perfect way to make sure you aren’t using any weapon in particular as a crutch.</p>

<p>One of the hardest tests <em>Mycopunk</em> is facing, and will continue to face in Early Access, is the balance between solo and co-op. I played entirely solo during my time, and it felt like the game was a little more skewed towards a team.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Instead of a teammate to revive, solo players get a set of 5 automatic revives. This makes fighting feel fair, but the missions feel pretty skewed towards co-op players. In addition, even with revives, the enemies will far outnumber you, and it can be hard to know which enemies to focus on and when. As a solo player, you might feel overwhelmed and frustrated more than having fun.</p>

<h2><em>Mycopunk </em>| Final Thoughts</h2>

<p><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/mycopunkboss.jpg?itok=UIIqF6gR 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/mycopunkboss.jpg?itok=hz5-T9A1 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture>At the moment, I think&nbsp;<em>Mycopunk&nbsp;</em>is a strong start with a bright future. There are some pains that I would love to see it shed as it develops. I’d especially like to see some mission adjustments for solo play and some ability tweaks.</p>

<p>Despite that, if you’re looking for a new co-op shooter, you won’t be disappointed by <em>Mycopunk</em>. Tight gunplay, fun movement, and varied missions will keep you exploring the corporate wasteland for a long time. Just make sure to bring a coworker or two for the best results.</p>

<hr><p><em><strong>Mycopunk&nbsp;</strong></em><em>was previewed on PC using a copy provided by the publisher over the course of 2 hours of gameplay - all screenshots were taken&nbsp;during the process of preview.</em><br>
&nbsp;</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Parker is a freelance writer based in Iowa, and the co-founder and editor of gaming satire site Palette Swap. Before Palette Swap, he was an editor at Hard… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/parker-johnson">More about Parker</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/mycopunk-preview]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Total War: Warhammer III Tides of Torment DLC Delayed to "Later This Year"]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/total-war-warhammer-iii-tides-of-torment-dlc-delayed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/total-war-warhammer-iii-tides-of-torment-dlc-delayed-to-later-this-year.1240476/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer Creative Assembly and publisher Sega have announced that&nbsp;<em>Total War: Warhammer III</em>'s upcoming&nbsp;<em>Tides of Torment&nbsp;</em>DLC has been delayed to "later this year".</p>

<p>Originally,&nbsp;<em>Tides of Torment&nbsp;</em>was intended to launch this summer, but as Creative Assembly reveals in a <a href="https://community.creative-assembly.com/total-war/total-war-warhammer/blogs/75" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">new blog post</a>, the DLC won't be meeting that release window. Instead,&nbsp;<em>Tides of Torment&nbsp;</em>will be launching sometime later in 2025, although the studio doesn't commit to a more specific release window than that.</p>

<p>Creative Assembly says that during recent playtesting for&nbsp;<em>Tides of Torment</em>, the studio's developers asked themselves if the DLC "met the standards...set in recent releases", and as you've probably gathered from the delay, the answer was no.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/total-war-warhammer-iii-tides-of-torment-delayed-firebreathing_0.jpg?itok=YsOA1tEi 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/total-war-warhammer-iii-tides-of-torment-delayed-firebreathing_0.jpg?itok=aGDp_7tf 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Total War: Warhammer III</em>'s&nbsp;<em>Tides of Torment&nbsp;</em>DLC is going to take a bit longer to launch.</figcaption></figure><p>As a result of this dissatisfaction, Creative Assembly says it's going to spend some time "working on [<em>Tides of Torment</em>], reviewing the content, and improving the gameplay experiences that it’s set to bring".</p>

<p>That also means that the info shared as part of the Slaanesh and Norsca previews released back in May is probably "no longer accurate", according to Creative Assembly. More will be shared about these factions, as well as the third and final DLC faction, when the final What's Next video for&nbsp;<em>Tides of Torment&nbsp;</em>arrives.</p>

<p>The studio acknowledges that this year "has been a slower year" for many&nbsp;<em>Total War: Warhammer&nbsp;</em>fans, and that while <i>Warhammer III&nbsp;</i>"is in a better space" this year than in previous years, Creative Assembly is "currently not meeting [its] commitments" to transparency, pledging to address this issue over the next few months through new updates, hotfixes, and preview videos.</p>

<p>With regards to the future of&nbsp;<em>Total War: Warhammer III</em>, Creative Assembly closes by saying that "one of the biggest <em>Total War: Warhammer</em> content packs ever created in the trilogy" is coming next year, and that the possibility of smaller DLC packs that include certain legendary lords or hero units is also on the table.</p>




<p><em>Total War: Warhammer III&nbsp;</em>is available to check out right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1142710/Total_War_WARHAMMER_III/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC via Steam</a>, and you can remind yourself of what our very own Andrew thought of the game <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/total-war-warhammer-3-review" rel="nofollow">right here</a>. The&nbsp;<em>Tides of Torment&nbsp;</em>DLC is set to launch sometime later this year.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/total-war-warhammer-iii-tides-of-torment-dlc-delayed]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>