<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 15:20:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Konami to Raise Base Domestic Employee Salary for Fourth Consecutive Year]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/konami-raising-salary-fourth-year</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/konami-to-raise-base-domestic-employee-salary-for-fourth-consecutive-year.1113225/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/konami-raising-salary-fourth-year<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Konami has announced that it will raise base employee salaries in its home country of Japan for the fourth consecutive year.</p>

<p>In a news <a href="https://www.konami.com/news/ja/release/2025/0219/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">post</a> on its website (for which we're using machine translation, since the original post is in Japanese), Konami says it will raise employee base salaries for all "full-time employees at domestic group companies" in order to create a "rewarding work environment".</p>

<p>Not only that, but new graduates' starting salaries will be raised from 300,000 yen to 305,000 yen per month. The changes will take effect starting from March 2026, with <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/konami-salary-increase" rel="nofollow">last year's base salary increase</a> set to go into effect next month.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/konami-salary-increase-2026-silent-hill-2.jpg?itok=7X2dlvbK 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/konami-salary-increase-2026-silent-hill-2.jpg?itok=iUPKDcjC 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Konami had a pretty good year last year thanks to&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill 2</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>Konami says that its staff are the "source" of its "competitive edge", and that by increasing salaries, the company is hoping to "improve employee engagement and continue to strive to create better products and services".</p>

<p>As with last year, Konami does add the proviso that "some domestic group companies and some job types are not included", but it doesn't go into detail regarding which jobs these are.</p>

<p>All in all, Konami had a pretty solid 2024, it seems. The&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill 2&nbsp;</em>remake was released in October last year, going on to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/silent-hill-2-remake-sales-1m" rel="nofollow">sell a million copies</a> within its first three days on launch and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/silent-hill-2-remake-sales-2m" rel="nofollow">reaching two million</a> as of late January.</p>

<p>Not only that, but in October, FIFA <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/fifa-konami-esports-partner" rel="nofollow">picked Konami as its new esports partner</a> after the organization's well-publicized split with EA, although it's worth noting that this doesn't mean Konami will be developing whatever FIFA's&nbsp;<em>EA Sports FC&nbsp;</em>competitor turns out to be.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-konami.jpg?itok=0UP7w8qW 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-konami.jpg?itok=fpxImTaE 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Konami is gearing up to launch&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater&nbsp;</em>later this year.</figcaption></figure><p>As for what awaits Konami in 2025, the company's biggest release for this year will likely be&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</em>, a remake of the original 2004 stealth adventure that will boast a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/metal-gear-solid-d-snake-eater-remake-reveals-first-spectacular-gameplay-in-unreal" rel="nofollow">full visual and gameplay overhaul</a>.</p>

<p>Set to launch in August (as revealed by <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sony-state-of-play-recap-february-2025" rel="nofollow">the State of Play presentation last week</a>), the game represents the first major entry in the&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear&nbsp;</em>series since 2018's&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear Survive&nbsp;</em>(discounting 2023's&nbsp;<em>Master Collection</em>).</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oxenfree Developer Night School Hit by Layoffs]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/oxenfree-night-school-layoffs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/oxenfree-developer-night-school-hit-by-layoffs.1113183/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/oxenfree-night-school-layoffs<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Oxenfree&nbsp;</em>developer Night School has been hit by layoffs, although how many staff have been affected by the move is unclear at the moment.</p>

<p>Per <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/netflix-has-laid-off-staff-at-oxenfree-developer-night-school-studio" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Game Developer</a>, an "undisclosed number of employees" have been laid off at Night School, which was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/netflix-acquires-oxenfree-developer-studio" rel="nofollow">acquired by parent company Netflix</a> back in 2021 as part of a wider expansion into the gaming industry.</p>

<p>While the layoffs apparently won't affect the games Night School is currently working on, Game Developer says that "current and former Night School employees" were "shocked" by the layoffs, which were revealed to the team in January.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/oxenfree-2-night-school-layoffs.jpg?itok=lUgP6FZk 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/oxenfree-2-night-school-layoffs.jpg?itok=8CbhHT5D 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Night School is best known for the&nbsp;<em>Oxenfree&nbsp;</em>games.</figcaption></figure><p>Despite these layoffs, Night School <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/night-school-studio_come-make-some-rad-games-with-us-were-hiring-activity-7297698599251910657-OACv" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">posted on LinkedIn just yesterday</a> that it's hiring a lead artist, a game director, and a senior producer, which probably isn't going to be particularly comforting to those who have been let go.</p>

<p>Game Developer says that Netflix declined to comment on the situation, so these layoffs haven't officially been confirmed by Night School's parent company, but a <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/stephanie-bedford-pmp_opentowork-activity-7297678853500506112-exik" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">couple</a> of ex-Night School <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7290496710072512512/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">employees</a> have posted about the situation on LinkedIn within the past couple of weeks.</p>

<p>Night School isn't the only studio to be targeted by Netflix's apparent desire to slim down its gaming industry presence in recent months. Back in October, the company <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/netflix-team-blue-shut-down-report" rel="nofollow">reportedly shut down star-studded AAA studio "Team Blue"</a>,&nbsp; which counted luminaries like&nbsp;<em>Halo</em>'s Joseph Staten and&nbsp;<em>Overwatch</em>'s Chacko Sonny among its ranks.</p>

<p>That was shortly before Netflix announced it would <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/netflix-generative-ai-vp" rel="nofollow">go all-in on generative AI</a> for its gaming division, appointing a dedicated AI VP in Mike Verdu, who previously worked as Netflix's overall gaming VP.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/night-school-layoffs-afterparty.jpg?itok=1viJV-PD 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/night-school-layoffs-afterparty.jpg?itok=BM0dRAh8 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Night School also developed 2020's supernatural adventure comedy&nbsp;<em>Afterparty</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>Frustratingly, Netflix has never been particularly transparent when it comes to its gaming metrics, so we don't know exactly why these layoffs are happening.</p>

<p>We can, however, assume that it's probably part of a wider industry trend that has also seen studios like <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/liquid-swords-layoffs-just-cause-creator" rel="nofollow">Liquid Swords</a>, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/rumbleverse-and-killer-instct-studio-iron-galaxy-suffers-layoffs" rel="nofollow">Iron Galaxy</a>, and even bigger companies like <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/bioware-layoffs-veilguard-failure" rel="nofollow">BioWare</a>&nbsp;letting staff go in recent months.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Annapurna Interactive Showcase Set for Next Week]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/annapurna-interactive-showcase-february-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-annapurna-interactive-showcase-set-for-next-week.1113180/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/annapurna-interactive-showcase-february-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Annapurna Interactive has announced that it will hold a new Showcase presentation next week, showing off some of its upcoming games as well as some extra "surprises".</p>

<p>The studio, which has published indie hits like&nbsp;<em>Outer Wilds&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>What Remains of Edith Finch</em>, will air its latest Annapurna Interactive Showcase on February 24th at 9am Pacific (that's around 12pm Eastern and about 5pm GMT).</p>

<p>According to a press release, the presentation will include information on upcoming 2025 Annapurna releases. Games getting more info include cozy adventure&nbsp;<em>Wanderstop</em>, cycling game&nbsp;<em>Wheel World</em>, and photography sim&nbsp;<em>Lushfoil</em>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/wheel-world-annapurna-interactive-showcase-2025.jpg?itok=fp3sKS3O 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/wheel-world-annapurna-interactive-showcase-2025.jpg?itok=NSeGa89k 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Annapurna will reveal new info about some of its upcoming projects next week.</figcaption></figure><p>We'll also get to learn more about FPS&nbsp;<em>Skin Deep</em>, "procedurally generated audiovisual experience"&nbsp;<em>Faraway</em>, and&nbsp;<em>to a T</em>, the 3D narrative adventure designed by&nbsp;<em>Katamari&nbsp;</em>creator Keita Takahashi, as well as creature-collecting roguelite <i>Morsels</i>.</p>

<p>All of this will come alongside "a few more surprises", as Annapurna says, so if you're a fan of offbeat indie games, you're not going to want to miss this one. The showcase is set to air on Annapurna's <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@AnnapurnaInteractive" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">YouTube channel</a> and will last around 30 minutes.</p>

<p>This will be Annapurna's first major showcase since a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/annapurna-interactive-staff-resign-after-company-spin-off-talks-fail" rel="nofollow">mass staff exodus at the studio</a> back in September, which took place after negotiations with the main Annapurna company to spin the interactive division off into its own entity broke down.</p>

<p>Following that, a report emerged in January this year which claimed that ex-Annapurna staff had <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ex-annapurna-staff-private-division-ips" rel="nofollow">banded together to form their own company</a>, and that their first purchase was the former Take-Two indie <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/take-two-private-division-sale" rel="nofollow">publishing outfit Private Division</a>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tales-of-the-shire-private-division-annapurna_0.jpg?itok=n4O3g3po 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tales-of-the-shire-private-division-annapurna_0.jpg?itok=RCpDatSK 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Ex-Annapurna Interactive staff have reportedly banded together to purchase&nbsp;<em>Tales of the Shire&nbsp;</em>publisher Private Division.</figcaption></figure><p>Elsewhere in the world of Annapurna,&nbsp;<em>Alan Wake&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Control&nbsp;</em>developer Remedy revealed earlier this year that it was teaming up with Annapurna in order to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/remedy-annapurna-control-2-tv-movies" rel="nofollow">pursue TV and movie projects</a> based on some of its properties.</p>

<p>You'll be able to check out the new Annapurna Interactive Showcase when it airs on February 24th at 9am Pacific. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokemon Go Developer Niantic Reportedly to Sell Gaming Business to Saudi Firm]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pokemon-go-niantic-saudi-rumor</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pokemon-go-developer-niantic-reportedly-to-sell-gaming-business-to-saudi-firm.1113132/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pokemon-go-niantic-saudi-rumor<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A new report has emerged which claims that Niantic, the developer behind hit games like&nbsp;<em>Pokemon Go&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Now</em>, is in talks to sell its gaming business to a company backed by the Saudi Public Investment Fund.</p>

<p>According to a Bloomberg <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-02-19/-pokemon-go-maker-nears-3-5-billion-deal-to-sell-games-unit" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">article</a>&nbsp;(which, as ever, cites the old "several people familiar with the discussions" chestnut), a deal between Niantic and the PIF-backed Scopely Inc "could be announced in coming weeks".</p>

<p>Bloomberg reporters Michelle Davis and Cecilia D'Anastasio say that the deal could be worth "about $3.5 billion", and that the agreement between Niantic and Scopely would include&nbsp;<em>Pokemon Go</em>&nbsp;as well as other games developed by the studio.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/niantic-saudi-deal-rumor-monster-hunter-now.jpg?itok=Qlce0fml 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/niantic-saudi-deal-rumor-monster-hunter-now.jpg?itok=YtxcAIbm 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Niantic is responsible not only for&nbsp;<em>Pokemon Go</em>, but also for games like&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Now</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>However, Davis and D'Anastasio also emphasize that "there's no assurance an agreement will be reached", so it's entirely possible Niantic will remain independent.</p>

<p>If the deal does go through, Niantic will become one of many video game pies in which the Saudi PIF has its fingers. Others include Nintendo, of which <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/saudi-pif-becomes-nintendos-largest-outside-shareholder" rel="nofollow">the PIF is now the largest external shareholder</a>, as well as <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/saudi-arabia-pif-adds-stakes-in-capcom-nexon" rel="nofollow">Capcom</a>&nbsp;and <em>King of Fighters&nbsp;</em>studio <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/saudi-arabian-crown-prince-to-buy-controlling-stake-in-snk" rel="nofollow">SNK</a>.</p>

<p>Additionally, rumors are currently swirling that new&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed Mirage&nbsp;</em>DLC is on the way courtesy of Saudi PIF funding sent Ubisoft's way, although Ubisoft itself <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/assassins-creed-mirage-dlc-report-ubisoft" rel="nofollow">declined to comment on these rumors</a> back in late January.</p>

<p>As Bloomberg points out, while&nbsp;<em>Pokemon Go&nbsp;</em>remains a major hit for Niantic, the company's other games have had some trouble replicating that success. Niantic <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pokemon-go-creator-niantic-cancels-4-projects-lays-off-staff" rel="nofollow">canceled four in-development projects</a> and laid off a number of staff back in 2022.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pokemon-go-dhelmise-niantic-saudi-sale-rumor.jpg?itok=9F6uqmW7 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pokemon-go-dhelmise-niantic-saudi-sale-rumor.jpg?itok=U68qNVjW 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Pokemon Go&nbsp;</em>remains a big hit for Niantic.</figcaption></figure><p>Whether or not operations will change if the deal goes through remains to be seen, but it's likely that, at least at first, Niantic will continue to operate just as it always has.</p>

<p>Of course, we'll have to wait and see what happens; the deal is far from confirmed, after all. Stay tuned for more on this and all other things Niantic-related.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>