<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 07:54:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dimension 20: Titan Takedown Combines Tabletop Storytelling with Pro Wrestling Personality]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/dimension-20-titan-takedown-combines-tabletop-storytelling-with-pro-wrestling</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dimension-20-titan-takedown-combines-tabletop-storytelling-with-pro-wrestling-personality.1119936/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/dimension-20-titan-takedown-combines-tabletop-storytelling-with-pro-wrestling<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Dropout has announced a new side quest for <em>Dimension 20</em>. The independent streaming series platform's latest actual play anthology, <em>Dimension 20: Titan Takedow</em>n will feature larger-than-life personalities from the WWE playing in an epic fantasy TTRPG campaign.</p>

<h2>The <em>Dimension 20: Titan Takedown</em> Announcement</h2>

<p>According to an official press release, <em>Dimension 20: Titan Takedown</em> will premiere on Dropout on April 2. New episodes will air every Wednesday for four weeks.</p>


<p>The series will be set in Ancient Athens and center around a group of legendary wrestlers as they compete in the titular Titan Takedown, a smackdown of epic proportions hosted by the King of the Gods himself, Zeus. The campaign will run on the most recent edition of Dungeons &amp; Dragons</p>

<p>Naturally, the personalities embodying these players are also larger-than-life warriors of the ring. The players are WWE Superstars Xavier Woods as the Julius Mortem, Kofi Kingston as Adonis Thanaformus, Bayley as Thea Kittleroo, and Chelsea Green as Tabatha.These wrestling giants will be guided by the host and Game Master, Brennan Lee Mulligan.</p>

<p>This connection between modern Pro Wrestling and Greek theatre is made more explicit in the trailer for Dimension 20: Titan Takedown. The sets show an arena filled with onlookers human and monstrous, temples held up by majestic pillars, and a roped square circle in the middle.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dimension-20-titan-takedown-brennan.jpg?itok=5qPYPp7m 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dimension-20-titan-takedown-brennan.jpg?itok=75470n-l 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>This personality crossover is not unheard of for <em>Dimension 20</em>. A similar show, <em>Dungeons &amp; Drag Queens</em>, featured characters from <em>RuPaul's Drag Race</em>. That show recently concluded its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dimension-20-dungeons-drag-queens-season-2-sashays-onto-dropout-in-january" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">second season</a>.</p>

<p><em>Dimension 20</em> is notable in the actual play space for its anthology format. Every season of the show tells a self-contained story with a rotating cast of players over several episodes. These include the temporal shenanigans of <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/dropout-announces-vod-dates-for-their-actual-play-live-show-dimension20-time-quangle" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Time Quangle</em></a>, the magic school hijinx of <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/misfits-magic-season-2-announced-return-three-years-later" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Misfits and Magic</em></a>, and the tale of a family of stoats in <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/fall-in-love-with-family-of-stoats-in-dimension-20-burrows-end" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Burrow's End</em></a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>