<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 12:51:30 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Asmodee Announces New Asmodee Kids Brand, Bringing Shorter, Child-Friendly Board Games to Tables]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/asmodee-announces-new-asmodee-kids-brand-bringing-shorter-child-friendly-board-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/asmodee-announces-new-asmodee-kids-brand-bringing-shorter-child-friendly-board-games-to-tables.1293474/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Asmodee has announced a new Asmodee Kids brand of board games. The <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/asmodee-rebrands-for-30th-anniversary-with-inspired-by-players-label" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">recently renamed</a> tabletop giant's new board game line is dedicated to making shorter, more approachable games for kids. Those games include reworked versions of their most popular titles.</p>

<h2>The Asmodee Kids Brand Announcement</h2>

<p>In a recent report by <a href="https://boardgamewire.com/index.php/2025/09/09/asmodee-to-adapt-its-most-iconic-games-into-shorter-child-friendly-versions-with-launch-of-kids-focused-brand/" rel="nofollow">BoardGameWire</a>, Asmodee plans to launch three board games under the Asmodee Kids brand. As mentioned above, these games will be shorter and simpler redesigns of titles from the company's esteemed catalog.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/asmodee-kids-splendor-kids-box-promo.jpg?itok=L4F-Eyyx 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/asmodee-kids-splendor-kids-box-promo.jpg?itok=rNLqZwx6 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The first of these games is <em>My First Unlock</em>, a simplified version of the escape room-inspired, cooperative card game, <em>Unlock!.&nbsp;</em>This version will be available sometime later this month.</p>

<p>The second title is <em>Splendor Kids</em>, a more accessible version of <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/splendor-game-review-splendid" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Splendor</em></a>, the resource management card game, which is set to launch in October. Third is <em>Dixit Kids</em>, a streamlined version of the creative storytelling card game coming next January.</p>

<p>All games launched under Asmodee Kids are designed for a maximum of thirty minutes of play. Furthermore, according to Asmodee, these reworked games were designed in collaboration with child development specialists and have been tested in both schools and community settings.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Asmodee CEO Thomas Koegler said the following regarding the announcement of Asmodee Kids:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>“Board games are more than just entertainment. And while we are keeping the fun at the core of the experience, because that’s what kids are seeking, they also get to develop focus, adaptability, and emotional skills. Asmodee Kids means that children and parents can enjoy our most iconic games together.”&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Releasing kid-friendly board games is not unheard of for Asmodee. They have launched similar games in their Catan and Ticket to Ride series, but those were sporadic compared to this more dedicated branded product line.</p>

<p>Curiously, at time of writing, only one of the Asmodee Kids board games are available for pre-order. Splendor Kids is available now at an MSRP of $29.99, which is ten dollars cheaper. The other games' prices haven't been listed.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/asmodee-announces-new-asmodee-kids-brand-bringing-shorter-child-friendly-board-games]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>