<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 19:56:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warcraft 2 Remaster Seemingly Leaked Ahead of Warcraft Anniversary Celebration]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/warcraft-2-remaster-leaked-rumor</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warcraft-2-remaster-seemingly-leaked-ahead-of-warcraft-anniversary-celebration.1028958/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/warcraft-2-remaster-leaked-rumor<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A&nbsp;<em>Warcraft 2&nbsp;</em>remaster may have just been leaked ahead of a major celebration for the franchise's 30th anniversary, which is due to take place next week.</p>

<p>As spotted by <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1gkkzj1/warcraft_2_remastered_internal_alpha_leaked_via/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Redditor Neggy5</a>, a <a href="https://blizztrack.com/view/w2rd?type=versions" rel="noopener" target="_blank">new listing on tracking site BlizzTrack</a>, which monitors changes in the backend of the company's Battle.net service, points to the existence of an internal alpha test for something called&nbsp;<em>Warcraft 2: Remastered</em>.</p>

<p>All things considered, it's pretty difficult to imagine that this is anything other than a reworked modern version of the seminal 1995 RTS, which was originally titled&nbsp;<em>Warcraft 2: Tides of Darkness</em>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/warcraft-2-remaster-leak-original-shot.jpg?itok=PEyMoc8Q 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/warcraft-2-remaster-leak-original-shot.jpg?itok=Eas5tPeJ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>A remaster of classic 1995 RTS&nbsp;<em>Warcraft 2&nbsp;</em>could be on the way.</figcaption></figure><p>The listing gives practically nothing away, as you might imagine, but it does potentially confirm the existence of a remaster that may well be announced during next week's celebration.</p>

<p>According to the Redditor who discovered the listing, an upcoming update for the controversial&nbsp;<em>Warcraft 3: Reforged&nbsp;</em>was also discovered on the BlizzTrack website, so it seems that Blizzard's attempts to redeem that <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/warcraft-3-reforged-developer-update-does-little-to-satisfy-irate-fans">ill-received rework</a> also continue, although the nature of said update hasn't been revealed.</p>

<p>It's also worth noting that none of this has officially been confirmed; this could well just be an experimental attempt on Blizzard's part to go through options rather than a confirmation that something concrete is in the works.</p>

<p>Still, the timing of this leak seems pretty serendipitous with the&nbsp;<em>Warcraft&nbsp;</em>anniversary stream due to air next week, so I wouldn't be surprised if a&nbsp;<em>Warcraft 2&nbsp;</em>announcement was officially made at that point.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/world-of-warcraft-the-war-within-blizzard.jpg?itok=ScnB5hX3 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/world-of-warcraft-the-war-within-blizzard.jpg?itok=wGY516Vx 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Blizzard recently released&nbsp;<em>World of Warcraft&nbsp;</em>expansion&nbsp;<em>The War Within</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>The&nbsp;<em>Warcraft&nbsp;</em>anniversary stream airs a few months after Blizzard released&nbsp;<em>World of Warcraft: The War Within</em>, the tenth major expansion for the long-running MMORPG, which launched back in August.</p>

<p>It's also arriving after developers on said MMO <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/world-of-warcraft-blizzard-union">formed Blizzard's first wall-to-wall union</a> back in July, which essentially means said union represents the entire studio rather than a single unit within the company.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>