<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 23:20:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Munchkin Vox Machina Brings First Critical Role Campaign to Iconic Card Game]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/munchkin-vox-machina-brings-first-critical-role-campaign-to-iconic-card-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/munchkin-vox-machina-brings-first-critical-role-campaign-to-iconic-card-game.1289283/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Steve Jackson Games has announced another collaboration with Critical Role. Their newest project, <em>Munchkin Vox Machina</em>, combines the addictive, zany card gameplay of Munchkin with the heroes, villains, and events of the actual play series' first campaign.</p>

<h2>The <em>Munchkin Vox Machina</em> Announcement</h2>

<p>According to the store page, <a href="https://munchkin.game/products/games/munchkin-vox-machina/" rel="nofollow"><em>Munchkin Vox Machina</em></a> is based on the first campaign of Critical Role. The campaign that made Critical Role into the wildly successful multimedia company that it is today, producing blockbuster TTRPGs like <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/daggerheart-review-narrative-forward-yes-and-ttrpg-that-is-force-to-be-reckoned" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Daggerheart</em></a> and beloved animated shows like <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/critical-role-confirms-2026-release-for-legends-of-vox-machina-s4-announces-fifth-and" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>The Legend of Vox Machina</em></a>.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/munchkin-vox-machina-game-board.jpg?itok=y5rfuNFn 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/munchkin-vox-machina-game-board.jpg?itok=0curuzqX 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The core gameplay is still the same Munchkin goodness. Explore, get loot, defeat monsters, and reach level 10 before anyone else does.It is the same malleable core loop that made <em>Munchkin</em> a household name since 2001, spawning countless <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/new-munchkin-babies-game-spits-up-over-tables-in-2022" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">spin-offs</a> and <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/munchkin-big-box-brings-definitive-game-to-backerkit" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">collector's editions</a>.&nbsp;The game is designed for 3-5 players ages 10+ and takes about 1-2 hours to finish.</p>

<p>Like their previous collaboration, <em>Munchkin Mighty Nein</em>, you play as a member of the iconic adventuring party. Each character has a thematically appropriate special ability. For example, Grog Strongjaw's <em>Heart of Gold</em> gives you a power boost if you help or get help in an encounter. The set will even include a d20 for some tabletop-themed shenanigans.</p>

<p><em>Munchkin Vox Machina</em> contains more than just the titular party. The game is packed with support characters like Shawn Gilmore, devious foes like Delilah Briarwood and Thordak, Leader of the Chroma Conclave, and powerful items like Percy's pistols and legendary Vestiges of Divergence like the Titanstone Knuckles.</p>

<p>A copy of <em>Munchkin Vox Machina</em> contains the following:</p>

<ul><li>172 Cards</li>
	<li>7 Character Cards</li>
	<li>A Deluxe Game Board</li>
	<li>7 Standies with Plastic Stands</li>
	<li>A Six-Sided Die and a Twenty-Sided Die</li>
	<li>A Rulesheet</li>
</ul><p><em>Munchkin Vox Machina</em> will be available in retail stores on March 2026. It will be sold at an MSRP of $39.95.</p>


</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/munchkin-vox-machina-brings-first-critical-role-campaign-to-iconic-card-game]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>