<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 16:39:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Core Keeper Bags and Blasts Update Brings New Sub-Biome and More Next Week]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/core-keeper-bags-and-blasts-update</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/core-keeper-bags-and-blasts-update-brings-new-sub-biome-and-more-next-week.1126983/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/core-keeper-bags-and-blasts-update<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer Pugstorm and publisher Fireshine Games have announced the&nbsp;<em>Core Keeper&nbsp;</em>Bags and Blasts update, which will bring a new sub-biome, a new boss, and more next week.</p>

<p>Bags and Blasts will serve as&nbsp;<em>Core Keeper</em>'s first major update since the sandbox survival game <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/core-keeper-10-update-patch-notes" rel="nofollow">launched out of Early Access back in August</a>. Its first major addition is the Oasis, a new sub-biome that you'll find within the game's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/guides/core-keeper-desert-of-beginnings-biome-guide" rel="nofollow">Desert of Beginnings area</a>.</p>

<p>In the Oasis, you'll find the adorable camel-like Drohmble, which you can ranch to "uncover a valuable (but stinky) resource useful for crafting new mid-late game weaponry". That one's only for those with strong stomachs, I suppose.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/core-keeper-bags-and-blasts-update-desert.jpg?itok=m_xQ3L4V 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/core-keeper-bags-and-blasts-update-desert.jpg?itok=5wj3e42f 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>You'll find&nbsp;<em>Core Keeper</em>'s new Oasis area in the Desert of Beginnings.</figcaption></figure><p>Of course, it's not just the Drohmble you'll have to look out for. Bags and Blasts will also introduce Nimruza, a giant "super cicada" boss who serves as one of&nbsp;<em>Core Keeper</em>'s "biggest fights yet", according to Pugstorm.</p>

<p>If you're a fan of using explosives in&nbsp;<em>Core Keeper</em>, you'll likely also appreciate the new Explosives skill tree, which comes complete with eight new skills for you to try out. New bomb types will also be added, as well as a new grenade weapon type.</p>

<p>Not only that, but&nbsp;<em>Core Keeper</em>'s Bags and Blasts update also introduces Pouches, a "highly-requested" community feature that allows you to carry various resources in dedicated spaces, making inventory management easier.</p>

<p>You can also take advantage of a new hotbar swapping feature that lets you decide which inventory row you see in your hotbar. All in all, it sounds like Bags and Blasts will be perfect for you if you like to tinker with your items for hours on end.</p>




<p><em>Core Keeper</em>'s Bags and Blasts update launches on March 10th. You can check the game out right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1621690/Core_Keeper/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/core-keeper/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-GB/games/store/core-keeper/9pkw4gmx4j8k" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/core-keeper-switch/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Nintendo Switch</a>, and you can read our Ashley's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/core-keeper-review" rel="nofollow">review of its 1.0 release here</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Xbox Insider Update Factory Resetting Xbox Consoles]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/new-xbox-insider-update-factory-reset</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-xbox-insider-update-factory-resetting-xbox-consoles.1126932/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/new-xbox-insider-update-factory-reset<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A new Xbox Insider update is apparently causing users' consoles to revert to factory settings, removing profiles and settings in the process.</p>

<p>According to <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/xboxs-latest-system-update-for-xbox-insiders-is-removing-their-user-profiles/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">VGC</a>, the problem is happening to those who are signed up to the Alpha and Alpha Skip-Ahead tiers of the Insider program, which allow users to download updates that will probably contain some pretty serious bugs given how early in the testing process they are.</p>

<p>That certainly seems to be the case with the latest update, which is apparently causing users' Xbox profiles, system setting preferences, and Quick Resume gameplay data to be deleted, essentially reverting the console to factory settings.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/xbox-insider-update-factory-settings-ui.jpg?itok=Hao4NWu2 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/xbox-insider-update-factory-settings-ui.jpg?itok=oa9t8KVo 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The latest Xbox Insider update comes with a pretty serious bug, by the sounds of things.</figcaption></figure><p>As VGC tells it, once the update is installed (which it will be if you're signed up to the aforementioned tiers, since it's now mandatory), the Xbox runs through its initial setup procedure rather than loading the Xbox dashboard as it normally would.</p>

<p>However, it sounds like the console isn't deleting users' installed games, which means it probably also isn't deleting save data stored locally. This does, however, mean that if this has happened to you, you'll probably need to re-add any profiles that were previously on your console.</p>

<p>If you're not signed up to the Xbox Insider program, then it sounds like you don't need to worry about this problem; it's just for those who are part of the Alpha and Alpha Skip-Ahead tiers.</p>

<p>Hopefully, by the time the latest system software update makes its way to the general populace, this problem will have been fixed; these tiers are for those who don't mind a few extra bugs with their updates, after all, although I don't think most Insider users bargained for this.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/xbox-insider-update-factory-settings-astronaut.jpg?itok=dCwMY8iJ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/xbox-insider-update-factory-settings-astronaut.jpg?itok=hffZpYqJ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Be careful if you're one of the Xbox Insider astronauts who likes to test new updates.</figcaption></figure><p>Rather amusingly, the update itself was only intended to fix a couple of bugs related to profile viewing and Dolby Vision, but it appears to have caused a much worse problem in the process.</p>

<p>Elsewhere in Xbox news, the company recently revealed that its upcoming&nbsp;<em>Fable&nbsp;</em>reboot has been <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/fable-reboot-delayed-2026" rel="nofollow">delayed to 2026</a>, but that work on the game is progressing apace. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40k: Darktide Nightmares and Visions Update Coming This Month]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/warhammer-40k-darktide-nightmares-and-visions-update-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40k-darktide-nightmares-and-visions-update-coming-this-month.1126875/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/warhammer-40k-darktide-nightmares-and-visions-update-announced<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Fatshark has revealed the&nbsp;<em>Warhammer 40k: Darktide&nbsp;</em>Nightmares and Visions update, a major patch for the game that will bring a new game activity, a rework for the Ogryn talent tree, and more later this month.</p>

<p>Set to release on March 25th across all platforms, Nightmares and Visions' first big addition to&nbsp;<em>Darktide&nbsp;</em>is the Mortis Trials activity, which is essentially a wave-based Horde-style mode in which you'll be able to build "new and exciting playstyles" each time you enter a trial.</p>

<p>Beating these trials will reward you with "secret information on some characters present on the Mourningstar", so it sounds rather like&nbsp;<em>Darktide&nbsp;</em>is <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/space-marine-2-datavault-update" rel="nofollow">following in the footsteps of&nbsp;</a><em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/space-marine-2-datavault-update" rel="nofollow">Space Marine 2</a>&nbsp;</em>by introducing extra lore as a reward for slaughtering the Imperium's enemies.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/warhammer-40k-darktide-nightmares-and-visions-update-ogryn.jpg?itok=7WLbriCS 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/warhammer-40k-darktide-nightmares-and-visions-update-ogryn.jpg?itok=RI2cHE5q 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Warhammer 40k: Darktide&nbsp;</em>is getting a new update later this month, and Ogryn players should be happy with what's coming.</figcaption></figure><p>You can also look forward to a rework for the Havoc game mode, with the endgame experience getting higher difficulty, a reassessed ranking system, and other miscellaneous improvements. Fatshark says it'll reveal more about the changes to Havoc soon.</p>

<p>If you're an Ogryn player, you'll also be pleased to know that the Ogryn talent tree is being reworked to give you "more build opportunities", and a few Ogryn weapons will also be tweaked to make the big guy feel a little better to play.</p>

<p>All in all, Fatshark says it has "37 pages of notes" relating to Nightmares and Visions. It's not clear whether the developer is referring to the patch notes with that number, but the update is set to be a big one, at any rate.</p>




<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Warhammer 40k: Darktide</em>, it's effectively Fatshark's grimdark&nbsp;<em>Warhammer 40k&nbsp;</em>answer to its horde-based FPS&nbsp;<em>Vermintide</em>.</p>

<p>The game, which sees you battling the minions of the Chaos God Nurgle as an Operative in the Hive City of Tertium, has been out for a couple of years now on PC and Xbox, but it <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/warhammer-40k-darktide-ps5-release-december" rel="nofollow">secured itself a PS5 release</a> late last year as well.</p>

<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Warhammer 40k: Darktide&nbsp;</em>on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1361210/Warhammer_40000_Darktide/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/EP4122-PPSA21255_00-0888672453602469" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/warhammer-40000-darktide/9nt3wc6rkbvq" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>. The Nightmares and Visions update lands on March 25th.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Until Dawn Remake Studio Ballistic Moon Reportedly "Effectively Closed"]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ballistic-moon-closed-report-until-dawn</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/until-dawn-remake-studio-ballistic-moon-reportedly-effectively-closed.1126836/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ballistic-moon-closed-report-until-dawn<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Until Dawn&nbsp;</em>remake developer Ballistic Moon has reportedly been "effectively closed", with only a handful of employees remaining at the studio.</p>

<p>According to a report by <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/until-dawn-remake-developer-ballistic-moon-effectively-closed/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Insider Gaming</a>, which cites "multiple sources with knowledge of the situation", the remaining staff at Ballistic Moon were let go in December. Those layoffs followed staff reductions back in September, just before the&nbsp;<em>Until Dawn&nbsp;</em>remake's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/until-dawn-remake-release-date" rel="nofollow">October release</a>.</p>

<p>Insider Gaming's sources say that around 40 staff were let go in September, and that about 20 more lost their jobs in December, with only the studio's founders and "possibly" a few more employees remaining at Ballistic Moon. No developers, marketing execs, or PR folks are still there, apparently.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/until-dawn-remake-ballistic-moon-closed-rumor-screens.jpg?itok=mrDN0JH6 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/until-dawn-remake-ballistic-moon-closed-rumor-screens.jpg?itok=XG57tRiK 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Until Dawn&nbsp;</em>remake Ballistic Moon has apparently effectively ceased to exist.</figcaption></figure><p>Ballistic Moon's gutting effectively means that the&nbsp;<em>Until Dawn&nbsp;</em>remake has nobody working on patches or updates; a source told Insider Gaming that people were "sharing bugs" to make Ballistic Moon aware of them, but that "there is no one working on patch support".</p>

<p>Apparently, Ballistic Moon's owners attempted to keep the ball rolling with regards to further support for&nbsp;<em>Until Dawn</em>, but Sony wasn't interested. Sources also told Insider Gaming that Ballistic Moon's owners were looking for new publishers for other projects, but they weren't successful.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, it probably isn't a surprise that Ballistic Moon is in its current position. Reportedly,&nbsp;<em>Until Dawn&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/until-dawn-remake-ps5-player-count-concord" rel="nofollow">debuted to a lower PS5 player count</a> than the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/concord-shutting-down-refunds" rel="nofollow">doomed shooter&nbsp;<em>Concord</em></a>, and its Steam player count peak of <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/2172010/charts/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">just over 2,600 players</a> isn't particularly noteworthy either.</p>

<p>Given that Sony currently seems to be in the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/playstation-studio-visual-arts-layoffs-report" rel="nofollow">middle</a> of a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sony-leadership-shakeup" rel="nofollow">rethink</a> when it comes to its gaming operations, studios like Ballistic Moon are unfortunately likely to be the first in the gaming giant's firing line.</p>




<p>Of course, with respect to Ballistic Moon, I'd question the necessity of remaking&nbsp;<em>Until Dawn&nbsp;</em>in the first place. The original's not particularly old, and it seems to me that a remaster along the lines of&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/horizon-zero-dawn-remastered-esrb" rel="nofollow"><em>Horizon Zero Dawn</em>'s</a> would have worked just as well.</p>

<p>In any case, if you do want to see the fruits of Ballistic Moon's labor, the&nbsp;<em>Until Dawn&nbsp;</em>remake is available now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2172010/Until_Dawn/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a> and <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/until-dawn/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PS5</a>, and you can read our Tyler's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/until-dawn-2024-review-new-faces-old-blood" rel="nofollow">review of the game here</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>