<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 14:46:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Sues Tencent Over Horizon-esque Light of Motiram]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sony-tencent-light-of-motiram-lawsuit</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-sues-tencent-over-horizon-esque-light-of-motiram.1256004/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Sony has filed a lawsuit against Chinese gaming giant Tencent over the latter's open-world survival game&nbsp;<em>Light of Motiram</em>, which Sony alleges is a "slavish clone" of its own&nbsp;<em>Horizon&nbsp;</em>series of games.</p>

<p>As spotted by <a href="https://www.reuters.com/legal/litigation/sony-sues-tencent-allegedly-ripping-off-horizon-video-games-2025-07-28/" rel="nofollow">Reuters</a>, the lawsuit was filed in California federal court and accuses Tencent of copyright and trademark infringement over&nbsp;<em>Light of Motiram</em>, which it says contains several elements from the&nbsp;<em>Horizon&nbsp;</em>franchise.</p>

<p>According to Sony, it declined to work with Tencent on a&nbsp;<em>Horizon&nbsp;</em>spinoff game last year, and the announcement for&nbsp;<em>Light of Motiram</em>, which looks suspiciously similar to&nbsp;<em>Horizon</em>, followed soon afterwards.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/light-of-motiram-sony-tencent-lawsuit.jpg?itok=ff21AEIv 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/light-of-motiram-sony-tencent-lawsuit.jpg?itok=gEzoLXQY 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Pop quiz: is this shot from&nbsp;<em>Horizon&nbsp;</em>or&nbsp;<em>Light of Motiram</em>? (It's the latter.)</figcaption></figure><p>As part of its lawsuit, Sony is asking for damages (although the amount is undisclosed), as well as an order to block Tencent from violating its IP rights, according to Reuters. Presumably, that means development on&nbsp;<em>Light of Motiram&nbsp;</em>would either immediately cease or swerve direction swiftly.</p>

<p>In case you need a reminder,&nbsp;<em>Light of Motiram&nbsp;</em>was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/light-of-motiram-announced-tencent-horizon" rel="nofollow">announced back in November last year</a>. When I reported on its announcement, I said it had "strong 'we have&nbsp;<em>Horizon&nbsp;</em>at home' energy", and I stand by that; the trailer is...well, brazen feels like too mild a word, honestly.</p>

<p>Let's just say that&nbsp;<em>Light of Motiram</em>'s aesthetics, robot wildlife, and tribal outfits are extremely strongly reminiscent of&nbsp;<em>Horizon</em>, so I can understand the grounds on which Sony is pursuing this lawsuit.</p>

<p>You can check out the original announcement trailer for&nbsp;<em>Light of Motiram&nbsp;</em>below if you want to remind yourself of what, exactly, it's being accused of stealing.</p>




<p>Tencent's proposed&nbsp;<em>Horizon&nbsp;</em>collab isn't the only external partnership in the franchise that Sony has backed away from in recent months; back in January, it was reported that an unannounced&nbsp;<em>Horizon&nbsp;</em>MMO, developed in conjunction with&nbsp;<em>Guild Wars&nbsp;</em>studio NCSoft, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/horizon-mmo-canceled-report" rel="nofollow">had been canceled</a>.</p>

<p>It remains to be seen whether this lawsuit will materially affect&nbsp;<em>Light of Motiram</em>'s development, but in the meantime, you can still <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3319630/LIGHT_OF_MOTIRAM/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">wishlist Tencent's game on Steam</a> if you want.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sony-tencent-light-of-motiram-lawsuit]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atari Acquires Majority Stake in SteamWorld Studio Thunderful]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/atari-thunderful-majority-stake</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/atari-acquires-majority-stake-in-steamworld-studio-thunderful.1255986/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Atari has announced that it will acquire a majority stake in&nbsp;<em>SteamWorld&nbsp;</em>publisher Thunderful, and the latter has also revealed that its CEO will be stepping down as soon as a successor is found.</p>

<p>According to an Atari press release, the company will be acquiring 82% of Thunderful's shares, a move CEO Wade Rosen describes as "another important milestone in Atari's development" and a big part of the expansion of Atari's "publishing and development capabilities in the European region".</p>

<p>In a separate <a href="https://thunderfulgroup.com/news-room/press-releases/2025-07-29-thunderful-group-initiates-restructuring-and-provides-business-update" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">press release</a> of its own, Thunderful says that it will be undergoing a restructuring operation that will result in layoffs across the studio, with <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/lost-in-random-eternal-die-roguelike-announced" rel="nofollow">recent release&nbsp;</a><em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/lost-in-random-eternal-die-roguelike-announced" rel="nofollow">Lost in Random: The Eternal Die</a>&nbsp;</em>selling less than Thunderful had hoped in its second quarter of the year.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/lost-in-random-the-eternal-die-atari-thunderful.jpg?itok=eYaPsEa9 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/lost-in-random-the-eternal-die-atari-thunderful.jpg?itok=wD0LkoCp 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Atari now owns a majority stake in Thunderful.</figcaption></figure><p>Despite the restructuring, Thunderful says its upcoming slate remains the same, although the studio says it has been "overly dependent on individual game releases" in recent years. It's not entirely clear how the studio intends to pivot away from that reliance, however.</p>

<p>One thing that will be changing as part of Thunderful's restructuring is its CEO. Per <a href="https://thunderfulgroup.com/news-room/press-releases/2025-07-29-martin-walfisz-to-leave-the-role-as-ceo-of-thunderful-group-ab" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">another press release</a>, current CEO Martin Walfisz will be departing the company, but he'll be remaining in his position "until a new CEO has assumed the role".</p>

<p>He will, however, not be remaining beyond December 31st this year at the latest, so we can assume that Thunderful will have found itself another CEO by then.</p>

<p>Atari's investment in Thunderful follows a challenging year and a half for the studio. In January last year, Thunderful <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/thunderful-layoffs-restructuring" rel="nofollow">laid off around 20% of its workforce</a>, and it followed that decision with the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/thunderful-closes-studio-financials" rel="nofollow">closure of Stage Clear Studios last May</a>&nbsp;and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/thunderful-layoffs-development" rel="nofollow">yet more staff cuts in November</a>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/last-kids-on-earth-atari-thunderful.jpg?itok=abtRRxyG 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/last-kids-on-earth-atari-thunderful.jpg?itok=Kowq6S90 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Thunderful closed&nbsp;<em>Last Kids on Earth and the Staff of Doom&nbsp;</em>developer Stage Clear Studios last year.</figcaption></figure><p>Atari, meanwhile, has been on something of an acquisition spree in the last couple of years. In 2024, the company <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/atari-intellivision-acquisition" rel="nofollow">acquired its erstwhile rival Intellivision</a>, as well as <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/surgeon-simulator-acquired-by-infogrames" rel="nofollow">the&nbsp;<em>Surgeon Simulator&nbsp;</em>IP</a> through its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/atari-infogrames-publishing-revival" rel="nofollow">newly-revived Infogrames label</a>.</p>

<p>We'll have to wait and see what its majority stake in Thunderful yields for the latter, but it's unlikely that the&nbsp;<em>SteamWorld&nbsp;</em>studio will continue without some major internal policy shake-ups. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/atari-thunderful-majority-stake]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shinobi: Art of Vengeance is the Perfect Balance Between Modern and Retro]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-is-perfect-balance-between-modern-and-retro</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-is-the-perfect-balance-between-modern-and-retro.1255914/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>It’s been 14 years since the last entry in the 2D action platformer series, <em>Shinobi</em>. Now, the game is back in a big way with <em>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance</em>, and <em>Streets of Rage 4</em> developer LizardCube is leading the charge. TechRaptor had the opportunity to play for two hours,&nbsp;and we came away impressed. Our take: fluid controls and flexible combat makes <em>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance</em> one of the most anticipated 2D action platformers of this year.</p>

<p><em>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance</em> follows Joe Musashi, the master ninja of the Oboro Clan. When he returns home, he finds it burned in flames while its inhabitants are turned to stone by the evil ENE Corporation. Joe sets out on a revenge quest against the corporation.&nbsp;</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-cinematic.jpg?itok=UaQlTlh6 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-cinematic.jpg?itok=VZYEu_eQ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The demo starts off right after these events in a dense forest, and the art style is immediately eye-catching. The clean lines and sharp lines making up Joe and his enemies create an immediate contrast between the foreground and background, an important distinction in a 2D game. It’s a similar approach that LizardCube took with <em>Streets of Rage 4</em>, but with a historical Japanese twist.</p>

<p>The gameplay is the true star in <em>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance</em>. Despite being a 2D platformer, I felt like I had a lot of freedom in deciding the direction of Joe’s attacks. For example, if there was an enemy above or below him, I could slash in that direction instead of only being able to attack right in front of me. This gives <em>Art of Vengeance</em> a much more modern feel. The visual effects also add to the visceral impact of each strike, confirming that my attacks struck the enemy. This doubles as a helpful visual guide to make sure that every enemy was dead before I moved on throughout the level.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-platforming.jpg?itok=FHHC3348 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-platforming.jpg?itok=N270lzd5 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>As you attack, you’ll also build up your ninja stack meter, which lets you unleash mystical attacks. The first one you receive has Joe spit out a fireball to burn his enemies. It’s a great way to switch up the gameplay and reward players with more attacking options.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Joe also has two incredibly powerful ultimate attacks. The first one is Shinobi Execution, which is an auto-kill attack on all enemies on the screen who have a Japanese kanji above them. To make the symbol appear, players will have to wear down enemies, usually close to emptying their HP bar. The screen turns red, and Joe slashes through all of them. Shinobi Execution doesn’t cost anything to utilize, so it makes for a stylish finisher during fights.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-flame.jpg?itok=FgLuoJhX 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-flame.jpg?itok=EuQe3B6j 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The second has Joe summoning his inner ninjutsu powers to conjure up draconic flames and leave enemies constantly burning. There aren’t any special conditions like the Shinobi Execution, but Ninjutsu requires three ninja stacks to activate. So there’s a strategic trade-off of using your regular mystical attacks and the ultimate Ninjutsu attack.</p>

<p>In this demo, I was also given a taste of the game’s Arcade mode, which lets you replay levels but without any of the cutscenes and story exposition. Once you clear these levels, you’re able to see a plethora of different stats that you’re graded on, including the number of deaths, the number of relics found, and whether you’ve taken no damage and avoided using Ninjutsu. It’ll also provide you with a final letter grade. While I seemingly didn’t receive any rewards for completing levels on Arcade mode, I’m hoping that changes as it could further incentivize players to try the mode out.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-map.jpg?itok=ghGERocY 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-map.jpg?itok=5QA6n2A6 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>I’ve only played a small portion of <em>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance</em>, but I definitely enjoyed what I’ve experienced so far. I love how Joe Musashi feels to control, with plenty of movement options and weapon variety to prevent gameplay from feeling stiff and stale. Nailing that down is important as you get further into the game, and I’m excited to see what the rest of the game has in store. <em>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance</em> launches on PC, PlayStation, Switch, and Xbox on August 29.</p>

<hr><p><em><strong>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance</strong>&nbsp;was played at an in-person event at SEGA.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>George is a freelance journalist, who has written about video games for publications like IGN, Digital Trends, and Variety.</p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-is-perfect-balance-between-modern-and-retro]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>