<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor.net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor.net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 07:14:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Void War Back On Steam After Games Workshop DMCA'd It]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/void-war-back-on-steam-after-games-workshop-dmcad-it</link>
            <guid>1428775</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>It was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ftl-like-void-war-dmcad-allegedly-by-games-workshop-0" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="c0fe5dc8-146f-4c11-b6a8-2b5f2365e5bd" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">two weeks ago when we reported </a>that <em>Void War</em> had been DMCA'd by a party claiming to be Games Workshop. Now, we can confirm that it was indeed Games Workshop that filed the <em>Void War</em> DMCA as Tundra Interactive has told us more about this story, and how <em>Void War</em> is back up on Steam now.</p><p>After failing to communicate with Tundra Interactive for a week, Games Workshop finally replied, and confirmed that the <em>Void War</em> DMCA was on their behalf. That means that Games Workshop does employ a lawyer named Mal Reynolds, despite how unlikely that seemed, and it is a deeply ironic name given the <em>Firefly</em> character with the same name. Tundra Interactive explains what issue Games Workshop had with <em>Void War</em>:</p><blockquote><p>They said their concern was limited to a specific shot from one of the trailers on the store page, arguing that certain elements could create the mistaken impression that Void War is associated with Games Workshop, specifically what they described as “the oversized convex shoulder pads with a metallic rim.”</p></blockquote><p>Tundra Interactive emphasizes that all the artwork in the trailer for <em>Void War</em> was original work created by their artists. Despite that, in the goal of a fast resolution, they have removed the story trailer that had the offending image. With that done, they were able to get the game back up on Steam. Tundra Interactive stated, "We may re-upload an updated version later after we find time to adjust that shot, but for now our priority is shipping content and finishing multi-language font support so we can finally deliver proper translations." saying that new versions of the trailer may come.</p><p>It is possible to view the trailer via a <a href="https://video.fastly.steamstatic.com/store_trailers/257147370/movie_max.mp4" rel="nofollow">link from SteamDB</a> which has an image at 34 seconds which match the description given by Games Workshop, as well as confirmed by Tundra Interactive that it is the offending image.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/void-war-armor.jpg?itok=UDHSN2MG 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1621" height="913">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/void-war-armor.jpg?itok=nSf2oecs 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="676">
                  

  </picture><p>Games Workshop has a history of being... very protective of its IP, dating back to actions like trying to trademark the term <a href="https://gizmodo.com/games-workshop-is-still-claiming-to-own-the-trademark-t-5982201" rel="nofollow">Space Marine</a>, to the contentious relationship with fans over things like fan animations that they <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games-workshop-is-trying-to-shut-down-fan-animations/" rel="nofollow">took steps to ban</a>.</p><p>We previously reached out to Games Workshop, but they did not reply regarding whether they had filed the DMCA against Tundra Interactive.&nbsp;</p><p>Hopefully, all's well that ends well and Tundra Interactive can get back to making their game without further legal hurdles. <em>Void War </em>is <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2853590/Void_War/" rel="nofollow">available on Steam </a>and also <a href="https://tundra-interactive.itch.io/void-war" rel="nofollow">on Itch.Io</a>, which will also provide a Steam key.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>A longtime lover of speculative fiction, in almost all its forms, Don joined TechRaptor in 2014 on a whim sending in an application as he was looking for… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/don-parsons">More about Don</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/void-war-back-on-steam-after-games-workshop-dmcad-it]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Echoes of Elysium Preview - More Sandbox than Survival, but all Airship]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/echoes-of-elysium-preview-more-sandbox-than-survival-but-all-airship</link>
            <guid>1428622</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Echoes of Elysium</em> is the brainchild of Loric Games, a group of former Mythic Entertainment employees with a smattering of Bethesda developers mixed in. Having worked on titles such as <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/opinion/endurance-star-wars-old-republic" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="b37f30ad-c8cb-4f8d-a44b-58b67d95bb81" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Star Wars: The Old Republic</em></a> and <em>Dark Age of Camelot</em>, the studio has taken their extensive experience to head into uncharted territory with their debut title. Learn how Loric Games is approaching Early Access, and whether the sandbox survival airship RPG is for you with our <em>Echoes of Elysium</em> preview.</p><h2>Colorful, Carefree, and Calming</h2><p>Set as a sandbox RPG with survival elements thrown in, <em>Echoes of Elysium</em> takes a different path than other games in the survival genre. You’ll find a bright blue sky, fluffy clouds, bright rooftops, and vivid flowers throughout the world’s floating islands. For the land of the dead, it is quite cheerful. Combined with the atmospheric music, the title can even be labeled calming.</p><p>The art is the main reason I became interested in the game. Survival games typically evoke an apocalyptic style with darker colors, dreariness, and an overbearing sense of despair. With a color scheme that deviates from the norm, it's easy for <em>Echoes of Elysium</em> to stand out in the crowded survival genre.<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/using-a-harpoon-echoes-of-elysium.jpg?itok=J0UTlEBf 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/using-a-harpoon-echoes-of-elysium.jpg?itok=CLMHnM4U 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture></p><p>While there are some survival aspects to the game, the title absolutely feels like a sandbox airship builder. You need to harvest rocks, trees, plant fiber, and fuel. You build your airship, which acts as a flying base. There’s food to forage and inventory to manage, but items don't spoil, and basic resources are easy to gather.</p><p>You don’t have any thirst or hunger, and your stamina mainly comes into play when gliding across the open expanse or fighting. Instead of having to track down your items, which you still have to do if you were away from your ship when you perished, you’ll be cursed with a debuff. When you die and respawn, you’ll need to find food that cures your new status or wait until the buff wears off.</p><p>I enjoyed gliding through the air, seeing the different islands, and finding new items to harvest. However, there’s not much else to do aside from that. The narrative, which is an element the team is still working on, is barely there, at best.</p><p>You get a story in the opening cutscene, are introduced to an NPC that aids you, and receive a quick tutorial. Once you capture your first Dry Dock, however, you can spend hours wandering the vast expanse without discovering another snippet of story. It’s even possible to skip part of the story if you find the boss’s den by accident.<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/npc-lethe-narrative-echoes-of-elysium.jpg?itok=71ehVh16 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/npc-lethe-narrative-echoes-of-elysium.jpg?itok=UVmS75fR 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture></p><p>During a preview presentation with Loric Games, it was admitted that the narrative doesn’t rank as high on the list of important items. Making airships into flying bases and nailing the associated mechanics are the focuses and stars of the game. The story will be coming, but it may not be as extensive or featured as prominently as some survival or RPG players will want.&nbsp;</p><p>As a survival title, <em>Echoes of Elysium</em> misses the mark. There’s no pressure to actually survive. If you don’t die, you never need to eat or drink. There are no elements affecting your mood. Aside from falling out of the air and the scattering of enemies you can encounter, death is far from a concern.</p><p>As a sandbox builder, the title hits the main points, making it far more successful in that regard. You can build beautiful airships without having to worry about your skill as a builder, thanks to the rounded walls. Weight isn’t even an issue as long as you have enough propellers, allowing you to truly get creative with your build.<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/enemy-airship-echoes-of-alysium.jpg?itok=Sk5fhY0a 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/enemy-airship-echoes-of-alysium.jpg?itok=ILm6cHwI 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture></p><p>The biggest downfall of <em>Echoes of Elysium</em> is the somewhat grindy nature of the game when it comes to advanced resources, especially fuel, and the time it takes to travel from one island cluster to another. I often abandoned my airship to traverse with my glider. Even over large expanses, it was my preferred method of travel. While airships aren’t as slow as the ships in Skull &amp; Bones, it’s still a time investment to make your way around the map looking for resources.</p><p>On top of that, the game crashes, there can be glitches causing enemies to become invincible, and items can fall out of the sky, making them inaccessible. At first, I experienced quite a bit of lag that made playing almost impossible. That has vastly improved, but people with older machines may experience what feels like never ending lag.</p><p><em>Echoes of Elysium</em> has great bones and some great potential, it just needed more time in the oven. More narrative would add some structure to the experience. Additional resources, more concrete ways to find said resources, and more mechanics to craft items easily would ensure everyone who plays the title understands how to advance.<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/echoes-of-elysium-gliding_0.jpg?itok=8NSx7aLS 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/echoes-of-elysium-gliding_0.jpg?itok=bSpD9Iz7 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture></p><h2><em>Echoes of Elysium</em> Preview | Final Thoughts</h2><p>Even though there are issues, Loric Games’ outlook on Early Access assures fans they will continue working on the title. Taking a stance, a few years old, the studio will be listening to player feedback and furthering development through the EA phase, with the player base in mind. While this was how EA originally started for many games in the past, this hasn’t been the modus operandi for the majority of current EA releases. If you’re interested in the growth of the game and impacting how the world evolves, <em>Echoes of Elysium</em> will be a great fit for you. If you’d rather have an almost completed title that’s pretty polished with lots of content for you to play through, you may want to wait until <em>Echoes of Elysium</em> fully launches.&nbsp;</p><hr><p><em><strong>Echoes of Elysium</strong> was previewed on PC with a code provided by the publisher over the course of 11 hours. All screenshots were taken during the course of the preview.</em><br>&nbsp;</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ashley Erickson is an experienced writer focusing on the video games industry since 2013. Starting off with cosplay features, she moved to game guides and… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/ashley-erikson">More about Ashley</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/echoes-of-elysium-preview-more-sandbox-than-survival-but-all-airship]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Adventuring Academy Season 7 Trailer Brings More Comedy and TTRPG Advice]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/new-adventuring-academy-season-7-trailer-brings-more-comedy-and-ttrpg-advice</link>
            <guid>1428604</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Dropout has dropped a new trailer for <em>Adventuring Academy</em> Season 7. The latest season of the comedy talk show features the company's resident TTRPG expert, Brennan Lee Mulligan, chatting with a new suite of guests.</p><p>The new <em>Adventuring Academy</em> Season 7 trailer provides more of what fans have come to expect from the Dropout crew. For those not aware, <em>Adventuring Academy</em> is a talk show where Brennan Lee Mulligan, the mind behind the platform's comedic actual play anthology series <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/dimension-20-gladlands-is-mad-max-if-everyone-wasnt-being-so-rude-interview" rel="nofollow"><em>Dimension 20</em></a>, casually chats with a host about tabletop gaming.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/adventuring-academy-season-7-vic-michaelis-set-photo.jpg?itok=BL1shiCB 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1600" height="900">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/adventuring-academy-season-7-vic-michaelis-set-photo.jpg?itok=2SaUTWJf 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><p>These talks span a wide number of topics in regards to play for both new and experienced players. How do you handle a player character dying? How do you make a memorable character in your game? How much worldbuilding is too much? What steps can you take to make your players feel comfortable and safe when undertaking dark or intense scenarios?&nbsp;</p><p>At the same time, these episodes can veer into comedic asides and passionate hot takes. That doesn't appear to have changed in the <em>Adventuring Academy</em> Season 7 trailer. A guest declaring their dislike of Gandalf from <em>Lord of the Rings</em>. Brennan's slightly changed relationship with snacking and almonds. The edict of "mandatory queerness." It is all in line with Dropout's distinct irreverent brand.</p><p>The new season's guests are a mix of Dropout regulars and other creatives in the space. They include Vic Michaelis, Robbie Daymond, Oscar Montoya, Kimia Behpoornia, Aabria Iyengar, Emily Friedman, Mica Burton, Quinns Smith, and Jasper William Cartwright.</p><p>Overall, the line-up is consistent with past seasons. Prior guests have included Dropout talent like Jacob Wysocki, Sam Reich, Lou Wilson, and Ally Beardsley, as well as other professional tabletop creatives like Jasmine Bhullar, Deborah Ann Woll, Dave Walters, Marisha Ray, and <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/critical-role-campaign-4-trailer-introduces-us-to-land-of-araman" rel="nofollow">Critical Role's</a> own Matt Mercer.</p><p><em>Adventuring Academy </em>Season 7 premieres exclusively on Dropout on February 20th.&nbsp;</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/new-adventuring-academy-season-7-trailer-brings-more-comedy-and-ttrpg-advice]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>