<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 16:37:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Embracer CEO Lars Wingefors Steps Down Ahead of Three-Way Split]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/embracer-ceo-lars-wingefors-steps-down</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/embracer-ceo-lars-wingefors-steps-down-ahead-of-three-way-split.1215702/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/embracer-ceo-lars-wingefors-steps-down<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Embracer Group has announced that its CEO Lars Wingefors will step down later this year, with current deputy CEO Phil Rogers set to take on the role when Wingefors departs.</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://embracer.com/releases/lars-wingefors-proposed-to-be-elected-as-executive-chair-of-the-board-of-embracer-phil-rogers-appointed-new-ceo/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">news post</a> on its official website, Embracer says that Wingefors' departure and Rogers' appointment are both part of the "transformation process", which will see Embracer <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/embracer-group-splitting-three-companies" rel="nofollow">becoming three separate entities</a> in charge of different aspects of the current company structure later this year.</p>

<p>That ongoing process also saw Embracer <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/embracer-fellowship-entertainment-coffee-stain" rel="nofollow">renaming itself to Fellowship Entertainment</a> last month, with current subsidiary Coffee Stain also due to spin off into its own entity sometime later this year.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/satisfactory-coffee-stain-embracer-group_0.jpg?itok=l--LqEHi 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/satisfactory-coffee-stain-embracer-group_0.jpg?itok=-mrteLVK 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Coffee Stain, publisher of games like&nbsp;<em>Satisfactory</em>, will spin off from parent Embracer Group later this year.</figcaption></figure><p>Wingefors says that while Embracer's "road has&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/embracer-group-financials-q2-2024" rel="nofollow">not always been straight</a>", he's "incredibly proud" of the company's achievements under his direction. He then says his move away from the CEO position will allow him to focus on "strategic initiatives, M&amp;A, and capital allocation", which I can't imagine was his response when asked what he wanted to be as a child.</p>

<p>Despite his departure, Wingefors won't be completely absent from Embracer (or Fellowship Entertainment, as it will be known by the end of the 2025 calendar year). He'll take the position of the board's executive chairman, with current chair Kicki Wallje-Lund moving to the deputy chair role.</p>

<p>Changes in Embracer's management come after a fairly turbulent time for the company. As part of a company-wide restructuring effort, Embracer <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/embracer-has-laid-off-8-of-its-employees-and-it-isnt-done-yet-despite-record-quarter" rel="nofollow">laid off hundreds of employees</a> last year, additionally closing studios like&nbsp;<em>Saints Row&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Agents of Mayhem&nbsp;</em>developer <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/embracer-shuts-down-saints-row-developer-volition" rel="nofollow">Volition</a>.</p>

<p>Despite this, Embracer has enjoyed a couple of recent successes, most notably Warhorse Studios'&nbsp;<em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2</em>, which <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-sales-3m" rel="nofollow">managed to sell three million copies</a> in its first three months on sale.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-sales-embracer-group-lars.jpg?itok=RUhwzc2p 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-sales-embracer-group-lars.jpg?itok=vddaszHx 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Medieval RPG&nbsp;<em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2&nbsp;</em>was one of Embracer Group's recent successes.</figcaption></figure><p>It remains to be seen whether Wingefors' stepping down will materially affect Embracer's (or Fellowship's) operations. Stay tuned for more on this.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Onimusha: Way of the Sword Preview - Miyamoto Musashi Mayhem]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/onimusha-way-of-sword-preview-miyamoto-musashi-mayhem</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/onimusha-way-of-the-sword-preview-miyamoto-musashi-mayhem.1215585/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/onimusha-way-of-sword-preview-miyamoto-musashi-mayhem<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Just recently, I had the chance to review&nbsp;<em>Onimusha 2</em>'s new remaster, and less than an hour in I was sold on this franchise. Since my passion for&nbsp;the series is so new, I am greatly anticipating the upcoming&nbsp;<em>Onimusha: Way of the Sword</em>.</p>

<p>Even better, we had a chance to see a hands-off gameplay demonstration of&nbsp;<em>Onimusha: Way of the Sword</em>&nbsp;at Summer Game Fest 2025. It's bold and action-packed. It's the series you know and love, redefined for the modern age.</p>



<h2>The Legendary Swordsman, Miyamoto Musashi</h2>

<p>Producer Koichi Shibata was playing the live demo for&nbsp;<em>Onimusha: Way of the Sword</em>. The setting appears to be largely in Kyoto. Our protagonist is one of Japan's most legendary historical figures: Miyamoto Musashi.</p>

<p>This is Musashi in his younger years, so he's more concerned with training with the blade, rather than the Oni Gauntlet attached to his arm.</p>

<p>Fans familiar with the series will recognize the Oni Gauntlet. It's the means by which our protagonist absorbs the souls of Genma, the enemies of the series.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This gauntlet appears to have a personality, so we see a bit of banter between Musashi and the feminine voice residing inside of it. This dynamic is intriguing, and Musashi seems like a silly fellow in this one.&nbsp;<em>Onimusha</em>&nbsp;is already a quirky series, so there's great potential in the storytelling.</p>

<p>In this demo, the players works their way through the grounds of a shrine or temple, called Kiyomizudera Shockingly, Genma are attacking people and Musashi is ready to dive into the action.&nbsp;</p>



<h2>Return of the Issen</h2>

<p>Returning players will find many familiar elements from the series return in this installment. Musashi can hack and slash away with his sword as a basic attack. Enemies, of course, drop colored souls which are absorbed in the gauntlet.</p>

<p>He's able to parry, and in one instance of combat, we see&nbsp;<em>Onimusha: Way of the Sword</em>&nbsp;leverage its next-gen capabilities. Musashi parries a blow from a Genma and redirects the enemy into a flaming torch. The enemy takes extra damage, so environmental damage adds a bit more depth to the combat.</p>

<p>In another instance of combat, an archer draws its bow and aims at Musashi. It's inside a small building, so Musashi grabs the tatami mat, blocks the arrows, then throws the mat at the Genma. This makes the Genma vulnerable to your attack and stuns them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Perhaps the most iconic element of&nbsp;the series, the Issen counter, also makes a return. Attacking an enemy right as they are about to hit you allows for a cinematic attack that usually one-hit kills lesser enemies. The hands-on demo makes it look easy, but I imagine that's from many hours of practice.</p>

<p>We saw Musashi use an Issen on multiple enemies at once; essentially, you can chain together an Issen attack on foes in close proximity to one another. This allows for you to take out multiple foes in quick succession, like the badass that you are.</p>



<h2>Terrifyingly Good Graphics</h2>

<p>Flying Genma -- the annoying little buggers that they are -- make a return and absorb souls from fallen foes. The way Musashi attacks and defeats these enemies are especially cinematic.&nbsp;<em>Onimusha: Way of the Sword</em>&nbsp;is a seriously gorgeous game.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Indeed, this might just be Capcom's best looking game yet. The forest surrounding the temple is gorgeous. Capcom uses light fog and lighting to create an astonishing view.&nbsp;</p>

<p>My favorite enemy we saw were these crow-like humanoids. They're swift and can evade attacks. There's this doppleganger-like effect where you try to hit them, but the real one comes just out of reach. It's a tricky fight for Musashi!</p>

<p>We carry on through the shrine grounds, this time coming across a dark mass. Musashi can absorb these masses and get a glimpse into the past. It seems like absorbing these might be a main objective of the game.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Absorbing the mass shows dark, shadowy figures on the shrine grounds. We reach a larger building in the shrine and see the Genma are throwing peasants over the edge of a railing, down a cliff.</p>

<p>This is actually inspired by real folklore of the area, something I was vaguely familiar with. But our trance is soon interrupted as Musashi's longtime rival, Ganryu Sasaki, appears. He has his own Oni Gauntlet and, apparently, fully embraces its power.</p>



<h2>Battle of the Oni</h2>

<p>An exhilarating sword fight ensues. This battle really seems to really capture the feeling of a duel, with the warriors trading blows, parrying and the like. We also noticed that Ganryu has a health and stamina gauge, giving me vague hints of&nbsp;<em>Sekiro</em>&nbsp;inspiration.</p>

<p>The battle is flashy. Ganryu's helmet breaks off from your fight. Depleting his stamina gauge also allows you to do a targeted strike; you can actually choose where on his body to attack. These are color-coded and give you orbs of a particular color.</p>

<p>So if you need health during a boss fight, targeting the corresponding color will give you orbs to heal. Stabbing Ganryu in the head or abdomen were choices here, adding a little strategic element to combat.</p>



<h2><em>Onimusha: Way of the Sword</em> Preview | Final Thoughts</h2>

<p>We also look at one final boss encounter after Ganryu. As if reality itself is shattering like glass, malice starts to ooze out of a fissure and out comes Byakue, a large, axe-wielding Genma boss.</p>

<p>This fight features more and more parries and clashes. The parrying of attacks really stands out hear, and there seem to be so many different animations. It's quite exciting to watch, so I can only imagine how fun it is to play.&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>Onimusha: Way of the Sword</em>&nbsp;had an impressive showing, and is perhaps my favorite game of the show. It's a game that shows so much dedication to the craft and doesn't deviate from what&nbsp;made&nbsp;<em>Onimusha&nbsp;</em>such a coveted IP in the first place: some good ol' action-packed demon slaying.</p>

<hr><p><em><strong>Onimusha&nbsp;</strong>was previewed Summer Game Fest.&nbsp;</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Austin cut his teeth writing various&nbsp; fan-fiction stories on the RuneScape forums when he was in elementary school. Later on, he developed a deep love for… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/austin-suther">More about Austin</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil 9 Requiem Closed Door Presentation Shows Classic RE Puzzles And A Horrific New Creature]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/resident-evil-9-requiem-closed-door-presentation-shows-classic-re-puzzles-and</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/resident-evil-9-requiem-closed-door-presentation-shows-classic-re-puzzles-and-a-horrific-new-creature.1215582/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/resident-evil-9-requiem-closed-door-presentation-shows-classic-re-puzzles-and<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>One of the largest surprises of the Summer Game Fest Showcase was the announcement and debut of a <em>Resident Evil 9 Requiem</em> trailer. Shortly after the public trailer was released, we got a chance to visit the Capcom theater to see not only live Onimusha gameplay but also a segment of gameplay from <em>Resident Evil 9</em>.</p>

<p>The gameplay segment opened with Grace hanging upside down and strapped to a hospital gurney. This scene was&nbsp;<em>tense</em>. Lingering on Graces face, and the subject of her attention, while she didn't say anything there was a clear conveyance of everything that was going through Grace's mind as she planned her escape.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/resident-evil-requiem-demo-start.jpg?itok=oFgfXfsq 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/resident-evil-requiem-demo-start.jpg?itok=r4bHeKtl 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Grace waking up, strapped to a gurney upside down, and hooked up to an IV slowly taking her blood</figcaption></figure><p>This portion of the cutscene was so precise. By pulling on the line from the IV drip in her arm, she was able to tip over and break the glass that was collecting her blood. Using the line again, she gathered up shattered glass to cut her wrists loose. Another free hand and a quick topple of the gurney, and Grace was free.</p>

<p>At this point, the experience shifted into a first-person view. Turning around, Grace began to make her way through a series of corridors. They were filled with the stable <em>Resident Evil</em> fare, tight corners, a door with a sigil that needed a key of the matching design, and a 16-foot monstrous woman that stalked Grace through the halls.</p>

<p>For many in the room the introduction of this monster was quite the jumpscare. After opening a door, Grace had a dead body collapse onto her, inspecting it on the ground a large hand quietly reached out of the darkness and with no effort picked up the dead body before raising it to her mouth and biting the head clean off. Grace's non-reaction through this process is a mix of panic and awe (much like those watching) as she's just trying to take in the abomination in front of her.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/resident-evil-requiem-hallway.jpg?itok=dtT_Z7hg 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/resident-evil-requiem-hallway.jpg?itok=y2iYz97p 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>This section of the demo shown was structured in equal parts puzzle, as Grace tried to escape this portion of the building she was in, while also doubling down on the idea of wanting to escape from the daunting and monstroust figure that was stalking her.</p>

<p>Within the same diverting hallways, with 3-5 rooms adjacent we got to see Grace find a locked door, return with a key, locate a fuse trapped behind a locked case, obtained a screw driver, unlocked the fuse, and then made her way to a gate that is in need of a fuse.</p>

<p>While there was a lot of movement to and from the different rooms within this portion of the building, each time Grace made it to a key objective, she would be faced with a small challenge, or she would only reach the location while trying to steer clear of the monstrous woman.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/resident-evil-requiem-monstrous-woman.jpg?itok=ApwAR4I7 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/resident-evil-requiem-monstrous-woman.jpg?itok=MJj5u4bt 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Resident Evil 9's Mr X?</figcaption></figure><p>We didn't get to see Grace do much to mitigate the oncoming threat, but for this segment of the gameplay, it seemed the idea of Grace's character was to not be the most competent when it comes to combat, but to be able to nimbly escape.</p>

<p>There were a number of cuts between footage while viewing this <em>Resident Evil 9</em> gameplay, the key information that was missing from the footage was things like the location of the key for the locked door, or when there was some repetitive backtracking.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/resident-evil-requiem-key-door.jpg?itok=BYlBC4oJ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/resident-evil-requiem-key-door.jpg?itok=aPW7C7w2 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>A key was obtained, but it's location obscured</figcaption></figure><p>There were a few moments when it did seem that there were some selective cuts around some additional context. Grace entered a room filled with medical equipment and while she was standing still there were some additional squealching noises. They didn't seem like they were coming from here, but they also seemed too frequent and light, they weren't coming from the giant humanoid creature.</p>

<p>This section had unsettling moment, some of the darkest corridors I've seen in games, and a plethora of jump scares as your way would get blocked by the monster.</p>

<h2>Resident Evil Requiem has First Person Mode and Third Person Mode</h2>

<p>A very interesting aspect of the gameplay clip, and one that was heralded by applause in the small showing room, was that by entering the pause menu and going to options the gameplay was able to be shifted to third person mode.</p>

<p>Once in third person and running from the monstrous woman Grace found her way to the fuse box, placed it inside, and was able to escape as the demo came to a close. The last thing that remained on the screen was "This is merely the overture to our dark symphony".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/resident-evil-requiem-grace.jpg?itok=fTMXSXk2 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/resident-evil-requiem-grace.jpg?itok=hFMZsGp6 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Grace in the hallway with the locked door, just around the corner to the left is where the fusebox can be found</figcaption></figure><p>The gameplay made me think of early Ethan Winters style gameplay for <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="1a560db9-346a-4407-98cb-00ff8b36ed59" href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/resident-evil-7-biohazard-review-groovy" rel="nofollow"><em>Resident Evil 7</em></a>. There was a lot of need to avoid combat, knowing that whatever it was you weren't going to want to take the face on. Grace, with her experience in the FBI, definitely has a lot of knowledge and skill under her belt, but a Resident Evil outbreak is definitely out of her comfort zone.</p>

<p>While we didn't see too much of the menus or additional mechanics when approaching the door without the key we got to see an empty inventory screen that looked like the ones being used in recent <em>Resident Evil</em> titles, and the one time that Grace was hit by the enemy a pulse meter in orange appeared in the lower left.</p>

<p>It looks like the UI will be aiming to be a light as possible, only showing relevant elements when necessary.</p>

<hr><p><em><strong>Resident Evil 9 Requiem </strong>was previewed at Summer Game Fest via a pre-recorded and edited gameplay demo.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Andrew has written Video Game and Entertainment news, reviews, and guides for 10+ years. As Senior Content Manager, he assists in creating and editing… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/andrew-stretch">More about Andrew</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>