<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 15:44:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Demonschool Credits Try "Something Different", List Full Staff Duties]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/demonschool-credits-something-different</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/demonschool-credits-try-something-different-list-full-staff-duties.1364143/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Demonschool&nbsp;</em>developer Necrosoft says that it tried "something different" for the credits sequence in the game, opting to list the full duties carried out by staff rather than a brief description of each person's role.</p>

<p>Over on <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/brandon.insertcredit.com/post/3m6fuipkh4k2u" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Bluesky</a>, Necrosoft director Brandon Sheffield says the team used a format of "name, title, lengthy description of what they did" for each staff member's credit on&nbsp;<em>Demonschool</em>.</p>

<p>This means that, rather than simply reading "art lead", a credit might outline that a staff member "did most of the 3D modeling and rigging as well as creating most backgrounds", or that they "created most avatars and poses, all overlays and menu art, [and] the game logo".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/necrosoft-demonschool-credits.jpg?itok=cqBDsfge 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/necrosoft-demonschool-credits.jpg?itok=WQKF_MDr 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Demonschool</em>'s credits are serious about giving staff members their due.</figcaption></figure><p>Sheffield says he wants to make sure that those who choose to watch&nbsp;<em>Demonschool</em>'s credits (which, he acknowledges, won't be everybody) will "come to understand how each person participated", and that doing things this way might help staff members to elucidate their roles during job interviews in future.</p>

<p>He also says that, in addition to&nbsp;<em>Demonschool</em>'s core team, Necrosoft credited "everyone who ever touched the game in any way". Sheffield acknowledges this means the credits for&nbsp;<em>Demonschool&nbsp;</em>are long for a small team, but to that, he says "why be stingy?".</p>

<p>It's refreshing to see an indie team being so upfront about its credits, especially in an era where specific studios and staff members often <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gaming-business-roundup-july-12th" rel="nofollow">aren't credited</a> in major <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/original-metroid-prime-developers-omitted-from-remastered-credits" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">releases</a> on which they worked. Whether or not this style gets adopted across the world of indie gaming remains to be seen, but I sure hope it does.</p>

<p>As for&nbsp;<em>Demonschool</em>, if you're unfamiliar with it, the game is a tactical RPG that combines the minutiae of school life with a strategic puzzle-style combat system in which you must battle demons between your own world and theirs.</p>




<p>The game was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/demonschool-persona-inspired-tactics-rpg-announced" rel="nofollow">revealed back in 2022</a>, but was subsequently <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/demonschool-release-date-september-2025" rel="nofollow">delayed numerous times</a>, most recently due to Necrosoft wanting to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hollow-knight-silksong-indie-delays" rel="nofollow">avoid a clash</a> with then-hotly-anticipated Metroidvania&nbsp;<em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em>.</p>

<p>Happily, however,&nbsp;<em>Demonschool&nbsp;</em>is finally out, and you can take a look at it right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1900250/Demonschool/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10007754" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/demonschool/9p7d4xfj2xwf" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/demonschool-switch/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Nintendo Switch</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/demonschool-credits-something-different]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Best New Tabletop Games At PAX Unplugged 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/best-new-tabletop-games-at-pax-unplugged-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-best-new-tabletop-games-at-pax-unplugged-2025.1364101/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Every year I make the short (relatively speaking) jaunt from Brooklyn down to Philadelphia, Pennsylvania for what I consider to be just about&nbsp;<em>the</em>&nbsp;best gaming convention of the year: PAX Unplugged. Last year, I put together a <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/best-new-games-at-pax-unplugged-2024" rel="nofollow">roundup of my fave games</a> I tried, and yes, you guessed it, I'm doing it again! From sneak peeks to new releases that shot right to the top of my "must-play" list, these were my favorite new Tabletop games (and one bit of accessory) I saw at PAX Unplugged 2025.</p>

<h2>Dice Words - Kosmos</h2>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pax-unplugged-dice-words.jpg?itok=d7mrNiN5 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pax-unplugged-dice-words.jpg?itok=0chqZXRi 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>If there's one thing I love more than just about any other type of party game, it's word games! I'm a regular word puzzle freak (go ahead and quote me on that one), and so it shouldn't come as a surprise that I was seriously take in by&nbsp;<em>Dice Words</em>.</p>

<p>This mechanically-simple game puts your word-smithing to the test, and I think it's fair to elevator pitch it as: Yahtzee meets Scrabble. What?! That's right, in this game you're trying to make the best word you can out of seven dice you roll, and if you don't have the letters you need, you can re-roll them! Fun, visually appealing with its throwback ice machine lettering -&nbsp;<em>Dice Words</em>&nbsp;is the real deal.</p>

<h2>Frosted Blooms - Synapses Games</h2>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pax-unplugged-frosted-blooms-board-game.jpg?itok=Ct4BtzLg 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pax-unplugged-frosted-blooms-board-game.jpg?itok=7tUC7F_I 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Designed by absolute legends&nbsp;Bruno Cathala and Ludovic Maublanc,&nbsp;<em>Frosted Blooms&nbsp;</em>puts you in the shoes of a Dutch master gardener, trying to create the most beautiful field of tulips possible. Can I just say - as an aside - how nice it is to see such a strong, rich tradition of "very gentle themes" still going strong in the gaming industry? It's just so nice.</p>

<p>Anyway, I got the chance to try out a sneak peek of&nbsp;<em>Frosted Blooms</em>, and I have to say the gameplay loop is so rewarding. You draft tiles of different shapes, and play a card as you place your tile which immediately scores based on flowers you connect. It's clean, simple design that somehow skirts the line between think-y and vibe-y -- in other words: there's plenty of strategy here, but not enough to burn your brain. I loved it!</p>

<h2>Botany - Dux Somnium Games</h2>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pax-unplugged-botany.jpg?itok=ASulAnOI 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pax-unplugged-botany.jpg?itok=EAXn-40Z 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p><em>Botany</em>&nbsp;is a game where you take on the role of an expert flower hunter out to find the rarest and most beautiful flora in the world. Set during Victorian times, this game immediately caught my eye with its gorgeous visual presentation and elegant, heightened theme.</p>

<p>In an expo hall full of neon colors (which, don't get me wrong, we love... and of which we'll see plenty in this list), this tonally beautiful game with its subdued presentation probably made me stop in my tracks harder than anything else on the floor.</p>

<h2>Gretchen's Garden - Lookout Games</h2>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pax-unplugged-gretchens-garden.jpeg?itok=vmDbYITz 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pax-unplugged-gretchens-garden.jpeg?itok=LCm4-gPd 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Everyone's talking about succulents - those easy-to-grow, hard-to-kill plants that are super trendy right now. Well, now that I'm back from frantically over-watering my succulents that I've let wither on the windowsill, let's chat about&nbsp;<em>Gretchen's Garden</em>, a brand new tableau-building game coming out next year from Lookout Games!</p>

<p>In&nbsp;<em>Gretchen's Garden</em>, you're building up a tableau of pots and plants, watering them each round, and converting that water (in the form of water tokens) into leaf tokens to score points! You can even snip clippings from your opponents' plants, giving a bit of player interaction that we don't always see in this type of game! Keep an eye out for this one, I got to playtest a few rounds of it and I was left wanting more!</p>

<h2>The Massive-Verse Fighting Card Game - Solis Studios</h2>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pax-unplugged-massive-verse.jpg?itok=s7ZOv2PA 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pax-unplugged-massive-verse.jpg?itok=2pk7xEcK 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Looking for a fun, quick, hard-hitting 1v1 card game where you throw everything you've got at your opponent? Of course you are! And that's why you should check out&nbsp;<em>The Massive-Verse Fighting Card Game</em>. Featuring eight characters from the&nbsp;<em>Massive-Verse</em>&nbsp;world, this game plays like an analog fighting game, where you'll try to outwit your opponent as you each lay down a card at the same time.</p>

<p>Some cards strike hard, others defend, and some help you power up to unleash special abilities! It's a think-y little fighting game, where you can really get in the weeds (in a good way) trying to figure out what your opponent will do next. I got a chance to playtest this one with Chris Solis of Solis Studios and, believe it or not, he whooped me! So fun, and the Starter Pack has everything two players need to jump into the action while fitting in your back pocket!</p>

<h2>Mountain Goats Legacy - Allplay</h2>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pax-unplugged-mountain-goats-legacy.jpg?itok=_NxBILbT 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pax-unplugged-mountain-goats-legacy.jpg?itok=ezHtpblF 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Now we're talking some&nbsp;<em>serious</em>&nbsp;sneak peeks, as I got the chance to playtest the absolutely incredible&nbsp;<em>Mountain Goats Legacy</em>. A new legacy version of the beginner-friendly classic&nbsp;<em>Mountain Goats</em>, this is a game about getting your cute little goats up a mountain by rolling dice and using said dice to advance your goat meeples (geeples?). Get to the top of the mountain and you score some points, but as soon as another goat makes it up there - they boot you back down to the bottom!</p>

<p>That was all present in the original game, but what makes&nbsp;<em>Mountain Goats Legacy&nbsp;</em>so special is the way each session slowly adds twists to the gameplay. In our first session (I got to try out four different scenarios), we had a simple rule that let us change how we use one of our dice. In the next scenario, a new "courage" mechanic gave us something to do with un-spent dice. And in the following scenario... an earthquake rumbled and completely switched up the numbers on the board, totally transforming how you play the game!</p>

<p>This one's not launching for a bit, but I'll be keeping an extremely close eye on it - as it was hands down one of the most fun gaming experiences I had in all of PAX Unplugged 2025!</p>

<h2>Re;MATCH - Brother Ming Games</h2>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pax-unplugged-re-match.jpg?itok=ZE2gAKnF 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pax-unplugged-re-match.jpg?itok=HGtALXYA 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Wow... just... wow! This is one of those games you play that, even when playtesting in the middle of a crowded convention floor, makes time kind of stand still for a moment.&nbsp;<em>Re;MATCH</em>&nbsp;by Brother Ming games is a fast-paced fighting game using a truly unique mechanic I've never seen in this kind of fighting game: marbles!</p>

<p>Combining marble puzzle mechanics like you'd find in&nbsp;<em>Potion Explosion</em>&nbsp;with card-based fighting, you play as one of six vibrant characters out to claim victory over your opponent. In the game, you'll pull clusters of marbles on your side of the drop tower to activate special abilities, gain the support of cheering fans, and pull off powerful attacks.</p>

<p>I played against Ming himself, and aside from being one of the most genuine, cool dudes at PAX, you can tell he's also got a ton of pride of this expertly crafted, ingenious game. <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/brotherminggames/rematch" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">It launches soon on Kickstarter</a>, and I can't wait to get back to the marble tower.</p>

<h2>Song of the Wildkin -&nbsp;Bōken Games</h2>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pax-unplugged-song-of-the-wildkin.jpg?itok=_JFoZjpp 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pax-unplugged-song-of-the-wildkin.jpg?itok=B0yXF5no 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>It's hard for any game to make a big impression while still in early prototype form -- the medium is truly a tactile one, where you want to be able to see, touch, and experience the game in its most final state. So you can understand my surprise when I was truly blown away by&nbsp;<em>Song of the Wildkin</em>, which as you can see from the images above is still very much in its early stages of production! But blown away I was, as I dove into this fantasy world full of anthropomorphic animals battling strange creatures on map tiles.</p>

<p>With an absolute powerhouse of designers and artists behind it (Andrew Bosley, the illustrator of<em> Everdell </em>and Paul DeStefano,&nbsp;<em>Oathsworn</em>'s writer, to name a few), this game sparkles with energy and evocative illustrations (even in these early days stages). Coming in 2026, and boasting over 30 hours of cooperative campaign gameplay,&nbsp;<em>Song of the Wildkin</em>&nbsp;is one to watch.&nbsp;</p>

<h2>Tabletop Things RPG Tiles</h2>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pax-unplugged-tabletop-things.jpg?itok=Lm_rxE6d 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pax-unplugged-tabletop-things.jpg?itok=JOFMgjyO 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Breaking the tide of board games in this list for a second, I had to drop a shout out to Tabletop Things. These locally produced (in their own small shop in New Jersey) RPG tiles set the standard for affordable, 3D RPG terrain. I was immediately taken by the sculpts on these, and love the bright, evocative colors used.</p>

<p>As you can see from the images above, Tabletop Things really leans into the modularity of dungeon tiles while still ensuring that all the pieces they produce have a lot of character to them. These aren't bland, gray corridors -- each piece pops in one way or another. In my opinion, they add a sort of dream-like quality to the table, with a bit of whimsy in their design and color choices.</p>

<h2>Wispwood - CGE</h2>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pax-unplugged-wispwood.jpg?itok=PH0rxxYE 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pax-unplugged-wispwood.jpg?itok=UIdSUU47 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Finally, let's dive into an upcoming game from&nbsp;CGE,&nbsp;<em>Wispwood</em>! This tile-laying game gives the genre a unique spin with a sort of tile rondel that forces you to place a wisp tile in a specific shape/formation. If you can't, you have to fill it a space with a tree card. But at the end of each round, your trees go away, and your wisps remain.</p>

<p>This creates a fun interplay and balance of getting the right wisps on your board when you can, while setting yourself up for success next round, too! I only tried a bit of a walk-through of this game, but I knew it was one my gaming group would love - so this is shooting right to the top of my list to try out as soon as it comes out.</p>

<h2>PAX Unplugged 2025 Wrap Up</h2>

<p>That wraps things up for this year's PAX Unplugged 2025 -- thanks so much to PAX Unplugged for having me, and thanks to all the incredible game creators, publishers, developers, artists, and more who showed off their new games with so much passion and excitement. If PAX Unplugged 2025 is any indication, next year's going to be a BIG one for tabletop gaming!</p>
</div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/best-new-tabletop-games-at-pax-unplugged-2025]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>