<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 15:18:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokemon Go Level Cap to Increase to 80 in October]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pokemon-go-level-cap-80-october</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pokemon-go-level-cap-to-increase-to-80-in-october.1279752/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Niantic and The Pokemon Company have announced that later this year, the level cap for&nbsp;<em>Pokemon Go&nbsp;</em>will be increased, which the developer says will lead to a "more fun and engaging" leveling experience.</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://pokemongo.com/en/post/pgo-leveling-update-announce-2025" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">blog post</a>, Niantic says that on October 15th, the&nbsp;<em>Pokemon Go&nbsp;</em>level cap will increase from 50 to 80, which, according to Niantic, will lead to players "celebrating leveling milestones with new rewards, new cosmetics, and more".</p>

<p>According to Niantic, the new level cap means that some players "can expect to jump in level based on their total earned XP", but that nobody's level will decrease. As such, when the update arrives, if you suddenly find yourself at a higher level, that's why.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pokemon-go-level-cap-increasing-art.jpg?itok=eXrT9rau 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pokemon-go-level-cap-increasing-art.jpg?itok=GX_FWCQL 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Pokemon Go</em>'s level cap will be increasing in October.</figcaption></figure><p>Not only is the level cap itself increasing, but leveling between 1 and 80 will be rebalanced, according to Niantic. Naturally, Level-Up Research tasks for levels 41 through 50 will be replaced with tasks from levels 71 through 80.</p>

<p>You can also expect other goodies like a boosted chance of becoming Lucky Friends with other players when you hit level 70, as well as new rewards for progression, including increased storage capacity and new avatar items.</p>

<p>By the time October 14th (the day before the update is set to hit) arrives, you'll get a "special medal" commemorating the highest level you've achieved in&nbsp;<em>Pokemon Go</em>, and if you hit 50, you'll get a special jacket and avatar pose.</p>

<p>Between now and October 15th, you'll get double catch XP from Nice, Great, and Excellent throws, and you'll get an extra 3,000 XP for winning raids and Max Battles. Timed Research will also become available to those level 7 or over, giving you the chance to "earn over 7 million XP", Niantic says.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pokemon-go-level-cap-increasing-bonuses.jpg?itok=piSccBxn 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pokemon-go-level-cap-increasing-bonuses.jpg?itok=AjXSrQJ5 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>If you play&nbsp;<em>Pokemon Go&nbsp;</em>between now and October 15th, you'll get bonuses galore.</figcaption></figure><p>News of the level cap follows the announcement of a new season in&nbsp;<em>Pokemon Go</em>, with various new 'mons set to debut from September 2nd, including Mega Metagross, Keldeo, and more.</p>

<p>All of this follows the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/niantic-scopely-sale-games" rel="nofollow">sale of Niantic to the Saudi-backed firm Scopely</a> back in February, a move that Scopely was quick to reassure fans would not affect the day-to-day operations of&nbsp;<em>Pokemon Go</em><em>.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pokemon-go-level-cap-80-october]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar Review - A Warm Welcome Home]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-review-warm-welcome-home</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-review-a-warm-welcome-home.1279728/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>With every <em>Story of Seasons</em> release, developing studio Marvelous gets closer and closer to finding the best recipe for a farming/life simulator, and <em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar</em> is its next remake that blends old-school farming sim mechanics with all of the quirks that made Zephyr Town a beloved location in the franchise.&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar</em> is a remake of the original Grand Bazaar title, though it was called <em>Harvest Moon DS: Grand Bazaar</em> at the time. The game sends players to Zephyr Town, where they not only take the role of the local farmer but also open a booth at the local bazaar.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-farm-view.jpg?itok=VOXcfesh 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-farm-view.jpg?itok=LctRgiJr 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Certain areas around&nbsp;<em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar&nbsp;</em>give special views of the surrounding areas that change through the seasons.</figcaption></figure><p>In the latest iteration of the game, players are asked to grow the bazaar after the previous farmer left town years prior. There’s a storyline that drives this bazaar growth, making <em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar</em> more narrative-driven than ever before in the franchise (with the exception of perhaps <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="34bff8c7-b745-4cf9-b20f-236a7829b85f" href="https://techraptor.net/games/story-of-seasons-wonderful-life" rel="nofollow"><em>Story of Seasons: A Wonderful Life</em></a>).&nbsp;</p>

<p>Every Saturday, players will sell anything they have at their own bazaar stall. The bazaar is also where players will buy most of their things, though there is a general store that carries seeds and animal food for emergencies.</p>

<p>That leaves the rest of the week for farming and general day-to-day activities, like talking to villagers and foraging for supplies.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar</em> Makes Every Area Shine</h2>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-bazaar-day.jpg?itok=k8TWXc2R 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-bazaar-day.jpg?itok=2dXaos11 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Selling at your own stall in&nbsp;<em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar&nbsp;</em>makes the stakes of farming feel even higher as you appeal to customers and try to boost your profits.&nbsp;</figcaption></figure><p>Whether it’s a busy bazaar Saturday or a leisurely Tuesday, <em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar</em> makes every in-game day enjoyable. Between an impressive number of events around town and plenty to do, there’s a feeling that every day matters.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Of course, the bazaar days are constantly busy. Selling to customers involves getting their attention with a cowbell and placing items they like on display. Don’t be fooled, this is harder than it sounds – things get hectic easily, and it’s easy to lose the interest of some customers while you’re serving others.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-playing-with-pet.jpg?itok=MvE8fwZT 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-playing-with-pet.jpg?itok=Ec5St1JC 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The animals in&nbsp;<em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar&nbsp;</em>are as full of life and love as the characters.&nbsp;</figcaption></figure><p>Events crop up around the map consistently as you get to know the characters, breathing life into an already-bustling town. Not only do these give each day meaning, they’re easy to find – a map with notifications when an event is happening and where leads you to where you need to be.&nbsp;</p>

<p>These events highlight all the villagers in Zephyr Town, and some of them are sweet glimpses into the lives of townspeople you’d otherwise know little about. These also do a great job at pushing the relationships of bachelors and bachelorettes and the main story.</p>

<p>All of this also helps push the idea that the player is welcome in a loving, full-of-life town. It also helps that, for the first time ever, the major events and story are completely voiced.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-windmill.jpg?itok=m2qEq-T5 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-windmill.jpg?itok=9jG5vShL 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The windmills in&nbsp;<em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar&nbsp;</em>are the key to making high profits -- once you've restored them, of course.</figcaption></figure><p>Even without events, there are plenty of quests to focus on. Villagers will ask for help as your relationship with them builds. Additionally, you can endlessly gather materials and forage to donate to sprites. Not only does this give rewards, but it also increases various quality levels of the things you donate.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Plus, crafting things is a major part of the game, and crafting takes time. As you get further into the game, you’ll be going through long, multiple-step crafting formulas using a variety of materials.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This isn’t something that’s really a big focus in newer games in the genre. It’s definitely something that adds complexity to a farming sim in a great way without being overbearing, and its presence in the remake is a welcome reminder of where the genre was nearly 20 years ago.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-mountain-view.jpg?itok=67jjSZMk 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-mountain-view.jpg?itok=DlsgDy2r 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Some of the views around&nbsp;<em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar&nbsp;</em>give a hint at the world around Zephyr Town that some of the other characters frequently visit.</figcaption></figure><p>However, all of this does take a bit to set up.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It’s easy to feel like things are slow at the beginning, as unlocking every available thing to do and starting to build relationships takes time. This does make the first Spring feel a bit slow, particularly if you know your way around farming sims or have played the original <em>Grand Bazaar</em> title.</p>

<p>After the first Spring, things progress at a nice pace, and I found I always had something to do around town the entire rest of the first year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Even Spring of Year 2, while a bit slower on festivals, still had plenty for me to focus on doing. As someone who’s an avid farming/life sim lover, this was something I’d never really experienced in other games in the genre.&nbsp;</p>

<h2>Zephyr Town Has Never Been More Beautiful</h2>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-sophie-and-june.jpg?itok=lzCR5pKN 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-sophie-and-june.jpg?itok=KtrggFvO 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The characters in&nbsp;<em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar&nbsp;</em>make every day an adventure between events, new dialogue, and quests.</figcaption></figure><p>It’d be easy for everything already mentioned to make a great <em>Story of Seasons</em> game, but <em>Grand Bazaar</em> outdoes itself with the aesthetics of Zephyr Town.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Zephyr Town is arguably the best-looking town in <em>Story of Seasons</em> history, and it’s always been gorgeous. It strikes a great balance between the natural environment and a tiny, yet bustling, town, and the windmills and traversal mechanics have always been fun.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The wind and movement mechanics, including jumping around and gliding to other areas, feel intuitive and make running around entertaining.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-fishing-in-the-rain.jpg?itok=hWMoKTL9 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-fishing-in-the-rain.jpg?itok=BzvJi6AM 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The first time I heard the rainy day music in&nbsp;<em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar</em>, I fished all day just to listen to it.&nbsp;</figcaption></figure><p>And then, perhaps the most surprising part of <em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar</em> for me was the music. Farming Sims aren’t known for their soundtracks, but <em>Grand Bazaar</em> had several gorgeous tracks that forced me to stop and appreciate them.&nbsp;</p>

<h2>Overall, Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar Is One of The Best Yet</h2>

<p><a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="c66e36ec-389d-4125-b93f-0d46957d3097" href="https://techraptor.net/games/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar" rel="nofollow"><em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar</em></a> is a home run for players who loved the original and an amazing introductory farming/life sim for newcomers.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It’s cozy without being too simple, the characters and town are brimming with life, and it’s one of the prettiest <em>Story of Seasons</em> games. I had high hopes for the remake, and I’m glad to see that Marvelous did more than deliver – it awed.&nbsp;</p>

<hr><p><em><strong>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar</strong> was reviewed on PC with a copy provided by the developer over the course of 49 hours of gameplay - all screenshots were taken during the process of review.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Brittany's been gaming since she could walk -- literally. A doctor told her parents to get her a handled console to improve her hand-eye coordination… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/brittany-alva">More about Brittany</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-review-warm-welcome-home]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>