<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 16:58:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin's Creed Boss Marc-Alexis Côté Reportedly Leaves Ubisoft After Two Decades]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/assassins-creed-boss-leaves-ubisoft-report</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassins-creed-boss-marc-alexis-c%C3%B4t%C3%A9-reportedly-leaves-ubisoft-after-two-decades.1324540/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Assassin's Creed&nbsp;</em>franchise boss&nbsp;Marc-Alexis Côté has departed Ubisoft after more than two decades with the company, having most recently overseen the development and launch of&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed Shadows</em>.</p>

<p>According to a statement given to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-franchise-boss-departs-ubisoft" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">IGN</a>&nbsp;by Ubisoft itself,&nbsp;Côté, who is affectionately known as "Mac" inside Ubisoft thanks to his initials, has "chosen to pursue a new path elsewhere outside of Ubisoft".</p>

<p>His decision follows the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ubisoft-creative-houses-q1-financials" rel="nofollow">setup of a brand new company</a>, Vantage Studios, to handle some of Ubisoft's most profitable IP, including&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed</em>. The company is headed up by&nbsp;Christophe Derennes and Charlie Guillemot, leading to <a href="https://aftermath.site/ubisoft-tencent-subsidiary-ceo-charlie-guillemot" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">accusations of nepotism</a>&nbsp;since the latter is the son of Ubisoft boss Yves Guillemot.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/assassins-creed-boss-leaves-ubisoft-shadows.jpg?itok=lf-cTdm7 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/assassins-creed-boss-leaves-ubisoft-shadows.jpg?itok=_ESENhZF 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Assassin's Creed&nbsp;</em>boss&nbsp;Marc-Alexis Côté has left Ubisoft after over 20 years.</figcaption></figure><p>Per IGN, in an internal Ubisoft memo, Derennes told staff that he was "disappointed" by Côté's departure and that Côté "had his own expectations and priorities related to Vantage Studios' creation and future".</p>

<p>That's not much to go on, but it sounds as though Côté may have butted heads with Derennes and Guillemot over the direction of either Vantage Studios as an entity or&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed&nbsp;</em>as a franchise (or perhaps both). It's hard to say.</p>

<p>Côté has worked on the&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed&nbsp;</em>franchise since 2010's&nbsp;<em>Brotherhood</em>, where he served as lead level designer. He worked as&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed 3</em>'s director, going on to become the creative director for titles like&nbsp;<em>Syndicate&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Odyssey</em>.</p>

<p>His departure comes at a busy time for the&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed&nbsp;</em>franchise, with a major story DLC launching for&nbsp;<em>Shadows&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/assassins-creed-shadows-claws-of-awaji-review-more-of-same-not-in-good-way" rel="nofollow">just last month</a>&nbsp;and a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/assassins-creed-mirage-valley-of-memory-update" rel="nofollow">big free update on the way</a> for the Baghdad-set&nbsp;<em>Mirage&nbsp;</em>in November.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/assassins-creed-boss-leaves-ubisoft-mirage.jpg?itok=YhJM4yUi 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/assassins-creed-boss-leaves-ubisoft-mirage.jpg?itok=aXyEn0wx 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>A big free update is coming soon for&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed Mirage</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>Additionally,&nbsp;Côté's exit from Ubisoft comes after a report that the company canceled an in-development&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed&nbsp;</em>game <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/reconstruction-assassins-creed-canceled-report" rel="nofollow">set in the Reconstruction-era Southern US</a> last year, citing concerns around the current political climate in the country.</p>

<p>It remains to be seen what effect&nbsp;Côté's departure will have on the&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed&nbsp;</em>franchise and on Ubisoft as a whole. Stay tuned for more on this.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/assassins-creed-boss-leaves-ubisoft-report]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pathologic 3 Release Date Revealed for January]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pathologic-3-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pathologic-3-release-date-revealed-for-january.1324537/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>HypeTrain Digital and Ice-Pick Lodge have announced the release date for upcoming immersive sim-style horror adventure&nbsp;<em>Pathologic 3</em>, and it's due out early next year.</p>

<p>As revealed in a brand new trailer,&nbsp;<em>Pathologic 3</em>, which was first announced <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pathologic-3-announced-2025" rel="nofollow">back in October last year</a>, will be arriving on PC on January 9th. The two studios say the new release date is "nailed down, screwed in, wrapped in commitments, and...isn't moving".</p>

<p>If you're looking to check out&nbsp;<em>Pathologic 3&nbsp;</em>before it launches, then there's also a new demo you can try out right now as part of the latest Steam Next Fest. This demo is distinct from the free&nbsp;<em>Quarantine&nbsp;</em>prologue section that was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pathologic-3-quarantine-release-date" rel="nofollow">released at the beginning of the year</a>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pathologic-3-release-date-corpses.jpg?itok=bLj2Asw0 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pathologic-3-release-date-corpses.jpg?itok=gqqD35cV 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Pathologic 3</em>&nbsp;brings more of the series' trademark weirdness in January.</figcaption></figure><p>As Ice-Pick Lodge tells it, the new demo is different to&nbsp;<em>Quarantine&nbsp;</em>"in every way"; rather than being a standalone prologue experience, the demo represents "a slice from the beginning of the full game", and therefore has a "different story" to&nbsp;<em>Quarantine</em>, as well as covering "different events".</p>

<p>The new demo should take you about an hour or two to complete, and it supports various languages including English, Russian, and Brazilian Portuguese. If you're at all interested in the game, give it a download, as Ice-Pick Lodge says this will help more Next Fest visitors see what they're offering.</p>

<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Pathologic 3</em>, it's the third game in the idiosyncratic&nbsp;<em>Pathologic&nbsp;</em>series, which melds the freeform approach of immersive sims with a strong investigative focus and a warped, surreal atmosphere.</p>

<p>This latest entry <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pathologic-2-bachelors-scenario-announced" rel="nofollow">began life as an expansion</a> for&nbsp;<em>Pathologic 2&nbsp;</em>before being spun out into its own standalone game last year.&nbsp;<em>Pathologic 2&nbsp;</em>itself serves as a sort of junction between reboot, remake, and sequel for the original&nbsp;<em>Pathologic</em>, so&nbsp;<em>Pathologic 3</em>'s origins feel curiously appropriate for the series.</p>




<p>You'll be able to check out&nbsp;<em>Pathologic 3&nbsp;</em>when it launches on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3199650/Pathologic_3/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC via Steam</a> on January 9th. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pathologic-3-release-date]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>