<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 18:51:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mantic Games Announces Assassin's Creed: Animus is Coming to Kickstarter]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/mantic-games-announces-assassins-creed-animus-is-coming-to-kickstarter</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mantic-games-announces-assassins-creed-animus-is-coming-to-kickstarter.1171632/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/mantic-games-announces-assassins-creed-animus-is-coming-to-kickstarter<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Mantic Games is partnering with Ubisoft for an Assassin's Creed board game. The tabletop developer behind Halo: Flashpoint will be developing <em>Assassin's Creed: Animus</em>, a game spanning multiple eras and protagonists from across the franchise.</p>

<h2>The <em>Assassin's Creed: Animus</em> Announcement</h2>

<p>According to an official press release, <em>Assassin's Creed: Animus </em>is an ambitious tabletop adaptation where 2-4 players work together using fan-favorite Assassin's Creed characters. The press release included characters like Ezio Auditore, Conner Kenway, Altair Ibn-La'Ahad, and Eivor Varinsdottir. Furthermore, it will feature "enjoyable, challenging, and choice-rich gameplay."</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/assassins-creed-animus-conner-promo-image.jpg?itok=-phvRV3Q 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/assassins-creed-animus-conner-promo-image.jpg?itok=HAUDIYoe 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The press release is lax on any further details regarding complexity or detail on <em>Assassin's Creed: Animus</em>. Given developer Mantic Games history of complex but accessible miniatures games like <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/overdrive-review" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Overdrive</em></a> and <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/halo-flashpoint-rise-of-banished-brings-alien-exiles-to-battlefield" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Halo: Flashpoint</em></a>, it is likely this board game will be in that mold.</p>

<p>This isn't the first time <em>Assassin's Creed</em> has gotten a tabletop adaptation. Back in 2021 there was <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/assassins-creed-board-game-raises-shipping-costs" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Assassin's Creed: Brotherhood of Venice</em></a> developed by Triton Noir, which focused more on Assassin's Creed: Brotherhood.</p>

<p>Since <em>Assassin's Creed</em> is about secret orders of assassins taking out targets with parkour, gadgets, and hidden blades across different eras of history, that kind of gameplay loop can translate well to a miniatures environment. A focus on spatial and environmental awareness, planning your moves. Choosing the right time to strike and escape. With some time and consideration, Mantic's style can mesh well here.</p>

<p><em>Assassin's Creed</em> is one of publisher Ubisoft's most popular action franchises. It began in 2007 and has continued to the present. The franchise has covered multiple historical eras, including The Crusades, the Italian Renaissance, the American Revolution, the Golden Age of Piracy, the French Revolution, the British Industrial Revolution, the time <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/assassins-creed-valhalla" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">of Vikings</a>, and recently, <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/assassins-creed-shadows" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Feudal Japan</a>.</p>

<p>The Kickstarter campaign for Assassin's Creed: Animus will be going live at some point later this year.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>