<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor.net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor.net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 23:06:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Echoes of Elysium Preview - More Sandbox than Survival, but all Airship]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/echoes-of-elysium-preview-more-sandbox-than-survival-but-all-airship</link>
            <guid>1428622</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Echoes of Elysium</em> is the brainchild of Loric Games, a group of former Mythic Entertainment employees with a smattering of Bethesda developers mixed in. Having worked on titles such as <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/opinion/endurance-star-wars-old-republic" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="b37f30ad-c8cb-4f8d-a44b-58b67d95bb81" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Star Wars: The Old Republic</em></a> and <em>Dark Age of Camelot</em>, the studio has taken their extensive experience to head into uncharted territory with their debut title. Learn how Loric Games is approaching Early Access, and whether the sandbox survival airship RPG is for you with our <em>Echoes of Elysium</em> preview.</p><h2>Colorful, Carefree, and Calming</h2><p>Set as a sandbox RPG with survival elements thrown in, <em>Echoes of Elysium</em> takes a different path than other games in the survival genre. You’ll find a bright blue sky, fluffy clouds, bright rooftops, and vivid flowers throughout the world’s floating islands. For the land of the dead, it is quite cheerful. Combined with the atmospheric music, the title can even be labeled calming.</p><p>The art is the main reason I became interested in the game. Survival games typically evoke an apocalyptic style with darker colors, dreariness, and an overbearing sense of despair. With a color scheme that deviates from the norm, it's easy for <em>Echoes of Elysium</em> to stand out in the crowded survival genre.<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/using-a-harpoon-echoes-of-elysium.jpg?itok=J0UTlEBf 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/using-a-harpoon-echoes-of-elysium.jpg?itok=CLMHnM4U 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture></p><p>While there are some survival aspects to the game, the title absolutely feels like a sandbox airship builder. You need to harvest rocks, trees, plant fiber, and fuel. You build your airship, which acts as a flying base. There’s food to forage and inventory to manage, but items don't spoil, and basic resources are easy to gather.</p><p>You don’t have any thirst or hunger, and your stamina mainly comes into play when gliding across the open expanse or fighting. Instead of having to track down your items, which you still have to do if you were away from your ship when you perished, you’ll be cursed with a debuff. When you die and respawn, you’ll need to find food that cures your new status or wait until the buff wears off.</p><p>I enjoyed gliding through the air, seeing the different islands, and finding new items to harvest. However, there’s not much else to do aside from that. The narrative, which is an element the team is still working on, is barely there, at best.</p><p>You get a story in the opening cutscene, are introduced to an NPC that aids you, and receive a quick tutorial. Once you capture your first Dry Dock, however, you can spend hours wandering the vast expanse without discovering another snippet of story. It’s even possible to skip part of the story if you find the boss’s den by accident.<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/npc-lethe-narrative-echoes-of-elysium.jpg?itok=71ehVh16 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/npc-lethe-narrative-echoes-of-elysium.jpg?itok=UVmS75fR 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture></p><p>During a preview presentation with Loric Games, it was admitted that the narrative doesn’t rank as high on the list of important items. Making airships into flying bases and nailing the associated mechanics are the focuses and stars of the game. The story will be coming, but it may not be as extensive or featured as prominently as some survival or RPG players will want.&nbsp;</p><p>As a survival title, <em>Echoes of Elysium</em> misses the mark. There’s no pressure to actually survive. If you don’t die, you never need to eat or drink. There are no elements affecting your mood. Aside from falling out of the air and the scattering of enemies you can encounter, death is far from a concern.</p><p>As a sandbox builder, the title hits the main points, making it far more successful in that regard. You can build beautiful airships without having to worry about your skill as a builder, thanks to the rounded walls. Weight isn’t even an issue as long as you have enough propellers, allowing you to truly get creative with your build.<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/enemy-airship-echoes-of-alysium.jpg?itok=Sk5fhY0a 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/enemy-airship-echoes-of-alysium.jpg?itok=ILm6cHwI 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture></p><p>The biggest downfall of <em>Echoes of Elysium</em> is the somewhat grindy nature of the game when it comes to advanced resources, especially fuel, and the time it takes to travel from one island cluster to another. I often abandoned my airship to traverse with my glider. Even over large expanses, it was my preferred method of travel. While airships aren’t as slow as the ships in Skull &amp; Bones, it’s still a time investment to make your way around the map looking for resources.</p><p>On top of that, the game crashes, there can be glitches causing enemies to become invincible, and items can fall out of the sky, making them inaccessible. At first, I experienced quite a bit of lag that made playing almost impossible. That has vastly improved, but people with older machines may experience what feels like never ending lag.</p><p><em>Echoes of Elysium</em> has great bones and some great potential, it just needed more time in the oven. More narrative would add some structure to the experience. Additional resources, more concrete ways to find said resources, and more mechanics to craft items easily would ensure everyone who plays the title understands how to advance.<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/echoes-of-elysium-gliding_0.jpg?itok=8NSx7aLS 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/echoes-of-elysium-gliding_0.jpg?itok=bSpD9Iz7 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture></p><h2><em>Echoes of Elysium</em> Preview | Final Thoughts</h2><p>Even though there are issues, Loric Games’ outlook on Early Access assures fans they will continue working on the title. Taking a stance, a few years old, the studio will be listening to player feedback and furthering development through the EA phase, with the player base in mind. While this was how EA originally started for many games in the past, this hasn’t been the modus operandi for the majority of current EA releases. If you’re interested in the growth of the game and impacting how the world evolves, <em>Echoes of Elysium</em> will be a great fit for you. If you’d rather have an almost completed title that’s pretty polished with lots of content for you to play through, you may want to wait until <em>Echoes of Elysium</em> fully launches.&nbsp;</p><hr><p><em><strong>Echoes of Elysium</strong> was previewed on PC with a code provided by the publisher over the course of 11 hours. All screenshots were taken during the course of the preview.</em><br>&nbsp;</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ashley Erickson is an experienced writer focusing on the video games industry since 2013. Starting off with cosplay features, she moved to game guides and… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/ashley-erikson">More about Ashley</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/echoes-of-elysium-preview-more-sandbox-than-survival-but-all-airship]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Adventuring Academy Season 7 Trailer Brings More Comedy and TTRPG Advice]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/new-adventuring-academy-season-7-trailer-brings-more-comedy-and-ttrpg-advice</link>
            <guid>1428604</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Dropout has dropped a new trailer for <em>Adventuring Academy</em> Season 7. The latest season of the comedy talk show features the company's resident TTRPG expert, Brennan Lee Mulligan, chatting with a new suite of guests.</p><p>The new <em>Adventuring Academy</em> Season 7 trailer provides more of what fans have come to expect from the Dropout crew. For those not aware, <em>Adventuring Academy</em> is a talk show where Brennan Lee Mulligan, the mind behind the platform's comedic actual play anthology series <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/dimension-20-gladlands-is-mad-max-if-everyone-wasnt-being-so-rude-interview" rel="nofollow"><em>Dimension 20</em></a>, casually chats with a host about tabletop gaming.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/adventuring-academy-season-7-vic-michaelis-set-photo.jpg?itok=BL1shiCB 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1600" height="900">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/adventuring-academy-season-7-vic-michaelis-set-photo.jpg?itok=2SaUTWJf 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><p>These talks span a wide number of topics in regards to play for both new and experienced players. How do you handle a player character dying? How do you make a memorable character in your game? How much worldbuilding is too much? What steps can you take to make your players feel comfortable and safe when undertaking dark or intense scenarios?&nbsp;</p><p>At the same time, these episodes can veer into comedic asides and passionate hot takes. That doesn't appear to have changed in the <em>Adventuring Academy</em> Season 7 trailer. A guest declaring their dislike of Gandalf from <em>Lord of the Rings</em>. Brennan's slightly changed relationship with snacking and almonds. The edict of "mandatory queerness." It is all in line with Dropout's distinct irreverent brand.</p><p>The new season's guests are a mix of Dropout regulars and other creatives in the space. They include Vic Michaelis, Robbie Daymond, Oscar Montoya, Kimia Behpoornia, Aabria Iyengar, Emily Friedman, Mica Burton, Quinns Smith, and Jasper William Cartwright.</p><p>Overall, the line-up is consistent with past seasons. Prior guests have included Dropout talent like Jacob Wysocki, Sam Reich, Lou Wilson, and Ally Beardsley, as well as other professional tabletop creatives like Jasmine Bhullar, Deborah Ann Woll, Dave Walters, Marisha Ray, and <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/critical-role-campaign-4-trailer-introduces-us-to-land-of-araman" rel="nofollow">Critical Role's</a> own Matt Mercer.</p><p><em>Adventuring Academy </em>Season 7 premieres exclusively on Dropout on February 20th.&nbsp;</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/new-adventuring-academy-season-7-trailer-brings-more-comedy-and-ttrpg-advice]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Cthulhu: The Sutra of Pale Leaves - Twin Suns Rising Review - Retro Freakout]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/call-of-cthulhu-sutra-of-pale-leaves-twin-suns-rising-review-retro-freakout</link>
            <guid>1428544</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>What if I told you a game of <em>Call of Cthulhu</em> didn’t have to take place in 1920s New England? What if it could, for example, take place in the neon-soaked world of 1980s Japan? Sounds pretty rad, right? Well dreams come true (whether we want them to or not)! I previously reviewed the fabulous <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/call-of-cthulhu-arkham-review-supplemental-strangeness" rel="nofollow"><em>Call of Cthulhu: Arkham</em></a>, and was thrilled to receive a review copy of the brand-new adventure module <a href="https://www.chaosium.com/call-of-cthulhu-the-sutra-of-pale-leaves-twin-suns-rising-hardcover/?srsltid=AfmBOorE18GDqZ_l9nqFt_Xb8c97pIqO4m82Rcwi7SXQzF1c0TIWPPKo" rel="nofollow"><em>The Sutra of Pale Leaves - Twin Suns Rising</em></a> from Chaosium.</p><p><em>Call of Cthulhu: The Sutra of Pale Leaves - Twin Suns Rising</em> is the first of two supplemental books for <em>Call of Cthulhu</em> set in 1980s Japan. Consisting of three standalone adventures (which can also each be strung together for a longer narrative), the game sees players tracking down The Sutra of Pale Leaves, a strange religious scripture with otherworldly origins.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/call-of-cthulhu-the-sutra-of-pale-leaves-twin-suns-rising-pallid-masks-large.jpeg?itok=9GCydur6 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1034" height="724">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/call-of-cthulhu-the-sutra-of-pale-leaves-twin-suns-rising-pallid-masks-large.jpeg?itok=DQhUi0z4 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1034" height="724">
                  

  </picture><p>The book begins with a very detailed look into 1980s Japan, describing in general details the culture, how society reacted to an economic bubble, and close-up views of various aspects of daily life. Like all books in Chaosium’s <em>Call of Cthulhu</em> line, it feels well-researched, inviting you into a world that feels real and tangible (before things get extremely unreal and intangible, of course).</p><p>From there, readers will find valuable information about key characters, an overview of the plot, and rules for tracking a very specific and secret status effect throughout the campaign.</p><p><strong>WARNING: </strong>If you’re interested in <em>playing</em> this game vs. <em>running</em> this game as a keeper, I suggest you turn back now. I can’t talk about the book without spoiling at least <em>some</em> of the mystery and surprise here! Okay, you’ve been warned, here we go!</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/call-of-cthulhu-the-sutra-of-pale-leaves-twin-suns-rising-tokyo-twin-suns-large.jpeg?itok=UMRCScBn 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1014" height="702">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/call-of-cthulhu-the-sutra-of-pale-leaves-twin-suns-rising-tokyo-twin-suns-large.jpeg?itok=EAznZedl 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1014" height="702">
                  

  </picture><h2><strong>What’s Going On With This Sutra of Pale Leaves?</strong></h2><p>While the Sutra of Pale Leaves seems to be a very old, obtuse religious text, it’s actually a kind of memetic virus created by the Prince of Pale Leaves, better known to Mythos fans as The King in Yellow.&nbsp;</p><p>Trapped underground in his home world, he seeks to infect Earth with this mind-virus by exposing as many people as possible to the Sutra of Pale Leaves.</p><p>This is where our investigators come in, though they’ll have no idea at the start of the adventure that that’s what they’re up against.&nbsp;</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/call-of-cthulhu-the-sutra-of-pale-leaves-twin-suns-rising-cops-large.jpeg?itok=YhwO_3c2 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1042" height="712">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/call-of-cthulhu-the-sutra-of-pale-leaves-twin-suns-rising-cops-large.jpeg?itok=y4Fqtgto 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1042" height="712">
                  

  </picture><p>In fact, they could go an entire adventure (they call them Chapters in the book) without realizing the Sutra is actually a problem - such is the insidious nature of the Prince of Pale Leaves.</p><p>As the investigators explore 1980s Japan in the three included scenarios presented in this book (there’s another book in this setting with an additional four adventures also available called <a href="https://www.chaosium.com/call-of-cthulhu-the-sutra-of-pale-leaves-2-carcosa-manifest-hardcover/" rel="nofollow"><em>Carcosa Manifest</em></a>), they’ll slowly gain Exposure Points (which are kept secret from the investigators) by coming into contact with the Sutra.&nbsp;</p><p>As these points accumulate, they’ll become more and more under the sway of the Prince of Pale Leaves.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/call-of-cthulhu-the-sutra-of-pale-leaves-twin-suns-rising-tokyo-large.jpeg?itok=6u25ODEG 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1280" height="762">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/call-of-cthulhu-the-sutra-of-pale-leaves-twin-suns-rising-tokyo-large.jpeg?itok=BkzJg_RU 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="714">
                  

  </picture><p>This creates a wonderfully tense, running problem that the investigators may have little awareness of (especially at the start), and as they begin to realize the danger of coming into contact with the Sutra in all its forms, they’ll have to balance the necessity of interacting with the text against the perils of infecting their minds further with it.</p><h2><strong>What Adventures are included in </strong><em><strong>Call of Cthulhu: The Sutra of Pale Leaves - Twin Suns Rising</strong></em><strong>?</strong></h2><p>Included in <em>Call of Cthulhu: The Sutra of Pale Leaves - Twin Suns Rising </em>are three distinct adventures that can be played solo or chained together to form a longer campaign. I’ll speak briefly here about the flavor and general thrust of each one.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/call-of-cthulhu-the-sutra-of-pale-leaves-twin-suns-rising-baku-large.jpeg?itok=qkAG0t93 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="916" height="566">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/call-of-cthulhu-the-sutra-of-pale-leaves-twin-suns-rising-baku-large.jpeg?itok=LmH_J47r 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="916" height="566">
                  

  </picture><p>First up is <strong>Dream Eater</strong>, in this adventure the investigators are called to a small town outside of Tokyo to help uncover the root cause of bad dreams plaguing the town. As they uncover more, they’ll learn that a Baku (a Japanese supernatural creature known for devouring dreams) is feeding on nightmares caused by exposure to the Sutra.</p><p>This Baku’s presence threatens the Prince of Pale Leaves, as he doesn’t want his nightmares gobbled up - and so the investigators, who have little foreknowledge of any of the goings on with the Sutra (especially if this adventure is played first), may unwittingly end up helping <em>defeat</em> the Baku! Starting slow without thrusting the players into the rush of big city Tokyo, this adventure is great when it serves as the first one played in a longer campaign.</p><p>Next up is <strong>Fan Fiction</strong>, where a talented indie manga artist has turned the Sutra into a manga to increase its viral appeal. Knowing that the Sutra as a sacred religious text won’t reach the masses, this new approach is sure to spread its influence.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/call-of-cthulhu-the-sutra-of-pale-leaves-twin-suns-rising-manga-large.jpeg?itok=XfCZJd0J 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="942" height="640">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/call-of-cthulhu-the-sutra-of-pale-leaves-twin-suns-rising-manga-large.jpeg?itok=MBCsF4gP 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="942" height="640">
                  

  </picture><p>But when the adventure starts, the threat of this manga may not seem overtly apparent, as a twisted off-shoot and poorly made copy of the manga has been making the rounds, distorting the original viral code of the Sutra with disastrous consequences.</p><p>Third and final adventure in this book is <strong>The Pallid Masks of Tokyo</strong>, which begins with the ghastly discovery of a corpse in one of the nightlife districts of Tokyo. But there’s a catch… the body is completely faceless, with no eyes, nose, mouth, or ears!</p><p>This adventure will take investigators briefly through the seedy underbelly of Tokyo before plunging them into a psychiatric ward where machinations are in place to create an army of faceless servants for the Prince of Pale Leaves!</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/call-of-cthulhu-the-sutra-of-pale-leaves-twin-suns-rising-coroner-large.jpeg?itok=8XrkUpv1 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1034" height="1048">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/call-of-cthulhu-the-sutra-of-pale-leaves-twin-suns-rising-coroner-large.jpeg?itok=Cp5cWvOF 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1034" height="1048">
                  

  </picture><h2><em><strong>Call of Cthulhu: The Sutra of Pale Leaves - Twin Suns Rising</strong></em><strong> - Final Thoughts</strong></h2><p><em>Call of Cthulhu: The Sutra of Pale Leaves - Twin Suns Rising</em> is, without a doubt, one of the most exciting run of adventures and settings in <em>Call of Cthulhu</em> I’ve read in a long time. The shift into 1980s Japan is a breath of fresh air, and I love how heady the overall conceit of the campaign feels.</p><p>This isn’t cultists trying to bring a big octopus monster out of the ocean in New England, it’s a dedicated conspiracy in Tokyo trying to blend power, indulgence, and religious and spiritual fanaticism together to virally infect the psyches of as many everyday people as possible. The threat is always immediate <em>and</em> looming, and it feels complicated and conflicted in a way we seldom see in <em>any</em> tabletop roleplaying game.</p><p>And while the scope, depth, and somewhat sandbox style of adventure writing here might feel daunting for new players, I cannot recommend this book enough to players familiar with <em>Call of Cthulhu</em>, or for experienced TTRPG players looking to dip their toes into the system, but aren’t interested in the Roaring ‘20s vibe of the core game.</p><hr><p><em>The copy of </em>Call of Cthulhu: The Sutra of Pale Leaves - Twin Suns Rising<em> used in the creation of this review was provided by Chaosium. All images are screenshots from the provided pdf of </em>Twin Suns Rising<em>, courtesy of Chaosium.</em></p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Giaco Furino joined the TechRaptor team as a Staff Writer in 2019 after searching for a dedicated place to write and talk about Tabletop Games. In 2020, he… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/giaco-furino">More about Giaco</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/call-of-cthulhu-sutra-of-pale-leaves-twin-suns-rising-review-retro-freakout]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>