<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 17:53:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After a Successful Year, Marvel Rivals Has Big Plans, Teases MCU-Related Content]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/one-year-into-marvel-rivals-team-ups-tasteful-design-and-community-driven-1</link>
            <guid>1386229</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>It's been a little over a year since NetEase released its hero shooter <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/marvel-rivals" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow"><em>Marvel Rivals</em></a>. Since then, the game has taken on a life of its own and become one of the most popular games of 2025. During <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/the-game-awards-2025-recap" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">The Game Awards 2025</a>, TechRaptor sat down with the publishing and marketing lead of NetEase Games, Yachen Bian, and the executive producer of Marvel Games, Danny Koo, to talk about the game's journey and what they plan for the future--including a tease of potential content timed with <em>Avengers: Doomsday</em>.</p><p>One of the things that <em>Marvel Rivals</em> has been doing well is releasing content at a steady rate. Each season usually lasts about two months, and once a month, the team <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/marvel-rivals-season-5-gambit-rogue" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">releases a new character based on the season's theme</a>. As one might expect, the team already has an internal roadmap and plans out who they want in the game a year in advance. But it's also so much more than that. Koo explained that it also has to make sense narratively for them to join the game, too.&nbsp;</p><p>Team-ups are such a core part of the game. In short, they give players special abilities when two or specific characters are both on the field at the same time. Not only are these team-ups fun to watch, but they can also make or break games depending on how you use them. Koo explained the reason for adding this was because it only seemed natural to have them, and when you look at any comic, you can see all sorts of team-ups, such as Deadpool &amp; Wolverine, or any of the Avengers and X-Men.&nbsp;</p><p>Even though certain team-ups like Venom x Spider-Man seem like a slam dunk, they won't be in the game forever. This is because the team wanted to "encourage fresh new mechanics every season." The fear is that if they keep one team-up in the game for too long, it'll become "stale," so they want to "inject new excitement every season." Although Koo didn't go into much detail, he explained that the team plans to "expand this system" in 2026.&nbsp;</p><p>One thing worth mentioning is that earlier this year, <em>Marvel Rivals</em> announced that they would eventually be working on new original characters not from the comics, to join the game. Shortly after that, the <span>team&nbsp;</span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Games/comments/1mtvffc/netease_given_green_light_by_marvel_to_create/" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow"><span>received</span> pushback</a> from the community on this. When asked if the team has an idea of when they would be implementing new original characters, Koo reassured me that this would be a last resort item they use when they run out of established Marvel Comic characters.</p><p>"At Marvel games, I've worked on several original characters, and that's [only] when we need to do it. With so many characters in the Marvel Universe, we want to make sure each hero feels distinct from each other," Koo explained. "That's why you don't see five similar Spider-Men swinging around. We're going to continue to make sure that the existing batch of heroes [joining the game] will be serving the community. Who knows, in the future, when there is a particular need that existing thousands of other heroes can't serve, then we'll think of something original. But at this point, we are not ready for that."&nbsp;</p><p>It's no secret that the team at Marvel Rivals is known for drawing their characters in very specific ways that complement their bodies. You don't have to look too hard to find examples of this (I'm looking at you, Daredevil and Emma Frost). During our talk, I brought up the famous <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/TwoBestFriendsPlay/comments/1m8hhx8/the_cast_of_fantastic_four_first_steps_react_to/" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">Pedro Pascal video where he first saw the Invisible Woman Malice skin. </a>It's clear that the team adopted their own art style that appeals to both the male and female gaze. Koo explained that the idea was to always be tasteful yet realistic.</p><p>"Being a superhero [is very physical], they have a certain body archetype. So, of course, players will gravitate and be shocked by it. But if you look at the history of comics, it's always [shown off various body types]. You always see those physics, and the costumes highlight the physics," Koo explained. "Also, we're not afraid to show that off while not going too far, because this is still a T-rated game. We're not going into uncharted territory; we don't want [our game] to be adult stuff."&nbsp;</p><p>Koo also made it a point to address that some of the skins they have are a lot tamer than their original counterparts. He used Malice as an example and explained how the original costume was more revealing than the one people see in <em>Marvel Rivals</em>, so the team wanted to "modernize it." The new Malice look was so popular that Marvel Comics decided to bring it back in a new series that is launching this month.&nbsp;</p><p>As the team looks ahead to 2026, Koo explained that "2025 was a great year, but we have bigger plans for 2026." This includes a steady stream of heroes to join the roster as well as a new PVE (Players Versus Environment) mode.&nbsp;</p><p>"[Our] PVE mode, Marvel Zombies, jived well with players, so we're gonna expand upon that. We're also going to expand upon the hero power fantasy and the team-ups," Koo says. "So you're gonna see more efforts towards that area to fulfill a player's fantasy of playing superheroes in the <em>Marvel Rivals</em> universe. And, of course, next year, we have on the Marvel [Studio] side, two big movies coming out. We're also going to collab on that front in a huge way."&nbsp;</p><p>One thing the <em>Marvel Rivals</em> team has been very vocal about is how successful the PVE Marvel Zombies mode has been. During our interview, Koo alluded that this might be a mode players will see again this time next year, and we aim to look at it more deeply to further expand the gameplay. But the team is also looking to experiment with other non-traditional PVE modes, like what we saw with the Ultron chess mode.&nbsp;</p><p>The team declined to confirm whether an upcoming PVE mode would tie into the upcoming MCU film <em>Avengers: Doomsday</em>, but they assured me they have a release date in mind for the next mode. That said, they did also tease that when <em>Avengers: Doomsday</em> comes out next year, certain story beats would be concluded in <em>Marvel Rivals</em>.&nbsp;</p><p>It's no secret that <em>Marvel Rivals</em> took a lot of inspiration from other games in the space, like <em>Overwatch 2</em>. It wouldn't be far-fetched to compare the two games because they look and play so similarly. Koo went on to say that the team is a massive fan of shooters in general and tends to gravitate toward games like <em>Overwatch</em> and <em>Counter-Strike</em>. Before <em>Marvel Rivals</em> was even greenlit, they often toyed with the idea of making a hero shooter.&nbsp;</p><p>"[NetEase] looked at all the available games out in the market and saw that there was really no superhero shooter. [So we thought] we're going to do it our own way, the Marvel way."&nbsp;</p><p>A large part of why the team has had great success is how it communicates with its fanbase. Whenever changes happen that the majority of players disagree with, they're quick to fix them, and on top of that, the team is super on the nose with the memes and jokes surrounding the game, even leaning into them. Koo attributed a large part of that to the game's Discord server, which is the largest in the world with almost 4.2 million members.&nbsp;</p><p>"We have an army of content creators and moderators who compile feedback and suggestions. It also helps that I'm on social media and I get pinged left and right with people saying, 'Hey, this is interesting.' Or complaints about game features and bugs. So we see all of that stuff, including the dev team," Koo said. "It's not like we're putting up a wall. We literally tore the wall down and said, 'Hey, say whatever you want. We're listening, and we're doing our best to find out what the issue or interest is.'"&nbsp;</p><p>This was something that Bian went on to echo, by explaining that the team doesn't necessarily have a department that surfs the web to see what people are saying. So whenever you see someone like Creative Director Guangyun Chen say something as silly as "Aura Walk" in a community update video, it's them being genuine about it. Koo admitted that sometimes they'll see something the community is asking about online and text Chen to see if it's something they can implement in the game.&nbsp;</p><p>It's clear that the <em>Marvel Rivals</em> team has many ideas in store for 2026. After our long conversation, I'm confident that the team can deliver on another successful year as they enter year two. If you haven't tried it yet, <em>Marvel Rivals</em> is a free-to-play game available on PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, PC, and Xbox Series X|S.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Luis Gutierrez is a journalist who's worked with various outlets, including IGN, GameSpot, Kotaku, and many more. He has a degree in journalism and loves… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/luis-gutierrez">More about Luis</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/one-year-into-marvel-rivals-team-ups-tasteful-design-and-community-driven-1]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>