<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 21:29:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2: The Board Game Coming Courtesy of Steamforged Games]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/helldivers-2-board-game-coming-courtesy-of-steamforged-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/helldivers-2-the-board-game-coming-courtesy-of-steamforged-games.1134030/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/helldivers-2-board-game-coming-courtesy-of-steamforged-games<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Steamforged Games has announced <em>Helldivers 2: The Board Game</em>. The tabletop studio known for creating complex bespoke tabletop games like <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/runescape-kingdoms-shadow-of-elvarg-review" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Runescape Kingdoms</em></a> and <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/steamforged-announces-sea-of-thieves-voyage-of-legends" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Sea of Thieves</em></a> will bring Arrowhead Game Studios' satirical sci-fi shooter to gaming tables.</p>

<h2>The <em>Helldivers 2: The Board Game</em> Announcement</h2>

<p>According to an official press release, Helldivers 2: The Board Game will be produced through a crowdfunding campaign on Gamefound. Much like the Helldivers 2 videogame, the board game will be a fast-paced, tactical co-op game for one to four players. Those players will utilize deadly weapons, powerful stratagems, and coordinated tactics to overcome enemy threats in service of Super Earth.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/helldivers-2-the-board-game-enemy-miniature.jpg?itok=zg2yvAtD 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/helldivers-2-the-board-game-enemy-miniature.jpg?itok=bBOIHK3t 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>In addition, <em>Helldivers 2: The Board Game</em> will translate the game's escalation and tongue-in-cheek humor. Objectives and threats will evolve as players progress. This will mean avoiding dangerous explosions, overwhelming waves of enemies, and the most dangerous threat of all: friendly fire. Every decision you make can mean the difference between glorious victory or total annihilation.</p>

<p><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/helldivers-2" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Helldivers 2</em></a> released on PC and PlayStation 5 in February 2024. It is one of PlayStation's fastest selling video games, selling over 12 million copies within its first 12 weeks. In addition, it has several accolades such as Best Multiplayer from the 2024 Golden Joystick Awards and The Game Awards 2024.</p>

<p>Arrowhead Game Studios' CEO Shams Jorjani said the following about working with Steamforged Games on <em>Helldivers 2: The Board Game</em>.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>As passionate tabletop gamers ourselves, we're delighted to partner with Steamforged to bring Helldivers 2 into a whole new realm. The game's intense action is a perfect fit for the tabletop experience, and we can't wait for players to blast their way through its chaotic and challenging missions soon.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Steamforged Games' reputation in tabletop games is stellar. In addition to making impressive board games based on videogame properties, they have also produced great TTRPG products and accessories such as their <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/epic-encounters-palace-of-drow-queen-and-lair-of-drider-review-new-shade-of" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Epic Encounters</em></a> miniature boxes.</p>

<p>The Gamefound campaign for <em>Helldivers 2: The Board Game</em> will go live on April 8, 2025.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>