<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 20:15:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Confront Cybernetic Hamsters and Sentient Pizza in Tavers: The Meow Wolf RPG]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/confront-cybernetic-hamsters-and-sentient-pizza-in-tavers-meow-wolf-rpg</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/confront-cybernetic-hamsters-and-sentient-pizza-in-tavers-the-meow-wolf-rpg.1274814/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The immersive entertainment company Meow Wolf has announced their next interactive experience, and it is a TTRPG. The company is working alongside Genuine Entertainment and Exalted Funeral for the aptly named <em>Tavers: The Meow Wolf RPG</em>.</p>

<h2>The <em>Tavers: The Meow Wolf RPG</em> Announcement</h2>

<p>According to an official press release, <em>Tavers: The Meow Wolf RPG</em> will be coming to Kickstarter in Spring 2026. In this RPG, players are the titular tavers, people with the power to open portals to new worlds, alternate realities, and new states of existence. Those worlds will include immortal cybernetic hamsters, sentient pizza, and underground rat punks, and more.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/meow-wolf-exhibit-promo-image.jpg?itok=qn9B31UB 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/meow-wolf-exhibit-promo-image.jpg?itok=LyeV55T6 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The game will emphasize creativity and imagination, utilizing an "exquisite corpse" approach to shared storytelling with a focus on mystery and the unknown.</p>

<p>Notably, the press release does not specify a certain RPG system or a central gameplay mechanic. It states that the game will "empower players to do far more than just skill checks;&nbsp;daring to manifest impossible ideas that defy logic, shift perception, and reshape<br>
reality itself."</p>

<p>As for the unusual worlds in <em>Tavers: The Meow Wolf RPG</em>, some may be familiar to fans of the studio's past work. Players are encouraged to shape the story and the worlds they enter through their choices and actions. Memories formed by both players and their characters can be used as currency.</p>

<p>Meow Wolf is one of the most popular immersive art companies in recent years. Their first exhibit, <em>House of Eternal Return</em>, debuted in Santa Fe in 2016. Since then, they have helmed other mind-bending exhibits, such as 2021's <em>Omega Mart</em> in Las Vegas and <em>Convergence Station</em> in Denver. Their most recent project was 2024's <em>Radio Tave</em>, a community radio station that spanned multiple dimensions.</p>

<p>Meow Wolf's partners in this project come from similar unconventional places. Exalted Funeral's body of work includes the quirky <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/monty-python-ttrpg-is-coming-to-kickstarter" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Monty Python TTRPG</em></a>, and Genuine Entertainment has had experience with TTRPG adaptations of <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/diablo-board-game-unleashes-hell-in-2024" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Diablo</em></a> and <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/walking-dead-ttrpg-shambles-to-tables-fall-2023" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>The Walking Dead</em></a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/confront-cybernetic-hamsters-and-sentient-pizza-in-tavers-meow-wolf-rpg]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Moonlighter 2 Early Access Release Date Revealed for October]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/moonlighter-2-early-access-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/moonlighter-2-early-access-release-date-revealed-for-october.1274811/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Publisher 11 bit studios and developer Digital Sun have announced that&nbsp;<em>Moonlighter 2&nbsp;</em>will be coming to Early Access before it gets a full release, and the two studios have also revealed the release date for that launch.</p>

<p>As announced during today's Gamescom Opening Night Live ceremony,&nbsp;<em>Moonlighter 2: The Endless Vault</em>&nbsp;will be hitting Early Access on PC on October 23rd. Evidently, this means the console releases will come later.</p>

<p>The two studios say that crafting&nbsp;<em>Moonlighter 2&nbsp;</em>into its "final form" will take time, and that while the game is "nearly complete", there are still "a few parts" of the experience that "need polishing".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/moonlighter-2-early-access-training-dummy.jpg?itok=Y3sv6Rvi 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/moonlighter-2-early-access-training-dummy.jpg?itok=bkePgZD3 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Much like Will here,&nbsp;<em>Moonlighter 2&nbsp;</em>needs to train a little before it's ready for the real thing.</figcaption></figure><p>Although&nbsp;<em>Moonlighter 2&nbsp;</em>is launching into Early Access, it doesn't sound like you're getting a significantly cut-back version of the game; 11 bit and Digital Sun promise "most of the story" will be available at launch.</p>

<p>You'll be able to explore three biomes, gather and sell over 120 relics and items, and explore a combat system with four main weapons, "nearly 100 shop and dungeon perks", and a smoother feel.</p>

<p>If you're wondering exactly what&nbsp;<em>Moonlighter 2&nbsp;</em>is, it's the sequel to 2018's shop management sim-slash-roguelite dungeon crawler&nbsp;<em>Moonlighter</em>. Announced <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/moonlighter-2-announced-2025" rel="nofollow">back in December</a>, the game switches its predecessor's pixel art look for a 3D visual style.</p>

<p>Other than that change, though, it sounds as though&nbsp;<em>Moonlighter 2&nbsp;</em>will largely be business as usual if you've played the first game; 11 bit and Digital Sun say you can expect "a quest demanding plenty of dodge rolling, fighting, looting, and clever shopkeeping".</p>




<p>You'll be able to check out&nbsp;<em>Moonlighter 2&nbsp;</em>when it launches on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2350790/Moonlighter_2_The_Endless_Vault/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC via Steam Early Access</a> (as well as on PC Game Pass) on October 23rd. PS5 and Xbox Series X|S versions are also planned, so while you wait, why not check out our very own Andrew Stretch's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/head-back-out-for-supplies-in-moonlighter-2-endless-vault" rel="nofollow">preview of the game here</a>?</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/moonlighter-2-early-access-release-date]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>