<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 14:40:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mario Kart World Is a Switch 2 Game Because of Mario Kart 8 Deluxe's DLC]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/mario-kart-world-originally-switch-1</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mario-kart-world-is-a-switch-2-game-because-of-mario-kart-8-deluxes-dlc.1195167/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/mario-kart-world-originally-switch-1<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Nintendo has revealed that&nbsp;Switch 2 launch title&nbsp;<em>Mario Kart World&nbsp;</em>was originally in development for the first Switch, and that the release of&nbsp;<em>Mario Kart 8 Deluxe</em>'s Booster Course Pass DLC is the reason the game ended up on Switch 2.</p>

<p>The Japanese gaming giant's latest Ask the Developer article is all about the new&nbsp;<em>Mario Kart&nbsp;</em>game, which launches <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/mario-kart-world-switch-2-launch-title" rel="nofollow">alongside the Switch 2 on June 5th</a>. It turns out, though, that Nintendo began prototyping&nbsp;<em>Mario Kart World&nbsp;</em>all the way back in 2017.</p>

<p>According to producer Kosuke Yabuki, work on&nbsp;<em>Mario Kart World&nbsp;</em>began in March 2017, a month or so before the release of&nbsp;<em>Mario Kart 8 Deluxe</em>. Programming director Kenta Sato says the original plan was to develop for the Switch, but that this threw up a lot of technical issues.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/mario-kart-world-switch-1-game-switch-2-shot.jpg?itok=9F4aF8SX 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/mario-kart-world-switch-1-game-switch-2-shot.jpg?itok=qtH1RAF- 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Mario Kart World&nbsp;</em>was originally intended as a Switch game.</figcaption></figure><p>Specifically, Sato says there were doubts about whether the original Switch was capable of accommodating&nbsp;<em>Mario Kart World</em>'s 24-player limit. The team discussed various solutions, including "toning down the visuals, lowering the resolution, and...dropping the frame rate to 30fps".</p>

<p>Yabuki says that the team "kick[ed] the can down the road" while trying to work out what to compromise on for&nbsp;<em>Mario Kart World</em>, but that when&nbsp;<em>Mario Kart 8 Deluxe</em>'s Booster Course Pass DLC was released, it gave the team "a bit more time to continue development".</p>

<p>During that time, the development team discussed moving&nbsp;<em>Mario Kart World&nbsp;</em>to the Switch 2, which became, as Yabuki puts it, "a ray of hope", opening up "a bunch of possibilities" and removing the need to compromise on performance or visual fidelity.</p>




<p><em>Mario Kart World&nbsp;</em>will launch for <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/mario-kart-world-switch-2/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Nintendo Switch 2</a> on June 5th. It's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-switch-2-launch-lineup" rel="nofollow">just one of the games</a> that will be available for the system on release, alongside the likes of&nbsp;<em>Split Fiction</em>,&nbsp;<em>Hogwarts Legacy</em>, and the bafflingly paid-for&nbsp;<em>Nintendo Switch 2 Welcome Tour</em>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Train 2 Review - To Hell and Back]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/monster-train-2-review-to-hell-and-back</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-train-2-review-to-hell-and-back.1195119/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/monster-train-2-review-to-hell-and-back<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Standing out as a roguelike deckbuilder is hard. New games in the genre seem to constantly be releasing on Steam. For every <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/high-stakes-how-balatro-confronts-addiction-and-roguelikes" rel="nofollow">breakout hit like&nbsp;<em>Balatro</em></a>, some games just get left behind. If you're going to release a deckbuilder in the current landscape, you better be sure you have a way to stand out.&nbsp;<em>Monster Train 2&nbsp;</em>uses the autobattler foundation of its predecessor to iterate by doubling down on player freedom.</p>

<p>From the selection screen to the last track on the map, there are so many ways for you to build your perfect army to storm the gates of Heaven with. Though the forces you face and friends you find can become a little repetitive, the toolbox Shiny Shoe gives to you feels near infinite in the ways you can customize each run.</p>

<h2><em>Monster Train 2</em> - Charming Challenges</h2>



<p>The structure of <em>Monster Train 2 </em>stands on the shoulders, like most roguelike deckbuilders, stands on the shoulders of <em>Slay the Spire</em>. However, beyond the deckbuilding and energy aspects, this deckbuilder is very much its own thing.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Fights take place on your train, which has three floors. You place units on each floor, trying to prevent monsters from climbing the floors of your train. If you can’t defeat them, they reach your train’s most valuable resource: the Pyre Heart. Your units can die without consequence, but when your Pyre Heart reaches zero health, you lose.</p>

<p>This gameplay is divided into different runs, each of which can take up to around an hour. These are eight battles, each with a track to choose from between battles. Tracks have different stops, including places to spend your gold, fireplaces to heal your Pyre Heart, and banners to recruit new units to your forces.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The main increasing challenge that each run presents is the difficulty system of Covenants. As the Covenant level increases from 1-10, you gain new challenges, like reduced control over your deck and increased strength for your enemies.</p>

<p>If you want some more interesting challenges, though, you can head over to the Dimensional Challenge portal. These challenges will provide interesting and compelling modifiers and restrictions to change how you see the game. For instance, in one early challenge, everything you receive is doubled.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It sounds great at first: double gold will make upgrades so much easier! Then, you realize it means that you also need to take two copies of every card. It really makes you rethink which cards to take in a creative way. If you find mutators you enjoy more than others, you can choose to add them to your standard runs before starting them from the menu.</p>

<h2><em>Monster Train 2</em> - Expression Excellence</h2>



<p>Deckbuilders are at their best when they give you the tools to break them in creative ways. <em>Monster Train 2</em> delivers in spades, and a major reason why is the clan system. In addition to choosing a primary clan that grants a primary champion to follow, you choose a secondary clan, which can impact your starting deck cards and cards you find along the way.&nbsp;</p>

<p>For instance, combining the Lazarus League’s Reanimate abilities with the Banished’s Valor spells can help your units revive near death with 1 health point, but high armor to withstand continued attacks.</p>

<p>As you collect cards, your runs can become even more personalized with upgrades you collect. Instead of a linear upgrade system, <em>Monster Train 2</em> takes a more open approach to upgrades, letting you choose which aspects of a card you want to upgrade in each shop.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Do you want to make a card that’s usually only single-use, able to be used multiple times in one combat? Reduce a card’s energy cost? Make a spell’s power more potent? The choice is yours, and you can go anywhere.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The best part is that there isn’t a single “correct” answer. There may be ones you become more comfortable with, but the best answer will change depending on how your run is developing, and what you’re focusing on to do heavy damage or build up your defenses in your run.</p>

<h2><em>Monster Train 2</em> - The Repetition Rut</h2>



<p>While you have loads of variety to express yourself, I wish the enemy forces you were fighting did the same. There are a couple of different possible permutations for each of the 8 encounters, but after a few runs, you'll see most of what there is to see as far as encounters.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The bosses are the same during each train ride through Heaven, with 3 in each run. There are a few different modifiers they have to freshen them up, but it definitely leaves runs feeling a little samey if you are playing as the same clans.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Celestial Alcove events, which are small events that let you make choices to affect your deck, also seem to pull from a pretty small variety. I started mostly ignoring these because while some were neat, it felt like I'd seen them all pretty early. When I did see them, more often than not, I ignored them due to the harsh penalties that some imposed.</p>

<p>This will also become the case with given clans. With so many different card types like Spells, Equipment, and Units, and specialized shops for each, you'll almost certainly start seeing the same cards in your runs. However, this was a small snag that was easy to circumvent. When I started seeing a lot of the same cards, changing up the clan made it feel fresh again. Even when I started seeing the same cards, I could make different upgrade choices to make things feel fresh.</p>

<p>More unlocks for content started to unlock throughout the process of the main story. As you progress the story, which will happen naturally as you unlock the various clans and Pyre Hearts, other mechanics, both for your foes and you, will reveal themselves. It's a neat way to gate content and drip-feed new stuff as you progress.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, the story itself is a little one-note and feels like it relies quite a bit on knowledge of the first&nbsp;<em>Monster Train</em>. It's easy to enjoy the game itself without the knowledge of the predecessor, but you might be scratching your head a bit during the dialogue exchanges without it.</p>

<h2><em>Monster Train 2</em> - Final Thoughts</h2>

<p><em>Monster Train 2&nbsp;</em>is a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/blue-prince-review-i-finished-game-50-hours-ago-and-theres-still-puzzles-to-solve" rel="nofollow">great deckbuilder</a> that fans of the genre should add to their collection. The resistance you face can start to feel a little repetitive as you start getting deeper into the game, and the story is more of a vehicle for unlocks than something that stands on its own. But the toolbox of deckbuilding creativity on the player side, from the synergies you can build in your deck to mutators you can add into your run, makes it feel like a game that anyone who takes the time can break in the best way.</p>

<hr><p><em><strong>Monster Train 2</strong> was reviewed on PC with a copy provided by the developer over the course of 15 hours of gameplay - all screenshots were taken during the process of review.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Parker is a freelance writer based in Iowa, and the co-founder and editor of gaming satire site Palette Swap. Before Palette Swap, he was an editor at Hard… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/parker-johnson">More about Parker</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oblivion Remastered Tops US Gaming Sales Chart for April]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/oblivion-remastered-sales-circana-april-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/oblivion-remastered-tops-us-gaming-sales-chart-for-april.1195116/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/oblivion-remastered-sales-circana-april-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Circana has released its gaming industry sales data for April in the US, and Bethesda's&nbsp;<em>Oblivion Remastered&nbsp;</em>has topped sales charts for the month, an impressive feat considering its availability on Game Pass.</p>

<p>According to Circana's Mat Piscatella,&nbsp;<em>Oblivion Remastered&nbsp;</em>topped the <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3lpoo44vmwk2e" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">all-format sales charts</a>&nbsp;for the month, and it also hit number one on both the <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3lpoo4byukv2e" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation</a> and <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3lpoo4dcbr52e" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox</a> charts individually. The game isn't available on the Switch, so that console's honor went to&nbsp;<em>Mario Kart 8 Deluxe</em>.</p>

<p>In case you need a reminder, the&nbsp;<em>Oblivion&nbsp;</em>remaster was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-released" rel="nofollow">shadowdropped last month</a> (although it had become a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/new-oblivion-remake-images-seemingly-leaked" rel="nofollow">pretty poorly-kept secret</a> by the time it was released). Developed by Virtuos, the game retains the original title's gameplay and underlying engine, but gives it a fresh Unreal Engine 5 coat of paint.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/oblivion-remastered-circana-april-spriggan.jpg?itok=FT8Ftecy 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/oblivion-remastered-circana-april-spriggan.jpg?itok=5lkIrgE8 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Oblivion Remastered&nbsp;</em>has sold pretty well, despite the fact that it's on Game Pass.</figcaption></figure><p>In second place on the all-format charts is&nbsp;<em>Forza Horizon 5</em>, no doubt bolstered by its PS5 release in April, with&nbsp;<em>MLB: The Show 25</em>,&nbsp;<em>Minecraft</em>, and&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed Shadows&nbsp;</em>in third, fourth, and fifth place respectively.</p>

<p>On a year-to-date basis (i.e. starting from January and running until May), the best-selling game of the year is still Capcom's&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>, which shouldn't come as a surprise given its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-sales-10m" rel="nofollow">phenomenal early sales performance</a>.</p>

<p>Second place goes to&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed Shadows</em>, which will likely come as a reassurance to Ubisoft given its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ubisoft-financials-layoffs-possible" rel="nofollow">grim financial state</a>, and the aforementioned&nbsp;<em>Oblivion Remastered&nbsp;</em>is the year's third best-selling game so far.</p>

<p>In the hardware stakes, the PS5 has once again emerged victorious in April on both unit and dollar sales. Switch hardware sales plummeted by 37% compared to last year, but that's arguably to be expected given that its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-switch-2-release-date" rel="nofollow">successor is just around the corner</a>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/monster-hunter-wilds-circana-april.jpg?itok=UEPpNWuP 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/monster-hunter-wilds-circana-april.jpg?itok=zC-TT8g2 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</em>is still the year's best-selling game.</figcaption></figure><p>As ever, you can check out Piscatella and Circana's full highlights thread <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3lpoo3w2xuc2e" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">over on Bluesky</a>&nbsp;if you want to take a more in-depth look at the numbers.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Senua's Saga: Hellblade II Coming to PS5 This Summer]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/senuas-saga-hellblade-ii-ps5</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/senuas-saga-hellblade-ii-coming-to-ps5-this-summer.1195071/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/senuas-saga-hellblade-ii-ps5<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Ninja Theory has announced that its narrative-led action-adventure game&nbsp;<em>Senua's Saga: Hellblade II&nbsp;</em>will be making its way to the PlayStation 5 sometime this summer.</p>

<p>In <a href="https://x.com/NinjaTheory/status/1925174749317185829" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">a post</a> on X, Ninja Theory celebrates the one-year anniversary of the game's release by freeing it of its Xbox exclusivity (on console, at least). We don't have a release date for the game yet; the studio simply says it's coming in "summer".</p>

<p>Alongside the PS5 version, Ninja Theory also says that&nbsp;<em>Hellblade II&nbsp;</em>will be getting some extra features, and that these features will also be coming to the Xbox and PC versions of the game, presumably when the PS5 version launches.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/senuas-saga-hellblade-ii-ps5-running.jpg?itok=523wL_XT 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/senuas-saga-hellblade-ii-ps5-running.jpg?itok=KTrLfUKS 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Senua's Saga: Hellblade II&nbsp;</em>is coming to PS5 this summer.</figcaption></figure><p>The PS5 version of&nbsp;<em>Senua's Saga: Hellblade II&nbsp;</em>will also sport some PS5 Pro improvements, with Ninja Theory "working hard to optimize [the game] for both PlayStation 5 and PlayStation 5 Pro" in order to provide the "very best experience".</p>

<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Senua's Saga: Hellblade II</em>, it's the sequel to 2017's&nbsp;<em>Hellblade: Senua's Sacrifice</em>, and it picks up the story of the titular character as she travels to Iceland in order to save her people from slavery.</p>

<p>Like the first game, <i>Hellblade II&nbsp;</i>is a linear journey that marries action-adventure gameplay and combat, exploration, and psychological horror elements. The titular character, Senua, suffers from psychosis, a condition that manifests itself in the form of voices that both guide and hinder her.</p>




<p>Ninja Theory's game is just one of several Xbox titles to come to PS5 in the last year or two. Others include the likes of&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-ps5-release-date" rel="nofollow"><em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</em></a>, Obsidian adventures&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sea-of-thieves-grounded-and-pentiment-officially-announced-for-playstation-platforms" rel="nofollow"><em>Grounded&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Pentiment</em></a>, and open-world racer&nbsp;<em>Forza Horizon 5</em>.</p>

<p>Additionally, the upcoming&nbsp;<em>Gears of War&nbsp;</em>remaster&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gears-of-war-reloaded-announced" rel="nofollow">Gears of War: Reloaded</a>&nbsp;</em>will bring the influential third-person shooter franchise to PlayStation for the first time when it launches later this year.</p>

<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Senua's Saga: Hellblade II&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/senuas-saga-hellblade-II" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a> and <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2461850/Senuas_Saga_Hellblade_II/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>. It's also available as part of a Game Pass subscription if you're signed up to the PC or Ultimate tiers.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>