<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 17:44:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PC Gamers Spent $1b in the Epic Games Store in 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/epic-games-store-year-in-review-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pc-gamers-spent-1b-in-the-epic-games-store-in-2024.1109787/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/epic-games-store-year-in-review-2024<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The Epic Games Store Year in Review for 2024 is here, and according to Epic, PC gamers spent a pretty impressive amount of money in the store last year, although there could well be a very good reason for that.</p>

<p>Epic says that PC players racked up $1.09 billion in spending on the Store throughout 2024, but that figure is "including Epic's games", so it's likely that the number includes spending for battle royale juggernaut&nbsp;<em>Fortnite</em>.</p>

<p>The figure represents a 15% increase on <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/epic-games-store-year-in-review-2023" rel="nofollow">last year's</a>, but if the number is restricted to just third-party games, it's much lower; just $255m was spent on third-party PC games in the store in 2024, representing an 18% drop from 2023's total.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/epic-games-store-2024-year-in-review-fortnite.jpg?itok=t9JYXZb0 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/epic-games-store-2024-year-in-review-fortnite.jpg?itok=L_Y9J8AM 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>PC spending on the Epic Games Store jumped to over $1b in 2024, but that probably includes&nbsp;<em>Fortnite</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>Elsewhere, Epic hit a new high of 295 million total Epic Games Store PC users last year, representing a 25 million increase on a year-over-year basis.</p>

<p>However, the highest monthly active user total on the platform was 74 million, which Epic achieved in December 2024. That represents a drop of 1% over last year's peak figure, although I'm sure Epic won't be losing sleep over that.</p>

<p>Average monthly active users rose by 6%, as did average daily active users, and the total number of hours players spent playing games on the store was 7.72 billion, a rise of 10% over last year's figure.</p>

<p>Epic's free game program also continued throughout 2024, bringing games like <i><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hell-let-loose-epic-games-store-free" rel="nofollow">Hell Let Loose</a>&nbsp;</i>and&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sifu-epic-games-store-free" rel="nofollow">Sifu</a>&nbsp;</em>to players for absolutely nothing. All in all, players redeemed almost 600 million free games via the store in 2024.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/epic-games-store-2024-year-in-review-sifu.jpg?itok=N6yros06 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/epic-games-store-2024-year-in-review-sifu.jpg?itok=42HgObl2 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Sifu&nbsp;</em>was just one of the free games available via the Epic Games Store last year.</figcaption></figure><p>So, what were the most-played Epic Store games in 2024? As ever, Epic divides its hall of fame into three separate tiers: Mythic, Legendary, and Epic. Here they are in all their glory!</p>

<h3>Most played Epic Games Store games in 2024: Mythic tier</h3>

<ul><li><em>Genshin Impact</em></li>
	<li><em>Rocket League</em></li>
	<li><em>Honkai: Star Rail</em></li>
	<li><em>Grand Theft Auto 5</em></li>
	<li><em>Fortnite</em></li>
</ul><h3>Most played Epic Games Store games in 2024: Legendary tier</h3>

<ul><li><em>EA Sports FC 24</em></li>
	<li><em>Destiny 2</em></li>
	<li><em>Alan Wake 2</em></li>
	<li><em>Fall Guys</em></li>
	<li><em>Wuthering Waves</em></li>
</ul><h3>Most played Epic Games Store games in 2024: Epic tier</h3>

<ul><li><em>EA Sports FC 25</em></li>
	<li><em>Cyberpunk 2077</em></li>
	<li><em>The Sims 4</em></li>
	<li><em>Black Myth: Wukong</em></li>
	<li><em>Satisfactory</em></li>
	<li><em>Warframe</em></li>
	<li><em>Farming Simulator 22</em></li>
	<li><em>Dead by Daylight</em></li>
	<li><em>Red Dead Redemption 2</em></li>
	<li><em>Dead Island 2</em></li>
</ul><p>You can check out Epic's full rundown of its store's year <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/news/epic-games-store-2024-year-in-review" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">here</a>&nbsp;if you want to pore over more stats and figures. It's an interesting read!</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dynasty Warriors: Origins Sales Top 1m Worldwide]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dynasty-warriors-origins-sales-1m</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dynasty-warriors-origins-sales-top-1m-worldwide.1109715/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dynasty-warriors-origins-sales-1m<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Koei Tecmo has revealed that&nbsp;<em>Dynasty Warriors: Origins&nbsp;</em>sales have hit their first major milestone exactly a month after the game's initial release.</p>

<p>Per a press release,&nbsp;<em>Dynasty Warriors: Origins&nbsp;</em>has racked up a million sales across PC and current-gen consoles. Not only that, but the game's demo, which is available to check out right now, has amassed over two million downloads.</p>

<p>To celebrate the sales milestone, Koei Tecmo also posted some new artwork featuring the amnesiac main character of&nbsp;<em>Dynasty Warriors: Origins</em>, along with the kindly doctor Yuanhua, who's helping our protagonist look for answers about his past.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dynasty-warriors-origins-sales-1m-artwork.jpg?itok=WqShp_vW 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dynasty-warriors-origins-sales-1m-artwork.jpg?itok=T5N-p9lS 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Dynasty Warriors: Origins</em>&nbsp;has officially sold over a million copies.</figcaption></figure><p>If you're unfamiliar with&nbsp;<em>Dynasty Warriors: Origins</em>, it's the latest entry in Koei Tecmo's long-running hack-and-slash series, which actually <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/guides/dynasty-warriors-fighting-game-turned-musou" rel="nofollow">started life as a one-on-one fighter</a> serving as a spinoff of the publisher's&nbsp;<em>Romance of the Three Kingdoms&nbsp;</em>franchise.</p>

<p>Although the name might lead you to believe that <i>Origins&nbsp;</i>is a prequel, that's only true in a certain sense. The game still takes place in the time period covered by the classical Chinese novel&nbsp;<em>Romance of the Three Kingdoms</em>, but it focuses heavily on the first half rather than encompassing the whole thing.</p>

<p>Rather uniquely for&nbsp;<em>Dynasty Warriors</em>,&nbsp;<em>Origins&nbsp;</em>features an original protagonist, and in much the same way as Team Ninja's&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/wo-long-fallen-dynasty" rel="nofollow"><em>Wo Long: Fallen Dynasty</em></a>, the story revolves around our main character as he meets famous historical figures and helps them to beat the snot out of hundreds of enemies on the battlefield.</p>




<p>Narrative changes aside, however,&nbsp;<em>Dynasty Warriors: Origins&nbsp;</em>offers more of the same large-scale tactical hack-and-slash combat you've come to know (and potentially love) from the franchise, so you'll probably already know whether this one's for you or not.</p>

<p><em>Dynasty Warriors: Origins&nbsp;</em>is available right now for <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2384580/DYNASTY_WARRIORS_ORIGINS/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/dynasty-warriors-origins/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/dynasty-warriors-origins/9p5hjqnx53xj" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>. Stay tuned for more on this one.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dark and Darker Studio Infringed on Nexon's Trade Secrets, Korean Court Rules]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dark-and-darker-lawsuit-trade-secret-infringement</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dark-and-darker-studio-infringed-on-nexons-trade-secrets-korean-court-rules.1109679/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dark-and-darker-lawsuit-trade-secret-infringement<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The Korean courts have ruled that Ironmace's dungeon-crawling PvPvE action RPG&nbsp;<em>Dark and Darker&nbsp;</em>did not infringe on Nexon's copyright, but that it did infringe on the company's trade secrets, necessitating a payment of around 8.5 billion Korean won (around $6 million).</p>

<p>Per Korean news platform <a href="https://biz.chosun.com/en/en-it/2025/02/13/MXHA4WV3ANHRFCJZQI4UE4HTQE/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Chosun</a>, the Seoul Central District Court's Civil Division 63 came to the decision yesterday. It essentially represents both a win and a loss for Ironmace.</p>

<p>For context, since 2023,&nbsp;<em>Dark and Darker&nbsp;</em>has been the subject of an ongoing legal battle between developer Ironmace and Korean studio Nexon, several ex-employees of which make up some of Ironmace's ranks.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dark-and-darker-court-case-trade-secret-infringement-skeletons.jpg?itok=o1901PnW 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dark-and-darker-court-case-trade-secret-infringement-skeletons.jpg?itok=LR9qxE_F 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Dark and Darker&nbsp;</em>developer Ironmace must pay Nexon around $6 million for trade secret infringement.</figcaption></figure><p>Nexon alleged in its lawsuit that&nbsp;<em>Dark and Darker&nbsp;</em>bore striking similarities to an internal game tentatively codenamed&nbsp;<em>P3</em>. That project's leader Ju-Hyun Choi was fired from Nexon in August 2021 and went on to create&nbsp;<em>Dark and Darker&nbsp;</em>alongside several other ex-Nexon staffers.</p>

<p>According to Nexon, assets from&nbsp;<em>P3</em>'s development were leaked by Choi onto an external non-Nexon server, and those assets were instrumental in Choi's decision to try and create a game that would play similarly to&nbsp;<em>P3</em>.</p>

<p>The lawsuit led to Nexon <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dark-and-darker-developers-respond-to-dmca-takedown-from-nexon-after-removal-from-steam" rel="nofollow">issuing a DMCA takedown</a> against&nbsp;<em>Dark and Darker&nbsp;</em>on Steam in March 2023 (although the game has since been restored to the platform) and also resulted in a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dark-and-darker-early-access-delayed-bit-following-legal-dispute-against-nexon" rel="nofollow">delay to the game's eventual 1.0 release</a>, according to Ironmace.</p>

<p>From Chosun's report, it sounds as though the Korean court agrees with Nexon that material was leaked onto a server from inside the company, but the court doesn't consider this matter to fall under the umbrella of copyright infringement.</p>




<p>It's not clear whether Nexon will pursue any further legal action against Ironmace and&nbsp;<em>Dark and Darker</em>, but for now, it looks as though the studio and its game won't be facing any more imminent legal threats or takedowns.</p>

<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Dark and Darker&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2016590/Dark_and_Darker/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a> and mobile devices.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>