<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - techraptor_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/techraptor_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for techraptor_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 16:58:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Global Release Timings Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-global-release-timings</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-global-release-timings-revealed.1119573/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-global-release-timings<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="page-content">
  
          
      
<article role="article">

  
    

  
  <div>
      
  
  
  <div>
      <div><p>Capcom has revealed the global release timings for&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>, so we now know what time each region around the world will be able to get its hands on the game.</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://x.com/monsterhunter/status/1894620982939193800" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">post</a> on X, Capcom both reveals the timings and also reminds players that pre-load is now available, so if you want to be able to play&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</em>as soon as it launches in your region, you can download the relevant data now.</p>

<p>For many regions, there will be a slight delay between the game's launch on PC and its arrival on consoles, and the timing isn't the same around the world, either.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/monster-hunter-wilds-global-release-timings-monsters.jpg?itok=aQXSzzdi 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/monster-hunter-wilds-global-release-timings-monsters.jpg?itok=3X23wNbi 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</em>is due for release in just a couple of days.</figcaption></figure><p>For the western US,&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</em>will technically land on February 27th, while for the rest of the world, it will <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-release-date" rel="nofollow">launch on the 28th</a>.</p>

<p>Here's a full list of all the launch timings for&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>. Remember to check your region to make sure you're ready to play the game as soon as it arrives!</p>

<ul><li>Los Angeles, USA: February 27th, 9pm PST on consoles and PC</li>
	<li>Mexico City, Mexico: February 27th, 12am CST on consoles, 11pm CST on PC</li>
	<li>Toronto, Canada: 12am EST on PC and consoles</li>
	<li>New York, USA: 12am EST on PC and consoles</li>
	<li>São Paulo, Brazil: 12am BRT on consoles, 2am BRT on PC</li>
	<li>London, UK: 12am GMT on PC, 5am GMT on PC</li>
	<li>Paris, France: 12am CET on consoles, 6am CET on PC</li>
	<li>Berlin, Germany: 12am CET on consoles, 6am CET on PC</li>
	<li>Helsinki, Finland: 12am EET on consoles, 7am EET on PC</li>
	<li>Cairo, Egypt: 12am EET on consoles, 7am EET on PC</li>
	<li>Johannesburg, South Africa: 12am SAST on consoles, 7am SAST on PC</li>
	<li>Riyadh, Saudi Arabia: 12am AST on consoles, 8am AST on PC</li>
	<li>Dubai, United Arab Emirates: 12am GST on consoles, 9am GST on PC</li>
	<li>Singapore, Singapore: 12am SGT on consoles, 1pm SGT on PC</li>
	<li>Seoul, South Korea: 12am KST on consoles, 2pm KST on PC</li>
	<li>Tokyo, Japan: 12am JST on consoles, 2pm JST on PC</li>
	<li>Auckland, New Zealand: 12am NZDT on consoles, 6pm NZDT on PC</li>
</ul><figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/monster-hunter-wilds-global-release-timings-full.jpg?itok=qi6asWav 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/monster-hunter-wilds-global-release-timings-full.jpg?itok=KVO4B-dt 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</em>is coming soon, don't worry.</figcaption></figure><p>If you're unfamiliar with&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>, it's the latest installment in the long-running&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter&nbsp;</em>series, and it's also probably the most-anticipated entry in the series as well, if its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta-steam-records" rel="nofollow">record-breaking first open beta</a> is anything to go by.</p>

<p>You'll be able to check out&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</em>on the dates and times outlined above on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2246340/Monster_Hunter_Wilds/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/monster-hunter-wilds/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PS5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/monster-hunter-wilds/9NMT6XFN0LVD" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>. Our own Tyler was impressed with the game; you can read <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/monster-hunter-wilds-review-new-frontier" rel="nofollow">his review here</a>.</p>
</div>


<div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div>

    </div>
  
  
  
  <div>
      <div><p><span><p>More Info About This Game</p>
<div>
<p>Learn More About Monster Hunter Wilds</p>
  
  <div>
            
                
                
                <div>
          <p>
              Release Date
          </p><p>
          February 28, 2025 (<a href="https://techraptor.net/game-calendar">Calendar</a>)
      </p></div>
                
                <div>
          <p>
              Purchase (Some links may be affiliated)
          </p>
        
      </div>
        </div>
</div></span></p></div>
<div>
  <ul>
    <p>Additional topics:</p>
          <p>
        <li><a href="https://techraptor.net/topic/announcement" hreflang="en">Announcement</a></li>
      </p>
      </ul>
</div>



    </div>
  

  </div>

</article>

  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[F.E.A.R. Added to GOG Preservation Program to "Recognize" Shuttered Dev]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/fear-gog-preservation-program-monolith</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/f-e-a-r-added-to-gog-preservation-program-to-recognize-shuttered-dev.1119537/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/fear-gog-preservation-program-monolith<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>GOG has announced that it's adding 2005 horror shooter&nbsp;<em>F.E.A.R.&nbsp;</em>to its Preservation Program ahead of schedule in order to "recognize" the contributions of shuttered developer Monolith.</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://x.com/GOGcom/status/1894753901540196781" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">post</a> on X, GOG says that while&nbsp;<em>F.E.A.R. Platinum&nbsp;</em>- which collects the base game and its expansions - was due to be added at "a later timeframe", the release has been accelerated to honor Monolith Productions.</p>

<p>For context, it was revealed yesterday that Monolith was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monolith-productions-and-more-reportedly-closed-by-wb-games" rel="nofollow">closed down by parent company Warner Bros</a>, and that the studio's upcoming&nbsp;<em>Wonder Woman&nbsp;</em>game has been canceled.&nbsp;<em>MultiVersus&nbsp;</em>developer Player First was also shut down following the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/multiversus-flop-warner-bros-100m" rel="nofollow">failure of the crossover fighter</a>, as was mobile studio Warner Bros San Diego.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/f.e.a.r.-gog-preservation-program-shooting.jpg?itok=NhAk4SMW 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/f.e.a.r.-gog-preservation-program-shooting.jpg?itok=p7q3MxAQ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>F.E.A.R. Platinum&nbsp;</em>is now a part of the GOG Preservation Program.</figcaption></figure><p>Along with&nbsp;<em>F.E.A.R.</em>, GOG says that "other Monolith icons" will join the Preservation Program, and that "even more news" will be shared regarding the Program tomorrow as well. These are exciting times for game preservation.</p>

<p>If you're wondering what the GOG Preservation Program is, it's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gog-preservation-program" rel="nofollow">an initiative</a> started by the GOG folks to ensure that certain PC games will always be supported, regardless of whether they're receiving official support from their publishers or not.</p>

<p>Many games have already been added to the program, including titles that have been delisted by their publishers, like <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gog-preservation-program-warcraft-delisting" rel="nofollow">the first two&nbsp;<em>Warcraft&nbsp;</em>games</a>. Other games that are already part of the project include classics like&nbsp;<em>Resident Evil</em>,&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dino-crisis-1-2-gog-rerelease" rel="nofollow"><em>Dino Crisis</em></a>, and&nbsp;<em>Fallout</em>, plus many more.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/gog-preservation-program-dino-crisis.jpg?itok=4wiGnRzs 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/gog-preservation-program-dino-crisis.jpg?itok=gSSQcij3 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Dino Crisis&nbsp;</em>is just one of many games already bearing the GOG Preservation Program stamp.</figcaption></figure><p>Other Monolith games that might make it to the Preservation Program include the likes of classic FPS&nbsp;<em>Blood</em>, cult shooter <i>The Operative: No One Lives Forever</i>, and, of course, the two&nbsp;<em>F.E.A.R.&nbsp;</em>sequels.&nbsp;<em>Middle-earth: Shadow of Mordor&nbsp;</em>is already part of the program, but&nbsp;<em>Shadow of War&nbsp;</em>has yet to be added.</p>

<p>Sadly, Monolith and Player First are just two of the latest casualties in what is somehow becoming an increasingly tumultuous time for the industry. Other studios to close in recent months include NetEase's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/marvel-rivals-studio-shockingly-closed-by-netease-laying-off-everyone" rel="nofollow">Seattle&nbsp;<em>Marvel Rivals&nbsp;</em>studio</a>, Dr. Disrespect's ex-studio <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/midnight-society-shutdown-dr-disrespect" rel="nofollow">Midnight Society</a>, and some of <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/xdefiant-shutting-down-ubisoft-studios-closing" rel="nofollow">Ubisoft's studios</a> as well.</p>

<p>If you want to support GOG and its efforts to preserve Monolith's games, you can check out&nbsp;<em>F.E.A.R. Platinum&nbsp;</em><a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/fear_platinum" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">right now via the storefront</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40K Roleplay: Imperium Maledictum Starter Set Review]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/warhammer-40k-roleplay-imperium-maledictum-starter-set-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40k-roleplay-imperium-maledictum-starter-set-review.1119456/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/warhammer-40k-roleplay-imperium-maledictum-starter-set-review<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><i>The others have found their way into the Inquisitor's service, but I was literally made for it. After passing trials at an early age, I was then molded into the tool that now serves the Imperium at Inquisitor Halikarn's request. The others may have misgivings, but I never do. The Inquisitor points, and I obey. But this hive city? This miracle? Even I have my doubts. But if there's corruption, either way, I will find it and snuff it out.</i></p>

<p>We've been fans of Cubicle 7's <em>Warhammer</em> roleplaying games for a while, and you can read our review of the <em>Age of Sigmar&nbsp;Soulbound</em>&nbsp;starter set&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/age-of-sigmar-soulbound-starter-set-review" rel="nofollow">here</a>, the&nbsp;<em>Warhammer Fantasy Roleplaying Game</em> starter set&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/warhammer-fantasy-roleplay-starter-set-review" rel="nofollow">here</a>, and the starter set for the other <em>Warhammer 40K</em> roleplaying system that they produce, <em>Wrath and Glory</em>,&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/warhammer-40k-roleplay-wrath-and-glory-stater-set-review" rel="nofollow">here</a>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/imperium-maledictum-starter-set-2.jpg?itok=-2lkQ2H0 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/imperium-maledictum-starter-set-2.jpg?itok=T8cp7KQO 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The&nbsp;<em>Imperium Maledictum</em> Starter Set includes 2 books for the GM and a load of great reference sheets for the players, with background as well as rules.</figcaption></figure><h2>Corruption and Miracles</h2>

<p>Similar to Cubicle 7's <em>Warhammer</em> fantasy roleplaying systems, their sci-fi <em>Warhammer 40,000</em> (or <em>40K </em>for short) roleplaying systems also have 2 options, with different mechanics and styles. The <em>Wrath and Glory</em> system that we've looked at <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/warhammer-40k-roleplay-wrath-and-glory-stater-set-review" rel="nofollow">here</a>&nbsp;uses 6-sided dice, similar to the tabletop wargaming system, and is much more combat-focused.&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>Imperium Maledictum</em> (which we are looking at here) uses a D100 system similar to that of the <em>WFRP </em>system that Cubicle 7 also produces and is much more focused on investigation and social encounters. Think of the split of systems between heroic systems using D6s (<em>Wrath and Glory</em> / <em>Soulbound</em>) and street-level using the D100 system (<em>Warhammer Fantasy Roleplay</em> and&nbsp;<em>Imperium Maledictum).</em></p>

<p>All of the previous starter sets we've covered recently have been out for a year or two, but the <em>Imperium Maledictum&nbsp;</em>starter set is brand new, released this month.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/imperium-maledictum-starter-set-5.jpg?itok=6sSfJeeg 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/imperium-maledictum-starter-set-5.jpg?itok=OPryp0cl 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>As well as thematic Inquisitorial seal for Inquisitor Halikarn, you get 2 awesome custom D10.</figcaption></figure><h2>The Tools Of The Ordo Hereticus</h2>

<p>Following the pattern of the other Cubicle 7 <em>Warhammer</em> roleplaying starter sets we've covered, <em>Imperium Maledictum</em> contains all the components for 6 players plus a Games Master to play through their first adventure and beyond. Each player gets a pre-generated character sheet, which we'll go into more detail about below, along with some quick reference sheets for all the rules they need to play.</p>

<p>The Games Master, who runs the adventure, gets 2 books, the&nbsp;Blazing Seraph, the core adventure and rules tutorial for <em>Imperium Maledictum,</em> and Rokarth: A Guide to the Hive, a sourcebook full of details background details for the hive, a giant city structure, and its inhabitants, from the ruling noble houses, merchant guilds ad the gangs that run the underhive.</p>

<p>It also contains some random encounter tables for the different levels of the hive that can be used to flesh out the introductory adventure or expand into a full campaign in Rokarth before picking up more&nbsp;<em>Imperium Maledictum </em>books.</p>

<p>The set also includes a custom set of dice, 2 10-sided dice, one with the 10s (10, 20, etc) and the other with 0 to 9 to show a number between 1 and 100 when rolled together. The dice have custom markings, and any 1s are represented by the InquisitoriaI I symbol. Out of all the custom dice in the 4 <em>Warhammer</em> starter sets, these are my favourite.</p>

<p>I say the same things in all my reviews of the Cubicle 7 <em>Warhammer</em>&nbsp;starter sets, that the Games Master needs to do some prep (which is standard for all GMs), but here if you're not a <em>Warhammer 40K</em> fan already it would be very helpful to read a little beyond the starter set books.</p>

<p>They do a great job of introducing the system and the hive, but a wider understanding of the setting would be beneficial, especially as this is aimed at the lower levels of society and is a lot more intrigue and investigation-based. Having a great understanding of that will make your games much more fun and vivid for your players.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/imperium-maledictum-starter-set-3.jpg?itok=wU0Nfb1Z 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/imperium-maledictum-starter-set-3.jpg?itok=PRcbJE3w 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The box the&nbsp;<em>Imperium Maledictum</em> Starter Set comes in turns into a GM screen with a map of the sector. Some helpful charts for the GM would have really added to the set though.</figcaption></figure><h2>Those Who Serve The Imperium</h2>

<p>The<em>&nbsp;Imperium</em><em>&nbsp;Maledictum</em> starter set includes 6 pre-generated characters, and similarly to the other starter&nbsp;sets, each character comes with a fold-out sheet full of background details to flesh out the character beyond the stats. Also, similarly, it includes a great spread of characters to introduce players to the setting.</p>

<p>Players can choose from a zealot of the Imperial creed, armed with their faith and a chainsword, a covert infiltrator, an Imperial scribe, who's knowledge and data access usually proves more useful than any of the combat effectiveness of the other characters, a sanctioned psyker, a powerful magic user allowed by the Imperium, a mechanically augmented member of the cult of the machine god, who amusingly is the best healer for the fleshier members of the team, and an Imperial soldier.</p>

<p>Unlike in the <em>Wrath and Glory</em> starter set, where some characters can be at odds with the others, here, they are all entirely dedicated to Inquisitor&nbsp;Halikarn and share the same passion for the Imperium. They're all unique characters, so they don't always get along, but they're entirely joined up about their mission and reasons for working together.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/imperium-maledictum-starter-set-4.jpg?itok=ySApL6FP 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/imperium-maledictum-starter-set-4.jpg?itok=sLrfbnXe 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The&nbsp;<em>Imperium Maledictum</em> Starter Set incudes a great spread of characters from the setting, that all have their own character folio with some great depth.</figcaption></figure><h2>Not Only War In Warhammer 40K</h2>

<p>The <em>Imperium</em><em>&nbsp;Maledictum</em> system requires players to roll 2D10 to get a number between 1 and 100, needing to score under their skill to succeed. The GM can add or subtract to the character's skill, depending on how hard the test is. Success levels (SL) can then be used to work out how well you succeed (or fail), and the 10s number rolled is subtracted from the difficulty of the test. The number left is compared to a table to show how successful you have been.</p>

<p>There is also the opportunity to gain superiority during the adventure, which can be used to further boost your SL. This is gained by learning about the enemy, the battlefield, and each other, and the mechanic plays extremely well into the investigatory nature of the system and rewards players for doing social and research encounters rather than just blasting their way into and through situations.&nbsp;</p>

<h2>Imperium Maledictum Starter Set Final Thoughts</h2>

<p>The <em>Imperium</em><em>&nbsp;Maledictum</em> starter set is a great introduction to the style and mechanics of the system, but not the setting as a whole, so if everyone is completely new to <em>Warhammer 40K</em>, some background reading is advised first. The focus on the other aspects, over bringing war to your enemies (which it still does well), is really brought out with the pre-generated characters, and the adventure takes players through that.</p>

<p>The components and design are of the quality standard I've come to expect from Cubicles 7's starter sets, and the range of characters and detail in the sheets is fantastic. I think that the only thing missing from the set is a small <em>Warhammer 40K</em> primer document for those new to the setting, but that detail can be found easily enough online. Otherwise, it's a fantastic product, with a great adventure and an awesome custom dice set.</p>

<hr><p><em>The copy of the&nbsp;</em><strong>Warhammer 40K Roleplay: Imperium Maledictum Starter Set&nbsp;</strong><em>used to produce this review was provided by Cubicle 7.</em></p>


</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Adam is a Tabletop Specialist for TechRaptor. He started writing for TechRaptor in 2017 and took over as Tabletop Editor in 2019 and has since stood down… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/adam-potts">More about Adam</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nacon Connect 2025 Announced for Next Week]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nacon-connect-2025-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nacon-connect-2025-announced-for-next-week.1119423/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nacon-connect-2025-announced<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Nacon has revealed the air date for its latest Nacon Connect presentation, which will feature information on some of the studio's previously-announced games as well as a few surprises.</p>

<p>You'll be able to check out Nacon Connect 2025 next week; it's airing on March 6th at 10am Pacific (that's around 1pm Eastern and about 6pm GMT, in case you're wondering). Nacon is remaining cagey about exactly what's going to be announced during the showcase.</p>

<p>Back <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nacon-connect-2023" rel="nofollow">in 2023</a>, Nacon gave us a look at games like&nbsp;<em>RoboCop: Rogue City</em>,&nbsp;<em>Clash: Artifacts of Chaos</em>, and&nbsp;<em>The Lord of the Rings: Gollum&nbsp;</em>(the latter of which was not yet wreathed in the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/lord-of-rings-gollum-studio-reportedly-abandons-game-development" rel="nofollow">tragedy that would subsume its developer</a> after its release).</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/robocop-rogue-city-nacon-connect.jpg?itok=G_ihziSU 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/robocop-rogue-city-nacon-connect.jpg?itok=k5X4lYoi 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>In 2023, Nacon showed off&nbsp;<em>RoboCop: Rogue City&nbsp;</em>as part of its Nacon Connect presentation.</figcaption></figure><p>The festivities <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/terminator-survivors-and-more-unveiled-at-nacon-connect" rel="nofollow">returned last year</a>, when Nacon revealed survival game&nbsp;<em>Terminator: Survivors</em>&nbsp;during Nacon Connect 2024, as well as showing off the likes of action RPG&nbsp;<em>Dragonkin: The Banished</em>,&nbsp;<em>GreedFall 2: The Dying World</em>, and racer&nbsp;<em>Test Drive Unlimited: Solar Crown</em>.</p>

<p>As for what could be coming in this year's showcase, the studio's upcoming slate still contains all four of the aforementioned games, all of which are yet to receive definitive release dates (although&nbsp;<em>GreedFall 2&nbsp;</em>is admittedly <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/greedfall-2-early-access-roadmap" rel="nofollow">out now in Early Access</a>).</p>

<p>In fact,&nbsp;<em>Terminator: Survivors&nbsp;</em>was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/terminator-survivors-early-access-release" rel="nofollow">delayed back in August last year</a>; it was originally slated for a 2024 release, but it was subsequently pushed back to 2025.</p>

<p>If I had to guess, I'd say we'll probably get a release date or a release window for&nbsp;<em>Terminator: Survivors</em>, and I'd be surprised if we didn't hear more about Rogue Factor's&nbsp;<em>Hell Is Us&nbsp;</em>and Midgar Studio's&nbsp;<em>Edge of Memories&nbsp;</em>as well.</p>




<p>Whatever's on the way - and whatever surprises Nacon has planned - will be revealed in full during the Nacon Connect 2025 presentation, which is set to air on March 6th. You'll be able to check it out via Nacon's YouTube channel.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>