<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:04:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Biped 2 Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/03/biped-2-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/biped-2-review.1342078/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="gp-content-wrapper">

	<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

		<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope="" content="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/03/biped-2-review/">
		<meta itemprop="headline" content="Biped 2 Review">			
		
		<meta itemprop="author" content="Adrian Burrows">			
		<meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2025-11-03">
		<meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2025-11-03">
		
		
			
		
								
		
			

																		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>Oh, sequels, what a tribulation you are for both gamers and developers alike. Sometimes a follow-up captures everything you loved about the original game and then manages to expand, develop and refine it. Other times a sequel seems to, with unerring accuracy, cherry pick everything that irked you about its predecessor and, for some obscure reason, seeks to do more of that. Biped 2, I’m saddened to say, is the latter kind of sequel.</p>
<p><iframe title="Biped 2 Release Date Trailer | November 5" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/N9NDROVfsLc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>A cute isometric puzzle platformer, Biped 2 tasks you and now up to three co-op partners with navigating your endearingly charming robots around an array of levels. Controls remain as fiddly as ever, though they are oddly satisfying when it finally clicks. Each thumbstick operates a leg of your bipedal bot, so movement requires a whole lot of alternate waggling to get you where you want to go. Precision control is available by standing on one leg and then spinning like a top to plant your other leg on your desired target, until you’re ready to lift your original leg and go again. To travel greater distances you can push both thumbsticks in the desired direction to activate your hover skis and propel yourself forward with rocket-fuelled abandon, though this erratic movement option will be of little help in solving the numerous physics-based puzzles ahead of you.</p>


<p>Biped 2 makes one critical mistake; it assumes you played the original game within the last month or two. Now, maybe you have, in which case you’ll be better prepared for the difficulty spikes you’ll encounter here, but when it’s been five years since you last played Biped, this sequel just feels plain nasty. An unrelentingly gruelling challenge that seems to forget that the players might actually want to have fun together.</p>


<p>It’s important to point out that my co-op partner and I have a rock-solid track record when it comes to these types of collaborative game. We’ve seen off numerous Trines, Double Fine’s finest, and a whole heap of metroidvanias, brawlers, and platformers together. So, when I say that Biped 2 broke us, it really means something. For a game that looks just as cute and adorable as the original, this has ended up as one mean SOB.</p>
<p>From the get-go, the challenges here demand a level of precise control and collaboration that was simply beyond us. With no means of altering the difficulty, you’re stuck trying each obstacle again and again until you reach the point that you relationship might shatter if you play anymore. Take an early challenge as an example, in which your bipeds need to cross a chasm; sections of chunky platforms can be briefly extended by your partner stepping on – using the obscenely fiddly control scheme, remember – three different symbols. As they do this, you need to drunkenly saunter – using the obscenely fiddly control scheme, remember – from each extending and retracting platform to the other. If your partner stands on the wrong symbol, you fall off. If you get the timing even slightly wrong, you fall off. Then if that wasn’t enough, entirely random puffs of wind from the nearby cliff-face blow you from your perch.</p>
<p>After numerous attempts, once you’ve reached the other side – mostly through dumb luck, may I add – you’d think there’d be a shortcut to bring your partner over quickly. Perhaps a catapult or cannon that you could activate? Oh no, my friend, now you must do it all again, only with <em>you</em> pressing the symbols on your side of the chasm instead. This is level three. Suffice to say it turned me into a broken mess.</p>

<p>Thing is, if the control scheme or the physics were more nuanced, this level of challenge would be appropriate, but they’re not. Controls are so clunky and silly they belong in a lightweight party game, not a precision platformer. Meanwhile, the physics regularly misbehave. So, you and your partner might make it across the giant rolling log, alternating your steps so the platform beneath your feet doesn’t disappear, only for the physics to throw you off because, well, reasons.</p>
<p>In short, Biped 2 is in conflict with itself, it wants to be a co-op party game, but it also wants to offer an intense challenge. These two things, like chalk and cheese, don’t belong together, the end result being something entirely insufferable.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div>

		
				
	<div id="gp-summary">
		<p>Summary</p><p>
		Do you enjoy playing co-op games with your partner, child, friend or assorted loved one? Then please, in the name of Zeus himself, don’t play Biped 2. The intense challenge of this sequel can ruin your relationships with those closest to you as you shout and yell at each other in a desperate, but futile, attempt to make it through the most masochistic level design I’ve ever encountered.	</p></div>
		

	<div id="gp-review-results">

									<div id="gp-good-points">
						<p>Good</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Still looks cute</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Main characters have lots of charm</li>
														
								<li><i></i>The control scheme idea has potential</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
				
									<div id="gp-bad-points">
						<p>Bad</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Far too difficult</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Feels unfair and frustrating</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
							
			</div>

					
	
						
			
			

			
						
		<div>

			<h3>Related stories from TSA			
			</h3>
			
				
				
		</div>

	
		
					
 
	
	
				
	</article>

</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/03/biped-2-review/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hotel Barcelona Review – Slaycation]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/03/hotel-barcelona-review-slaycation/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hotel-barcelona-review-%E2%80%93-slaycation.1341952/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="gp-content-wrapper">

	<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

		<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope="" content="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/03/hotel-barcelona-review-slaycation/">
		<meta itemprop="headline" content="Hotel Barcelona Review – Slaycation">			
		
		<meta itemprop="author" content="Steve C">			
		<meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2025-11-03">
		<meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2025-11-03">
		
		
			
		
								
		
			

																		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>In the realm of gaming auteurs, Swery and Suda51 are synonymous with incredible and outlandish presentation. The likes of Deadly Premonition, Killer 7, No More Heroes, and many more all share a style DNA whilst managing to retain their own identity. If you’re a fan of these creators then you’ll be well used to zany dialogue, weird moments, and a requisite amount of jank. Hotel Barcelona feels like the perfect distillation of this collaboration as it oozes style, but requires some perseverance to overcome the initial limitations.</p>
<p><iframe title="Hotel Barcelona Official Launch Trailer  PC Gaming Show | Tokyo Game Show 2025" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qEun1BEcit4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Agent Justine sets out to investigate a mysterious case, only to find herself trapped in the titular Hotel Barcelona and stuck in an unwanted possession by the infamous serial killer Dr Carnival. While they are polar opposites in their intentions and approaches, they are forced to bond over their imprisonment at the hands of an evil witch who is closely connected to both of their pasts. Their mission is made more complicated by the fact that the Hotel is now home to the spirits of the most notorious and evil serial killers in American history.</p>


<p>Hotel Barcelona plays out across two main modes but one is effectively an option select screen given a graphical overhaul as you explore the Hotel to talk to characters and unlock skills and weapons. After you talk to each merchant they are added to your phonebook, so eventually you hardly need to leave your room in between attempts. This may sound like there are a range of characters with which to interact, but in fact there are only four in total. One sells consumables, one weapons, another allows you to apply challenge penalties to access greater bonuses and the last is in charge of character upgrades. This makes the Hotel feel like a surprisingly lonely place, though there is some background flavour text.</p>


<p>There’s a fantastic grindhouse cartoon aesthetic throughout, which features splashes of colour and a cast of over the top characters. The various levels have distinctive styles that reflect the deranged personalities of the bosses too. The Hotel and the levels also feature a myriad of Easter egg references to classic slasher and horror icons from Jason Vorhees to Pennywise. Dialogue takes place through static character images that look destined to become cult classic Halloween costumes in the future with inspirations taken equally from The X Files and Rocky Horror. Music and voiceovers are in keeping with the atmosphere and work well, with Dr Carnival’s gravelly tones being a particular highlight.</p>
<p>At heart, the game is a roguelite 2D action platformer with a focus on close quarters combat and large-scale boss fights. The narrative framing of this repetition is based on the action taking place in Justine’s dreams, a framing that works well with the overall surreal nature of the game. You can choose between three different melee weapon types as you progress, with knives, axes, and whirling sawblades. Each type has numerous unlockable variations that you can buy, giving different strengths and bonus parameters. These range from simple damage buffs to others that gain benefits from specific contexts such as rain or aerial attacks. You also have access to a support ranged weapon that can be used with a cooldown, with a simple pistol being your starting point. Shotguns and flamethrowers are also available later on, so there is an element of strategy in choosing your loadout.</p>

<p>At first you only have very basic combo attacks to take on the many enemies you’ll face, but the permanent upgrade system features multiple unlockable attacks for each melee type. Some of these feel far more useful than others which speaks to a lack of balance, but that could also be due to my own playstyle. The roguelite system means that there is a lot of grinding repetition required to get to the fun stuff. This is a problem as the basic controls are not great, with Justine feeling turgid and clunky to control. Action platformers live and die through their movement and Hotel Barcelona is a far more rigid experience than most. Attacks seem locked in and it is easy to take damage with little to no way of countering it.</p>
<p>Exploration in each level requires you to jump between platforms, fight off enemies and destroy environmental objects for collectable currencies. Dollars, bones, teeth, and ears are the various forms of payment needed for upgrades and consumables which can be frustrating as these are locked to each run so leftovers are lost. With there being a random element to what you collect each time this can make grinding for upgrades a frustrating process. There is a skill that lets you keep a percentage in storage but this is also slow to upgrade.</p>

<p>Bosses are the high point of the game’s combat and are hugely challenging at first. You do have the ability to repeat fights a limited number of times, during which your previous attempts are played out in the form of Slasher Phantoms and continue to do the attacks and damage of that run. This leads to a neat layered approach in which failed runs can make the next one easier, but it’s a concept that never felt as fleshed out as I would have liked. Combined with random elements like weather effects, day and night cycles, and even player size (being giant makes for some comical encounters given the scale of the levels and enemies), there is a welcome variety to runs but the actual combat and level design quickly becomes repetitive.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div>

		
				
	<div id="gp-summary">
		<p>Summary</p><p>
		I am left conflicted with Hotel Barcelona. It absolutely oozes the kind of style you’d expect its leading creators and there is real potential in the setting and story, but the actual game just isn’t that fun to play. The clunky controls stand out against the many similar action platformers and the multiple currencies make upgrades an unwelcome grind. I can’t help but think the story would be better suited to an anime rather than its current form. It’s worth a look if you can see past the jank (and many longtime fans of Swery and Suda51 are well used to that) but its shortcomings make this a booking you might regret.	</p></div>
		

	<div id="gp-review-results">

									<div id="gp-good-points">
						<p>Good</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Dripping with style</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Interesting character designs</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Combat improves as you unlock more combo attacks</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
				
									<div id="gp-bad-points">
						<p>Bad</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Controls are clunky</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Levels become repetitive</li>
														
								<li><i></i>It’s just not as fun to play as it should be</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Initial release featured undeclared generative AI use</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
							
			</div>

					
	
						
			
			

			
					
		
					
 
	
	
				
	</article>

</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/03/hotel-barcelona-review-slaycation/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>