<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 09:09:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout 4: Anniversary Edition announced for its 10th birthday]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/24/fallout-4-anniversary-edition-announced-for-its-10th-birthday/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallout-4-anniversary-edition-announced-for-its-10th-birthday.1333750/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>For Fallout Day, Bethesda Game Studios brought some updates on the Fallout franchise and mark some of the milestones that the series has passed. In particular, to celebrate its 10th anniversary, the company announced: Fallout 4: Anniversary Edition will arrive on 10th November (and 2026 for Switch 2!), and there’s a physical 15th anniversary bundle for Fallout New Vegas on the way as well.</p>
<p><iframe title="Fallout 4: Anniversary Edition - Reveal Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tWVT9eYOPas?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Similar to <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/08/19/skyrim-anniversary-edition-ps5-free-upgrade-xbox-series-x-s-pc-ps4/">Skyrim: Anniversary Edition from 2021</a>,&nbsp;<strong><em>Fallout 4: Anniversary Edition</em></strong> bundles the game and all its official add-ons together with over 150 mods of Creation Club content, looking to create a curated ultimate collaboration between the original developers and the community.</p>
<p>Creations are coming to Fallout 4 broadly through the new in-game Creations menu, which will make it easier to discover and download more mods as well.</p>
<p>The Fallout 4: Anniversary Edition is coming to Xbox Series X|S, PS5, Xbox One, PS4, and PC this year, with a Switch 2 release set for 2026. There will also be an Anniversary Upgrade for existing platforms, and Game Pass and PS Plus subscribers will also have upgrade options.</p>

<p>Another anniversary is being celebrated for Fallout: New Vegas, which is turning 15 this year. There’s no new port of the game (sadly), but Bethesda has created a new physical Fallout: New Vegas 15th Anniversary Bundle, which is probably already out of stock on the Bethesda Gear Store.</p>
<p>The bundle includes:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Fallout: New Vegas: Ultimate Edition PC Code</strong></li>
<li><strong>Victor Statue (8″ PVC):</strong> The friendly Securitron stands tall and is ready to roll</li>
<li><strong>Doc Mitchell’s Evaluation Cards (8×8 cardstock set):</strong> Straight from your first moments in Goodsprings, a true piece of New Vegas history</li>
<li><strong>Vault Boy Enamel Pin (1.5″):</strong> Vault Boy stacks the odds with poker chips in hand</li>
<li><strong>Mojave Express Patch (3.5″ × 1.9″):</strong> Woven, iron-on, and full of wasteland charm</li>
<li><strong>NCR Recon Patch (3.25″ × 3.5″):</strong> Woven, iron-on insignia of the New California Republic’s finest</li>
<li><strong>Collector’s Big Box:</strong> A throwback-style display box created exclusively for the anniversary</li>
</ul>
<p>And then there’s Fallout 76, with more details on the Burning Springs update which will arrive on 2nd December, and introduce a new region in Ohio where you’ll battle the Rust King and desert Deathclaws.</p>
<p><iframe title="Fallout 76: Burning Springs Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JJ_SER3SwSQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>In good news for this game, native PS5 and Xbox Series X|S versions are on the way for next year.</p>
<p>And finally, Fallout Shelter is getting new updates in the form of Seasons:</p>
<p>“Inspired by Vault-Tec’s experiments, Seasons introduces limited-time Vaults to the game that are completely separate from your original Vault. Each Season will have a unique theme, bringing new challenges and rewards as players hit different milestones.”</p>
<p><em>Source: Press release, Bethesda (<a href="https://bethesda.net/en/article/N00XVTawnzBBH7HNwv0hN/fallout-4-anniversary-edition-announced">F4AE</a>, <a href="https://bethesda.net/en/article/3JJBru63nqXU4VT9hajQQK/new-content-coming-to-fallout-shelter-soon">Shelter</a>)</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/24/fallout-4-anniversary-edition-announced-for-its-10th-birthday/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roman city builder Nova Roma enters early access in January]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/23/roman-city-builder-nova-roma-enters-early-access-in-january/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/roman-city-builder-nova-roma-enters-early-access-in-january.1333498/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Lion Shield has announced that players will be able to get their hands on the Roman city builder Nova Roma, with the date being January 22nd 2026. The Nova Roma early access release will be available on both Steam and Epic Game Store. The game is not just about mimicking Rome, but striking out and building an improved version.</p>
<p><iframe title="Nova Roma - Release Date Trailer | Roman City-Builder" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/P0Is5zmKugs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>In Nova Roma, the Roman Empire is falling into decay so you have to lead a small group of citizens to build a new version of the city in new lands. To build successfully you will need to meet the needs of the citizens, and gain the favour of the gods through building temples. Nova Roma is not just a builder where you throw up some buildings a be done with it. You will need to plan where to place dams and aqueducts to get water flowing to the city, without causing floods, and set up supply routes to get raw materials to the city without spreading too quickly.</p>
<p>Advisors and senators will be there to help guide you build Nova Roma, and deal with the different issues that come up which will need balancing. You will need to make sure there is enough variety of entertainment to keep citizens happy after days of working, otherwise they may become unhappy too leading Nova Roma to ruin.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2426530/view/505090299391902387">Steam</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/23/roman-city-builder-nova-roma-enters-early-access-in-january/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>