<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 18:36:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Genshin Impact – Ineffa Build & Weapons Guide]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/30/genshin-impact-ineffa-build-weapons-guide/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/genshin-impact-%E2%80%93-ineffa-build-weapons-guide.1257369/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Genshin Impact’s latest character is Ineffa, an android who is getting slightly ahead of the 6.0 versions and showing us a glimpse of what we can expect from Nod-Krai mechanically. The final patch of each version is always a big old beach episode, so filler filled with little lore nods here and there, but Ineffa is certainly bringing the hype by literally changing one of the core reactions. To get the most out of her though, you’ll need the best Ineffa build you can put together.</p>
<p><iframe title="Character Trailer - &quot;Ineffa: Essentials for Home and Travel&quot; | Genshin Impact #GenshinImpact #Ineffa" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/s-n9weZtcN0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>

<p>Ineffa changes the electro-charged reaction into lunar-charged, which is unique (for now), in that it uses every character involved in the reaction to calculate damage, and it can also crit, which electro-charged couldn’t do. While this isn’t going to be especially well-utilised with just Ineffa, we have a feeling it’ll be more relevant when we get to Nod-Krai properly with the 6.0 patch.</p>


<p>Her elemental skill summons Birgittato to deal off-field electro damage, but also gives a skill based on Ineffa’s ATK. Her burst does a big old burst of damage, and also re-summons Birgitta. If you’ve been playing for any length of time, comparing Ineffa to Fischl is the simplest way to understand things. However, most of Ineffa’s power is in one of her passives, which allows Birgitta to do additional lunar-charged damage if the effect is already in play when Birgitta attacks. With all of this in mind, Ineffa is a sub-DPS with some shielding capabilities, and she could be a nice little boost to hydro and electro teams.</p>
<h3>Genshin Impact Ineffa Best Weapon</h3>
<p>Ineffa’s signature weapon is Fractured Halo, a polearm that boosts ATK after using the elemental skill or elemental burst, and boosts lunar-charged damage if the equipping character creates a shield during that effect. However, if you’re not using this, any of the five-star weapons can do an alright job of things, but you might be better off going with a four-star weapon if you’re not using her signature.</p>

<p>Kitain Cross Spear is an excellent option because it not only gives elemental mastery and boosts elemental skill damage, but it also gives Ineffa some more energy. Ineffa does need to be able to use her burst, so this weapon ticks all of the boxes you need it to, at least for a four-star option. You can also go for the Ballad of the Fjords, or the trusty Favonius Spear, because it’s good on everyone.</p>
<h3>Genshin Impact Ineffa Best Artifacts</h3>
<p>As of Ineffa’s release, there really isn’t a great artifact set for her. We’re expecting one to come along in the 6.0 patch, but for now, you’ve got a few options that’ll do the job. The frontrunner for us is to use a set that just fits well enough for now, which is going to often just be two two-piece sets of ATK boost, like Gladiator’s Finale.</p>
<p>You can also run her with Tenacity of the Millileth if you want more shield strength and more buffs, or with Gilded Dreams for boosting her damage. For stats, you basically want an ATK sands, an ATK goblet, and a Crit circlet, most likely Crit DMG as Ineffa ascends with Crit Rate. You can go for EM if you’re interested in messing around with a hyperbloom team too.</p>





<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/30/genshin-impact-ineffa-build-weapons-guide/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Slime Rancher 2 gloops toward v1.0 with a September release date]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/30/slime-rancher-2-gloops-toward-v1-0-with-a-september-release-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/slime-rancher-2-gloops-toward-v1-0-with-a-september-release-date.1257330/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Monomi Park has announced that the v1.0 full release of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/slime-rancher-2">Slime Rancher 2</a> is coming on 23rd September 2025, the game launching across PS5, Xbox Series X|S and PC on that date.</p>
<p>The full game will bring a big update that adds things like a new twist on Drones – something to do with Quantum – more gadgets and upgrades, new places to explore and more.</p>
<p><iframe title="Slime Rancher 2 - Release Date and Physical Pre-Order Announcement" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JHjvTdgS_p0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Beyond this, Monomi Park is partnering with iam8bit for a physical release, which will come out on 14th January 2026 for PS5 and Xbox Series X|S. Pre-ordering will net you a Slime Rancher 2 soundtrack download, a fold-out poster designed by renowned art director, Yusuke Naora, and pre-orders of the iam8bit Exclusive Edition, you can also get a sticker sheet of the wiggliest slimes and an O-Sleeve featuring Beatrix LeBeau and the rest of the Slime Rancher 2 crew. That Exclusive Edition will only be available for pre-order through 26th August.</p>
<p>The full release of Slime Rancher 2 has been a long time coming. <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/06/13/slime-rancher-2-announced-and-it-is-an-xbox-console-launch-exclusive/">Originally announced in the summer of 2021</a>, the game entered into PC and Xbox early access in 2022, with a slow drip feed of updates and content in the years since then. Heck, it’s even been a full year since the early access game came to PS5 in June 2024!</p>

<p>It’s also been a long time since I checked in with the game. We have to go back to <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2022/09/27/slime-rancher-2-early-access-review-xbox-game-pass/">my initial impressions</a>, where I said, “There’s a reason why the original Slime Rancher was so popular, and it’s clear even from the opening couple hours that Slime Rancher 2 is building on the exact same relaxed farming gameplay. The Early Access release shows a gentle evolution of the formula, giving a few morsels of what’s to come as the game grows, and we hope there’s bigger surprises down the road.”</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://slimerancher2.iam8bit.com/us/">Monomi Park</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/30/slime-rancher-2-gloops-toward-v1-0-with-a-september-release-date/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>