<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 14:44:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Nightreign release date has been set as May 30th]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/12/elden-ring-nightreign-release-date-has-been-set-as-may-30th/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-nightreign-release-date-has-been-set-as-may-30th.1106751/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/12/elden-ring-nightreign-release-date-has-been-set-as-may-30th/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Elden Ring Nightreign, the multiplayer spin off of Elden Ring, has been given a release date of May 30th, Bandai Namco has confirmed. Additionally, pre-orders are now open for the game too. This was all announced via a brand new trailer which shows more of Elden Ring Nightreign’s gameplay, which you can watch below.</p>
<p><iframe title="ELDEN RING NIGHTREIGN | Official Pre-Order Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-z3Le3HeKQs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>There are four different versions of Elden Ring Nightreign that are available for pre-order, with those being the Standard Edition, Deluxe Edition, Seekers Edition, and the Collector’s Edition.</p>
<ul>
<li>Standard Edition – The full Elden Ring Nightreign game at £34.99.</li>
<li>Deluxe Edition – This version of the game includes access to the post release DLC, digital artbook, and mini soundtrack. Those who pre-order will also get a bonus gesture. This version is priced at £47.99.</li>
<li>Seekers Edition – This version includes a steelbook with the full game, post release DLC, digital artbook, and digital soundtrack. Again, those who pre-order will get a bonus gesture too. It is also worth noting that the Seekers Edition is only available on PS5 and Xbox Series X|S.</li>
<li>Collector’s Edition – Included with this is the full game, steelbook, digital soundtrack, a 25cm statue of Wylder, eight Nightfarers cards, and a 40 page hardback artbook.</li>
</ul>
<p>We scored Elden Ring top marks,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2022/02/23/elden-ring-review/">10/10 in our review</a>&nbsp;back in February 2022. “Elden Ring is the game Souls fans have been waiting for,” said Jason. “From the open world design, to riding into battle on Torrent’s back, and the dark narrative woven through the world, this is a clear Game of the Year frontrunner that will have us all ensnared for a long time to come.”</p>
<h3><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/games/elden-ring/guides/">Elden Ring Guides from TheSixthAxis</a></h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2022/02/25/elden-ring-tips-%E2%80%A6ners-new-players/"><strong>Elden Ring Tips and Tricks for new players and beginners</strong></a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2022/02/25/how-to-level-up-in-elden-ring-vigor-stat/"><strong>How to level up in Elden Ring</strong></a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2022/02/25/elden-ring-stats-everything-you-need-to-know-to-spec-your-build/"><strong>Elden Ring Stats: Everything you need to know before you spec your build</strong></a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2022/02/25/elden-ring-spiri%E2%80%A6you-need-to-know/"><strong>Elden Ring Spirits: Everything you need to know</strong></a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2022/02/25/elden-ring-flask-of-wondrous-physick-psychic-map-location-what-does-it-do/"><strong>Elden Ring Flask of Wondrous Physick: What&nbsp;does it do and how can you get it?</strong></a></li>
</ul>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://youtu.be/Z_fmEDsQPh4?si=diqo4qIPyw26SoAQ">YouTube</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Crysis 4 development put on hold as Crytek confirm layoffs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/12/crysis-4-development-put-on-hold-as-crytek-confirm-layoffs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/crysis-4-development-put-on-hold-as-crytek-confirm-layoffs.1106718/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/12/crysis-4-development-put-on-hold-as-crytek-confirm-layoffs/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Crytek has confirmed a round of layoffs that will affect around 15% of its 400 employees – so around 60 people from the team – and stated that development of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/crysis-4">the next Crysis game</a> was put on hold last year.</p>
<p>“Like so many of our peers, we aren’t immune to the complex, unfavourable market dynamics that have hit our industry these past several years,” the company wrote on social media.</p>


<p>“It pains us greatly to share today that we must lay off an estimated 15 percent of our around 400 employees. The layoffs affect development teams and shared services. This has not been an easy decision to make, as we deeply appreciate the hard work of our talented teams.”</p>
<p>A new Crysis game was in development, but put on hold in Q3 of 2024, with Crytek prioritising the work on their extraction game revamp <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/hunt-showdown-1896">Hunt: Showdown 1896</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2022/01/26/crysis-4-crytek-china-crysis-battleground/">Crysis 4 was announced back in 2022</a> with a short teaser trailer, the company looking to revive the first person shooter series on the heels of the Crysis trilogy remasters that arrived through 2020 and 2021. However, Crytek was also enjoying some success within the burgeoning extraction shooter genre with Hunt: Showdown, an occult and monster-infused take on the genre.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/07/25/hunt-showdown-1896-will-replace-the-original-in-august-sunsetting-ps4-and-xbox-one/">Hunt: Showdown 1896 has been a big reboot and sequel to that game</a>, bringing a new generation of Cry Engine to bear on the game (shutting the original down in the process), as well as overhauling the game’s core content. It didn’t strike true for us in our <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/15/hunt-showdown-1896-review/">Hunt: Showdown 1896 review</a>, but has been a solid evolution for the company.</p>
<p>They continue, “While Hunt: Showdown 1896 is still growing, Crytek cannot continue as before and remain financially sustainable. Even after ongoing efforts to reduce costs and cut operating expenses, we have determined that layoffs are inevitable to move forward. Crytek will offer affected employees severance packages and career assistance services.”</p>
<p>Our thoughts go out to those affected by these layoffs, and hopefully they can find their feet again soon.</p>
<p><em>via <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/crytek-is-laying-of-15-of-its-400-person-workforce-and-the-next-crysis-game-is-on-ice.1106511/">Resetera</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>