<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 17:54:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hyperkin is remaking the PS5’s DualSense, but for Xbox]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/06/hyperkin-competitor-dualsense-for-xbox-compatibility/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hyperkin-is-remaking-the-ps5%E2%80%99s-dualsense-but-for-xbox.1075095/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/06/hyperkin-competitor-dualsense-for-xbox-compatibility/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Hyperkin has revealed a new Competitor wired gamepad for Xbox, and you’d be forgiven for thinking it looks rather familiar. In fact, it’s basically a PlayStation 5 <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2020/11/06/dualsense-review-feeling-the-future-of-gaming/">DualSense</a> controller remade for <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/xbox-series-x">Xbox</a>.</p>
<p>Hyperkin absolutely plays up to this, with the announcement blurb saying, “If you prefer PS5’s DualSense controller but want to play something on Xbox or PC, then this is probably going to be the controller for you.”</p>
<p><iframe title="Hyperkin's Redesigned Competitor Xbox Controller Teaser (DualSense-Style Gamepad for Xbox)" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/k6rko8BbWgw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>The Competitor comes with the striking two-tone white and black design of the DualSense controller or in an all-black version, but absent the rectangular touchpad, has a bit more of an X-Men vibe as the white panels continue in to meet a white and black Xbox button. Everything else looks very DualSense as well, from the D-pad design (which we really hope nails the feel and muted sound of the PlayStation D-pad), to the analogue stick placement, and the shoulder buttons and triggers.</p>
<p>Of course, this is a pro controller, so there are back buttons, and on the whole, the controller does look a bit chunkier than the DualSense – perhaps just from the flattened bottom below the sticks, which Sony has more moulded.</p>

<p>At this time there’s no details on pricing or availability, but if you’re a PlayStation fan suffering in the land of Xbox, this could be for you. The symmetrical analogue sticks will do a huge amount of the heavy lifting on that front, though it’s a shame that this is a wired controller and not wireless.</p>
<p>Hyperkin has made a lot of headlines over the years for their recreations of historic Xbox controllers, updating them for modern machines. That started with a recreation of the ‘<a href="https://hyperkin.com/hyperkin-duke-wired-controller-for-xbox-series-x-s-xbox-one-windows-10-xbox-20th-anniversary-limited-edition-black-officially-licensed-by-xbox.html">Duke</a>‘ controller from the original Xbox, continued on with a ‘<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2022/11/23/hyperkin-is-remaking-the-xbox-360-controller/">Xenon</a>‘ recreation of the Xbox 360 gamepad, and most recently they revived the smaller ‘<a href="https://shop.hyperkinstore.com/products/hyperkin-duchess-wired-controller-white-officially-licensed-by-xbox">Duchess</a>‘ controller that Microsoft made to cater to smaller hands.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>