<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 09:43:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Popucom Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/15/popucom-review/</link>
            <guid>1406647</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="gp-content-wrapper">

	<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

		<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope="" content="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/15/popucom-review/">
		<meta itemprop="headline" content="Popucom Review">			
		
		<meta itemprop="author" content="Adrian Burrows">			
		<meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2026-01-15">
		<meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2026-01-15">
		
		
			
		
								
		
			

																		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>The giant inflatable multi-coloured spider demon looms towards us. My co-op partner and I unleash a barrage of bubbles towards the beast, each bubble affixing to the ball-like structure of the creature, distorting it into a misshapen nightmare version of Bertie Bassett. Once three coloured bubble balls meet, in a match-3 style, they burst, leaving our opponent missing several legs and spasming on the ground. Akin to a daddy-long-legs that just fell afoul of a particularly vindictive three-year-old. With a final whimper, the boss explodes in a brightly coloured eruption. This is totally bonkers. This is P.</p>
<p><iframe title="POPUCOM Nintendo Switch Launch Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kDm9YuO8y1M?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>A third-person puzzle shooter, Popucom is intended to be played with a buddy in split-screen co-op. There’s a plot, but it amounts to little more than establishing the mission of rescuing dozens of little fried egg looking aliens. To do this, the players must navigate linear levels cram-packed with rather ingenious puzzles and colour coded bad guys made up of a load of balls.</p>
<p>With a series of bizarre inventions – including a drone flown by a kitten, force shields, teleportation devices and the ability to transform into a Nintendo-lawyer baiting Samus Aran ball – the two of you must work with something resembling synchronicity to overcome countless physics-based traps. Proceedings are tremendous fun, and all constructed around the simple premise of each player being able to switch between two colour types, and every interactable object or enemy to shoot being one of those corresponding four colours.</p>


<p>One moment, you’ll be in a purple colour configuration, walking along a purple path, holding aloft your force shield with your partner stood on top. They, in turn, are using their blue force shield to deflect blue laser beams, before switching to yellow mode to blast some yellow light-sabre wielding minion-looking dude. Suddenly, both the path and the laser beams change colour, and you and your buddy must quickly switch roles to prevent death by touching the wrong colour. It’s frenetic, furious, and often demanding, yet oh-so satisfying when you finally manage to clear a challenge that’s take several attempts.</p>
<p>The game starts off simple enough, but through the twelve hours of content, the difficulty soon rockets up, demanding swift reactions and expert off-screen communication to beat later levels. Thankfully, frustration is mostly alleviated by frequent and smartly placed checkpoints, though there will be some teeth-gnashing when a handful of particularly nasty challenges respawn you too far back, forcing you to get through a particularly tricky bit just to have another go at the trap that killed you.</p>

<p>Collision detection can be occasionally poor, with players slipping from a platform even though they just successfully made that tricky final leap. Indeed, jumping in general feels a little woolly, often failing to provide the responsiveness the game demands. Still, with numerous accessibility options to tweak, including activating temporary invulnerability and granting auto-aim, this is perfect family gaming, and something people of varying gaming abilities can enjoy.</p>
<p>Other than some notable frame rate drops when things get busy on screen, this is bright, bold, over-the-top brilliance. The sort of sunny fun that will effortlessly pass a rainy Sunday afternoon or two.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div>

		
				
	<div id="gp-summary">
		<p>Summary</p><p>
		Unlike anything you’ve ever played before, Popucom is the inventive family fun the Switch was made for. With a unique charm and smart accessibility choices that mean everyone can join in, this third-person puzzle ‘em up is going to keep our family occupied for some time to come.	</p></div>
		

	<div id="gp-review-results">

									<div id="gp-good-points">
						<p>Good</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Superb puzzles that require creative solutions</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Requires genuine communication between players</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Exploding weird blow-up spider demons makes you feel good</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
				
									<div id="gp-bad-points">
						<p>Bad</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Some frame issues when the screen gets busy</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Jumping lacks the finesse the game sometimes demands</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
							
			</div>

					
	
						
			
			

			
					
		
					
 
	
	
				
	</article>

</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/15/popucom-review/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ryan Hurst will be Kratos in the God of War series]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/14/ryan-hurst-will-be-kratos-in-the-god-of-war-series/</link>
            <guid>1406464</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Amazon have found their Kratos and he is not new to the God of War universe.&nbsp; Ryan Hurst will be playing the PlayStation icon, having previously voiced Thor in <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/god-of-war-ragnarok/">God of War Ragnarok.</a></p>
<p>The show has had two seasons ordered before the first scene has been filmed, with pre-production currently underway. The series will be skipping the Greek games and beginning in Norse mythology, but one would assume they are going to have explain why Kratos is covered in white ash and has giant chains wrapped around his forearms.</p>


<p>Ryan Hurst is best known for playing Opie Winston in Sons of Anarchy and will be seen on the big screen later this year in Christopher Nolan’s The Odyssey.</p>
<p>Amazon’s TV adaption of Sony’s God of War games landed an Emmy award-winning director for the first two episodes. Frederick E.O. Toye has signed up and should be familiar with historical violence, having directed Shogun for Disney, and also The Boys for Amazon.</p>
<p>He joins Ronald D. Moore, creator of the highly acclaimed Battlestar Galactica remake, who will be the showrunner. The series was announced in 2022 with Rafe Judkins as the showrunner, but he left the project in 2024 due to creative differences.</p>

<p><em>“’God of War’&nbsp;is a compelling, character-driven franchise that we believe will captivate our global customers as much with its expansive and immersive worlds as its rich storytelling,”</em> Vernon Sanders, head of global television at Amazon Studios, said. <em>“We are honored to share in the adventure of exploring the&nbsp;God of War&nbsp;mythology in such a momentous way with Sony Pictures Television, PlayStation Productions, and Santa Monica Studio.”</em></p>
<p id="caption-attachment-467828">Ryan Hurst</p>
<p>Sony has a Horizon Zero Dawn movie in the works and a sequel to the Uncharted movie was announced years ago, but that seems to be dead in the water, perhaps due to Tom Holland’s busy schedule.&nbsp; Sony Pictures are also producing the Metal Gear Solid movie.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://deadline.com/2026/01/ryan-hurst-cast-kratos-prime-video-god-of-war-1236683097/">Deadline</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/14/ryan-hurst-will-be-kratos-in-the-god-of-war-series/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>