<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 09:57:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Two Point Museum Fantasy Finds DLC rolls a Nat 20 on D&D themed exhibits, coming out in July]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/27/two-point-museum-fantasy-finds-dlc-rolls-a-nat-20-on-dd-themed-exhibits-coming-out-in-july/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/two-point-museum-fantasy-finds-dlc-rolls-a-nat-20-on-d-d-themed-exhibits-coming-out-in-july.1229799/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>The first DLC expansion for <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/two-point-museum">Two Point Museum</a> will launch on 17th July, bringing Fantasy Finds into the exhibit halls with magical artefacts, class-based Fantasy Experts and a whole new realm for you to send them adventuring across.</p>
<p><iframe title="Two Point Museum: Fantasy Finds | Coming 17th July" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GRgEvhYj1L0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Fantasy Finds will add 40 new exhibits to discover, from the Teanie Kettle and Novel Wardrobe through to a Flying Carpet or a Mimic chest. With such wondrous magical marvels to behold, guests can easily get wrapped up in the action and become cursed, if you don’t maintain them properly.</p>
<p>That’s where Fantasy Experts come in, with Barbarian, Wizard, Rogue and Bard classes, each of which comes with specific stats. When sending them out on expeditions, you’ll have to juggle whether they’ve got enough Strength, Dexterity, Intelligence or Luck to overcome the challenges that await them, adding a little something extra to the expeditions found in the main game.</p>
<p>Of course, it wouldn’t do to just plop down your magic carpet in the middle of a boring hall. There’s 26 new decorations and utility items, interactive displays, banners, wallpapers, and floors to get the vibes just right for the three new guest archetypes that you’ll want to entertain. You can also buff museum staff with Mythical Gear to provide bonuses for protecting exhibits and giving a little more job security.</p>

<p>In the run up to the DLC release, Two Point Museum is 20% off in the Steam Summer Sale, while the DLC will have a 10% discount across PC, Xbox and PlayStation for its first week on sale.</p>
<p>Launching earlier this year, Two Point Museum is another great spin on the humorous management sim series. <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/25/two-point-museum-review/">I said in our review</a>, “There’s great strides to allow for more customisation and creativity, a revamped structure to make revisiting levels more rewarding, and great variety in the core disciplines, but there’s also a few snags along the way and elements that could improved through updates and DLC.”</p>
<p><em>Source: press release</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/27/two-point-museum-fantasy-finds-dlc-rolls-a-nat-20-on-dd-themed-exhibits-coming-out-in-july/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>