<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 19:27:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dinosaur survival horror Deathground has launched into Early Access]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/07/dinosaur-survival-horror-deathground-has-launched-into-early-access/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dinosaur-survival-horror-deathground-has-launched-into-early-access.1319068/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Jaw Drop Games has released its co-op dinosaur survival horror Deathground into Early Access on Steam, with a 15% launch discount. Its regular price will be $14.99 / €14.79 / £11.99. The development team has also released a roadmap of what player should expect for the future of Deathground, including additional content.</p>
<p><iframe title="Deathground | Dinosaur Survival Horror Game | Official Launch Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-WcSU8wAHhU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Deathground has launched with six operatives to choose from including Scout, Medic, Observer, Engineer, Survivalist, and Hunter. There are two AI enemy types with those being the Utahraptor and Compsognathus, two training grounds and three missions across three maps. Those missions are Restart the Power Plant on the Geothermal map, Spray The Greenhouse in the Agricultural map, and Secure The Specimen in the Biomedical map. Players also have access to four tools with those being the motion detector, hacking device, tranquilizer gun, and and a med kit. Following on from today, there will be monthly mini updates which will add two story events, three sub missions, three items, and bug fixes. In the future, the Allosaurus will be added along with two more maps with associated missions, more story events, proximity chat, and two more loadout items. Even further down the line, more enemies will be added with even more story events, maps, missions, items, and collectables.</p>
<p>In Deathground, teams of up to four players have to work together to complete the missions while trying to survive the threat of dinosaurs that are hunting them. Deathground was first announced back in 2020, so it has been a long journey for the game to stomp on to Steam.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-WcSU8wAHhU">YouTube</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/07/dinosaur-survival-horror-deathground-has-launched-into-early-access/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>