<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 11:20:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PowerA OPS V3 Pro Wireless Controller Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/13/powera-ops-v3-pro-wireless-controller-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/powera-ops-v3-pro-wireless-controller-review.1187727/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/13/powera-ops-v3-pro-wireless-controller-review/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>PowerA are asking a very specific question with the OPS V3 Pro Wireless Controller – how much RGB is too much RGB? That is, admittedly, a flippant introduction to a controller that sits at the top end of PowerA’s lineup, boasting wireless and wired play for PC and cloud gaming, Hall Effect sensors, mechanical switches, six additional inputs and a magnetic charging base, but when you turn it on, you’ll find that you’re holding one of the brightest, most colourful controllers. Ever.</p>
<p><iframe title="PowerA OPS v3 Pro Wireless Controller for PC and Cloud Gaming with Lumectra" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YauMt7AqZo0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>I’m going to deal with the RGB first, as it is genuinely the overarching first impression that this controller gives. Branded with their in-house Lumectra lighting, an RGB strip runs around the perimeter of the OPS, while there’s further RGB lighting around the analogue sticks, the D-pad and each of the four main face buttons. Personally, I think it looks pretty great, though the width of the lighting around each button feels a little bit too wide. Whatever the case, this is a controller that you won’t miss, and especially not in a darkened room.</p>


<p>There is thankfully a lighting button on the back of the controller that lets you turn the effects on and off, as well as tinker with the colourways and lighting, but this is not the most intuitive implementation I’ve ever seen. Part of that is due to the multiple zones of lighting, with several different areas that you can alter, and even when you know what buttons you’re supposed to press, it’s overly fussy to remember it all. That said, you can create some spectacular effects, with each area blending into the next and giving you lots of different combinations. I opted for blue and yellow, and every time I turned it on I was left impressed by the overall look.</p>
<p>Well, I did until the OPS V3 ‘forgot’ my settings, defaulting to pure green a couple of times during my review period. You can fix it using the manual controls, but I imagine there is a point where you will give up and stop readjusting it, even if it doesn’t match your mouse and keyboard anymore.</p>


<p>Beyond the eye-catching lighting effects, the OPS V3 Pro belongs to the school of official Xbox controllers, with the overarching form being nigh-on identical to Microsoft’s timeless creation, and with its two Hall Effect sticks laid out asymmetrically. They feel great in use – taut and precise – and rather than offer the option of different height caps, you can twist each stick into a higher or lower position, giving you extra precision when you want it, and the ability to quickly make adjustments.</p>
<p>The OPS V3 Pro is constructed from solid-feeling black plastic, with texturised grips built into the bottom of each grip. They feel tactile, and grippy, but I did notice an alarming amount of dust and grime building up in them in only a short amount of time. You can clean it easily with a damp cloth, without causing any damage to the internals, but it’s a strange phenomenon that I’ve not seen happen so readily with other controllers. If dust and grime gives you the ick, maybe steer clear.</p>
<p>The stars of the OPS V3 are the mechanical face buttons, shoulder buttons and D-pad. They feel and sound stunning to use, giving you such an immediate response that you can’t help but be delighted with them. I’ve been playing a heap of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/08/revenge-of-the-savage-planet-review/">Revenge of the Savage Planet</a> with this gamepad, and all of the platforming and alien combat felt spectacularly tuned in. Returning to Overwatch 2 also showed that the OPS V3 has some competitive chops, and I never once felt that a death was the result of my equipment, rather that it was helping me to get the drop on unsuspecting foes.</p>
<p>That’s helped by the OPS V3’s copious amount of additional inputs. Besides the expected, Xbox-esque main controls, there are six programmable buttons to aid you in whatever fight you’re involved in. Four of them sit in the expected places beneath your fingers as you grip the controller, and they’re of a good size and substantial activation to balance ease of use while avoiding accidental presses.</p>

<p>They’re joined by the unusual placement of two further buttons on the top of the controller, alongside the triggers and beneath the extended reach of the shoulder buttons. Once you’re used to them being there, I actually found these to be the most intuitive and easiest of the extra inputs to use, and thanks to the Program button on the rear of the controller you can change them – and any of the other additional buttons – up at a moment’s notice.</p>
<p>My one disappointment with all of these is that they lack the same mechanical switches found in the main buttons. It makes them feel like a downgrade, though I expect that fewer people use these extra buttons compared to the central inputs, and it’s part of PowerA’s attempts to keep the controller’s price down.</p>
<p>The final, and perhaps key, inclusion is trigger lockouts. In my opinion, all controllers need these, and PowerA have opted for a stepped setup that lets you choose from three different trigger input lengths. Once again, they don’t have mechanical activations at the end as we’ve seen with the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/28/gamesir-cyclone-2-controller-review/">Gamesir Cyclone</a>, but they’re certainly swift enough, aided no doubt by the magnetic Hall Effect sensors running the show.</p>
<p>The OPS V3 has three different connection modes, with the wired or RF receiver options for PC and Bluetooth for mobile platforms. It’s a real shame that the OPS V3 isn’t certified for Nintendo Switch as well, limiting it compared to some of its key rivals, and also because it’s a well-made, enjoyable controller to use.</p>

<p>The OPS V3 also includes a charging station with a USB-A socket for the RF dongle to sit in. I love this sort of functionality, and anything that makes it easy to keep your peripherals charged is a clear win. However, it’s so small and light, that it just comes away with the controller, and you have to yank it off each time. It’s hardly a problem, but compared to the Gamesir Super Nova or Cyclone, it’s a far more workmanlike solution rather than something to display your fancy new controller.</p>
<p>At £99.99, the OPS V3 straddles the line between affordability and becoming a true premium option, and with its wealth of extra inputs and cool lighting it’ll be a great choice for many players. That said, its feature set puts it in direct competition with Gamesir’s Super Nova and Cyclone, both of which offer more value for money, a better stand, and are overall more comfortable to use.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Remedy is holding an FBC: Firebreak technical test this weekend – sign ups now open]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/13/remedy-is-holding-an-fbc-firebreak-technical-test-this-weekend-sign-ups-now-open/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/remedy-is-holding-an-fbc-firebreak-technical-test-this-weekend-%E2%80%93-sign-ups-now-open.1187703/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/13/remedy-is-holding-an-fbc-firebreak-technical-test-this-weekend-sign-ups-now-open/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Remedy Entertainment has announced an <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/fbc-firebreak">FBC: Firebreak</a> Closed Technical Test for this coming weekend, bringing the public in to stress test and play the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/control">Control</a> co-op shooter spin-off.</p>
<p>Available across PS5, Xbox Series X|S and PC with cross-play enabled, the FBC: Firebreak Closed Technical Test will run from May 15th, 6AM PDT/9AM EDT/2PM BST/4PM EEST, until May 19th, 1:59PM PDT/4:59PM EDT/9:59PM BST/11:59PM EEST.</p>


<p>You can <a href="https://firebreak.firstlook.gg/signup/tech-test-may-2025">sign up to take part here</a>.</p>
<p>However, it should be noted that this is a closed test and Remedy are not allowing public sharing of impressions, screenshots, videos or live streaming. Discussions will be limited to an area of the official Discord server.</p>
<p>The technical test will help Remedy smooth out kinks in the matchmaking and balance for <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/24/fbc-firebreak-release-date-confirmed-for-june/">the game’s full launch next month</a>. Aiming to get as large an intake of invited participants as possible, the tech test will have two of the Jobs in the game,&nbsp;Paper Chase and Ground Control, and access to three of the kits with all equipment unlocked – Garden Gnome, Teapot, and Piggybank – and three of the guns.</p>

<p>For PC players, the system requirements that Remedy are pushing at this time are:</p>
<ul>
<li>OS: Windows 10 64-bit</li>
<li>Processor: Ryzen 7 3700X or equivalent</li>
<li>Memory: 16GB RAM</li>
<li>Graphics: GeForce RTX 2080 Ti</li>
</ul>
<p>For more details, Remedy has shared <a href="https://firebreak.firstlook.gg/static/faq">a closed technical test FAQ</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/fbc-firebreak">FBC: Firebreak</a> is launching on 17th June, dropping onto PS5, Xbox Series X|S and PC via Steam and Epic at that time. It will also be available day one via PC Game Pass, Game Pass Ultimate, and the PlayStation Plus Game Catalog (Extra and Premium).</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/app/2272540/eventcomments/597400564876236928?snr=1_5_9_">Steam</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Sinking City Remastered is available right now!]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/13/the-sinking-city-remastered-is-available-right-now/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-sinking-city-remastered-is-available-right-now.1187667/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/13/the-sinking-city-remastered-is-available-right-now/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>The Sinking City Remastered has been given a surprise launch by Frogwares, who have made the game available today for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series XS. <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/31/the-sinking-city-remastered-announced/">The Sinking City Remastered&nbsp;</a>was announced at the end of March, along with confirmation that owners of the original release for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S would get this upgrade for free.</p>
<p><iframe title="The Sinking City Remastered - Comparison &amp; Launch Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NEoQxVMzBEg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p><em>”We plan to do big things with The Sinking City IP, starting with the sequel and then beyond. So, after our rather well-known struggles with the original, it feels amazing to have this positive moment be part of the game’s twisted history and for us to be the ones to fully decide it. Making it free to all our existing fans is our way of giving back to them for having supported us all this time through thick and thin.</em>”, said Sergiy Oganesyan, Publishing Director at Frogwares.</p>
<p>The Sinking City Remastered sees the original game remade in Unreal Engine 5, adding enhanced details to environments and objects. The game has 4K textures and an added photo mode so you can zoom in and check the details for yourself. There is also support f<span>or DLSS, FSR and TSR upscaling, as well as new accessibility options.</span></p>
<h2><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2019/06/27/the-sinking-city-review/">The Sinking City Review</a></h2>
<p>In our The Sinking City review, Steve said,<em>&nbsp;“The Sinking City promises a nightmarish journey through a Lovecraftian townscape filled with monsters and threatening cults, but too often falls into a loop of forced combat and resource hunting. The investigative parts are excellent, and this is probably the best Lovecrat adaptation since Call of Cthulu: Dark Corners of the Earth, but it still never really lives up to its potential. Close, but no Shoggoth.”</em></p>

<p><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/03/06/the-sinking-city-2-has-gone-full-on-horror-coming-out-in-2025/">The Sinking City 2</a> was announced last year with a release window of 2025, with some funding coming from a Kickstarter. The final amount raised in the Kickstarter was 553,100 euros, way above the target of 100,000 euros.</p>
<p><em>Source: Press Release</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>