<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 19:05:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Quarantine Zone: The Last Check release has been delayed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/12/quarantine-zone-the-last-check-release-has-been-delayed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/quarantine-zone-the-last-check-release-has-been-delayed.1351624/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Quarantine Zone may not be released in November, according to an update from developer Brigada Games, but the studio is still aiming for a 2025 release. The change to the release date has come due to feedback from players who are testing Quarantine Zone in a closed playtest, and that feedback has led to the team needing to make changes before release.</p>
<p><iframe title="Quarantine Zone: The Last Check | Demo Gameplay Trailer | Demo releases on May 22nd, 2025" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kH06uTaVMTk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>In a statement, Brigada Games wrote, <em>“Hello, everyone! Some of you have seen that info on our Steam page was first changed from November to simply 2025. Currently we are running a closed playtest and while it is ongoing – us (the developer team) and the publisher will determine the exact release date but as of yesterday we’re still working toward a 2025 release. We might require some extra time to polish the game, thanks to the copius amount of feedback we are receiving and processing at the moment. The decision on the exact release date and price will be made soon, and we will update everyone the moment it is made. We apologize for the uncertainty but rest assured we’re furiously working on the game, taking in feedback, and working to figure out the best release date to get you all into Quarantine Zone!”</em></p>
<p>Quarantine Zone: The Last Check is set in a world that is facing a zombie outbreak, and you are a checkpoint guard. Your job is to stop anyone infected with the zombie virus, as well as anyone carrying contraband, from passing your checkpoint to a safe zone. Fail and it could lead to catastrophe. As a guard, players are equipped with scanners to detect the virus, but other resources are limited so decisions will need to be made to keep the camp safe.</p>
<p><em>Source:<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/3419520/view/622187063917150288"> Steam</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/12/quarantine-zone-the-last-check-release-has-been-delayed/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>