<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 19:47:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cronos: The New Dawn gameplay trailer released by Bloober Team]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/16/cronos-the-new-dawn-gameplay-trailer-released-by-bloober-team/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cronos-the-new-dawn-gameplay-trailer-released-by-bloober-team.1166061/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/16/cronos-the-new-dawn-gameplay-trailer-released-by-bloober-team/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Bloober Team has released the first gameplay trailer for its upcoming survival horror Cronos: The New Dawn, naming this trailer ‘Don’t Let The Merge.’ You can see why from the trailer as enemies can absorb other enemies to become bigger threats, with more powerful attacks and increased speed. The trailer also shows how you will navigate different locations, including some areas where gravity doesn’t have much of a pull.</p>
<p><iframe title="Cronos: The New Dawn | Official Gameplay Trailer |  DON'T LET THEM MERGE" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZblwGH-C7eg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/17/bloober-team-reveal-cronos-the-new-dawn/">Announced last October</a>, the behind the scenes video explores Cronos: The New Dawn’s setting, a post-apocalyptic rendition of 1980s Poland. This is the home to a survival horror adventure with some hefty helpings of sci-fi and time travel. You’ll play as a time-hopping Traveller, going back through time rifts to try and extract people who didn’t survive the apocalypse. Some of the most notable inspirations include the Dead Space franchise and the movie Twelve Monkeys. The Traveller’s own suit takes its inspiration from older deep sea diving suits, alluding to the theme of diving through time to save people.</p>
<p>Cronos: The New Dawn is set to launch in 2025 on PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X|S.</p>
<p><em>Source: Press Release</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>