<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 18:38:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Test Drive Unlimited Solar Crown players to get free Porsche and stickers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/11/04/test-drive-unlimited-solar-crown-porsche-stcikers-dlc-free/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/test-drive-unlimited-solar-crown-players-to-get-free-porsche-and-stickers.1027194/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/11/04/test-drive-unlimited-solar-crown-porsche-stcikers-dlc-free/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Nacon and studio KT Racing have announced&nbsp; free in-game items for those who purchased and played Test Drive Unlimited Solar Crown before the first major patch which was released on &nbsp;September 30th 2024.&nbsp; The goodies are compensation as the game suffered server issues when it launched with a reported 55% of players failing to log in to the game.</p>
<p>“NACON and studio KT Racing have decided to offer them two unique items: an exclusive special edition of the&nbsp;1986 Porsche 911 Carrera Coupe custom-built as an&nbsp;“Adventurer” edition, fully equipped for the island’s off-road roads, as well as a pack of 5 exclusive stickers for customizing their cars,” said Nacon in a press release.&nbsp; “This compensation will be offered to all players who played Test Drive Unlimited Solar Crown before the arrival of the first major patch, which was released on September 30. These items will be automatically added to players’ inventories in December, for the opening of Season 2.”</p>


<p>Tomorrow, Tuesday, November 5th, the second patch will be released. “This update primarily focuses on graphical enhancements for PS5,” comment Nacon. “The patch also optimizes game performance on PC and Xbox Series. Additionally, it includes network upgrades, improved peripheral compatibility, and numerous bug fixes.”</p>
<p>“We understand your frustration, given the difficulties that have been encountered during the launch of TDUSC. We are sorry for this situation and we want to acknowledge your concerns. We genuinely appreciate your patience and commitment to Test Drive Unlimited Solar Crown.”</p>

<p>In our <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/09/13/test-drive-unlimited-solar-crown-review/">Test Drive Unlimited Solar Crown review</a>,&nbsp; Stefan said, “After years and years of waiting, Test Drive Unlimited is back. Kind of. Solar Crown is an open world racer for gamers who don’t need constant gratification, but can be patient and work toward a key unlock and crowning car. It’s just a shame that the game at launch will require patience while KT Racing fix, improve and hopefully expand it to meet more of its potential.”</p>
<p><iframe title="Test Drive Unlimited Solar Crown | Launch Dev Diary &amp; Next Steps" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/k2I14V-HqOA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><em>Source: Press Release / <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1249970/view/4505380324428942357">Steam</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Empire of the Ants Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/11/04/empire-of-the-ants-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/empire-of-the-ants-review.1027095/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/11/04/empire-of-the-ants-review/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>The beauty of nature never ceases to enthral us, and while many of its mysteries have been revealed by pesky scientists figuring out how stuff works, that hasn’t diminished its beauty or wonder. Empire of the Ants – based on the Bernard Werber novel of the same name – is the first game to fully capture that beauty and wonder on modern systems, bringing the insectoid kingdom to life in a way that simply wasn’t possible before.</p>
<p><iframe title="Empire of the Ants - Launch Trailer | PS5 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xJDlwPZqv28?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>It will give you some insight into our household that the first few hours of Empire of the Ants were accompanied by hooting, hollering, whistling and gasping. Our now-teenage son has always been fascinated by ants and other bugs and creepy crawlies, and it’s an interest that’s spread throughout the house (at times quite literally when ants have escaped from his ant farm).</p>


<p>Empire of the Ants first and greatest trick is its visuals. Utilising Unreal Engine 5, it is nearly photorealistic, and the natural landscape of woods and gardens play home to some of the most stunning ant and insect-based animations you will have ever seen. Everything is alive, everything is moving, and as the colony sets about individual tasks you can wander about as Ant 103,683rd, marvelling at just what Tower Five have created.</p>
<p>The visual magic is enhanced by the audio, in particular the orchestral soundtrack, which lends itself perfectly to magnifying the sense of wonder and drama. It’s particularly high-quality, making Empire of the Ants feel as much like an animated film or an Attenborough documentary as it does a video game.</p>


<p>You play sister Ant 103,683rd – I didn’t know that all ants are female prior to playing, and that was only the first of many things I learned along the way – and you’re the ant that everyone seems to turn to in times of need. Bel-o-kan, your home colony, is consistently under attack by outside forces, or in need of expanding and protecting its territory, and you are a very singular ant amongst many.</p>
<p>There are different mission types for you to tackle in Empire of the Ants, with platforming and RTS sections the two main options. The RTS sections see you take command of a small legion of ants. At first, you have access to a couple of units, growing as you progress, and they’re made up of Workers, Gunners and Warriors, alongside different support units, before you start to unlock more powerful variants. There’s a nice combat triangle at work here, with different units strong against different enemy types, and if you want to maximise your efficiency you need to choose the right group for the job, while also thinking about positioning them in the most useful place.</p>
<p>That’s not to say you can’t launch every unit you have at a single one to overpower it, but eventually, you’ll see a clear downside to doing so. Rather than forcing you through a bunch of menus, all of the resource and upgrade tree is centred on your nests, with the UI appearing on the ground within them. You have to directly interact with them, which later on becomes a bit tiresome, but does make you feel an integral part of this ecosystem, and that these are real locations that you can directly affect.</p>

<p>The platforming sections are tricky, particularly if you’re attempting to catch something along the way, but they become easier if you think and behave more like an ant, feeling out your way across leaves and up stems rather than trying to rush across without any thought. They’re very rewarding when you get them right, and I never tired of leaping from rock to rock on my way to the destination, not least because of 103,683rd’s bum wiggling each time you do.</p>
<p>There a few foibles to Empire of the Ants that start to nag the longer you spend with the game. One of them is the visual presentation of the menus and UI, which just feel a little lifeless and low-rent compared to the stunning visuals in-game. The other is controlling your ant who, as an ant, is capable of sticking to whatever surface they’re walking on. This is great for traversing logs, branches, leaves and trees, but you can often find yourself upside down and turned around, and not quite sure which way is forward or back. You do get better at it, but it never completely goes away. Fortunately, neither of these things is a dealbreaker.</p>
<p>Empire of the Ants is largely a very tranquil game, punctuated by the more action-packed RTS sections. It’s often just you and nature, with the gentle music being replaced by the sounds of crickets and distant birdsong. I don’t think it’ll be for everyone, but I really enjoyed each section’s alternating atmosphere. That said, it doesn’t hold your hand, so you’re often left to explore and figure things out for yourself, which is actually refereshing.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>