<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 16:53:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oblivion Remastered is perfect for fans on the long wait for The Elder Scrolls VI]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/25/oblivion-remastered-is-perfect-for-fans-on-the-long-wait-for-the-elder-scrolls-vi/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/oblivion-remastered-is-perfect-for-fans-on-the-long-wait-for-the-elder-scrolls-vi.1173879/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/25/oblivion-remastered-is-perfect-for-fans-on-the-long-wait-for-the-elder-scrolls-vi/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>“Stop right there, criminal scum!” Before it was a meme – in a time before memes – this famous quote yelled by <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/oblivion">Oblivion’s</a> patrolling lawmen once filled me with dread. Probably because my Argonian rogue could often be found skulking Cyrodiil’s cities by night, my inventory chock full of stolen goods I’d later fence to a dodgy bloke in Bruma.</p>
<p><iframe title="The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered - Official Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wFJ3PZuAjK4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Now, almost 20 years later those same words conjure a grin of familiarity, being just as comically melodramatic as I remembered. There’s no denying the colossal influence The Elder Scrolls IV had on the action roleplaying genre these past two decades yet, at its core, it’s a beautifully weird fantasy pantomime.</p>


<p>With its successor, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/skyrim">Skryim</a>, being playable on almost every household device, when people hear “The Elder Scrolls” they often think of battling dragons on snow swept battlefields, but there’s so much more to Bethesda’s long-running series. Returning to those older games, though, can trigger headaches, technically and gameplay-wise, despite their rich stories, settings, and characters boasting a timeless allure.</p>


<p>Developed by Virtuos in collaboration with Bethesda, what Oblivion Remastered offers is a more accessible way of playing The Elder Scrolls IV. Not only does it bring the game to modern systems, it features a slew of smart improvements that round off some of those rough mid 2000s edges. Thankfully, this isn’t just a top-to-bottom Skyrimification; sure, certain elements have been retrofitted, but they do little to diminish Oblivion’s unique identity. For example, character progression differs from Bethesda’s newer RPGs, giving players attribute points to tailor their playstyle, the level-up screen only activating once you’ve found somewhere in-game to sleep.</p>
<p>It’s clear to see that Virtuos has been careful not to alter core aspects of the Oblivion experience while trying their hardest to reduce friction and busywork. Inventory management has been streamlined with quickslots allowing players to seamlessly access weapons, spells, and other items without digging into menus. Oblivion Remastered even has a sprint button which purists may balk at, but it sure comes in handy when backtracking through dungeons or getting from A to B in Cyrodiil’s vast open world.</p>

<p>As for presentation, Oblivion has received a full makeover using Unreal Engine 5 and the results are mostly magnificent. Character models are bursting with life thanks to improved facial animations, lighting, lip sync, and textures, with Cyrodiil’s myriad landmarks and vistas given the same treatment.</p>
<p>For better or worse, one area of the game that hasn’t changed much is the core combat. Quality of life improvements have made Oblivion more tolerable for mages and rogues, though melee duels often result in mindless button-bashing, waiting to see whose health bar depletes fastest. In an age where almost every video game has a parry action, Oblivion’s combat feels stiff with little scope to pull off skill-based feats. Then again, if this was something Virtuos had changed, it may have been a bridge too far, fundamentally altering that core moment-to-moment gameplay.</p>

<p>This kind of restraint creates a game that floats between being a remaster and a remake, though the end result is still the same. Oblivion Remastered is the perfect nostalgia hit for fans of The Elder Scrolls eagerly awaiting the series’ eventual sixth instalment. It’s a revival that respects those gamers who loved the original, while sprucing it up enough to entice a new generation of players.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DOOM: The Dark Ages Cosmic Realm has been revealed in new footage]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/25/doom-the-dark-ages-cosmic-realm-has-been-revealed-in-new-footage/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/doom-the-dark-ages-cosmic-realm-has-been-revealed-in-new-footage.1173831/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/25/doom-the-dark-ages-cosmic-realm-has-been-revealed-in-new-footage/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>A brand new trailer has been released for DOOM: The Dark Ages, and it introduces a brand new area called the Cosmic Realm. It represents a new type of location for the DOOM franchise, one the developers have wanted to explore for a while. At its core, the Cosmic Realm is a Lovecraftian dimension and in the DOOM universe it has formed an alliance with Hell.</p>
<p><iframe title="DOOM: The Dark Ages - Cosmic Realm First Reveal Trailer | PS5 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DVBI55DbNQI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>The Cosmic Realm is more than just a new location for players to rip and tear through, as it is home to a host of new enemies. One of those new enemies is the Cosmic Baron who is a twin bladed brute that attacks quickly to put players under pressure. You won’t be safe if you get some distance from the Cosmic Baron either as he has psionic attacks which are able to block your attacks too. The Cacodemon is another enemy which floats and is able to immobilise you with shield attacks from range which can be followed up be tentacle attacks when it gets close.</p>
<p>Of course, it isn’t all gloom in the Cosmic Realm because within it is a brand new weapon. That weapon is the Reaver Chainshot. The Reaver Chainshot fires a ballistic mace. You can use it as a quick attack to take on a single enemy, or charge it up to unleash the Chaos Sphere. According to the development team, the Reaver Chainshot is unlike any other weapon found in the DOOM games.</p>

<p>The&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/doom-the-dark-ages">Doom: The Dark Ages</a>&nbsp;release date has been confirmed for 15th May, coming to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/playstation-5">PS5</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/xbox-series-x">Xbox Series X|S</a>&nbsp;and PC, and on day one with applicable tiers of&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/xbox-game-pass">Xbox Game Pass</a>.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/04/25/revealing-cosmic-realm-gameplay-from-doom-the-dark-ages-out-may-15/">PS Blog</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>