<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 13:04:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hell Clock Review – Playing Through Trauma]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/11/hell-clock-review-playing-through-trauma/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hell-clock-review-%E2%80%93-playing-through-trauma.1294605/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="gp-content-wrapper">

	<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

		<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope="" content="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/11/hell-clock-review-playing-through-trauma/">
		<meta itemprop="headline" content="Hell Clock Review – Playing Through Trauma">			
		
		<meta itemprop="author" content="Steve C">			
		<meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2025-09-11">
		<meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2025-09-11">
		
		
			
		
								
		
			

																		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>Sometimes you can tell how a game will play at a first glance, with the huge explosion of Hades clones generally easy to recognise. I went into my first experience with Hell Clock fully expecting a take on Supergiant’s classic but what I found was actually something far more original and interesting, albeit not without some issues and flaws. While it shares the general rogue-like approach of Zagreus’ adventures, the actual gameplay is far more in keeping with classic Diablo, and scratched a nostalgic itch I didn’t realise I had.</p>
<p><iframe title="Hell Clock | Launch Trailer | Play Now!" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0EXoQ_s6ppw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Perhaps the most important aspect of the game is its real historical backdrop, taking place 8 years after Brazil’s War of Canudos, a tragic event in which tens of thousands of refugees were slaughtered by the new Brazilian Republic in the 19<sup>th</sup> century. This is a historical event about which I was totally unaware before coming across this game and it shows how well games can educate alongside entertain. This is exactly the kind of experience that my erstwhile colleagues are looking at in the forthcoming <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/03/playing-with-history-now-live-on-kickstarter/">‘Playing With History’ book</a> and I’ll be recommending they take a gander at Hell Clock.</p>


<p>This real world context doesn’t mean that the game is hyper realistic, however. Indeed, such is the depth of historical trauma surrounding the War of Canudos that the game’s dark fantasy aesthetic feels like a metaphorical attempt to come to terms with those memories. This is most obviously seen through the monstrous bosses that represent major figures in the invading army. These are truly grotesque and prove extremely challenging until you’ve refined your build.</p>


<p>While the general tone of Hellclock is dark the graphics benefit from an excellent balance of light and shade. A cel-shaded comic book effect helps enemies and backgrounds to stand out and there is a decent range of environments across the various stages – although the layouts themselves tend to repeat relatively quickly. Depending on your choice of skills and powers there can be a vast amount of visual effects on display soon and this can be both a blessing and a curse. Fully powered up attacks look incredible but can bring the framerate crashing down – particularly in the last main area of the game.</p>
<p>Performance as a whole here was decent until that last area (one that I won’t spoil here) where the solid 75fps gradually dropped until it fell off a cliff. The one time I beat the final boss was a battle of attrition with 5fps and took fully 35-40 minutes whilst watching a YouTube video. This is not what the game is intended to play as though and says a lot about my general stubbornness and desire to see the ending for this review.</p>

<p>In fact, the main loop of Hellclock is all about speed and min-maxing your builds. The standard mechanics include the titular Hellclock which constantly counts down towards your death – only pausing during boss battles. At first you have a measly 7 minutes but there are upgrades to unlock that increase this and bosses also drop extra time pick-ups when defeated. This mechanic ensures that every run is a test of your dps rather than skill which clearly appeals to the Path of Exile and Diablo players but is a far cry from the Hades style I was expecting.</p>
<p>There is an option to disable the clock and play the game in a more strategic way but after completing the game this way I would advise against it. While this mode does prevent the constant time pressure it ends up becoming a war of extreme attrition and the resultant drawn-out kiting of damage-sponge enemies can quickly sap your enjoyment. I would go so far as to suggest that the devs should probably remove this option and stick to their preferred approach.</p>

<p>Playing as a resurrected victim of the massacre, you’re armed with a revolver that serves as your primary weapon. I was a little disappointed that there are no alternatives here (rifles, shotguns, or sabres could have mixed things up build-wise) but you can level it up and apply buffs through equipped relics to increase your damage. Basic shots are free but all other attacks require mana to activate so there is a balance to be drawn between attacking and allowing your mana to recharge. The real build strategy comes in choosing from a wide range of spells to add to your arsenal.</p>
<p>These skills range from support effects such as dash and shield to more offensive abilities such as rapid fire and high damage explosives and all are well designed to fit in with the general aesthetic. Each set of skills is unlocked as you progress through the game’s acts but some of the early skills remain useful right up to the end. I found a combination of magical crosses that surrounded my character and life steal from equipped relics was overpowered as it meant I survived far longer than my damage output should have allowed but I think this has been balanced in part through patches (and of course would not have helped with the Hellclock in play).</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div>

		
				
	<div id="gp-summary">
		<p>Summary</p><p>
		Hellclock is a solid game that offers something new to both the roguelike and Diablo genres but may not have the wider appeal of titles such as Hades due to its focus on min-maxing and DPS over skill. The confused approach of offering game modes that actively undermine the title’s central gameplay mechanic, and the current performance issues in the latter stages, are real negatives but the first can be avoided and the second is being worked on. If the idea of a roguelike Path of Exile appeals, then Hellclock may well be the game for you.	</p></div>
		

	<div id="gp-review-results">

									<div id="gp-good-points">
						<p>Good</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Important historical context</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Good range of skills and builds</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Challenging metagame to min-max</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
				
									<div id="gp-bad-points">
						<p>Bad</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Disabling the clock leads to attritional gameplay</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Lack of weapon choices</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Performance in the last Act still needs addressing</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
							
			</div>

					
	
						
			
			

			
					
		
					
 
	
	
				
	</article>

</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/11/hell-clock-review-playing-through-trauma/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grit & Valor 1949 Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/11/grit-valor-1949-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grit-valor-1949-review.1294449/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>Grit &amp; Valor 1949 is set, fairly obviously in 1949, but it’s not the 1949 that our grandparents experienced. This is an alternate history, and one where WW2 still rages on. It’s also an alternate history drawing on Steampunk ideas and aesthetics, where battlefields clamour with the sounds of mechs and unlikely weaponry. Grit &amp; Valor takes this setting and turns it into a real-time tactical roguelite, fusing ideas from games like <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/04/19/advance-wars-1-2-reboot-review/">Advance Wars</a> and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2018/08/31/into-the-breach-review/">Into The Breach</a> with small scale RTS games like Bad North into a new, mostly cohesive, whole.</p>
<p><iframe title="Grit and Valor - 1949 | Official Console Launch Trailer: XBOX X|S and PS5" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sv2Cs_oZhl4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>You’re part of the Resistance, fighting back against the evil Axis from a small island outpost off the coast of Scotland. Your task is to liberate each region from its Axis occupiers, forcing them from the British Isles, back into France and Western Europe, before finally facing the enemy’s seat of power in New Germany. Each area has multiple stages, and multiple pathways through which, as this is a roguelite, you’ll be hoping to pick up the best enhancements along the way.</p>


<p>The tutorial is suspiciously straightforward, and extremely quick before sending you over the top into live combat. While you move around each battlefield by stomping through a fixed grid, you don’t select individual targets for regular attacks; instead, you rely on your mechs targeting the nearest villain in their sights.</p>
<p>Just like Fire Emblem, there’s a weapon triangle at work here to distinguish who will have the upper hand, so Ballistic Class is strong against Fire, Fire is strong against Explosives, and Explosives beat out Ballistics.</p>


<p>Each Mech has a different class then, but also its own pilot, with each driver having their own special ability to help you out in the field. Archie Miller, the chap in control during the tutorial, has a Jump Jet ability that lets you leap across the battlefield and cause damage to enemies in a wide area, while Emilia Rochefort can heal her Mech. The third starting pilot, Jan Nowak, can lay traps, leaving mines in the path of advancing enemy vehicles. You need to know when to deploy these skills, not least because they have a limited number of uses, and they’ll often mean the difference between success and failure.</p>
<p>During each battle, there are crate drops containing enhancements for your mechs. Each crate gives you three options to choose from, with different levels of rarity denoting the most powerful or unique abilities. You might also pick up repair packs here, letting you regain some health for one of your team, while you steadily try to create an arsenal that will see you through to the very end.</p>
<p>That’s unlikely to happen in one run. As you fight you’re also earning currency to spend on permanent upgrades, and it’s these that will fundamentally raise your chances of success.</p>

<p>There’s a lot going on in Grit &amp; Valor’s diorama-like levels. You have to juggle grabbing objectives, taking cover, protecting your Command unit, and taking out the Axis forces, all the while making sure you’ve got the best matchups going on through the weapon triangle. As it takes place in real time, it can be a little chaotic, and while the pad controls do a good job, I can’t help but feel that a mouse makes these things easier. Now, if they happen to drop a Switch 2 patch with mouse support, that might be the perfect answer.</p>
<p>It’s all a lot of fun though. While the game on Switch isn’t as detailed or high resolution as on other platforms, I still appreciate the Steampunk comic-like visuals. The action is easy to parse, but challenging, and there’s a clear sense of progression, as every run grants you new Mechs, new parts or the ability to upgrade something that will make your life easier next time out. It’s fast-paced and it doesn’t waste your time, and as a Switch game, it’s an ideal title to pick up and play, get a run in, or a couple of stages within one, and then head off to do something else.</p>

<p>There were a couple of times where the game crashed while playing, with it soft-locking in the menus and preventing me from advancing. However, a quick reset let me progress, and it didn’t get in the way of things too much – it’s possible that it might have been an oddity compatibility support when playing on Switch 2.</p>
<p>By its very nature, Grit &amp; Valor becomes quite repetitive. It’s carried through by your steadily expanding arsenal and abilities, and that search for an ideal run into enemy territory, but you have to be completely sold on the fundamental gameplay early on. Personally, I think it pulls it off, with the visuals and alternate history setting really drawing me in, but I could see some players losing faith with the repetition and chaos-tinged battles.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/11/grit-valor-1949-review/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>