<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 14:08:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zelda movie actors revealed for live-action adaptation]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/16/zelda-movie-actors-revealed-for-live-action-adaptation/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zelda-movie-actors-revealed-for-live-action-adaptation.1244967/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Nintendo has revealed the two lead actors for the upcoming live-action film of The Legend of Zelda, with the film scheduled for release in just under two years on 7th May 2027.</p>
<p>Shigeru Miyamoto grabbed the social media logins to make the reveal:</p>


<p>“This is Miyamoto. I am pleased to announce that for the live-action film of The Legend of Zelda, Zelda will be played by Bo Bragason-san, and Link by Benjamin Evan Ainsworth-san. I am very much looking forward to seeing both of them on the big screen.”</p>

<p>Yeah, I can see those faces as Zelda and Link, definitely.</p>

<p>Ainsworth already has a number of major credits to his name at the age of 16. He was Pinocchio in the live action remake of that in 2021, was Miles Wingrave in The Haunting of Bly Manor on Netflix, and played William Spiver in the Disney+ film Flora &amp; Ulysses.</p>
<p>Bo Bragason, meanwhile, has been in the BBC productions Three Girls in 2017 and The Jetty in 2024, as well as the Disney+ series Renegade Nell.</p>
<p>The movie is a collaboration between legendary game creator Shigeru Miyamoto and renowned film producer Avi Arad – he led Marvel back from bankruptcy in the mid 90’s pushing licensing deals for film and television, prior to the company’s sale to Disney, and has continued to have producer credits on Sony’s extended Spider-Man universe of films, while Kingdom of the Planet of the Apes and The Maze Runner trilogy’s Wes Ball is on board as director.</p>
<p>At this stage we know nothing about the story that this film adaptation will tell, though things are clearly falling into place with the casting of the two leads. We’d obviously expect them to lean on the established tropes of Link being a mythical, destined hero that has to save Hyrule from Ganon and/or Ganondorf, but the games go back and forth on whether Zelda herself is a princess that needs rescuing, or a hero in her own right. It’s entirely plausible that the film looks to latch onto the story told through Breath of the Wild, Tears of the Kingdom and the two Hyrule Warriors spin-offs, it could retell the epic Ocarina of Time, or weave its own story around familiar themes. We’ll have to wait and see.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://xcancel.com/Nintendo/status/1945431647530491955">Nintendo</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/16/zelda-movie-actors-revealed-for-live-action-adaptation/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>