<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 17:26:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No Sleep For Kaname Date – From AI: THE SOMNIUM FILES Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/18/no-sleep-for-kaname-date-from-ai-the-somnium-files-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/no-sleep-for-kaname-date-%E2%80%93-from-ai-the-somnium-files-review.1247403/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>I wasn’t sure what to expect from&nbsp;No Sleep For Kaname Date.&nbsp;As a big fan of the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2019/10/16/ai-the-somnium-files-review/">AI: The Somnium Files</a>&nbsp;games, it’s hard to picture where in the timeline a third entry could fall that would cleanly follow up on the ending of the second game, while also giving us the characters that this one seemed to be specifically focusing on. Much like how the series tasks you with disregarding your main options and seeking out a hidden third path, that’s the exact route that the developers have ended up taking with this No Sleep For Kaname Date.</p>
<p>This game is neither a prequel nor a sequel – in carving out a hidden third path for themselves, the team behind this title have made a game that creates it’s own context somewhere vaguely in-between both entries. While it doesn’t deliver a satisfying continuation of the main narrative as a result, it still ends up being a really enjoyable, fan-pleasing side-story that I couldn’t help but smile at.</p>
<p><iframe title="No Sleep For Kaname Date - From AI: THE SOMNIUM FILES, System Trailer | Switch, Switch 2, Steam" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LzXuPDXSi-E?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>No Sleep For Kaname Date sees the return of the iconic investigative duo from the first game – perverted slacker ABIS agent Kaname Date and his cybernetic AI, the eyeball-shaped companion Aiba. Protagonist duties don’t squarely belong to them, though – you’ll also spend a lot of the game playing directly as Iris, the iconic bubbly social media influencer that the first game revolved around. I’ve already talked a bit about how this game is heavy on fan-pleasing moments for people who enjoy the rest of the series, but it’s also surprisingly packed with send-ups to creator Kotaro Uchikoshi’s other iconic sci-fi murder mystery series, Zero Escape.</p>
<p>Iris suddenly finds herself kidnapped by a UFO and trapped in a mysterious set of escape room puzzles that are part of something called The Third Eye Games. These puzzles literally play out like gameplay from the&nbsp;Zero Escape&nbsp;franchise, all the way down to minute aesthetic details like the “SEEK A WAY OUT” message popping up at the start of a puzzle or the iconic item pickup sound effect returning from&nbsp;999: Nine Hours, Nine Persons, Nine Doors.</p>


<p>Much like those games, puzzles in this title are also incredibly absurd, and are nearly impossible to gauge at a base level. The items you need to find, the combinations you need to concoct, and the reactions you need to unfurl to escape each room feel like they’re being made up on the fly – it’s equal parts maddening and entertaining, but rarely feels unfair. In the moments where it does, the game provides some precise difficulty options and hint systems that you can toggle between pretty freely as you play. For a purist, you can stick to hard mode and never use the Seek system that points out your next item to interact with. For a story-focused player or someone struggling with a particular puzzle, the malleability of the difficulty and hints is really helpful for ensuring that the frustration of these escape rooms never boils over.</p>
<p>Between solving escape rooms as Iris, you’re also doing familiar investigations and Psync dives as Kaname Date. These play out exactly as they would in prior games, with nothing new mechanically going on to spice them up. If the entirety of No Sleep For Kaname Date were just these investigation scenes, they would be a bit of a drag considering how familiar and almost formulaic they’ve become. But drizzled in between the escape rooms, they help ground the experience a bit and keep it feeling like a proper AI: The Somnium Files&nbsp;entry, while also helping break up the gameplay a bit.</p>

<p>All these moments ultimately serve to support and amplify the writing of the game – that’s something that No Sleep For Kaname Date delivers on in spades. Characters are consistently funny, weird, and absurdist in that way that I love so much. Part of me is still frustrated that the game sort of captures so many of these characters in a bubble of sorts, presenting flanderised versions of them that don’t reflect the growth or changes they go through in the main series. It’s especially frustrating to see Kaname Date and Mizuki presented in the way they are, because the versions of these characters that come later in the story are so much more interesting to explore.</p>
<p>At the same time, this game delivers some really exciting new character interactions that I was sorely missing from the last game. Tama the flirty and air-headed AI companion always felt like such an exciting character to see Kaname Date interact with, and finally having moments in this game where the two of them bounce their idiocy off each other is so much fun.</p>

<p>Ultimately, if you come to No Sleep For Kaname Date looking for a continuation of the story from the first two games, or a title that carves a brave and destructive path for itself the way that games from Kotaro Uchikoshi tend to do, this ain’t it. What it is, though, is like a really creative and entertaining filler arc from a long-running anime. The events of this game might not entirely matter in the grand scheme of things or push the more serious elements of the narrative in any particularly exciting direction, but it is full of fun character moments, wild puzzles, and so much of the charm and absurdity that made the first two games such a blast.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/18/no-sleep-for-kaname-date-from-ai-the-somnium-files-review/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Drifter Review – Grindhouse point and click perfection]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/18/the-drifter-review-grindhouse-point-and-click-perfection/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-drifter-review-%E2%80%93-grindhouse-point-and-click-perfection.1247277/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="gp-content-wrapper">

	<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

		<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope="" content="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/18/the-drifter-review-grindhouse-point-and-click-perfection/">
		<meta itemprop="headline" content="The Drifter Review – Grindhouse point and click perfection">			
		
		<meta itemprop="author" content="Steve C">			
		<meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2025-07-18">
		<meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2025-07-18">
		
		
			
		
								
		
			

																		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>While the genre has never returned to the heights of the Lucasarts and Sierra boom of the mid-90s, point and click adventure games have never gone away. Every now and again one will break through (such as Excavation of Hob’s Barrow or Kathy Rain) but a devoted community of developers and players continue to enjoy their gripping storylines and challenging puzzles. I often go back and check out recent releases and am always excited to find one that blends in my fondness of the dark and mysterious. The Drifter is a game that ticks all my boxes, ending up as a real standout entry in the genre.</p>
<p><iframe title="The Drifter - Launch Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2GiHlkE2z8g?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Powerhoof, the devs behind The Drifter, have made the game through their own custom designed Unity point and click creation tool, called Powerquest, with the ending credits including an invocation for players to tell their own stories through this. This passion for the form really shines through in the game, which is a love letter both to gritty pulp science fiction and adventure classics. There is more here than tribute and nostalgia, though, as the quality of the writing, voice acting, and storytelling are all extremely high.</p>


<p>The opening to the game immediately strikes you with its gorgeous pixel graphics and animation, alongside the superb voice acting of the main character and narrator, Mick Carter by Adrian Vaughan. Other characters are all professionally voiced but it is Mick’s story to tell and the rough Aussie voiceover fits the style of the game to perfection. There is a grittiness to Vaughan’s acting here that elevates the story to a level of polish that is rare to see.</p>
<p>We first meet Mick stowing away aboard a freight train en route to the home he abandoned under mysterious circumstances. He is returning to attend his mother’s funeral, but it is clear that there are layers of regret and sorrow beneath his rough exterior. Immediately upon arriving at his destination, a fellow stowaway is murdered in front of him and the narrative of intrigue and terror begins.</p>


<p>The opening section (which is also in the demo if you want to get a taste of the game) sets out the broad outline of the story, introduces several characters and takes you through the familiar point and click controls. Everything is carried out through a highly intuitive graphical interface that is tailor made for either mouse or controller. I played the game through on desktop, but it is designed to work just as well on console or Steam Deck. With mouse you follow the familiar point and click whereas on controller you can scroll through interactive points which removes some of the frustration of pixel hunting or lesser accuracy of an analogue stick.</p>
<p>At the end of the first chapter, Mick has been drowned (with a clear nod to Guybrush Threepwood in both setting and a hidden achievement) and come back to life. The remainder of the game sees Mick try to find out how he has unlocked this new found ability, survive against sinister plots, and rescue those closest to him. The narrative zips along at a thrilling pace, with each chapter building and escalating to create an emotional crescendo that is surprisingly affecting. These chapters could be taken individually to give an episodic feel that would be well in keeping with the pulp thrillers that have influenced the game, but I felt compelled to binge the game in two sittings.</p>

<p>So, graphics, voice-acting, and narrative are all excellent, but what really matters with point and click adventures is the quality of the puzzles. The Drifter focuses on item-based puzzles, with dialogue furthering the story at times or revealing new areas to investigate. There are none of the overly complex dialogue trees that can prove frustrating as you repeat lines multiple times to try and find the one path that opens up new information. Instead, all conversations are clearly laid out with icons representing the subject, and these light up when they haven’t been discussed or when new information is available. This is one of the most intuitive dialogue systems I’ve seen and shows just how refined the Powerquest engine is.</p>
<p>Inventory manipulation is the main area for puzzles and you’ll pick up the traditional array of items, many of which would never fit in a real pocket. Puzzles either involve combining items to create new ones, or interacting with the environment with others. Stripped down to that basic description, this mechanic always sounds somewhat limited, but the skilful design of puzzles, alongside the ever-present threat of death (albeit with a swift return) constantly keep you on your toes. There are some memorable moments where you have to quickly react to threats to survive whilst some late game puzzles involving deliberately dying and resurrecting bring in a level of depth and time travel that reminds me of peak Day of the Tentacle (with a much darker aesthetic).</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div>

		
				
	<div id="gp-summary">
		<p>Summary</p><p>
		The Drifter is a new standard in point and click adventures and deserves to be spoken about in the same breath as the very best the genre has to offer. The look, sound, and feel of the game are all superb and it tells a story that never stops being thrilling. All in all, it’s an essential purchase for anybody who has even a passing interest in the genre.	</p></div>
		

	<div id="gp-review-results">

									<div id="gp-good-points">
						<p>Good</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Beautiful pixel graphics</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Superb voice acting</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Thrilling and twisting narrative</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Excellently designed puzzles</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
				
									<div id="gp-bad-points">
						<p>Bad</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>A handful of obtuse moments where you’ll die a lot</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
							
			</div>

					
	
						
			
			

			
					
		
					
 
	
	
				
	</article>

</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/18/the-drifter-review-grindhouse-point-and-click-perfection/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>