<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 10:21:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FBC: Firebreak gameplay reveals a new supernatural threat: Sticky Notes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/21/fbc-firebreak-gameplay-reveals-a-new-supernatural-threat-sticky-notes/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fbc-firebreak-gameplay-reveals-a-new-supernatural-threat-sticky-notes.1141065/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/21/fbc-firebreak-gameplay-reveals-a-new-supernatural-threat-sticky-notes/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Remedy Entertainment has confirmed that <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/fbc-firebreak">FBC: Firebreak</a> will launch this summer for PS5, Xbox Series X|S and PC, shared a healthy dose of gameplay and revealed one of the big supernatural dangers you’ll face in the game: Sticky Notes.</p>
<p><iframe title="Jobs and Gameplay – FBC: Firebreak (Community First Look)" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4rdE55zqOOc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Oh sure, yellow sticky notes seem innocuous enough to you and me, their small size (often cut into cute shapes these days) and weak glue making them mildly useful, but in The Oldest House and with the Hiss still running rampant? Well, haunted sticky notes are a real problem. The gameplay reveal for FBC: Firebreak focuses on this Job, a crisis-filled mission that will take you to the Executive Sector of the Federal Bureau of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/control">Control</a>. This mission, titled Paper Chase, is just one of many to take on in the game, with the sole objective to destroy as many sticky notes as possible. Other missions might have you try to find mannequin ski instructors and load them onto a paranatural ski lift…</p>
<p>With three-player PvE co-op at its heart, you’ll have three saved loadouts to choose from, Crisis Kits, which are themed around a particular tool and playstyle. You’ll then pick the Threat Level and Clearance Level of a Job, determining the difficulty of enemies and then the complexity and length of the mission.</p>
<p>The trailer and dev diary both show plenty of what you’ll expect to face. There’s regular Hiss zombie-type enemies, bomb squad Hiss with much heavier armour, and then humanoid forms constructed entirely of sticky notes. There’s even a giant Sandman-like boss to battle. One thing you’ll have to be wary of is getting covered with sticky notes yourself, with allies able to wash you down or showers dotted around the world to do the same – albeit at the cost of slowing you down for a bit from the cold water, unless you fix the heaters for the showers.</p>

<p>In addition to standard weapons like shotguns, there’s also a crank-fired fluid projector, an electric charge impactor, and the big wrench which can have a squeaky toy pig attached to it.&nbsp;There’s plenty of Left 4 Dead vibes to the action here, with safe rooms helping to provide some structure to the levels, and the need to defend from alerted enemies.</p>
<p>Remedy has already confirmed that FBC: Firebreak will be available day one on <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/xbox-game-pass">Xbox Game Pass Ultimate</a>, PC Game Pass, PlayStation Plus Extra and PlayStation Plus Premium. In addition to this, they’ve now confirmed that all playable content will be available to all players for free, meaning any new levels will be playable for all. There’s no word on monetisation outside of that, but Remedy will share those details another time.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dive into underwater horror Dark Mass, coming to PC, PS5, and Xbox Series XS]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/20/dive-into-underwater-horror-dark-mass-coming-to-pc-ps5-and-xbox-series-xs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dive-into-underwater-horror-dark-mass-coming-to-pc-ps5-and-xbox-series-xs.1140840/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/20/dive-into-underwater-horror-dark-mass-coming-to-pc-ps5-and-xbox-series-xs/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Developer Path Games has announced its next game and it is called Dark Mass. Much like its previous game Insomnis, Dark Mass is a first person horror title but it swaps a regular, land based mansion for a manor that is deep underwater in the middle of the sea. How did it get there? Well, that’s one of the mysteries. The announcement trailer gives a sense of what to expect in this unusual deep sea dive.</p>
<p><iframe title="Dark Mass - Announcement Trailer | 4K" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/j2sv9NAia24?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Dark Mass puts you in the role of deep sea explorer Alice who, along with her brother Reed, set off to to explore a ship wreck. However, they instead find the out of place manor that still retains much of its identity, despite being on the sea bed. Alice soon becomes trapped within the manor and has to solve its puzzle and avoid the horrors that still inhabit the house, including the monster Silas, who stalks Alice through the manor. Throughout the story, Alice maintains contact with Reed, who is on the boat, through a walkie talkie. Navigating through the manor will be slow at times as Alice’s movement is impacted by the deep sea currents. The story will have multiple choices with these leading to different endings.</p>
<p>A release date for Dark Mass is yet to be confirmed, but it is expected at some point this year.</p>
<p><em>Source: Press Release</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>