<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 09:54:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Among Us 3D is Among Us VR without the VR – Steam Next Fest demo incoming]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/21/among-us-3d-is-among-us-vr-without-the-vr-steam-next-fest-demo-incoming/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/among-us-3d-is-among-us-vr-without-the-vr-%E2%80%93-steam-next-fest-demo-incoming.1115205/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/21/among-us-3d-is-among-us-vr-without-the-vr-steam-next-fest-demo-incoming/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Innersloth and Schell Games have revealed an un-VR-ified version of Among Us VR. Among Us 3D is coming to PC via Steam with a Steam Next Fest demo coming next week.</p>
<p><iframe title="Among Us 3D ???? Teaser Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UYMaaMTgxa4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>In the fullness of time, Among Us 3D will be a flatscreen counterpart to Among Us VR, coming with cross-play between the two 3D adaptations of the hit social deduction game. In turn, it is very much like the original 2D Among Us… but in three dimensions. The game can be played with 4-10 players, all running around completing tasks on the map until a murdered body is discovered, calling an Emergency Meeting to try and determine who the imposter is, and eject the into space. Of course, playing either in VR or 3D makes this all much closer and more personal…</p>
<p>The Steam Next Fest demo is more limited than the full Among Us 3D release will be, and will not support all features or game modes. So there’s no crossplay or additional cosmetics, until the full release comes down the pipe.</p>
<p>Here’s the feature breakdown from the Steam listing:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Native Proximity Voice Chat</strong> — Yap with your friends directly in-game. No need for additional third-party platforms!</li>
<li><strong>New and Returning Minigames</strong> —&nbsp; Experience the tasks you know and love, along with some new ones. Now, with first-person controls.</li>
<li><strong>Crossplay Functionality —</strong> Join lobbies with other VR<i> </i>players! (<i>Note: <strong>The game is NOT compatible with the original </strong></i><strong>Among Us <i>game</i></strong><i>. Sorry, beans.</i>)</li>
<li><strong>Customize Your Beansona </strong>— Expand your wardrobe of hats, gloves, and skins with an endless number of cosmetic customization combinations!</li>
</ul>
<p>After Among Us became one of the breakout hits of 2020, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/12/10/among-us-is-getting-vr/">Innersloth partnered with Schell Games to produce Among Us VR</a>, launching in 2022. It’s a great fit conceptually for VR, adding more tactile minigames, the isolation of running around doing tasks, while trying to be aware of your surroundings and spot suspicious behaviour. But VR games have often been adapted back to flatscreen, and now it’s Among Us’ turn to make that return trip. The 2D original game will surely remain the most popular version of Among Us, but a 3D counterpart is sure to pick up an audience of its own, especially with VR cross-play.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1849900/view/544475871458623550">Steam</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cosy LOTR life sim Tales of the Shire delayed again to July]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/21/cosy-lotr-life-sim-tales-of-the-shire-delayed-again-to-july/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cosy-lotr-life-sim-tales-of-the-shire-delayed-again-to-july.1115202/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/21/cosy-lotr-life-sim-tales-of-the-shire-delayed-again-to-july/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Tales of the Shire: <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/the-lord-of-the-rings">A Lord of the Rings</a> game has been delayed again, being pushed back from March to a new 29th July 2025 release date. The cosy Hobbit life sim is coming to PC, PS5, Xbox Series X|S, Switch, and Netflix gaming.</p>
<p>Weta Workshop announced the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/tales-of-the-shire">Tales of the Shire</a> delay on a place we ain’t linking to these days:</p>


<p>Dear Fellow Hobbits,</p>
<p>A good Hobbit feast takes time, and so does <a title="Series > Tales of [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/tales-of">Tales of</a> the Shire! We’re taking a little longer to ensure that every Hobbit, on every platform, can enjoy the same cozy experience. The game will now launch on July 29, 2025.</p>
<p>We want this game to feel like a warm hug from Middle-earth, and we are making sure that no matter where you play, you’ll feel right at home in The Shire. From foot-hair styles to the fluffiest cakes, every detail will be just right.</p>

<p>We appreciate your patience and cannot wait for you to experience life in The Shire this summer. In the meantime, arrange the table, polish your silver and get ready for a feast fit for a Hobbit!</p>
<p>Looking forward to welcoming you to Bywater.</p>
<p>—From the folks at Weta Workshop Game Studio</p>
<p>Tales of the Shire allows players to create their own Hobbit, who lives in Bywater and can establish their own life. As time passes in Bywater, other Hobbits will come to ask your Hobbit for help on matters. Additionally, you can do all the cosy things a Hobbit’s life should consist of, including growing your own vegetables, going fishing, trading items with neighbours, and cooking up meals. You can wander around Bywater visiting other Hobbits and going to the shop, or venture a bit further out to forage in the fields for supplies.</p>
<p>Originally <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/04/22/tales-of-the-shire-is-a-cosy-life-sim-set-in-the-lord-of-the-rings-universe/">announced</a> and expected to launch in 2024, Tales of the Shire has now had multiple delays. <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/09/14/cosy-hobbit-life-sim-tales-of-the-shire-delayed-to-2025/">A rough 2025 window</a> was <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/09/23/tales-of-the-shire-gets-a-new-march-25th-release-date/">narrowed to March 2025</a>, but clearly Weta need more time to realise this cosy take on fantasy world.</p>
<p><em>Source: Weta Workshop on The Bad Place</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>