<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 18:22:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rhythm Heaven and Tomodachi Life are coming back in 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/27/rhythm-heaven-groove-switch-tomodachi-life-living-the-dream-2026-release-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rhythm-heaven-and-tomodachi-life-are-coming-back-in-2026.1146795/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/27/rhythm-heaven-groove-switch-tomodachi-life-living-the-dream-2026-release-date/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Nintendo revealed the return of two of their oddball game series, with Rhythm Heaven Groove and Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream both coming to Nintendo Switch in 2026.</p>
<p><iframe title="Rhythm Heaven Groove – Nintendo Direct 3.27.2025" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZkgjFacpnLE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>The new entry in the Rhythm Heaven series is sticking to some very familiar ideas for the series. This is all about pressing buttons at just the right time, matching the specific beat that the game is giving you with some quirkily animated scenes as you get things right (or a little bit wrong).</p>
<p>The first new game since <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2016/10/28/rhythm-paradise-megamix-review/">Rhythm Heaven Megamix</a> in 2015 (which was a bit of a best of collection for 3DS), Rhythm Heaven Groove will continue the series’ traditional partnerships with Nintendo and TNX co-developing.</p>
<p><iframe title="Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream – Nintendo Direct 3.27.2025" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Dvo1V7DWYsA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>And then there’s Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream, bringing your Mii out of semi-retirement and sending them off to an idyllic seaside town to go about their lives, hanging out with other Miis and completing certain tasks to earn rewards. There’s also some thoroughly weird moments, like the dream sequence with a giant Mii running along to interrupt a dream – it looks like we’ll still get to experience Mii dreams here, and it’s a neat tie in with the game’s subtitle.</p>

<p>After the original game on DS, Tomodachi Life was an off-beat hit for the Nintendo 3DS in 2013. There were other Mii-based spin-offs like <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/miitomo">Miitomo</a> on mobile and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/miitopia">Miitopia</a>, but the main Tomodachi Life experience is now being revived after well over a decade.<sup id="cite_ref-65"></sup></p>
<p>I guess Miis are still going to be relevant for a few more years, as well…</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>