<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 14:20:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sumo Group’s founders announce retirement]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/09/sumo-groups-founders-announce-retirement/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sumo-group%E2%80%99s-founders-announce-retirement.1185228/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/09/sumo-groups-founders-announce-retirement/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>The founders of Sumo Group have announced their retirement. CEO Carl Cavers, COO Paul Porter and Director of Excellence and Integration Darren Mills are all leaving the company after leading Sumo since 2003. Under their leadership, Sumo has released games such as Outrun 2, Sonic &amp; All-Stars Racing: Transformed, LittleBigPlanet 3, Snake Pass, and Sackboy: A Big Adventure.</p>
<p>“Stepping away from something we’ve built over two decades is never easy, but it’s the right time,” said Carl Cavers, outgoing CEO and co-founder. “We’re incredibly proud of what we’ve achieved together, and we’re confident that Sumo is in a strong position to continue evolving and thriving.”</p>


<p>With the retirement of the three founders there is obviously a change in leadership at Sumo Group. Gary Dunn will take on the role of COO and be co-CEO with &nbsp;Andy Stewart, who is also the Chief Financial Officer. Tim Repa-Davies has moved onto the company’s board of directors, while remaining as the Head of Legal and Business Affairs.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/04/sumo-group-stops-making-original-ip-to-focus-on-partner-titles/">Sumo Group announced it would stop making original IP to focus on partner titles</a>, due to the company’s position and need to maintain a long term strategy for the continued survival of the group. In March, Sumo Group sold off its publishing arm <a href="https://www.sumo-digital.com/news-insights/emona-capital-completes-acquisition-of-secret-mode/">Secret Mode to Emona Capital</a>, a financial investment firm which also has holdings in Relic Entertainment and Amber Studio. At the time of the sale, Ed Blincoe and James Schall remained in leadership positions within of the company. Sumo is currently working to support development of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/05/gears-of-war-reloaded-announced-for-pc-xbox-series-xs-and-ps5/">Gears of War: Reloaded</a>.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.sumo-digital.com/news-insights/sumo-group-announces-leadership-transition-as-founders-retire/">Sumo Group</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>