<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 15:36:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What We Played – Infinity Nikki, Phasmophobia & Indiana Jones and the Great Circle]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/06/what-we-played-infinity-nikki-phasmophobia-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what-we-played-%E2%80%93-infinity-nikki-phasmophobia-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle.1053717/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/06/what-we-played-infinity-nikki-phasmophobia-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>What a great end to the year we’re having – at least in terms of game releases! I’ve had the good fortune to check out <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/05/infinity-nikki-review/">Infinity Nikki</a>, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/05/mythwrecked-ambrosia-island-review/">Mythwrecked: Ambrosia Island</a> and Snow Bros. Wonderland (more on that one to come). Other than those, I’ve patiently waited for Marvel Rivals to release, and I’m literally just about to hop into the first matches. Excelsior! Or… something like that.</p>

<p><strong>Jim</strong> wrapped up Assassin’s Creed Mirage and then got back to playing Valiant Hearts which he’s been chipping away at for a little while. He says, “It’s a thoughtful little puzzle set during World War I from a time when Ubi were doing plenty of cool smaller games. I also dipped my toes in Alan Wake II before picking up Warhammer 40,000: Darktide.”</p>
<p><strong>Steve</strong> has mostly been playing being ill in bed, but he’s been hammering Mario and Luigi which has been about the right level of challenge for his poorly brain. Oh, he also managed a couple of hours killing Skaven on Vernintide 2 multiplayer before the bronchitis really set in. Hope you’re on the mend, mate!</p>
<p>If he’s playing Destiny 2, you know he’s <strong>Tuffcub</strong>, but he’s also played other things too! Funko Pop Fusion “is a bit of a mess”, and the Jurassic Park Classic Game Collection is “a useful reminder that collision detection was awful back in the day”. Meanwhile, <strong>Gamoc</strong> played Phasmophobia, telling us, “It’s still great despite its janky bugginess. Also The Thaumaturge for review.”</p>


<p><strong>Ade</strong> has been playing Shadow Tactics: Aiko’s Choice for review, as well as a spot of Helldivers 2 (he’s so close to getting a mech-thingy now!). He tells us, “I also picked up Astral Chain in the sales and boy-oh-boy what a game! I’m only a few hours in but already slathering for a sequel, for Switch 2 perhaps?”</p>
<p><strong>Aran</strong> has been playing The Witcher 3 and revisiting old haunts. He says, “I’m just taking my time exploring and clearing the hundreds of question marks off the map. Also playing Overthrown for early access review. Balataro has been a massive time sink as it is very addictive when trying to get a good run going.” It wouldn’t be a What We Played without a spot of Football Manager too, continuing, “In FM24, I’ve guided Valencia to the last 16 of the Champions League and semi final of the Spanish Cup. Lost both, but competing in the league to qualify for Europe again. Not sure if the board will give me a new contract yet though, after all I’ve done for them over the last 4 seasons like winning their first European title in over 20 years.”</p>

<p>And finally there’s <strong>Tef</strong>, who dished out a beating to hundreds of fascists while <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/06/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-review/">reviewing Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a> this past week. He really enjoyed it, and felt that the first person view really helped get the tone and pacing just right for and Indy adventure. Now if only he could remember that it’s a “Great” circle and not a “Giant” one, that’d really help…</p>
<p>What about you? What have you played?</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>