<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 10:44:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Learn how to design a house with Architect Life: A House Design Simulator]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/14/learn-how-to-design-a-house-with-architect-life-a-house-design-simulator/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/learn-how-to-design-a-house-with-architect-life-a-house-design-simulator.1081623/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/14/learn-how-to-design-a-house-with-architect-life-a-house-design-simulator/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>The simulator genre is an unusual and ever-evolving array of experiences. Some might task you with specific or bespoke roles that people dream about, like becoming a paramedic or a train driver, while others let you become a car mechanic and dive into the nitty-gritty of how an engine works. Shine Research’s latest, with support from publisher Nacon sees you becoming an architect, with Architect Life: A House Design Simulator giving people the opportunity to build and design incredible homes without the lengthy or expensive university education. Sounds like a pretty good deal, right?</p>
<p><iframe title="Architect Life: A House Design Simulator | Official Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HXyH9aJs2qA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>The official trailer immediately shows off the kind of builds that are going to be possible, aping ultra-modern or Grand Designs-styled properties with clarity. It’s clear that you’re going to be put to work by a range of clients, whose every wish you have to try and turn into a series of workable walls with a roof on top of them. It’s an intriguing set-up, and who knows, maybe you’ll find you have a taste for working in this field. Equally, you might discover that you hate people, but we’ll wait and see how needy these particular clients turn out to be.</p>
<p>It’s all very precise, with each section of the build displaying the kind of measurement details and iconography that you’d expect to see in a blueprint or architectural diagram. Don’t let that put you off though, as it seems as though the building itself looks very intuitive, at least with a keyboard and mouse in tow, though the team have been clear to say that it’s just as easy to control with a controller. Once you’ve built the building itself, you have to dress it as well, channelling your inner interior designer for maximum effect.</p>


<p>There’s two main modes, with a 60-mission campaign – that’s a lot of clients – and a sandbox mode where you can let your imagination run riot without constraints or someone breathing down your neck. Things can still go wrong though, and you have to also become a site manager, ensuring that the build continues on schedule despite inclement weather or supply delays.</p>
<p>Architect Life : A House Design Simulator will be available on PC, PS5, Xbox Series and Nintendo Switch in June 2025.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Uncle Chop’s Rocket Shop Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/14/uncle-chops-rocket-shop-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/uncle-chop%E2%80%99s-rocket-shop-review.1081605/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/14/uncle-chops-rocket-shop-review/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="gp-content-wrapper">

	<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

		<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope="" content="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/14/uncle-chops-rocket-shop-review/">
		<meta itemprop="headline" content="Uncle Chop’s Rocket Shop Review">			
		
		<meta itemprop="author" content="Dominic L">			
		<meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2025-01-14">
		<meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2025-01-14">
		
		
			
		
								
		
			

																		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>I can refuel a spaceship. That’s right, a ship that can go into space. Can you? Uncle Chop’s Rocket Shop is a game about being a mechanic and, weird flex aside, it’s actually capable of teaching you important and useful skills. Admittedly, these are more about being able to follow instructions and retain information rather than actually refuelling spaceships. Still, NASA know where you are if they need you, right?</p>
<p><iframe title="Uncle Chop's Rocket Shop | Release Date Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0RsRnMhqQgI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>You play Wilbur, a four-eyed space fox with more than a little Wes Anderson film about him, who somehow falls into mechanical-based servitude to Uncle Chop. You rent a space above the café, and each morning, you clock in for work and attempt to repair and maintain a steady stream of extraterrestrial craft. The better job you do and the faster you perform, the more money you earn, which in turn lets you pay your R.E.N.T. and continue to survive for another day or two. Phew, I’m glad the real world isn’t quite like that.</p>


<p>This isn’t the only brush with the real world that Uncle Chop’s Rocket Shop has, as you have to research and remember the correct way to maintain all these spaceships. That means opening your Grimoire and finding the correct section on whatever part or subsection needs looking at. At first, that’s just figuring out how to refuel the ship, but as you progress the tasks become longer, tougher and more complicated.</p>


<p>What makes Uncle Chop’s Rocket Shop so special is how tactile these tasks are. You have to physically complete them, with Kasedo Games translating each of these to the physical controls on your controller. So, analogue sticks operate as levers or socket wrenches and screwdrivers, all of which need to be selected, grabbed and physically moved. Even clocking in requires you to pick up your card, stamp it in the machine with an oh-so-satisfying pull of the lever, and then slot it into the waiting slot on the other side. It’s clever and utterly unique.</p>
<p>As you leaf through your Grimoire, you really have to learn the different methods and machines that will enable you to complete the task. Each page has a batch of infographics, and while they’re not always completely explicit, relying as much on arrows and ticks to show you the right place or correct way of doing things, they help you come to understand the task at hand.</p>
<p>You’ll fumble through the first few, before, without warning, you can suddenly replace a spaceship’s oil in the fastest, most efficient way possible. It’s bizarre how easily this previously complicated task becomes, and frankly, maybe we should put a bit of Uncle Chop’s Rocket Shop into our secondary curriculum planning. They’re definitely onto something educational, though the puzzling action can be slightly more frantic than you’d probably want a classroom to be. Its academic chops are also hidden away behind an alien fox and more than a couple of rude words.</p>

<p>Uncle Chop’s Rocket Shop is set up as a Roguelite, and while it might feel like this has become the most ubiquitous gameplay mechanic of recent years, it does at least make sense and have some narrative drive behind it, as each run lets you gain more currency to unlock permanent upgrades and boons. Spaceships are procedurally generated too, so each time you start a new run, you’ll encounter all-new layouts and different customers behind the wheel.</p>
<p>Everything is complimented by the off-kilter, irreverent humour. There’s plenty of expletives, wry nods to the camera and a bucketload of self-awareness that has the game taking aim at those in positions of power, capitalism and the conditions that the working classes endure. It’s fun and knowing, and it’ll put a smile on your face while giving you something to think about, which is what good comedy is all about. The soundtrack is flipping fantastic too, with a Western guitar drawl that feels cool and laidback, even when everything is going to hell and you’re fumbling with the socket wrench again.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div>

		
				
		

	<div id="gp-review-results">
				<p>Summary</p><p>
				Unique and ever so smart, Uncle Chop's Rocket Shop is fiendish and fun in equal measure. 			</p></div>

					
	
						
			
			

			
					
		
					
 
	
	
				
	</article>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mai gameplay trailer for Street Fighter 6 has dropped]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/14/mai-gameplay-trailer-for-street-fighter-6-has-dropped/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mai-gameplay-trailer-for-street-fighter-6-has-dropped.1081584/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/14/mai-gameplay-trailer-for-street-fighter-6-has-dropped/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Capcom has released a new gameplay trailer for Fatal Fury’s Mai, who is part of Street Fighter VI’s Year 2 Character Pass. The trailer shows her facing off against Chun Li and Ryu in two different bouts, wearing two different outfits, both from her Fatal Fury wardrobe. Mai has been part of the Fatal Fury series since Fatal Fury 2, which released back in 1992.</p>
<p><iframe title="Street Fighter 6 - Mai Gameplay Trailer | PS5 &amp; PS4 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RhcsgO4jse4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>As you can see from the trailer, Mai brings her Shiranui Ninja style into the fighter mix of Street Fighter VI. It is a hand to hand style that also encompasses throws, kicks, elbows, fire, and paper fans. Players who like putting together combos will have plenty to work with when it comes to Mai’s fighting style, and it looks like it will favour those who prefer fast moving characters. Mai will be available from February 5th in Street Fighter VI.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/05/30/street-fighter-6-review/">In our Street Fighter 6 Review,</a>&nbsp;Nick said,&nbsp;<em>“Street Fighter 6 doesn’t need recommending to hardcore fighting fans – you all already know how incredible it is – but do I recommend it for more casual players? Street Fighter 6 has a real sense of community, welcoming all players old and new, teaching new tricks and providing something for those that just want a bit of fun. This is truly a fighting game for everyone.”</em></p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RhcsgO4jse4">YouTube</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Blood of Dawnwalker is a new RPG from former The Witcher 3 devs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/14/the-blood-of-dawnwalker-is-a-new-rpg-from-former-the-witcher-3-devs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-blood-of-dawnwalker-is-a-new-rpg-from-former-the-witcher-3-devs.1081569/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/14/the-blood-of-dawnwalker-is-a-new-rpg-from-former-the-witcher-3-devs/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Back in October, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/21/bandai-namco-will-publish-rebel-wolves-rpg-dawnwalker/">Bandai Namco and new studio Rebel Wolves</a> agreed a publishing deal for Rebel Wolves new RPG, at the time named Dawnwalker. Rebel Wolves was founded in 2022 by the game director of The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt, Konrad Tomaszkiewicz. He has been joined by other CD Projekt RED alumni, including Chief Publishing Officer Tomasz Tinc, and Narrative Director Jakub Szamałek. Today, the first cinematic and gameplay teaser for The Blood of Dawnwalker has been released.</p>
<p><iframe title="The Blood of Dawnwalker — Cinematic Trailer &amp; Gameplay Teaser" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HkICrJEVTjI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>The Blood of Dawnwalker is set in Europe during the 14th century, with the Black Plague wiping out people at a high rate. One of the people affected is Lunka, the sister of main character Coen. In the trailer, you can see him fleeing a patrol to stop them from killing his sister and ending up in a ruined church. Cornered, Coen is saved by an unlikely source. That is a vampire and his allies. The vampire saves Lunka’s life, but has his own motivations to take advantage of humanity’s time of weakness to grab power and gain freedom, along with other creatures of the night.</p>
<p>While the cinematic ends on a bit of a cliffhanger, the trailer shows some gameplay with Coen wielding dark powers. Coen is the Daywalker, and the assumption is that the vampire made him this way as payment for saving Lunka. Coen has vampiric powers but can navigate the world during the day. As the story of The Blood of Dawnwalker&nbsp; progresses, players will make choices on whether to try and remain human or use the vampiric dark powers, moving further away from humanity. You will also be able to use a combo of human and vampire skills in combat, with all sorts of foes from soldiers to other monsters being enemies. Allies could be found among any group too, be they human or a creature of the night. It all depends on the decisions you make as Coen.</p>

<p>The Blood of Dawnwalker does not have a release date yet, and a gameplay reveal will be coming in the summer. The Blood of Dawnwalker has been confirmed for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://dawnwalkergame.com/gb/en/home#about">The Blood of Dawnwalker official site</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>