<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 03:49:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 Endgame revealed and it’s a lot]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/10/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-endgame-revealed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-endgame-revealed-and-it%E2%80%99s-a-lot.1349224/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Treyarch have posted a video explaining the Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 Endgame content, and the short answer is “a lot.”</p>
<p>Once you have finished the main campaign, the entire Avalon map unlocks for 32-player PvE epilogue with new gamplay, and new intel. You can bring teammates into Endgame even if they have not completed the campaign themselves. You will play as either a character from the campaign or an entirely new combatant of your own making with unique abilities.</p>


<p>Black Ops 7 Endgame has four zones of difficulty and the map features landmarks and features from many older COD games, including Black Ops 2, Black Ops 4, and Black Ops 6. As you fight your combat rating will increase and at certain points you will be given the option to pick a new skill.</p>
<p><iframe title="Dev Talk - Co-Op Campaign: Endgame | Call of Duty: Black Ops 7" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/inK3eFlCIu4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Recently the file size for the game has been revealed. The back of the physical box states the game requires 166GB, but a report from PlayStation Game Size, who dig about in the back end of the PSN, reveals that the main game is 96.677 GB, with the co-op campaign adding 15.594 GB and Warzone an additional 19.734 GB. There is no mention of Zombies, which may be part of the main file or an additional download that has yet to be listed.</p>

<p>The Xbox download size has not been revealed, but PC gamers are going to need a minimum of 116GB. By comparison, the rather good Arc Raiders is 16Gb on PlayStation 5.</p>
<p>Check out our <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/05/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-multiplayer-beta-impressions/">Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 multiplayer beta impressions</a> here.</p>
<p>The following game modes will be available in BLOPS 7 at launch:</p>
<ul>
<li>New mode: Overload</li>
<li>Team Deathmatch</li>
<li>Domination</li>
<li>Search and Destroy</li>
<li>Kill Confirmed</li>
<li>Free-for-All</li>
<li>Hardpoint</li>
<li>Kill Order</li>
<li>Control</li>
<li>Face Off Moshpit</li>
<li>New Mode: Skirmish</li>
<li>Gunfight</li>
<li>Face Off Domination</li>
<li>Face Off Team Deathmatch</li>
<li>Face Off Kill Order</li>
<li>Face Off Kill Confirmed</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=inK3eFlCIu4">YouTube</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/10/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-endgame-revealed/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>