<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 11:20:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monaco 2 pilfers an April release date for PC, PS5 and Xbox]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/18/monaco-2-pilfers-an-april-release-date-for-pc-ps5-and-xbox/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monaco-2-pilfers-an-april-release-date-for-pc-ps5-and-xbox.1138329/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/18/monaco-2-pilfers-an-april-release-date-for-pc-ps5-and-xbox/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Pocketwatch Games and publisher Humble Games have announced that their cooperative heisting sequel <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/monaco-2">Monaco 2</a> will release on 10th April for PC, PS5 and Xbox Series X|S.</p>
<p><iframe title="Monaco 2- Release Date Announcement Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rXsfJzrKRIc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Monaco 2 invites you to play with heisting teams of up to four players – you can, of course, tackle missions solo as well – and picking from eight playable characters. You can switch mid-run if the obstacles before you don’t meet your character’s skill set, but you can preview a mission’s layout with the Blueprint Mode before you set foor in a stage.</p>
<p>Where the original Monaco was a linear adventure, in which you assembled a crew of misfits to pull off an audacious series of heists and capers, the sequel is taking a different tack. While there is a structured campaign, this is going down the path of a more freeform heist simulator, testing you and your co-op buddies through procedurally generated levels that have been cooked up by an AI mastermind.</p>
<p>After the minimalist top-down shenanigans of the original, Monaco 2 is much more fleshed out visually with an isometric view into 3D worlds and a painterly art style. It looks rather lovely.</p>

<p>A demo of Monaco 2 was released back in February for Steam Next Fest. The demo features around 2 hours of missions that present their own unique challenges, picking from the line up of five of the thieves from the full game. The demo also featured a mode called “Unreliable Narrator”, which scrambles up the missions in interesting ways.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>