<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 12:55:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bithell Games lays off “majority of full time staff”]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/11/bithell-games-lays-off-majority-of-full-time-staff/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bithell-games-lays-off-%E2%80%9Cmajority-of-full-time-staff%E2%80%9D.1266987/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Tron Catalyst developer Bithell Games has been unable to secure funding for a new project and has laid off the “majority of full time staff”. Mike Bithell took to<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/mikebithell.bsky.social/post/3lvvmqk6r7c2b"> Bluesky</a> to explain the situation and while it’s awful that people have to lose their jobs, at least this boss cares.</p>
<p>“Sad news today, Bithell Games, having been unable to secure a new larger scale project, is reducing in size. This means that eleven jobs are being made redundant. This constitutes the majority of our full-time staff.&nbsp; This constitutes the majority of our full time staff,” reads the post.</p>


<p>“It became clear leading up to the release of our most recent game that we were not immune to the challenges faced by many game development teams seeking funding partners in 2024 and 2025. We’ve fortunately been able to communicate these challenges ahead of time, and work with affected staff to ease departures as much as possible via severance packages.”</p>
<p>“Bithell Games was always defined and elevated by our people. Today we are less.”</p>
<p>The layoffs will not affect any existing self-published games and these will continue to receive support.</p>

<p>We have always been fans of Bithell; I recall chatting with him just as his breakout hit, Thomas Was Alone, was released on PS Vita. Since then he has gone from strength to strength, moving from indie titles like Volume to games based on massive franchises like <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2019/10/08/john-wick-hex-review/">John Wick</a> and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/19/tron-catalyst-review/">Tron.</a> He has also has talked to us <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2019/10/08/interview-mike-bithell-on-distilling-the-action-of-john-wick-hex/">numerous tim</a>es, and also came to chat on the much missed <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2015/12/29/podcast-the-year-according-to-mike-bithell/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TSA Podcast</a>.</p>
<p>We wish the laid-off staff and those remaining at Bithell Games all the best.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/mikebithell.bsky.social/post/3lvvmqk6r7c2b" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bluesky</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/11/bithell-games-lays-off-majority-of-full-time-staff/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>