<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 09:41:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40,000: Darktide adds the brutal Arbites class this June]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/23/warhammer-40000-darktide-adds-the-brutal-arbites-class-this-june/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40-000-darktide-adds-the-brutal-arbites-class-this-june.1197204/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/23/warhammer-40000-darktide-adds-the-brutal-arbites-class-this-june/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>It’s been a great week if you’re a fan of the Warhammer 40,000 universe and its digital interpretations, with the yearly Skulls event dropping a load of Games Workshop-related information on us. You’ve got to love the return of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/22/warhammer-40000-dawn-of-war-and-space-marine-are-getting-fresh-remasters/">Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War</a>, or a <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/22/warhammer-40000-dawn-of-war-and-space-marine-are-getting-fresh-remasters/">remaster of the original Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine</a>, but <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2022/12/19/warhammer-40000-darktide-review/">Warhammer 40,000: Darktide</a> players haven’t been left out in the cold, with the announcement of the all-new Arbites class joining the roster next month on the 23rd of June.</p>
<p><iframe title="Warhammer 40,000: Darktide - Arbites Class Reveal | Cinematic Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rZ176VVTJZo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>It’s fair to say that the Arbites are not messing around. They’re the brutal law enforcers of the Imperium – think Judge Dredd, with fewer hangups – and not only do they get to handle some tasty weaponry, they also have a dog. It’s not one you’re going to want to pet mind you, at least not if you want to keep your arm, as this cybernetic pooch is trained to chasedown and maim the Emperor’s enemies without hesitation. The CG trailer showcases that in visceral fashion, and, frankly, I can’t wait to try the new class out.</p>
<p>Originally launching in 2022 for Xbox and PC, before arriving on PS5 last year, Darktide is a multiplayer-focussed co-op shooter, where you’re tasked with bringing the Emperor’s light to the decidedly dark and dismal Hive City of Tertium. It’s an absolute blast, with action reminiscent of classic co-op shooters like Left 4 Dead, all set against the compelling backdrop of the grim Warhammer 40,000 universe.</p>
<p>We awarded the original version an excellent 8/10, saying, “Darktide is an absolute blast. Its heavyweight blend of melee and gunplay ensure that the flow of frantic runs into the hive city just keep on coming.”</p>

<p>The Arbites Class will arrive across PC, PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series consoles on the 23rd of June, priced at $11.99 / €11.99. Stay tuned to TSA for more as we have it.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[XYZ Tear Them Down takes cyberpunk traversal to school]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/23/xyz-tear-them-down-takes-cyberpunk-traversal-to-school/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xyz-tear-them-down-takes-cyberpunk-traversal-to-school.1197183/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/23/xyz-tear-them-down-takes-cyberpunk-traversal-to-school/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>You can feel the adrenalin rush of XYZ Tear Them Down almost immediately. This first-person, low-poly cyberpunk title gives you the ability to alter gravity while handing you an energy sword. While that already sounds like everything you could possibly need, in action this is a fast, visceral slice of futurism that keeps you on the move, and constantly on the edge of your gaming chair.</p>
<p>We were able to go hands on with the game at Digital Dragons in Krakow, where, incidentally, it came second in the show’s indie game awards. That’s immediately a glowing recommendation from the Polish game industry, and one that, based on our time with it, is thoroughly well deserved.</p>
<p><iframe title="XYZ - DEMO OUT NOW TRAILER" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MiHty-eH_CY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>XYZ is fast. The movement here is sublime, and you can race through levels at lightspeed if you have the reactions and chops to do so. Specific surfaces allow you to change the gravity, making the wall the floor and vice versa, and once you’ve got the hang of it, this is a game that flows.</p>
<p>These sections are what the team term as ‘running’ sections, distinct from the second type which is ‘arena’. Here you get to put that energy sword to use, swinging it with abandon into the metallic bodies of the robot drones that stand in your way.</p>

<p>You can also bounce their projectiles back at them with a well-timed swing, though you have to also aim it with your cursor which takes a little more practice to perfect.</p>

<p>Each arena zone has a large door with the remaining number of enemies to dispatch emblazoned on it, and so you have to search around, utilising the gravity changing mechanic to find where they are in the level. It’s clever stuff, and even here, in its unfinished state, the game has a distinct vision and purpose.</p>
<p>It looks great too. I’d like to see more interactivity with your environment – smashing vases is surely the nunber one feature to put into your game – but the low-poly look works incredibly well here, providing a look that’s basically timeless.</p>

<p>Clearly influenced by games like Ultrakill, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2022/06/22/neon-white-review/">Neon White</a> and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2020/10/26/ghostrunner-review-pc/">Ghostrunner</a>, speed and movement lie at the heart of XYZ. The team have absolutely nailed that aspect from the off.</p>
<p>What’s most impressive is that, not only is this their debut title, but they’ve also only just graduated from high school, which is astonishing. I can’t wait to see the finished article, and, on the strength of XYZ – Tear It Down this is a group of developers to keep an eye on.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>