<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:29:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Season 2 delayed to February, but there’s a bonus bit of Season 1 to fill the gap]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/14/battlefield-6-season-2-delayed-to-february-but-theres-a-bonus-bit-of-season-1-to-fill-the-gap/</link>
            <guid>1405690</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Season 2 of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/battlefield-6">Battlefield 6</a> has been delayed until February, Battlefield Studios has announced, with an extension to Season 1 coming to fill the extra month wait.</p>
<p>Season 2 will now start on 17th February, with Season 1’s battle pass extended up until that point, and with new weekly challenges and a Frostfire Bonus Path of content being added on 27th January.</p>
<p><iframe title="Battlefield 6 Season 2 Teaser" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ylKfsTB3uKM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>The team writes, “During our ongoing development, we’ve continued to review community feedback and, in order to keep our promise, determined that our best path forward is to extend Season 1 and give ourselves extra time to further polish and refine Season 2.”</p>
<p>So what’s coming to fill out Season 1? Well, an update is set to land on 20th January with fixes and stability improvements, and this will be followed on 27th January by the Frostfire Bonus Path of battle pass. This includes a weapon package, soldier skin XP Boosts and more for those with the premium Battle Pass, while a free track will include Hardware XP Boost, vehicle skin, player card customisation, and the like.</p>

<p>The Bonus Path will work alongside and not instead of the Season 1 Battle Pass, so you still have more time to round off any more unlock tiers you need or want. However, all Bonus Path Points are earned through Weekly Challenges, and not all Weekly Challenges reward those points. Expect people to get annoyed by this.</p>
<p>A little further away, a Valentine’s Day event is coming with duos, there’s more daily login rewards and double XP weekends to flesh everything out.</p>
<p>This has all been rather disappointing for the community on Reddit, with a fairly doom-laden outlook on how much content has been added to the game so far. There’s been comparisons to the map output of Battlefield 4’s paid DLC, memes about map design, critiques of cosmetics and general concern for the future of the game. EA struck a huge and symbolic victory over Call of Duty with Battlefield 6, but they need to keep up the game’s support in order to cement their status as a true rival and counterpart.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/Battlefield/comments/1qbv6tf/battlefield_6_and_redsec_season_1_january_update/">Reddit</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/14/battlefield-6-season-2-delayed-to-february-but-theres-a-bonus-bit-of-season-1-to-fill-the-gap/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DuneCrawl Review – A fascinating but flawed adventure]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/14/dunecrawl-review-a-fascinating-but-flawed-adventure/</link>
            <guid>1405687</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="gp-content-wrapper">

	<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

		<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope="" content="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/14/dunecrawl-review-a-fascinating-but-flawed-adventure/">
		<meta itemprop="headline" content="DuneCrawl Review – A fascinating but flawed adventure">			
		
		<meta itemprop="author" content="Jason Coles">			
		<meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2026-01-14">
		<meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2026-01-14">
		
		
			
		
								
		
			

																		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>There’s a game for the original DS called Dragon Quest Heroes: Rocket Slime. In it, you play as a slime and have to load up your cool tower with all sorts of powerful ammunition to beat other towers. It’s one of those games that stands out in my memory as not only being a lot of fun, but also a concept I don’t feel like has been revisited since. DuneCrawl has a couple of mechanics that feel in the same spirit, and while the whole package is a bit uneven, that did put a smile on my face.</p>
<p><iframe title="DuneCrawl - Launch Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9Im0Hx3iLVE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>DuneCrawl is an open-world adventure game where you get to sit on top of a big old crab and fight other big crabs using cannons, yourself, and anything else you find. That’s only part of it though; it’s really more of a game where you explore dungeon-like areas to rescue people, find treasures, and progress the story. I wish the game was more weighted towards the cool crab fights, but alas, here we are.</p>



<p>Combat on the crab is loading up the cannons, firing, and using a shield to bounce things back. You can load yourself or another player in the cannon for cool boarding shenanigans though, and that’s wonderfully silly in a Sea of Thieves kind of way.</p>

<p>Non-crab combat is fairly standard hack and slash stuff. You get a bunch of weapons you can cycle through for different effects, which weirdly includes health potions, and have to try and hit stuff before stuff hits you. It’s fine, really, and some of the weapons are pretty cool, but it’s not a standout example of this genre.</p>
<p>The world is nice though. I enjoyed exploring things both on and off-crab, and there’s a solid sense of humour running through a lot of the quests that’ll help keep you entertained. The idea of this world that has issues with pottery and worships crabs is just kind of fun, and it helps make it feel genuinely unique very early on. I just wish the gameplay felt a little bit more special as well. It all just feels okay for the most part, and I want more than that from my games.</p>

<p>DuneCrawl is at its best with friends, which is really the saving grace here. As is so often the case, running around all of this stuff with a friend or two really elevates everything and ends up being a genuinely entertaining time. After all, where else can you load a friend into a cannon and then fire them off into the distance just for fun? That’s the kind of experience that we’re all after, and sure, it can be used to actually play the game as intended, but it’s nice to mess around with too.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div>

		
				
	<div id="gp-summary">
		<p>Summary</p><p>
		DuneCrawl is an interesting game that blends together giant crab combat, dungeoneering and multiplayer shenanigans. It's fun enough, but I really wish it did a little bit more with the more unusual aspects of its game design.&nbsp;	</p></div>
		

	<div id="gp-review-results">

									<div id="gp-good-points">
						<p>Good</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>A lot of interesting concepts</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Co-op experience is a lot of fun</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
				
									<div id="gp-bad-points">
						<p>Bad</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Combat is a little underwhelming</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Doesn't do enough with its best ideas</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
							
			</div>

					
	
						
			
			

			
					
		
					
 
	
	
				
	</article>

</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/14/dunecrawl-review-a-fascinating-but-flawed-adventure/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>