<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 13:19:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wildgate Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/28/wildgate-review-ps5-xbox-pc/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wildgate-review.1254813/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>It’s a scary time to launch a new multiplayer video game. The live service bubble has well and truly burst, with publishers collectively sinking hundreds of millions into promising online titles, only to pull the plug just months later. As we’ve seen with games like <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/steel-hunters">Steel Hunters</a>, <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/splitgate-2">Splitgate 2</a>, and <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/concord">Concord</a>, quality isn’t the issue, yet there’s a real struggle to capture and hold the attention of transient multiplayer gamers. <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/wildgate">Wildgate</a> doesn’t have the same pull as a <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/call-of-duty">Call of Duty</a> or <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/fortnite">Fortnite</a>, but it has enough fun ideas working in tandem to make for one of the most interesting live service hits of 2025.</p>
<p><iframe title="Wildgate | Launch Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lDcX7Kf_gTg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>There’s a lot going on in Wildgate and the tutorial doesn’t do a particularly great job of explaining what the various moving parts are, or their strategic importance. At its most basic, Wildgate can be described as a sci-fi extraction shooter where five spaceship crews (of up to four players) attempt to locate precious artefacts, surviving long enough for a warpgate to appear so they can escape with their hard-earned booty.</p>
<p>Players must divide their attention between chasing loot, gathering resources, and manning their ship, which is essentially a mobile base of operations. Equipped with turrets, probes, shields, and upgrade slots, those opening minutes of a match are usually spent plumbing nearby ruins and stations for gear to outfit your ship.</p>
<p>These map landmarks each have objectives to complete before you can access their loot, typically requiring the solving of an environmental puzzle or gunning down AI patrols. They’re basically mini-dungeons with higher difficulty zones holding Wildgate’s rarest gear that can then be ferried back to your ship, whether that’s a Sniper Cannon turret upgrade or a module that passively replenishes ammunition.</p>


<p>The biggest threat is other player-controlled ships with almost all of the matches we played ending in head-to-head dogfights. Getting ambushed while your shields are down can result in a swift elimination though there are other ways of bringing down enemy crews. Boarding other ships is risky, but if you catch rival players unaware you can gun them down (forcing a respawn), plant bombs, set fires, and become an all-round nuisance. Clever pilots can also outrun and outmanoeuvre other ships, potentially drawing them into hazards such as firestorms and cosmic rifts.</p>
<p>As you can tell, there are a lot of plates that need to be kept spinning: this isn’t your straightforward Team Deathmatch or Capture the Flag. Learning the ropes will take at least a dozen or so rounds before you turn your attention to loadout optimisation and mastering the game’s different heroes with more options becoming available as you progress via a quasi battle pass system.</p>
<p>As you earn experience points in Wildgate, they’ll be funneled into whatever “Adventure” you currently have active, filling its progress bar and unlocking rewards such as new characters, ships, guns, and equipment. Making your way along this track can feel like a slog at first, though it’s clearly developer Dreamhaven’s intention not to give players all of Wildgate’s tools from the get go while steering them towards completing daily objectives.</p>

<p>Speaking of Dreamhaven – whose employees consist of ex-<a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/blizzard">Blizzard</a> staff – there’s definitely some continuity when it comes to vibrant, comic-style visuals, some of Wildgate’s Prospectors passing for upcoming Overwatch heroes. There’s a slickness to the game’s UI too, giving crews a quick oversight of how their ship is holding up while presenting unobtrusive tooltips exactly where needed. While there isn’t a great deal of worldbuilding or storytelling happening front and centre, this actually works in the game’s favour, allowing players to grow a natural attachment to the setting and its characters through gameplay, those moments of emergent gameplay weaving its own narrative tapestry.</p>
<p>From our experience, that narrative rarely involves one of Wildgate’s main focuses: Artefacts. Matches will begin to repeat in terms of flow as crews clear a handful of PvE zones before hunting rival ships, preferring quick and decisive battles rather than slowly scouring the stars for a chance to loot an Artefact, then waiting for a Wildgate to finally open before escaping. Making Artefacts easier to find or opening extraction points earlier into a match may help, though it’s a delicate balancing act.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/28/wildgate-review-ps5-xbox-pc/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Once Upon a Puppet Review – Pulling at your heart strings]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/28/once-upon-a-puppet-review-pulling-at-your-heart-strings/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/once-upon-a-puppet-review-%E2%80%93-pulling-at-your-heart-strings.1254804/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="gp-content-wrapper">

	<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

		<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope="" content="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/28/once-upon-a-puppet-review-pulling-at-your-heart-strings/">
		<meta itemprop="headline" content="Once Upon a Puppet Review – Pulling at your heart strings">			
		
		<meta itemprop="author" content="Steve C">			
		<meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2025-07-28">
		<meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2025-07-28">
		
		
			
		
								
		
			

																		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>The first thing to hit you about Once Upon a Puppet is that it is a visually striking game, taking the 2.5D stylings of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/02/09/little-nightmares-2-review/">Little Nightmares</a> and adding a gorgeous wooden aesthetic on top. What truly surprised me, though, was the emotionally touching story that it told. Issues of grief, regret, and reconciliation are played out through a metaphorical narrative of puppets and adventure.</p>
<p><iframe title="Once Upon A Puppet | Available now on Switch!" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eMh8OAz5TwQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The world of Once Upon a Puppet is strictly divided into two areas, the regular areas and the Understage to which those out of favour with the King are banished. As the game begins we discover that the current King is throwing everything that annoys him into the Understage, and while he initially appears to be a tyrant abusing his power, we come to discover the tragic reason for this as the story progresses. We immediately face this through Nieve, a Stagehand (literally just a sentient glove) who has disappointed the King with their latest design. Once thrown into the Understage, Nieve becomes magically entwined with the puppet Drev, and they have to set out on an adventure to uncover the mystery that has brought them together.</p>


<p>The dual character protagonist is an interesting approach and enables some effective mechanical complexities. You control Drev with the left stick, whilst Nieve is mapped to the right. Most of the time you can just navigate the world as Drev, but there are interactions and puzzles that involved both characters to be controlled. At first you have only very basic controls and must find magical spools to expand your abilities so that by the end you’ll be double jumping, gliding, wielding a bow, and more. All of these abilities are tested through complex environmental puzzles which form the main body of the gameplay.</p>


<p>The theatrical setting for the game is not just a backdrop. Drev is an actor puppet and can be dressed as different characters to access new areas – although Nieve needs to sew them up first. While some of these are purely cosmetic, others link into specific performance memories and affect dialogue with NPCs. The effect is more linear than this sounds, though, as there are no dialogue choices to uncover. Instead there is a well-written and crafted narrative that provides the emotional drive for the game.</p>
<p>Once Upon a Puppet features no real combat, but isn’t a game without peril or danger. Some intricate platforming challenges abound as well as avoiding the evil creatures and lethal pools of black goo (identified as stage-fright) that litter the corrupted Understage. The former must be avoided through stealth for the most part (although late in the game you obtain a power that is effective against them) whilst stage-fright is destroyed by light.</p>

<p>Some of the most memorable setpieces in the game involve rearranging stage sets to recover one of the King’s lost memories. These environmental puzzles generally involve all of the various skills and are particularly rewarding. Successfully completing one of these leads to Drev taking the spotlight and revealing a key aspect of the game’s deeper narrative. There is a mystery running through the game that is fundamental to the narrative that I won’t spoil here but I did guess it fairly early on. That being said, the eventual reveal was emotionally effective still and led to a satisfying conclusion.</p>
<p>I played through on a Switch 2 and it suited the handheld really well, but there was an annoying bug late on where dying to a particularly tight timing puzzle broke the camera and necessitated a restart. This solved the checkpointing but I reloaded the level more than once before realising that closing the game and reloading it was the solution. This was the only real moment of frustration though.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div>

		
				
	<div id="gp-summary">
		<p>Summary</p><p>
		I very much enjoyed the majority of my time with Once Upon a Puppet, and while it was not entirely without issues, it's a nice fusion of search adventuring and the linearity of Little Nightmares. This one is well worth a look for platforming fans.	</p></div>
		

	<div id="gp-review-results">
						<p>Good</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Good range of abilities</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Well designed puzzles</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Eye-catching aesthetic</li>
													</ul>
					</div>

					
	
						
			
			

			
					
		
					
 
	
	
				
	</article>

</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/28/once-upon-a-puppet-review-pulling-at-your-heart-strings/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>