<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 14:05:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stygian: Outer Gods looks like it’ll have that special HP (Lovecraft) sauce]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/22/stygian-outer-gods-looks-like-itll-have-that-special-hp-lovecraft-sauce/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/stygian-outer-gods-looks-like-it%E2%80%99ll-have-that-special-hp-lovecraft-sauce.1116174/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/22/stygian-outer-gods-looks-like-itll-have-that-special-hp-lovecraft-sauce/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>2019’s Stygian: Reign of the Old Gods was a promising CRPG that featured some neat madness mechanics and a tone and atmosphere that perfectly suited its Lovecraftian influences. It did, however, suffer from some difficulty spikes and a few terrible bugs that have never been fixed. I was therefore surprised to see another game in the series appear, especially given that it comes from a completely different developer and takes on an entirely new gameplay style and perspective. The old-school top down approach has been replaced in Stygian: Outer Gods by a first-person view that provides a more immersive and, dare I say, modern experience.</p>
<p><iframe title="Stygian: Outer Gods | Demo Coming to Steam Next Fest" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/k5ex7hUEPK8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>My time with the demo – which will be available as part of Steam Next Fest from Monday 24th February – began with a mysterious vision in a strange otherworldly environment before reverting to the familiar setting of an office stacked with esoteric items. This is textbook Lovecraft and reminded me of the likes of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2018/10/31/call-of-cthulhu-review-maddening/">Call of Cthulhu</a> and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2019/06/27/the-sinking-city-review/">The Sinking City</a>. Similar to those titles you soon find yourself stranded in a coastal town with a mystery to solve and dangers to overcome.</p>


<p>Before you set out on your investigation, however, you can customise your character by interacting with the mirror in your bathroom. A series of questions are posed and your answers affect various character stats, from your occult knowledge to your lockpicking skills. The latter proved a little unhelpful in my playthrough as every attempt to pick a lock failed, despite that being my chosen skill. Hopefully these aspects will be refined for the final build although I quite liked how the effects of the dialogue choices weren’t spelled out for you.</p>


<p>The atmosphere of Stygian: Outer Gods is on point with derelict buildings and a stark coastline setting the scene and items that are clearly visible for the most part. There wasn’t a lot of variety in enemy design in this, but this isn’t surprising for what amounts to the game’s prologue. Audio design is also good and the otherworldly noises disturb and unsettle you.</p>
<p>The section contained in this build featured a mixture of stealth and combat, but it is clear that the final game is not going to be all-out action. Even single enemies will quickly kill you if you try and take them on toe to toe. Sneaking around them or using thrown bottles to distract them is far more effective, whilst manipulating the scenery is important to survive any unavoidable fights. Fortunately the AI is pretty easy to abuse, with knee high fences coming in clutch to protect you from damage. The demo features a few different melee weapons, with firearms being seen in preview footage of later areas.</p>

<p>Exploring the town is made necessary as you must find three panels for a locked gate in order to gain access a large mansion which seems to be the source of the mystery. This is a standard survival horror puzzle but feel somewhat out of place here given the game’s adoption of some immersive sim elements. Whilst exploring the town you’ll be blocked by a series of fences, but stacking boxes against them can create steps that allow you to bypass them. I was never entirely sure how intentional these moments were, although more traditional area blocking is achieved through boards that you can only break once you find an axe. The question remains, why couldn’t I just prop some boxes up against the gate and climb over it?</p>
<p>That kind of interior logic breaking aside, Stygian: Outer Gods is a promising stealth horror title that showed enough in the demo to both pique my interest and leave me wondering what other gameplay elements it’ll introduce. If Lovecraftian horrors are your bag of tentacles then make sure to wishlist this particular cosmic horror ready for its release – first with PC early access this year, and a full release in 2026.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Something for the Weekend – 22/02/25]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/22/something-for-the-weekend-22-02-25/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/something-for-the-weekend-%E2%80%93-22-02-25.1116150/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/22/something-for-the-weekend-22-02-25/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Even though it’s the shortest month, it’s been a little surprising just how quickly it feels like February has raced by. We’re just a few short days away from the release of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a>, and I know that’s one that series fans have been salivating over for a long time – and not just for the in-game chef’s creations!</p>
<p>But MHW is still in the future, what about in the here and now? Well, the week’s two biggest releases (full releases, not pre-order shenanigans releases) are the excellent <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/13/avowed-review/">Avowed</a> and Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii. Are you playing either of these this weekend?</p>
<p><span>In the News This Week</span></p>
<p>Steam Next Fest was the big and interesting thing this week, flooding the airwaves with announcements and demos. Let’s see what’s been happening:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/20/dune-awakening-launches-in-may-for-pc-create-your-character-benchmark-now/">Dune: Awakening launches in May for PC – create your character &amp; benchmark now</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/19/netease-cuts-marvel-rivals-seattle-based-devs-to-optimize-development-in-china/">NetEase cuts Marvel Rivals’ Seattle-based devs to “optimize development” in China</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/20/space-marine-2-devs-saber-and-hasbro-partner-for-a-tentpole-aaa-game/">Space Marine 2 devs Saber and Hasbro partner for a “tentpole” AAA game</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/21/play-the-gothic-1-remake-demo-with-steam-next-fest/">Play the Gothic 1 Remake demo with Steam Next Fest</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/17/ubisoft-announce-rainbow-six-siege-x-with-a-full-reveal-coming-in-march/">Ubisoft announce Rainbow Six Siege X with a full reveal coming in March</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/21/cosy-lotr-life-sim-tales-of-the-shire-delayed-again-to-july/">Cosy LOTR life sim Tales of the Shire delayed again to July</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/21/among-us-3d-is-among-us-vr-without-the-vr-steam-next-fest-demo-incoming/">Among Us 3D is Among Us VR without the VR – Steam Next Fest demo incoming</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/19/monster-train-2-chugs-to-release-this-year-with-a-debut-demo-playable-today/">Monster Train 2 chugs to release this year, with a debut demo playable today</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/20/gta-v-on-pc-gets-the-ps5-xsxs-upgrade-for-free-in-march/">GTA V on PC gets the PS5 &amp; XSX|S upgrade for free in March</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/18/nintendo-ditches-gold-points-reward-scheme-ahead-of-switch-2-launch/">Nintendo ditches Gold Points reward scheme ahead of Switch 2 launch</a></strong></li>
</ul>
<p><span>Games in Review &amp; Featured Articles</span></p>

<p>We don’t have our Like A Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii review in the can just yet – look for that next week, hopefully – but we’ve had some fun with these games:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/17/citizen-sleeper-2-starward-vector-review/"><strong>Citizen Sleeper 2: Starward Vector</strong></a> – PS5, XSX|S, NSW, <strong>PC</strong> – 8/10</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/18/stories-from-sol-the-gun-dog-review/"><strong>Stories from Sol: The Gun-Dog</strong></a> – PS5, PS4, NSW, <strong>PC</strong> – 7/10</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/18/dog-man-impawsible-mission-review/"><strong>Dog Man: Impawsible Mission</strong></a> – <strong>PS5</strong>, XSX|S, NSW, PC – 7/10</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/20/warriors-abyss-review-ps5-xbox-steam/"><strong>Warriors: Abyss</strong></a> – <strong>PS5</strong>, XSX|S, PS4, XBO, NSW, PC – 6/10</li>
</ul>
<p>And we got pad in hand for a controller review:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/19/scuf-valor-pro-controller-review/"><strong>SCUF Valor Pro</strong></a> – XSX|S, XBO, PC – 9/10</li>
</ul>
<p>We had the film projector out for a video game documentary with <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/21/grand-theft-hamlet-comes-to-mubi-theres-something-rotten-in-the-city-of-vinewood/"><strong>Grand Theft Hamlet</strong></a>, chronicling the 2021 efforts to put on a production of Hamlet within GTA Online – you can watch this now on MUBI, by the way.</p>
<p>Over in the preview room, we checked out the upcoming exo-suit extraction game <strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/17/exoborne-preview-an-extraction-shooter-action-that-could-go-down-a-storm/">Exoborne</a></strong>, which is all about seismic weather events mixing up the map. Dom and I also teamed up for the MudRunner spin-off <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/19/roadcraft-preview-where-were-going-we-need-to-build-roads/"><strong>RoadCraft</strong></a>, which is all about what happens after seismic weather events have rolled through the world.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Dom checked out <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/19/xenoblade-chronicles-x-definitive-edition-preview-the-last-great-wii-u-switch-port/"><strong>Xenoblade Chronicles X on Nintendo Switch</strong></a>, and had a hands on look at the next project from PlayerUnknown, the procedural survival experience that is <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/20/prologue-go-wayback-playerunknowns-glimpse-of-a-digital-future-that-teaches-us-to-survive-in-the-present/"><strong>Prologue: Go Wayback!</strong></a></p>
<p>Rounding out the week,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/21/what-we-played-roadcraft-pirate-yakuza-in-hawaii-avowed/"><strong>What We Played</strong></a> featured RoadCraft, Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii, and Avowed.</p>
<h2>Trailer Park</h2>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/20/relic-reveals-earth-vs-mars-advance-wars-meets-mars-attacks/">Relic reveals Earth vs Mars – Advance Wars meets Mars Attacks!</a></strong></p>
<p><iframe title="Earth vs Mars - Announce Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Dh0Jabqmb90?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/21/shotgun-cop-man-sees-the-my-friend-pedro-creator-blast-their-way-to-hell/">Shotgun Cop Man sees My Friend Pedro creator blast their way to Hell</a></strong></p>
<p><iframe title="ARREST SATAN in SHOTGUN COP MAN | From the Creator of My Friend Pedro" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cWSNEN2mZH8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><strong>Hades 2 – The Warsong Update is now live</strong></p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Hades II - The Warsong Update Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yrpGYTlCjNQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><strong>Dive into Solasta 2 with the Steam Next Fest demo</strong></p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Solasta II - Demo Release Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ejBj_VijIVQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<h2>Your Achievements</h2>
<p>What have you been playing this week? Well…</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Andrewww</strong> has been playing a bunch of backlog games and titles that were soon to leave the PS Plus catalogue. That included The Outer Worlds, though this was too old fashioned, and he started Life Is Strange 2. He also got The Shapeshifting Detective, which didn’t speak to him, and he played Call of the Sea with his daughter, but got a little stuck on a riddle.</li>
</ul>
<p>That’s the round up for this week. Hope you have a great weekend ahead!</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>