<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 17:40:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony, Bad Robot Games & the designer of Left 4 Dead are making a new co-op shooter]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/04/sony-bad-robot-games-the-designer-of-left-4-dead-are-making-a-new-co-op-shooter/</link>
            <guid>1373086</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Sony Interactive Entertainment and Bad Robot Games have announced a partnership to create a new game together. SIE will publish Bad Robot’s first internal game project, which is to be a four-player cooperative shooter directed by <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/left-4-dead">Left 4 Dead</a> designer Mike Booth. The game is in development for <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/playstation-5">PS5</a> and PC.</p>
<p>“Partnering with Sony Interactive Entertainment allows us to bring our new IP to life, with an expansive vision for this new universe,” said Anna Sweet, CEO of Bad Robot Games. “With the support of PlayStation, we hope to deliver a bold, innovative experience that is truly special for players. I could not be more excited that Mike Booth is at the creative helm, crafting a cooperative adventure that will lead to unforgettable moments with friends.”</p>


<p>Booth has been at Bad Robot Games since December 2020, and has been Chief Creative Officer since 2022, managing the company’s in-house game developments. Booth is obviously most famous for his work in creating Left 4 Dead, at Turtle Rock Studios which he had founded in 2002. He stayed with Valve for a couple years after Turtle Rock was shut down and refounded separately, but left in 2012, joined Blizzard for a time, worked on social VR projects with Facebook in the late 2010s, and eventually landed with Bad Robot in 2020.</p>
<p>Which is to say that, while he was there for the beginning of Left 4 Dead and the co-op shooter genre, he’s not been involved with later attempts at this and adjacent genres – Turtle Rock went on to create Evolve and Back 4 Blood, but neither saw the same level of success and stature as Left 4 Dead. Can Booth, who created the AI Director that managed the dynamic ebb and flow of zombie attacks and monsters through the game, come up with a fresh perspective and hook to revolutionise the co-op shooter all over again?</p>

<p>We’ll have to wait and see.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://sonyinteractive.com/en/press-releases/2025/sie-partners-with-bad-robot-games/">Sony</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/04/sony-bad-robot-games-the-designer-of-left-4-dead-are-making-a-new-co-op-shooter/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>