<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 19:07:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Double Fine’s new living lighthouse game is Keeper]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/08/double-fines-new-living-lighthouse-game-is-keeper/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/double-fine%E2%80%99s-new-living-lighthouse-game-is-keeper.1212441/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/08/double-fines-new-living-lighthouse-game-is-keeper/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Coming from Lee Petty and Double Fine, Keeper is a wonderful looking narrative adventure where you play as a lighthouse come to life.</p>
<p><iframe title="Keeper - Official Announce Trailer | Xbox Games Showcase 2025" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AWAwVgTsFfk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>“Keeper is a story told without words”, Double Fine writes in the trailer blurb, “in which a long-forgotten lighthouse is awakened and, joined by a spirited seabird, embarks upon a heartening tale of unlikely companionship and an unexpected journey into realms beyond understanding.”</p>
<p>It honestly looks delightful with all the charm that you would expect from Double Fine. The Lighthouse reassembles itself after falling over in a storm, forming legs for itself and then scrambling crab-like across the land. The rickety structure is full of personality, and can look and shine light from its top. It also makes friends with a seabird who wants to come along for the ride.</p>
<p>Keeper is in development for Xbox Series X|S, PC and will on Xbox Game Pass on day one, the game launching on 17th October.</p>

<p>This is the first game from Double Fine since Psychonauts 2, which I handed <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/08/23/psychonauts-2-review/">a fantastic 9/10 back in 2021</a>. Is said, “A decade and a half on from the original, Psychonauts 2 is a worthy successor to Double Fine’s cult classic. The platforming and combat gameplay is tighter, the world design is as varied and inventive as ever, and while the story is full of twists, turns and comedic moment, there’s also a wonderful sense of empathy and tenderness throughout. Simply put, Psychonauts 2 has been worth the wait.”</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>