<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 18:43:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Subnautica 2 Voices from Beyond first episode released]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/25/subnautica-2-voices-from-beyond-first-episode-released/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/subnautica-2-voices-from-beyond-first-episode-released.1364560/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>The first episode for Subnautica 2’s tie in audio drama Voices from Beyond is now available to listen to, and this episode is called Don’t Fear. The Voices from Beyond story follows a family from the universe who are settled in a Mongolian settlement, as they work out how to live in a constantly shifting world unaware there is a big threat hurtling towards them.</p>
<p><iframe title="Subnautica 2 | Voices from Beyond - Don’t Fear (Episode #1) ????️" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9On9vY7bJNM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Subnautica 2 Voices from Beyond stars Griffin Puata as the Dad/Mongolian Politician, Hester Lee as Mom/Alterra Engineer, Jessika Van as the Daughter/Singer, Nell Barnes as Baby/Young Daughter, Dan Gordon as Ryley Robinson/Podcast Host, Emily O’Brien as Radio News Host #1 / PSA Announcer / Admiral Rathine Studaber, and Townsend Coleman as Radio News Host #2 / Alterra Advertiser.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/10/subnautica-2-delayed-to-2026-just-a-week-after-krafton-fired-studio-co-founders/">Subnautica 2 early access was delayed to 2026</a>, a few months ago with lots of drama surrounding the studio and the game. Krafton replaced the co-founders and leaders of&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/subnautica-2">Subnautica 2</a> developer Unknown Worlds. Krafton accused studio founders Charlie Cleveland and Max McGuire of effectively abandoning <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/subnautica-2">Subnautica 2’s</a>&nbsp;development to focus on other projects – including&nbsp;<a href="https://www.abyssal.co/nutmeg-mistletoe">an independent movie by Cleveland with a podcast and… uh… AI-generated movie posters</a> – despite repeated requests by Krafton for them to return to work. But in another twist, &nbsp;Jason Schreier suggested that along with the Christmas film, Cleveland was also working on a Subnautica film for Krafton. “In the lawsuit, they argue that Krafton was aware of their roles and that Cleveland was working on a Subnautica film — that Krafton requested.”</p>

<p>All of this has ended up with Charlie Cleveland and Max McGuire suing Krafton, with new allegations that the Krafton CEO used ChatGPT to find ways to avoid paying a £250 million bonus, and also discussed a company takeover in Slack. It will be a little while before we know the final outcome of the court case.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9On9vY7bJNM">Subnautica 2 | Voices from Beyond – Don’t Fear (Episode #1)</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/25/subnautica-2-voices-from-beyond-first-episode-released/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>