<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:34:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gungrave GORE Blood Heat is a “full rebuild” of 2022’s Gungrave GORE]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/25/gungrave-gore-blood-heat-is-a-full-rebuild-of-2022s-gungrave-gore/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gungrave-gore-blood-heat-is-a-%E2%80%9Cfull-rebuild%E2%80%9D-of-2022%E2%80%99s-gungrave-gore.1308303/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Remasters come sooner every generation, it seems. Gungrave GORE Blood Heat has just been announced, a fully rebuilt version of Gungrave GORE.</p>
<p><iframe title="Gungrave GORE Blood Heat – Announce Trailer | Tokyo Game Show 2025" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/U90lcQ3_aHY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Blood Heat brings the game to a new engine – Unreal Engine 5 – with enhanced visual quality and modernised systems as well. Which is odd, because <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2022/12/01/gungrave-gore-review/">Gungrave GORE first launched in 2022</a> and was already on current generation consoles.</p>
<p>But that doesn’t mean the game can’t be improved further. There’s new systems, more refined characters and background visuals, the return of heritage, exclusive new characters and more.</p>
<p>Gungrave GORE Blood Heat is coming to PS5, Xbox Series X|S and PC. Also Game Pass.</p>

<p>Looking all the way back to 2022, we said of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2022/12/01/gungrave-gore-review/">Gungrave GORE,</a> “Gungrave G.O.R.E is a decent game. It’s not the best shooter, but it is often very entertaining if just for the spectacle. It has a few issues, mostly in level design, and the story isn’t particularly memorable, but there’s plenty of fun to be had in chainsawing your enemies with a transforming coffin.”</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/25/gungrave-gore-blood-heat-is-a-full-rebuild-of-2022s-gungrave-gore/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Forza Horizon 6 is heading to Japan in 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/25/forza-horizon-6-is-heading-to-japan-in-2026/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/forza-horizon-6-is-heading-to-japan-in-2026.1308243/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Just ahead of the Xbox Tokyo Game Show event at 11AM UK time, Forza Horizon 6 has leaked, confirming that &nbsp;the next entry in the open world racer is heading to Japan, when it launches in 2026.</p>



<p>The teaser shows a number of license plates from the locations that the series has visited in the past, before panning past some Japanese memorabilia and up to reveal Mount Fuji off in the distance.</p>
<p>The leak came from Forza’s own social media accounts, posting the teaser to Instagram almost 12 hours ago, and it’s seemingly appearing as an advert across social streams. With the cat out of the bag – the neko, if you will – it seems they’ve just left it all live.</p>
<p>No word on platform specifics just yet, but the game is definitely coming to Xbox Series X|S and PC at launch, with Xbox Play Anywhere and availability on Game Pass. Whether it’s day and date for PS5 as well, we won’t have to wait too long to find out, I suspect.</p>



<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/25/forza-horizon-6-is-heading-to-japan-in-2026/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>