<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 23:42:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Heretic + Hexen get the Nightdive remaster treatment, and it’s out now!]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/07/heretic-hexen-get-the-nightdive-remaster-treatment-and-its-out-now/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/heretic-hexen-get-the-nightdive-remaster-treatment-and-it%E2%80%99s-out-now.1265169/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Opening up Quakecon with yet another back catalogue remaster, id Software and Nightdive Studios have announced and released a collection of Heretic + Hexen, which is out now across PlayStation, Xbox, Switch and PC, and available on <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/xbox-game-pass">Game Pass</a></p>
<p><iframe title="Heretic + Hexen Official Launch Trailer (4K) | Now Available" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IheADxVkpI4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Originally developed by Raven Software using a modified Doom engine and released in 1994 and 1995, the games pushed in the direction of RPGs, building in inventory systems, vertical aiming, character classes and more. While Nightdive avoid calling their releases remasters – technically I think they’re being fed into the KEX Engine to gain these new features – it’s still a handy shorthand.</p>
<p>This is an all-encompassing and even an expanded collection, that includes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Heretic: Shadow of the Serpent Riders</li>
<li>Hexen: Beyond Heretic</li>
<li>Hexen: Deathkings of the Dark Citadel</li>
<li>Two all-new episodes created in collaboration between individuals at id Software + Nightdive Studios:
<ul>
<li>Heretic: Faith Renewed</li>
<li>Hexen: Vestiges of Grandeur</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Beyond that, the games have been furnished with support for up to 4K and 120FPS on consoles, widescreen, modern controllers, in-game mod support, online cross-platform and local split-screen. There’s also an enhanced soundtrack from&nbsp;Andrew Hulshult, but you can stick with the originals.</p>

<p>In a great move, existing owners of <em>any</em> of the games will receive a free upgrade to the new combined game, and will still have access their previously owned versions.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://slayersclub.bethesda.net/en-US/article/heretic-hexen-release-notes">Bethesda</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/07/heretic-hexen-get-the-nightdive-remaster-treatment-and-its-out-now/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>