<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 10:11:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RuneScape: Dragonwilds is a new open world survival game in the MMO universe]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/01/runescape-dragonwilds-is-a-new-open-world-survival-game-in-the-mmo-universe/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/runescape-dragonwilds-is-a-new-open-world-survival-game-in-the-mmo-universe.1150698/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/01/runescape-dragonwilds-is-a-new-open-world-survival-game-in-the-mmo-universe/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Exploring the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/runescape">RuneScape</a> universe in a completely new way, Jagex has revealed the co-op open world survival game RuneScape: Dragonwilds. The game is launching into Steam Early Access this spring, with a deep-dive reveal coming on 15th April.</p>
<p>By the way, this was actually announced on 31st March, so it’s definitely not an April Fools.</p>
<p><iframe title="RuneScape: Dragonwilds - Official World Teaser Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ssbPDfS92o4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>RuneScape Dragonwilds will explore some rather familiar territory within games, with open world survival games having been a huge part of the indie gaming scene for quite a few years. Major hits like Valheim, Enshrouded and Grounded have set out the tone for this style of adventure, but Jagex is taking that template and putting a RuneScape twist on things, thematically and with the story that it’s looking to tell.</p>
<p>RuneScape: Dragonwilds will head to the forgotten continent of Ashenfall, where dragons have now awoken. You’ll have to gather, build, craft and skill up in order to survive the lands, uncover some ancient secrets, and look to slay the Dragon Queen.</p>


<p>There’s some light RPG elements mixed with familiar RuneScape vernacular and lore for fans of the long-running MMO. That flavour includes things like using the power of Anima, summoning spectral axes to chop down trees and using nature’s energy to repair armour. The progression system. All of this can be played solo or with parties of up to four players.</p>
<p>Just as familiar to gamers is the game engine that Jagex has chosen to pull this off with. Instead of the rather distant top-down view of traditional RuneScape, the camera’s pulling right in on the characters and with that closeness, Jagex has chosen to adopt Unreal Engine 5.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Introducing RuneScape: Dragonwilds | Q&amp;A With Mod Dutch" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/30mkN1Hw83Q?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>“We’re so excited to finally give players a glimpse at the next entry in the RuneScape franchise today with RuneScape: Dragonwilds,” said Jon Bellamy, Jagex CEO. “RuneScape: Dragonwilds is an entirely new RuneScapeexperience set within the iconic world of Gielinor and is a game which is worthy of wearing the RuneScape name.</p>
<p>“From the very beginning, community feedback has been at the heart of <em>RuneScape: Dragonwilds</em>. We’ve already conducted closed alpha tests with some of our closest community members, and we’ll be listening to player feedback when building the game throughout Early Access. We’ve built an entirely new team filled with industry veterans who are focussed on making sure that <em>RuneScape: Dragonwilds</em>&nbsp; sits naturally within the <em>RuneScape</em>franchise, and a game that is loved by both our biggest <em>RuneScape</em> fans and entirely new players alike.”</p>
<p>RuneScape: Dragonwilds is heading into Early Access this spring, with a full reveal set to come on 15th April at 5PM UK time.</p>
<p><em>Source: press release</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>