<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 09:44:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Lenovo Legion Go S will be the first third party SteamOS handheld]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/08/the-lenovo-legion-go-s-will-be-the-first-third-party-steamos-handheld/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-lenovo-legion-go-s-will-be-the-first-third-party-steamos-handheld.1076817/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/08/the-lenovo-legion-go-s-will-be-the-first-third-party-steamos-handheld/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Valve and Lenovo have announced that they’re bringing <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/steamos">SteamOS</a> to the Lenovo Legion Go S, making it the first officially licensed third party handheld that can be powered by Valve’s gaming-oriented branch of Linux.</p>
<p>The Lenovo Legion Go S will also be available with Windows 11, but there’s a big price advantage if you opt for SteamOS. The Windows edition will have an entry level price of $600, but you can save $100 by going with SteamOS, this edition costing $500 instead. The entry level models will be available from May 2025, though a Windows edition Legion Go S will debut later this month, starting at $730 for that particular configuration.</p>


<p>This is part of a big new push for the handheld PC gaming market by Lenovo. The Legion Go S is a slightly smaller 8″ rendition of the upcoming Legion Go 2, which has an 8.8″ display. The Go S’s 8″ screen is still impressive, with a 1920×1200 resolution and 120Hz refresh rate, this is allied with the AMD Ryzen Z1 Extreme, up to 32GB of LPDDR5X RAM and up to 1TB of SSD storage. All models come with Wi-Fi 6e support, a pair of USB 4 ports and a microSD card slot as well.</p>
<p>This follows through on Valve’s plan to open up SteamOS to third parties once again. The gaming OS originally debuted with Steam Machines back in the day, but its return with <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/steam-deck">Steam Deck</a> has been exclusive to Valve’s own handheld up until this point. Last year they talked about <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/13/24219469/valve-steamos-asus-rog-ally-steady-progress-dual-boot">porting it to the Asus ROG Ally</a>, for example.</p>
<p>The tricky thing for Valve is that, where SteamOS was able to target Steam Deck as a fixed platform, where they were able to leverage specific hardware features for the screen, implement quick suspend / resume and other tweaks, it’s trickier to be a more general OS.</p>

<p>A lot of PC handhelds have common ground to the Steam Deck by using AMD integrated chipsets as their foundation, but everything else will require dedicated support. That can be the display driver to enable VRR and other refresh rate controls, supporting back buttons, different Wi-Fi chipsets, and much more. Still, Valve is committing to providing the same experience to their new and upcoming partners, and many gamers are hoping that they’ll offer SteamOS as a basic download that anyone can use with their game PC – handheld, laptop, or desktop.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://news.lenovo.com/pressroom/press-releases/lenovo-legion-unleashes-next-gen-gaming-power-at-ces-2025/">Lenovo</a>, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/593110/view/529834914570306831">Steam</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Open Beta 2 is coming in February]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/08/monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta-2-is-coming-in-february/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta-2-is-coming-in-february.1076811/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/08/monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta-2-is-coming-in-february/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>It’s a good time to be a Monster Hunter fan, what with the launch of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> coming on 28th February… but what if you want to play sooner? Well, Producer Ryozo Tsujimoto has good news for you, announcing that Monster Hunter Wilds Open Beta 2 is also coming in February!</p>
<p><iframe title="New Year's Greetings 2025 | Monster Hunter Wilds Open Beta Test 2 Announcement" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YXWAYmEQKso?start=12&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Monster Hunter Wilds Open Beta 2 will take place across two weekends, across PS5, Xbox Series X|S and PC, with crossplay enabled.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Weekend 1</strong> – Thursday 6th February 7PM PT through Sunday 9th February 6:59PM PT</li>
<li><strong>Weekend 2</strong> – Thursday 13th February 7PM PT through Sunday 16th February 6:59PM PT</li>
</ul>
<p>That translates to a 3AM start time on Friday mornings in the UK.</p>
<p>Open Beta Test 2 will expand on the first beta test with some additional monsters for you to take on. In addition to the full character creation suite, the story trial and the slay Doshaguma quest, you’ll also be able to hunt Gypceros.</p>

<p>You can carry forward your characters created for the first beta test, and that can also be transferred to the full game, though game progress is not transferring. If you do take part in the beta, you’ll also get a cute little charm for your weapon or Seikret.</p>
<p>The development team does warn that outside of content this will not be a significant shift when compared to the first beta. This includes adjustments to performance, weapon changes, Hitstop, quality of life improvements and more that will only be made for the full game. Capcom detailed the changes being made in a <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/20/monster-hunter-wilds-pre-launch-update-addresses-open-beta-issues/">community update</a> back in December.</p>
<p>We got to go hands on with the game last year, sharing impressions in <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/09/10/monster-hunter-wilds-preview-a-seikret-ride-on-the-wild-side/">our Monster Hunter Wilds preview</a>. Nic said, “Time will tell how Wilds eventually plays out, but I must say — I am more excited than ever to get my hands on the final game. Just like at the Meowscular Chef’s kitchen, this small taste of a gorgeous offering from Capcom has me desperately wanting more.”</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>