<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 22:16:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A new Life Is Strange will be announced next week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/15/a-new-life-is-strange-will-be-announced-next-week/</link>
            <guid>1407481</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Square Enix has set the date and time for the next <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/life-is-strange">Life is Strange</a> game reveal. Tune in next week on Tuesday 20th January at <span dir="auto">10am PST / 1pm EST / 6pm GMT / 7pm CET for the Life is Strange reveal livestream.</span></p>
<p><iframe title="Life is Strange Returns in 2026" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/b2eHeCKYHJc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The blurb on the YouTube trailer just reads “Separate the real from the rumor… Join us for the exclusive reveal of the next Life is Strange game.” However, the more enticing fact is that the placeholder page is titled “Life is Strange Returns in 2026.”</p>


<p>Unfortunately for Square Enix, Life is Strange: Reunion was leaked last week by the PEGI ratings board. The synopsis for the game on the now removed listing read “Chloe Price was Max Caulfield’s partner in time… Losing her is Max’s greatest regret. Now Chloe has come to Caledon University. Haunted by nightmares and impossible memories, Chloe needs Max’s help. But Max is already in crisis: in three days, a deadly inferno will destroy the campus.”</p>
<p>Sounds pretty familiar, doesn’t it?</p>

<p>The Life is Strange series has been in the hands of Deck Nine for a good few years now, with the IP held by Square Enix and original developer Dontnod branching off to other projects since Life is Strange 2. Having bounced between new protagonists and settings, Deck Nine brought us back to Max Caulfield’s story with 2024’s <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/life-is-strange-double-exposure">Life is Strange: Double Exposure</a>.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/29/life-is-strange-double-exposure-review/">our review</a>, Reu said, “Life is Strange: Double Exposure is a very easy game to recommend. If you have enjoyed previous games in the series, this is doing enough of the same to scratch that same lowkey mystery vibes itch. The ability to shift between timelines can become a touch overwhelming at times, but there’s several things in place across the UI, accessibility options, and narrative flow to keep the gameplay smooth. What’s more, I think this game might have redeemed Max Caulfield for me too, so take that how you will.”</p>
<p><em>Source: YouTube, PEGI via <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/a-rating-has-leaked-an-unannounced-life-is-strange-sequel-with-strong-language-and-drug-use/">VGC</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/15/a-new-life-is-strange-will-be-announced-next-week/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>