<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 18:44:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starward Industries’ disaster adventure Into The Fire has a hot trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/10/starward-industries-disaster-adventure-into-the-fire-has-a-hot-trailer/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/starward-industries%E2%80%99-disaster-adventure-into-the-fire-has-a-hot-trailer.1160976/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/10/starward-industries-disaster-adventure-into-the-fire-has-a-hot-trailer/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Last year, Starward Industries announced the disaster survival adventure Dante’s Ring, but today the studio has confirmed a renaming of its project alongside a new trailer. Dante’s Ring is no more with that name being replaced by Into The Fire. The name aptly fits the game as you play as a firefighter on the volcanic area of <span>Dante’s Archipelago, with the mission to save as many people as possible while also dealing with demons. Into The Fire will be coming to Steam Early Access later this year.</span></p>
<p><iframe title="Into the Fire - Extended Gameplay Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WlbEGWwJap0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Into The Fire’s trailer shows just how high stakes everything is. The game’s fire replicates real fire in the way it quickly spreads and consumes things in its path for fuel. With your limited resources, including a fire axe and water, you will need to think on your feet to figure out the best path forward to save those trapped by the flames, while also dealing with the otherworldly influence of the fiery demons that are thriving in this environment. You will be armed with other unique tools including a shotgun that can extinguish flames. Maybe that will help with the pesky demons too. The terrain is not going to be easy to navigate but you will have different modes of transport including a sled and an acid resistant boat.&nbsp; When not in a disaster zone, you will be monitoring things from the Hub. The Hub is your command centre where you will get information, upgrade gear, and plan the rescues using data including seismographs. It will also be a place to rest and take stock of the events you have come across, peeling back the layers to understand the secrets of Dante’s Archipelago.</p>
<h2><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/11/02/the-invincible-review/">The Invincible Review</a></h2>
<p>Starward Industries last game was The Invincible, and in our review I said, <em>“The Invincible is a novel brought to life, blending its story and stunning visuals with engaging exploration. The Invincible goes back to the roots of sci-fi, offering something both classic and new when it comes to exploring the relationship between humanity and the final frontier.”</em></p>
<p><em>Source: Press Release</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Alters release date has been confirmed as June 13th]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/10/the-alters-release-date-has-been-confirmed-as-june-13th/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-alters-release-date-has-been-confirmed-as-june-13th.1160913/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/10/the-alters-release-date-has-been-confirmed-as-june-13th/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>11 bit studios has announced that its clone-filled survival strategy game The Alters will be releasing on June 13th. It will be available day one on Xbox Game Pass and PC Game Pass. As part of the news, a brand new trailer has been released which gives some more details about the threats that players will face on the dangerous planet.</p>
<p><iframe title="The Alters | Release Date Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WF48QDkg3Cw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>In The Alters there are dangers outside the ship, some of which are invisible, across the various biomes. These can as weird as floating rocks to scenarios that can deal instant death by disintegrating the suit, and other scenarios could see time and space distortions. Night time is even more dangerous due to radiation levels increasing.</p>
<p>In The Alters you are Jan, a space builder stranded on a distant alien planet who simply wants to try and survive and find a way home on his weird ring ship filled with habitable shipping container type things. To do this, he has to create ‘Alters’, essentially clones, of himself. They’re not quite clones as is each able to have distinct character skills and traits. They also have their own personalities. It’s from this that elements of psychological horror and an underlying mystery unfold. This is brought to the player through binary decisions, bringing up the fundamental question “what if?” as you head down deeper and darker paths. Even though biologically, they are all the same, each Alter has their own wants and needs, as well as motivations. Fail to meet their wants and needs, and they will turn on each other making the survival situation more desperate.</p>
<p><em>Source: Press Release</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>