<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 21:19:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kojima is also working on Niantic Spatial: A New Dawn, a new way of storytelling]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/23/kojima-is-also-working-on-niantic-spatial-a-new-dawn-a-new-way-of-storytelling/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kojima-is-also-working-on-niantic-spatial-a-new-dawn-a-new-way-of-storytelling.1305855/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Kojima is teaming up with Niantic to create a new… thing. It’s not a game, but will “l<span lang="EN-US">everage Niantic Spatial’s geospatial AI technology to bring Hideo Kojima’s iconic storytelling into the real world. </span>”</p>
<p>The video makes it look like some sort of AR app that might expand on the mechanism in Death Stranding that allowed you to leave markers and notes for other players. That’s just a guess but we do know NSAND is not linked to Niantic’s other big game,<a href="https://ingress.com/en"> Ingress.</a></p>
<p><iframe title="KOJIMA PRODUCTIONS and Niantic Spatial: A New Dawn" width="780" height="585" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oKyj6CDUH64?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>“The collaboration marks a significant moment for both companies and a shared vision to push the boundaries of what’s possible in interactive storytelling. For KOJIMA PRODUCTIONS, it’s a bold expansion into new forms of media beyond traditional gaming. For Niantic Spatial, it underlines the potential of geospatial AI technology to transform how people and machines understand and interact with the physical world,” say Kojima Productions.</p>

<p>“At Niantic Spatial, we’re building a living model of the world that people and machines can talk to, creating a new canvas for real-world storytelling and interaction,” said John Hanke, CEO of Niantic Spatial. “We are delighted to be working with KOJIMA PRODUCTIONS to explore what our combined creativity and innovation can accomplish for new and existing fans.”</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.kojimaproductions.jp/en/niantic-spatial-announcement">Kojima Productions</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/23/kojima-is-also-working-on-niantic-spatial-a-new-dawn-a-new-way-of-storytelling/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Peak Dillydally mini update is out now, adds option to rebind controls]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/23/the-peak-dillydally-mini-update-is-out-now-adds-option-to-rebind-controls/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-peak-dillydally-mini-update-is-out-now-adds-option-to-rebind-controls.1305819/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="gp-content-wrapper">
					
						
<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

	<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope="" content="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/23/the-peak-dillydally-mini-update-is-out-now-adds-option-to-rebind-controls/">
		<meta itemprop="headline" content="The Peak Dillydally mini update is out now, adds option to rebind controls">			
		
		<meta itemprop="author" content="Aran Suddi">			
		<meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2025-09-23">
		<meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2025-09-23">
		
	
							

		
	
		

		
															
	<div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Team PEAK has announced that its new dillydally update is now available for its co-op climbing game Peak, adding rebindable controls and some additional minigames to play including chess and basketball. A photo booth has been added in the airport too, and you can ask Bing Bong some questions to help you on your climbs.</p>
<p><iframe title="PEAK: mini-dillydally-update is OUT NOW!" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oBHWq0cQoiY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>The full patch notes for the Peak Dillydally update are below:</p>
<p><b>OPTIONS</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>The “Controls” page is now “Rebind Controls” and you can rebind your controls there.<wbr></p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><b>FEATURES</b><wbr></p>

<ul>
<li>Added Chess to the Airport.<wbr></li>
<li>Added Basketball to the Airport.<wbr></li>
<li>Added a Photobooth to the Airport.<wbr></li>
<li>Added a new badge.<wbr></li>
<li>Added Ask Bing Bong feature.<wbr></li>
<li>Added two new costumes for completing the new badge.<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>BALANCE</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>The Tomb maze is now less likely to be blocked off.<wbr></p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><b>FIXES</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>It’s no longer possible for the Capybara oasis to spawn in walls in the MESA.<wbr></li>
<li>It’s no longer possible for the Campfire to spawn on a tree at the top of the TROPICS.<wbr></li>
<li>It now takes less stamina to let go and regrab the wall at the same or lower position.<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the main menu played SFX when SFX was muted.<wbr></li>
<li>Being passed out from Thorns now will not cause the death timer to decay at a faster rate.<wbr></li>
<li>FIxed an issue where a large piece of wall would sometimes be visible in the Airport mirror.</li>
</ul>
<p>Those who are beta testing Peak also have Lava Rising enabled so changes to it can be tested, before it is released to the wider audience.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oBHWq0cQoiY">YouTube</a></em><wbr></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div>

				
			
		
	

				
	
		

	
			
	
	
 
	
	

</article>						
					</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/23/the-peak-dillydally-mini-update-is-out-now-adds-option-to-rebind-controls/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Painkiller will get a roguelike mode called Rogue Angel]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/23/painkiller-will-get-a-roguelike-mode-called-rogue-angel/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/painkiller-will-get-a-roguelike-mode-called-rogue-angel.1305726/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>3D Realms and Anshar Studio have announced that Painkiller will get a roguelike mode called Rogue Angel, the day the game launches. This new mode is separate to the story mode and will take players to an area of Purgatory where the levels are procedurally generated which are home to a mix of bosses. Players will be able to collect weapons, tarot cards, and items as they progress through the levels to take on the challenges that will lay ahead.</p>
<p><iframe title="Painkiller - Rogue Angel Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/b06H_XLzfwM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Painkiller’s story puts you in Purgatory where you have been given a chance to redeem yourself after transgressing against Heaven. The way to redeem yourself is by blasting away the demons of purgatory in an attempt to stop the fallen angel Azazel’s invasion of Earth. Painkiller can be playable solo and will also support co-op for up to three players.</p>
<p>There are two versions of Painkiller available for pre-order including the standard version and the deluxe edition. The standard edition is priced at €39.99/£34.99 with a pre-order bonus of the Iron Crusade skin pack. This pack includes skins for all four of the game’s characters, who are Ink, Void, Sol, and Roch. The Iron Crusade pack also has skins for six of the game’s weapons, with those being the Electrodriver, Stakegun, Shotgun, SMG, Hand Cannon and Rocket Launcher. You can check out the weapons in action&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/18/painkillers-latest-trailer-showcases-some-of-its-weapons/">Painkiller’s last trailer that showcased t</a>hem. The Painkiller Deluxe Edition is priced at €49.99/£44.99 will have the Iron Crusade pack, as well as three other post launch DLC packs that will each have six weapon skins and four character skins.</p>

<p>Painkiller is due to release on October 21st for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series XS.</p>
<p><em>Source: Press Release</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/23/painkiller-will-get-a-roguelike-mode-called-rogue-angel/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>