<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - www.thesixthaxis.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for www.thesixthaxis.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 05:29:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bungie delay Shadow and Order, Destiny 2’s next big update, until June]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/18/bungie-delay-shadow-and-order-destiny-2s-next-big-update-until-june/</link>
            <guid>1439914</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Bungie have announced that their next large update to <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/destiny-2/">Destiny 2</a>,&nbsp; titled Shadow and Order, has been delayed.<br>
<em><br>
“Our next Major Update, Destiny 2: Shadow and Order, is undergoing large revisions and will be delayed. This update is being changed and expanded to include sizable quality-of-life updates and as a result, will also be renamed. This update will now launch on June 9, 2026. </em></p>
<p><em>We will provide exact details closer to release covering previously announced Weapon Tier Upgrading, but also additions like expanding Tiered Gear to all Raid and Dungeon activities, Pantheon 2.0, Tier 5 stats for Exotic Armors, and more. Through June, we will continue to have routine bug fixes and stability improvements, continued portal modifiers, Guardian Games (March), and the return of a more frequent Iron Banner cadence</em></p>


<p><em>In terms of communications, we will be focusing on providing you with updates about our live game content, community activations, and general upkeep through the TWID and our Destiny social channels. Thank you for your continued patience and support. We will have more information on our next major update and future plans for Destiny 2 closer to launch.</em></p>
<p><em>See You Starside.”</em></p>
<p>The Shadow and Order update had been due to arrive just after the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/12/the-marathon-server-slam-takes-place-a-week-before-launch/">Marathon Server Slam</a> and just before <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/19/marathon-gets-a-march-5th-release-date/">Marathon itself launched,</a> so it seemed inevitable that it would be moved to allow Bungie some space for that.</p>

<p>Bungie have not released a roadmap for future updates but if Shadow and Order – or whatever it gets called – is delayed by three months then there is a very good chance that the next expansion, Shattered Cycle, will also get pushed back.</p>
<p>Bungie are clearly prioritising Marathon, and they really have to as they need another big hit. Destiny 2 is a shadow(keep) of its former self, and delaying big updates for months on end is not going to incentivise the players left.</p>
<p><em>Source:<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/destinythegame.bungie.net/post/3mf63bvtcms2g"> BlueSky</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/18/bungie-delay-shadow-and-order-destiny-2s-next-big-update-until-june/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>