<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 22:14:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vampire Survivors cross-save feature will not be available on PS4 and PS5]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/08/vampire-survivors-cross-save-feature-will-not-be-available-on-ps4-and-ps5/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/vampire-survivors-cross-save-feature-will-not-be-available-on-ps4-and-ps5.1158732/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/08/vampire-survivors-cross-save-feature-will-not-be-available-on-ps4-and-ps5/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Poncle Games has announced that the PlayStation versions of Vampire Survivors will not have the cross-save feature due to a legal issue. This legal issue is that the cross-save feature on PlayStation would have required Poncle to share partner information, which is something the studio is saying it is unable to share. There is still a miniscule chance of cross-save coming further down the line, but this will require more discussion with PlayStation. The full statement is below.</p>
<p><iframe title="Vampire Survivors - Launch Trailer | PS5 &amp; PS4 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oG4Sx0HlX3o?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p><em>“We’re sorry to say won’t be able to bring the Vampire Survivors Cross-Save feature to PlayStation 4/5 alongside our next update. Last month, we told everyone that Cross-Save would be available on PlayStation 4/5, PC, Xbox, Android and iOS alongside our next free VS update in April. But at last minute, we’ve run into a legal issue on PlayStation we weren’t aware of that requires us to share info on our partners that we’re unable to. The chances of Cross-Save coming to PlayStation consoles are now very slim, but not impossible, so we’re going to keep working alongside PlayStation to resolve these problems. We’re so sorry to build up any anticipation for this feature on PlayStation only to change plans at the last minute Cross-Save will still be available on PC, Xbox, Android and iOS in the next few weeks, with Nintendo Switch following at a later date (+ Apple Arcade if we can do so without breaching any privacy commitments).&nbsp;</em></p>
<p><em>PS: for anyone wanting Cross-Save just to unlock trophies, it’s worth noting that PS Trophies are automatically disabled on a platform level for all games when using a save file from another platform”</em></p>

<p>The cross-save feature will still be coming to PC, Xbox, Android, and iOS in the next game update. It will also be available on Switch later on down the line too.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.threads.net/@poncle_games/post/DIL_TXtNAF9?xmt=AQGzT11AYDnA6zZWZztKxo7tK6F76HIzOu_KfzLbVETYUQ">Threads</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>