<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 11:23:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Something for the Weekend – 10/05/25]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/10/something-for-the-weekend-10-05-25/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/something-for-the-weekend-%E2%80%93-10-05-25.1186032/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/10/something-for-the-weekend-10-05-25/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>We’re less than a month away now from two of the biggest moments of the gaming calendar for 2025, with Nintendo Switch 2’s launch coming&nbsp;<em>just</em> before Summer Game Fest and the E3-like bonanza of press conferences, trailers, announcements and more.</p>
<p>But don’t let that fool you into thinking that May’s going to be a quiet month. Oh Hell no, as we’re about to see in this week’s round-up!</p>
<h2>In the News This Week</h2>
<p>The biggest news story of the week was the new Grand Theft Auto VI trailer dropping alongside a big batch of new screenshots, but there’s plenty other impactful news to trawl through as well:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/06/grand-theft-auto-vi-gets-a-second-trailer/">Grand Theft Auto VI gets a second trailer</a>, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/06/check-out-tons-of-new-gta-6-screenshots-from-around-vice-city/">and a huge drop of screenshot</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/06/destiny-2-the-edge-of-fate-expansion-revealed/">Destiny 2: The Edge of Fate expansion revealed</a>, and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/06/the-destiny-2-renegades-expansion-is-based-on-actual-star-wars/">there’s a Star Wars expansion too?!</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/05/gears-of-war-reloaded-announced-for-pc-xbox-series-xs-and-ps5/">Gears of War: Reloaded announced for PC, Xbox Series X|S and PS5</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/07/sony-founds-new-studio-teamlfg-from-former-bungie-incubation-project/">Sony founds new studio teamLFG from former Bungie incubation project</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/09/pocketpair-confirms-palword-changes-are-in-response-to-pokemon-company-lawsuit/">Pocketpair confirms Palword changes are in response to Pokémon Company lawsuit</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/08/paradox-interactive-reveal-europa-universalis-v/">Paradox Interactive reveal Europa Universalis V</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/06/ecco-the-dolphin-remasters-and-brand-new-game-announced/">Ecco the Dolphin remasters and brand new game announced</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/10/alien-rogue-incursion-is-getting-a-non-vr-evolved-edition-port/">Alien: Rogue Incursion is getting a non-VR Evolved Edition port</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/07/starbreeze-acquires-rights-to-self-publish-payday-3-from-plaion/">Starbreeze acquires rights to self-publish Payday 3 from Plaion</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/07/ea-confirms-next-battlefield-reveal-will-come-this-summer-still-on-target-for-release-before-gta-6/">EA confirms next Battlefield reveal will come this summer, still on target for release before GTA 6</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/08/nintendo-forecasts-15-million-switch-2-sales-in-first-year/">Nintendo forecasts 15 million Switch 2 sales in first year</a></strong></li>
</ul>
<h2>Games in Review &amp; Featured Articles</h2>
<p>Heavy metal blasting and humorous adventuring dominated the reviews this week, but we also handed in our verdict on the simply stellar Clair Obscur and a bunch of other games, too!</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/05/clair-obscur-expedition-33-review/"><strong>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</strong></a> – <strong>PS5</strong>, XSX|S, PC – 10/10</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/07/spiritfall-review/"><strong>Spiritfall</strong></a> – PS5, XSX|S, PS4, XBO, <strong>NSW</strong>, PC – 9/10</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/09/doom-the-dark-ages-review/"><strong>DOOM: The Dark Ages</strong></a> – PS5, XSX|S, <strong>PC</strong> – 8/10 (<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iuTCe5ZVKos">Video Review</a>)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/08/revenge-of-the-savage-planet-review/"><strong>Revenge of the Savage Planet</strong></a> – PS5, XSX|S, <strong>PC</strong> – 8/10</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/06/drop-duchy-review/"><strong>Drop Duchy</strong></a> – <strong>PC</strong> – 8/10</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/05/moroi-review-a-slice-of-weirdness/"><strong>Moroi</strong></a> – <strong>PC</strong> – 7/10</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/06/captain-blood-review-original-pirate-material/"><strong>Captain Blood</strong></a> – <strong>PS5</strong>, XSX|S, PS4, XBO, NSW, PC – 6/10</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/07/kiborg-review/"><strong>Kiborg</strong></a> – <strong>PS5</strong>, XSX|S, PS4, XBO, PC – 5/10</li>
</ul>
<p>With such a review heavy week, there was just the one preview to go alongside, as I went hands on with <strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/08/europa-universalis-5-preview-hands-on-eu5/">Europa Universalis V</a></strong>, the big new entry in the grand strategy franchise that’s coming over 12 years on from the last!</p>

<p>And <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/09/what-we-played-doom-the-dark-ages-revenge-of-the-savage-planet/"><strong>What We Played</strong></a> featured DOOM: The Dark Ages and Revenge of the Savage Planet.</p>
<h2>Trailer Park</h2>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/08/mafia-the-old-country-launches-august-8th-check-out-the-new-trailer/">Mafia: The Old Country launches August 8th, check out the new trailer</a></strong></p>
<p><iframe title="Mafia: The Old Country - “Whatever it Takes” Gameplay Trailer | PS5 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KTmJDf6CuZs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/09/killing-floor-3-has-a-new-release-date-of-july-24th/">Killing Floor 3 has a new release date of July 24th</a></strong></p>
<p><iframe title="The Art and Design of Killing Floor 3 - PAX East Live Stream" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/A2Komzj_nNQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><strong>And here’s that GTA 6 trailer</strong></p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Grand Theft Auto VI Trailer 2" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VQRLujxTm3c?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>That’s the round up for this week. Hope you have a great weekend ahead and we’ll see you back here on Monday!</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pocketpair confirms Palword changes are in response to Pokémon Company lawsuit]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/09/pocketpair-confirms-palword-changes-are-in-response-to-pokemon-company-lawsuit/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pocketpair-confirms-palword-changes-are-in-response-to-pok%C3%A9mon-company-lawsuit.1186026/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/09/pocketpair-confirms-palword-changes-are-in-response-to-pokemon-company-lawsuit/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Palworld developer Pocketpair has confirmed that they are making various thematic changes to their hit monster catching survival game in response to <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/09/19/nintendo-the-pokemon-company-are-suing-palworld-maker/">the lawsuit and barrage of patent infringement claims</a> being made by The Pokémon Company.</p>
<p>In particular, Pocketpair changed how Pals are summoned in a November 2024 update to <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/palworld">Palworld</a>, making it so they no longer emerge from Pal Sphere, and with Patch 0.5.5, they are now now adding a glider, so that you’re no longer riding a Pal while floating through the sky. Players will still get a passive buff to gliding from Pals in their team, but you require a glider in the inventory to glide.</p>


<p>These are in direct response to The Pokémon Company’s claims that Palworld infringes on patents that they have recently acquired and then used as the basis for litigation against the developer. They’re described as “compromises” by the studio, being made to avoid the effect of any injunctions that could block the game’s development and sale going forward, while the cases will still go through the courts. Pocketpair will continue to dispute the claims in the lawsuit – The Pokémon Company is seeking financial compensation as well – and is focusing on invalidating the patents through prior art and how broad the concepts are.</p>
<p data-cy="paragraph">Here’s Pocketpair’s statement from a vapid social media hellhole:</p>
<p>We would li<em>ke to express our sincere gratitude and appreciation for the continued support of our fans over the past few months. We apologize for not being able to share as much information as we would like, but we trust our fans understand how difficult it is to be fully transparent while litigation is ongoing.</em></p>

<p><em>Currently, we remain involved in prolonged legal proceedings regarding alleged patent infringement. We continue to dispute these claims and assert the invalidity of the patents in question. However, we have had to make certain compromises in order to avoid disruptions to the development and distribution of Palworld.</em></p>
<p><em>On November 30th, 2024, we released Patch v0.3.11 for Palworld. This patch removed the ability to summon Pals by throwing Pal Spheres and instead changed it to a static summon next to the player. Several other game mechanics were also changed with this patch. As many have speculated, these changes were indeed a result of the ongoing litigation. Everyone here at Pocketpair was disappointed that this adjustment had to be made, and we fully understand that many players feel the same frustration. Unfortunately, as the alternative would have led to an even greater deterioration of the gameplay experience for players, it was determined that this change was necessary.</em></p>
<p><em>Furthermore, we regret to inform our players that with the implementation of Patch v0.5.5, we must make yet another compromise. From this patch onward, gliding will be performed using a glider rather than with Pals. Pals in the player’s team will still provide passive buffs to gliding, but players will now need to have a glider in their inventory in order to glide.</em></p>
<p><em>We understand that this will be disappointing for many, just as it is for us, but we hope our fans understand that these changes are necessary in order to prevent further disruptions to the development of Palworld.</em></p>
<p><em>We also want to extend our apologies to our fans for the discomfort and concern this ongoing litigation has caused.</em></p>
<p><em>We remain committed to developing Palworld and delivering exciting new content to our fans.</em></p>
<p><em>On behalf of everyone at Pocketpair and Team Palworld, thank you again for your continued support.</em></p>
<p>Palworld is available across PC, Xbox Series X|S, Xbox One and, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/09/24/palworld-is-out-today-on-ps5/">since last September</a>, across PlayStation 5 and PlayStation 4. December saw <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/11/29/palworld-december-update-new-island/">a major new update for the game that added a whole new island region</a> for players to explore, and the company recently revealed an ambitious roadmap with co-op crossplay, Pal world transfers, game collabs and more.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://xcancel.com/Palworld_EN/status/1920360001794945232">Pocketpair</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alien: Rogue Incursion is getting a non-VR Evolved Edition port]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/10/alien-rogue-incursion-is-getting-a-non-vr-evolved-edition-port/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/alien-rogue-incursion-is-getting-a-non-vr-evolved-edition-port.1186011/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/10/alien-rogue-incursion-is-getting-a-non-vr-evolved-edition-port/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Following its release for virtual reality at the end of 2024, Alien: Rogue Incursion is coming to PS5 and PC with a non-VR Evolved Edition launching on 30th September 2025.</p>
<p><iframe title="Alien: Rogue Incursion Evolved Edition | PS5 &amp; PC Announce Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0Ho3DAL11eA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>“FEAR HAS EVOLVED,” the trailer blurb declares. “Alien: Rogue Incursion Evolved Edition has been re-envisioned for PS5 &amp; PC in full HD at 60fps.”</p>
<p>Alien: Rogue Incursion casts you as ex-Colonial Marine Zula Hendricks, who’s intent on exposing Weyland-Yutani experiments on the planet Purdan. With a synth companion Davis 01 alongside her, you have to get into the research facility and then survive what you find there – xenomorphs, of course.</p>
<p>This is also described by developer Survios as part one of a two-part story, so while there is a conclusion to this story, there’s also a big cliffhanger leading to a sequel. This flatscreen launch no doubt intended to grow the game’s audience in anticipation of a second game.</p>

<p>Sadly, this wasn’t quite the Alien: Isolation VR successor that we hoped for with its initial launch. In <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/18/alien-rogue-incursion-review/">our review of the game on PSVR 2</a>, Tuffcub said, “I really wanted Alien: Rogue Incursion to be good and it starts so well, but then things just fall apart. There are many bad design decisions in the game so that you feel like you are fighting them rather than the Xenomorphs.”</p>
<p>Hopefully the Evolved Edition can improve upon and enhance the quirks and complaints we had.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0Ho3DAL11eA">YouTube</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starbreeze acquires rights to self-publish Payday 3 from Plaion]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/07/starbreeze-acquires-rights-to-self-publish-payday-3-from-plaion/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/starbreeze-acquires-rights-to-self-publish-payday-3-from-plaion.1186008/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/07/starbreeze-acquires-rights-to-self-publish-payday-3-from-plaion/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/payday-3">Payday 3</a> developer Starbreeze has acquired the publishing rights to their co-op heist shooter from publisher Plaion, intending to self-publish the title going forward and accelerate the game’s continued support and development.</p>
<p>To fund this, Starbreeze is issuing new shares in the company, looking to boost capital by around 10% and raise 33 million SEK (which is roughly £2.55 million). 29 million SEK (~£2.24 million) is being used to repay Plaion for certain obligations.</p>


<p>“This agreement enables Starbreeze to fully acquire the publishing rights to PAYDAY 3 from Plaion, significantly accelerate our content development roadmap, and pursue broader strategic opportunities for the PAYDAY franchise as a whole. We appreciate PLAION’s support, which underscores their confidence in Starbreeze’ future and strengthens our strategic alignment with major global industry players.” says Thomas Lindgren, Board Member of Starbreeze.</p>
<p>Despite the split, Starbreeze says that there could still be a long-term partnership between Starbreeze and Plaion for future Payday games and projects.</p>

<p>Payday 3 launched in late 2023, but failed to hit the highs and expectations from its predecessor. While it made a solid first impression – “a welcome return for the heist ’em up series, and a reminder of why the first two games were so popular,” <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/09/21/payday-3-review/">I wrote at the time</a> – it faced an uphill battle with its fans and launched into a much more competitive and time-demanding market for co-op games. After around 18 months of hefty reworks and patches, and the addition of the classic World First Bank heist in December it could be worth diving in. The game was a part of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/04/the-ps-plus-monthly-games-for-february-2025-payday-3-high-on-life/">PS Plus monthly games back in February</a>, and is currently on sale with <a href="https://www.paydaythegame.com/news/payday3/2025/05/weekend-deal-consoles/">60% off on Xbox and PlayStation consoles</a>.</p>
<p>Source: <a href="https://www.starbreeze.com/news/starbreeze-enters-into-agreement-regarding-the-publishing-rights-for-payday-3-and-carries-out-a-directed-share-issue-of-class-b-shares-amounting-to-sek-33-million/">Starbreeze</a></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>