<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 14:39:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lumo 2 announced for PC, Switch, and PS5 with a release set for 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/04/lumo-2-announced-for-pc-switch-and-ps5-with-a-release-set-for-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lumo-2-announced-for-pc-switch-and-ps5-with-a-release-set-for-2025.1155369/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/04/lumo-2-announced-for-pc-switch-and-ps5-with-a-release-set-for-2025/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Lumo 2 has been announced by Numskull Games and developer Triple Eh?, with this sequel coming nine years after Lumo first came out. Lumo has been available on PC, PS4, PS Vita, Xbox One, Switch, and Xbox One. Lumo 2 will be released for PC, PS5, and Switch at some point in 2025, though a more specific release window is yet to be announced.</p>
<p><iframe title="Lumo 2 Announcement Teaser Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rFtJJv46jfI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Lumo 2 has been inspired by the era of 8-bit games, with the levels being based on games from that period. Dimensions will shift dungeon to dungeon with perspectives and gameplay also changing. In our <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2016/05/24/lumo-review/">review for Lumo</a>, I said, <em>“Lumo is full of well thought out puzzles, but it lacks certain gameplay touches that could have pushed it into being a great game. My main gripe is that the jumping feels awkward and, coupled with perspective issues, means you can fail a simple puzzle dozens of times. The game does have a certain charm to it, and I would recommend it as a nostalgia trip for players that grew up with similar games, but this will not be for those who aren’t fans of classic titles or puzzles.”</em></p>
<p><em>Source: Press Release</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>