<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 10:46:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Promise Mascot Agency has a release date of April 10th]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/28/promise-mascot-agency-has-a-release-date-of-april-10th/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/promise-mascot-agency-has-a-release-date-of-april-10th.1121604/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/28/promise-mascot-agency-has-a-release-date-of-april-10th/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Promise Mascot Agency has finally been given a release date by developer Kaizen Game Works, with the studio confirming April 10th is the day Michi and the mascots will be unleased. This date applies to all platforms the game is coming to including PC via Steam and Epic, PS5, Xbox Series X|S, and Nintendo Switch. To mark the announcement, a new trailer has been released featuring some of the characters including Michi, To-Fu, Pinky, Captain Sign, Mama-San, Shiori, and Mayor Maeda.</p>
<p><iframe title="Promise Mascot Agency: Release Date Trailer!" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bwTNI-MKKPE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Right now, you can grab the Promise Mascot Agency demo, which gives access to 80 minutes of the game.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2585830/Promise_Mascot_Agency/">Promise Mascot Agency on Steam</a></li>
<li><a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/promise-mascot-agency-promise-mascot-agency-demo-85764f">Promise Mascot Agency Demo Coming Soon – Epic Games Store</a></li>
<li><a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-gb/product/UP6440-PPSA27233_00-0249946431476665/">Promise Mascot Agency Demo</a>&nbsp;on PS5</li>
<li><a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-GB/games/store/promise-mascot-agency-demo/9PC42205125W">Get Promise Mascot Agency Demo | Xbox</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Promise Mascot Agency! is an open world mascot management crime drama, where you play as a disgraced Yakuza lieutenant called Michi. He is sent to the bankrupt agency and is tasked with turning it into a profitable business, which is a lot harder said than done when the location is a small town called Kaso-Machi. The gameplay will consist of exploring Kaso-Michi, recruiting mascots, and sending them on jobs around the area. Sometimes, these jobs will go wrong so Michi will have to find solutions to get them back on track.</p>

<h2><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2020/10/02/paradise-killer-review-pc-switch/">Paradise Killer Review</a></h2>
<p>Kaizen Game Works previously made Paradise Killer, and in our Paradise Killer review, Miguel wrote, <em>“Paradise Killer is a pure, unguided detective mystery that doesn’t dare hold your hand. You, and you alone, are in charge of seeking out not only the truth of this locked room murder, but the truth of the wild and cosmically corrupt world that the game takes place in. The open ended nature of the investigation can be daunting at first, and while some clunky platforming and frequent periods of downtime can sour the experience just a bit, Paradise Killer still manages to be one of the most well put together and utterly satisfying mystery games I’ve ever experienced.”</em></p>
<p><em>Source: Press Release</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayerUnknown Productions drop the first gameplay trailer for procedural survival Prologue: Go Wayback!]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/28/playerunknown-productions-drop-the-first-gameplay-trailer-for-procedural-survival-prologue-go-wayback/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playerunknown-productions-drop-the-first-gameplay-trailer-for-procedural-survival-prologue-go-wayback.1121568/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/28/playerunknown-productions-drop-the-first-gameplay-trailer-for-procedural-survival-prologue-go-wayback/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>One of the most exciting projects we’ve been able to check out recently has been <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/20/prologue-go-wayback-playerunknowns-glimpse-of-a-digital-future-that-teaches-us-to-survive-in-the-present/">Prologue: Go Wayback!</a>. There’s a whole host of reasons as to why it’s exciting, but the first amongst them is that it’s coming from PlayerUnknown Studios, the development team headed by Brendan ‘PlayerUnknown’ Greene, known globally for the smash hit battle royale PlayerUnknown Battlegrounds, or PUBG. This new trailer is the first true taste of the game’s gameplay outside of our press viewing and selected beta testing. You should definitely join us in the excitement.</p>
<p><iframe title="Prologue: Go Wayback! Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KI6H_WNHUlU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Prologue uses procedural generation and machine learning to create an 8km by 8km map every single time you play. For context, that’s the same size as Skyrim’s map, and just as with Bethesda’s RPG hit, if you can see it, you can walk there. In fact, that’s the whole point of the game. Your task here is to survive, with each iteration of the map liable to cause you immense stress and strain as you fight against the elements, and your own hunger and thirst. You have to stay warm, dry, fed and watered, and that is far harder than you might first think.</p>
<p>Your task is to make it to the weather station. Each time you drop into the game you’ll start in a cabin, and the weather station will be somewhere between 3km and 6km away. There’s no mini-map, or route finding, you have to use an in-game physical map that your character holds up to read, while then referring to your compass to choose the direction. Just as you would in real life if you were lost in the woods, you have to navigate by the monuments and landscape details that you can see, finding other shacks or cabins along the way that hopefully contain better clothing or additional food to keep you going through the night.</p>


<p>Prologue: Go Wayback! is the perfect survival game, and it can really look quite beautiful, assuming you’re able to survive long enough to see it. Prologue: Go Way Back will release into Early Access this summer for PC.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>