<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 16:51:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Destiny 2: The Edge of Fate expansion revealed!]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/06/destiny-2-the-edge-of-fate-expansion-revealed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/destiny-2-the-edge-of-fate-expansion-revealed.1182333/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/06/destiny-2-the-edge-of-fate-expansion-revealed/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>The next chapter for Destiny 2 has been revealed by Bungie along with details of the upcoming year.&nbsp; A new trailer shows The Emissary, who is a friend of Drifter,&nbsp; being lectured to by The Nine and eventually transformed into a cybernetic body.</p>
<p><iframe title="Destiny 2: The Edge of Fate | Cinematic Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/buh6WERf-zY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Without writing a million pages of Lore, The Nine are extra-dimensional beings that existed before The Traveller, before Ghosts and essentially before Destiny started. They have been mainly background characters during the first chapter of the game, but it seems they are going to be the new bad guys in The Fate Saga, which is going to be running over multiple years. They are individual characters, they are not a collective, so that would give the game plenty of new end of chapter bad guys to fight.</p>
<p>A gameplay trailer for The Edge of Fate was released that shows new weapons, new expansions and new powers. It begins with an invitation to a moment in time “for a very specific” reason,&nbsp; and you will be heading to Kepler, a tiny planet in the Oort cloud on the edge of our Solar System. We are also told that parts of Earth’s past have been pulled in to Kepler, which explains the subway trains and could be the rumoured level based on Chicago.</p>

<p>The new expansion will have ‘World Tiers’ with varying difficulty levels, with puzzles and events changing depending on the level. There’s also a new ability called “Matterspark” that allows you to turn in to Sonic the Hedgehog, or at least the Destiny 2 version, which is a sparkling ball of death.&nbsp; Matterspark is powered by Dark Matter (which is what The Nine are made of) and lucky for us there’s completely made-up thingy that allows everyone to see it.</p>
<p><iframe title="Destiny 2: The Edge of Fate | Official Gameplay Reveal" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qlylquFX6EE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The Edge of Fate launches on July 15th, with Renegades launching in Winter, followed by Shattered Cycle and The Alchemist in 2026, but before that we have The Right of the Nine, a free prologue event that reuses some dungeons but with a new twist.</p>

<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@destinythegame/videos">YouTube</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>