<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 21:19:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rumours suggest more Xbox games will be coming to PS5 and Switch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/10/rumours-suggest-more-xbox-games-will-be-coming-to-ps5-and-switch/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rumours-suggest-more-xbox-games-will-be-coming-to-ps5-and-switch.1079424/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/10/rumours-suggest-more-xbox-games-will-be-coming-to-ps5-and-switch/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Now I am not going to suggest the people behind these leaks are making stuff up, but at this point, almost any Xbox exclusive title seems likely to come to PS5. Microsoft has broken the barrier and with PS5 sales massively outstripping Xbox sales throwing a bunch of older games to hungry PS5 players is a no-brainer.</p>
<p>Two reliable sources – NateTheHate and Windows Central’s Jez Corden – have been posting about the games in question.</p>
<p>“So, games that I have heard will be released multiplatform in 2025 beyond the obvious include Flight Simulator, which will come to PlayStation 5 and Switch 2, and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2014/11/07/halo-the-master-chief-collection-review/">Halo: The Master Chief Collection</a> will be coming to PS5 and Switch 2 as well,” states Nate on his <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AIhoTirZxlk">podcast.</a></p>


<p>If you are reeling from the idea of Halo on PlayStation, he also suggests that the rumoured Gears of War collection will also come to PS5.</p>
<p>Jez has confirmed he had also heard about Flight Simulator and Halo, and<a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/gaming/xbox/a-new-rumor-suggests-final-fantasy-7-remake-is-finally-coming-to-xbox-in-2025-with-rebirth-heading-across-in-2026-as-more-xbox-games-head-to-ps5-and-nintendo"> adds</a> “I’ve heard that also Hellblade 2, Age of Mythology, and potentially Gears of War 1 Ultimate Edition are all also slated for PlayStation 5 this year, although I’m unsure if that includes the Nintendo Switch 2.”</p>

<p>Doom: The Dark Ages and Indiana Jones and the Great Circle are already set to land on PS5 this year.</p>
<p>It’s not all one way though, Nate also suggests that Final Fantasy VII Remake will land on&nbsp; Xbox this year with Rebirth following in 2026.</p>
<p><em>Source:<a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/gaming/xbox/a-new-rumor-suggests-final-fantasy-7-remake-is-finally-coming-to-xbox-in-2025-with-rebirth-heading-across-in-2026-as-more-xbox-games-head-to-ps5-and-nintendo"> Windows Central</a> / <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AIhoTirZxlk">YouTube</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>