<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 15:55:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade will launch January 22nd for Switch 2 and Xbox]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/12/final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade-will-launch-january-22nd-for-switch-2-and-xbox/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade-will-launch-january-22nd-for-switch-2-and-xbox.1296342/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Square Enix has announced that Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade will be launching on January 22nd for Switch, Xbox Series X|S, and Xbox on PC. Square Enix has also confirmed that Final Fantasy VII Rebirth, and the third game in the trilogy will be released for Switch 2 and Xbox Series X|S too, with more information for both to come at a later date.</p>
<p><iframe title="FINAL FANTASY VII REMAKE INTERGRADE - Release Date Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0eIb6WcuAeo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade will feature a streamlined progression setting that will allow players to get through the game faster. Each of the settings can be toggled on or off individually, with this being the list of those settings. Essentially, each of the settings make the game easier to get through, handy for those who just want to experience the story.</p>
<ul>
<li><em><strong>HP is always full</strong>&nbsp;– your HP is at its maximum value at all times. Even when hit by an enemy, your HP won’t go down. Instant death is also removed (sorry Tonberries!)</em></li>
<li><em><strong>MP is always full</strong>&nbsp;– your MP is always at its maximum value. Sling out spells with wild abandon!</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Limit gauge is always full</strong>&nbsp;– the Limit gauge is at maximum when you enter battle, and using powerful Limit Breaks won’t deplete it.</em></li>
<li><em><strong>ATB gauge is always full</strong>&nbsp;– your ATB gauge is always maxed out, so you can unleash abilities as much as you want without restriction!</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Damage dealt is always 9999</strong>&nbsp;– with this set on, you’ll do maximum damage with every attack. No boss can stand against you!</em></li>
</ul>
<p>Pre-orders for Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade are open too. In our <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2020/04/06/final-fantasy-vii-remake-review/">Final Fantasy VII Remake Review</a>, Tuffcub said, <em>“An utter joy to play from start to finish, packed with memorable scenes, moustache-twirling baddies, and epic battles. The first part of Final Fantasy VII Remake isn’t just polished, it’s opulent.”</em></p>
<p>While in our <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/06/17/final-fantasy-7-remake-intergrade-review-ps5/">Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade Review,&nbsp;</a>Nic said, <em>“You should absolutely get Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade. It’s easy to be critical and nitpick, but it’s worth remembering we’re looking at the DLC for one of the best and most-loved games of the PS4. The PS5 upgrade for Intergrade looks and feels incredible, and the chance to play as Yuffie is warmly received, especially when she completely changes the tone to something more light-hearted. However, the DLC isn’t quite perfect and, despite the filler, it feels very short for its price, especially if you’re not interested in the side missions.”</em></p>

<p>To avoid any confusion the Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade that is coming to Switch 2 and Xbox features the full game and INTERmission DLC.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.square-enix-games.com/en_US/news/final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade-switch2-xbox-series-x-s">Square Enix</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/12/final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade-will-launch-january-22nd-for-switch-2-and-xbox/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil Requiem coming to Switch 2, along with Resident Evil Biohazard and Village]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/12/resident-evil-requiem-coming-to-switch-2-along-with-resident-evil-biohazard-and-village/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/resident-evil-requiem-coming-to-switch-2-along-with-resident-evil-biohazard-and-village.1296252/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>A trio of Resident Evil games are heading to Nintendo Switch with Resident Evil 7, aka Resident Evil Biohazard, and Resident Evil 8, aka Resident Evil Village, all launching on the same day as the new game, Resident Evil Requiem.</p>
<p>You can read our hands of preview of<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/20/resident-evil-requiem-preview-first-person-frights-third-person-delights/"> Resident Evil Requiem here</a>, and there’s a handy video as well.</p>
<p><iframe title="Resident Evil Requiem Preview – First person frights, third person delights" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pIE471UnNVc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>The ninth mainline Resident Evil game casts players as Grace Ashcroft who – as RE law dictates – finds herself embroiled in an apocalyptic scenario that has players running a gauntlet of jump scares as they peel back layers of a grander conspiracy.</p>

<p>Much like Resident Evil 7, and Village, Requiem will feature first person gameplay and visuals powered by Capcom’s silky smooth RE Engine. Instead of being chased by the shambling undead, Gamescom footage shows Grace and her mother escape the clutches of someone who appears to be a deranged serial killer. It’s definitely a change of direction for Resi though one that will no doubt loop back to the familiar tropes this series is known for, with fan favourite characters likely to make an appearance at some point.</p>
<p><iframe title="Resident Evil Requiem - 2nd Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tOYqFlgF6t8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Director Koshi Nakanishi gave insides on how the game is built around the concept of addictive fear –&nbsp;as in, the cathartic effect of overcoming fears. He also discussed how that ties in with the new protagonist, FBI agent Grace Ashcroft, who is shy and introverted, needing to overcome her fears and leaning on her training to be able to use a gun and fast deduction skills.</p>
<p>Leon had been in consideration to be the lead character for this new game, and would certainly have been popular, so why not return to the franchise staple?</p>
<p>“We always thought about making Leon the protagonist,” Nakanishi-san said. “But making a horror game based around him is difficult. He wouldn’t jump at something like a bucket falling. No one wants to see Leon scared by every little thing, so he’s actually quite a bad match for horror.”</p>
<p>All three Resident Evil games will launch on Nintendo Switch 2 on 27th February 2026.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tOYqFlgF6t8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">YouTube</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/12/resident-evil-requiem-coming-to-switch-2-along-with-resident-evil-biohazard-and-village/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>