<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 15:30:51 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Laika: Aged Through Blood Nintendo Switch Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/30/laika-aged-through-blood-nintendo-switch-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/laika-aged-through-blood-nintendo-switch-review.1095942/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/30/laika-aged-through-blood-nintendo-switch-review/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>When is a game too difficult? For my sanity, it’s when playing it becomes such a chore that you’d rather do household chores instead. For me, Laika: Aged Through Blood is one such game; obviously brilliant but stupidly hard.</p>
<p><iframe title="Laika: Aged Through Blood │ Pre-Order Teaser │ Nintendo Switch ????????" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2UoWNET0bRo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Released on <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/01/08/laika-aged-through-blood-review/">PC and other consoles back in 2023</a>, Laika: Aged Through Blood has now been ported over to Nintendo Switch. It tells the dark tale of Laika, an anthropomorphic coyote. Half mum, half warrior, half butt-kicking bad ass, Laika is up against the Bird faction, a tyrannical bunch of megalomaniacs, intent on taking over the land and wiping out her village.</p>


<p>Despite its gorgeous hand-drawn artwork, sumptuous animation, and cute animal characters, Laika: Aged Through Blood is unrelentingly bleak. The game opens with the depiction of a child cayote who has been strangled to death and strung up by their own innards. Grim. Frankly, the levels of gore, despair, and cruel unrelenting violence were rather too much for me. But hey, to each their own, and regardless of my sensitive constitution, Laika: Aged Through Blood tells an engaging and emotional story. Maybe just don’t eat before playing?</p>


<p>The game is an intriguing hybrid that’s Metroidvania and part motorbike sim. That’s right, you get the exploration, power-up gathering, puzzle solving and resource gathering of a Metroidvania, alongside the motorbike controls and physics of an entry from Ubisoft’s <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2014/04/16/trials-fusion-review/">Trials</a> series. It’s an eclectic mix to be sure, but it works, forging the two disparate elements into a cohesive experience, one dubbed ‘Motorvania’ by the developers.</p>
<p>Laika speeds around the environment with a squeeze of the trigger, leaving you responsible for spinning her bike into front flips or back flips. Doing so will recharge both your parry ability – only, you know, parrying with <em>a motorbike</em> – and your ammunition. Shooting from the bike activates slow motion bullet time, which is absolutely essential to stand a chance at hitting one of the many bird henchavians, blasting away with their rifles as you zoom along. Ammunition is scarce, your first weapon, a pistol, carries only two shoots, so incorporating opportunities to flip your bike is integral to success.</p>

<p>It sounds like it shouldn’t work but it does, brilliantly so. Gameplay is satisfying and morish. Each encounter will result in your death numerous times, but on each try your reflexes improve a little, until you finally nail the timing of that back flip, blocking a spray of bullets with your bike, before landing perfectly, reloading, and blowing away the crow that blocks your path. Alongside all the action there’s some welcome downtime, allowing you to explore the gorgeous labyrinthian surroundings, discovering new abilities that might, <em>just might</em>, keep you alive a little longer during the next battle.</p>
<p>So, as you may have gathered, Laika: Aged Through Blood is unrelentingly difficult. Get hit, you’re dead. Fail to land your bike just right, you’re dead. Do pretty much anything wrong, you’re dead. Controls are precise and demanding, but there’s little room for error. Accessibility is almost absent – other than the option to not die quite as instantly if you mistime a landing – with no difficulty levels to choose from, meaning you’re stuck with evil mode. Thankfully, quick save points are plentiful, but that doesn’t mitigate the unrelenting grind of the difficulty, which quickly wore me down.</p>

<p>Normally the darling of Indie games, the Switch in handheld mode is a poor fit for Laika: Aged Through Blood. The 6.2″ screen is too small to enable you to see the teeny tiny bullets that you’ll need to dodge and reflect with the required ninja-like timing, and the controls of the Switch are too fiddly to provide the precision demanded. It’s also rather erratically laggy when the screen gets busy, making the game even harder than anything should have any right to be. Docked mode is frankly the only way you stand a chance of success, and even then, chances are slim.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How did Sony spend so much money on new live service games when they have a ready made hit in their vault?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/30/how-did-sony-spend-so-much-money-on-new-live-service-games-when-they-have-a-ready-made-hit-in-their-vault/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-did-sony-spend-so-much-money-on-new-live-service-games-when-they-have-a-ready-made-hit-in-their-vault.1095789/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/30/how-did-sony-spend-so-much-money-on-new-live-service-games-when-they-have-a-ready-made-hit-in-their-vault/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Sony’s plan to launch twelve ‘Games As Services’ titles has been a complete disaster by any standards, fuelled by mismanagement and poor business decisions to the point that almost all of the titles have been cancelled.&nbsp; Naughty Dog spent years making The Last of Us 2 multiplayer before <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/12/15/the-last-of-us-online-has-been-cancelled/">someone pointed out that they’d needed a full time team</a> to work on ongoing content, staff that Naughty Dog simple did not have. <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/29/sony-permanently-shuts-down-concord-and-developer-firewalk-studios/">Concord’s demise has been widely covered</a>, the game was good but launching a colourful team shooter and not making it free-to-play meant it was dead on arrival.</p>
<p>Most recently, the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/17/report-sony-cancels-two-more-live-service-games-at-bluepoint-bend-studio/">live service games at Bluepoint and Bend Studio</a> have been cancelled, both had been in development for at least four years. This leaves just&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/05/24/haven-studios-fairgame-playstation-exlcusive/">Fairgame$ from Jade Raymond’s studio Haven</a>, a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2022/11/09/a-horizon-mmorpg-is-reportedly-in-development-by-ncsoft/">Horizon MMORPG</a>, and an unknown live service game from Jason Blundell.</p>
<p>All of this has cost Sony hundreds of millions of dollars, and they’ve had very little success with this strategy.&nbsp;Some of this could have easily been predicted, as launching a game that is competing with the likes of Overwatch was always going to be a massive battle. To do that, you need to generate huge interest in your game and market the socks off it, something Sony failed to do with Concord. Spending millions on a game that looks and feels like ten other free-to-play titles is never going to work – players need a unique hook such as <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/helldivers-2">Helldivers 2’s</a> award-winning take on Starship Troopers, or the surefire success of a <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/gran-turismo-7">Gran Turismo 7</a>. Those are Sony’s only live service successes so far.</p>


<p>If only Sony had something in its back catalogue, a well-known franchise that has sold millions of copies in the last couple of generations, already has a track record with multiplayer, and runs on an engine that means a PC version could be made. Oh wait, they do: it’s Killzone.</p>


<p>The Killzone franchise began back in the days of the PlayStation 2 with Sony looking for a shooter to rival Microsoft’s massive hit, Halo. It did not quite reach those heights but a sequel was soon green-lit and developer Guerrilla Games was purchased by Sony.&nbsp; Killzone 2 was released in 2009 and is widely agreed to be the best of the franchise with a Metacritic score of 91, with Killzone 3 following on in 2011. The next game, Killzone: Shadow Fall was a showcase launch title for Sony’s next-gen console, the PS4, while Killzone: Mercenary was a boundary-pushing title on the PS Vita.</p>
<p>The franchise has sold well over six million copies which these days doesn’t sound that good, Shadow Fall certainly fell short of sales expectations, but the fan base still exists and calls for a new game are heard regularly. Guerrilla Games has moved on to the Horizon franchise, which has now sold over 32 million copies and no one can blame them for wanting to do something different, but Killzone is still recent enough that it could be revived.</p>
<p>One of the best things about these games were their multiplayer modes, built around complimentary classes, large 32-player battles in Killzone 2, and shifting game objectives in the main Warzone mode. From Killzone 2 through to Shadow Fall, there’s more than enough maps, modes and ideas to draw upon that would stand out against the main multiplayer games of the last few years. Even just having a grounded, militaristic sci-fi style would contrast to the over-the-top cosmetics of Call of Duty.</p>

<p>Now, I am not a game developer and will make this sound much easier than it actually is, but ripping out the multiplayer from Killzone: Shadow Fall and using this as the foundation for a new game would be much more cost-effective than creating a brand new game from scratch. It’s still one of the best-looking games on PS4, and with eleven years of updates to the Decima engine, on which it runs, there should be some straightforward technical improvements to make beyond that.</p>
<p>Warming up the Shadow Fall servers probably wouldn’t be flashy or new enough, and it could be desirable to roll back to having more classes and roles, as in Killzone 2 and 3. Even starting from scratch, Killzone could easily provide the basis for a new game in the free-to-play market, and it’s far more obvious to greenlight a shooter than to keep trying to bring back Twisted Metal or God of War multiplayer, as Bend and Bluepoint were rumoured to be doing.</p>
<p>There’s even easy wins when looking for ongoing content. There are plenty of maps from older Killzone games that could be rebuilt, and a seasonal story could be wrapped around it, maybe retelling the franchise’s main narrative as maps are added. For cosmetics, Sony could raid their back catalogue with skins. There’s the recent Killzone cosmetics for Helldivers 2, so it’s only fair that they repay the favour, and stylised Resistance: Fall of Man cosmetics would go down a treat without breaking the sci-fi military tone too much. Halo Infinite has had some pretty out-there cosmetics, like the samurai armour and other alternate universe designs, but always manages to keep the sci-fi tone running throughout.</p>
<p>The main question would be who could take this project on? Guerrilla themselves have no real interest in returning to Killzone – they’re busy making a Horizon multiplayer game, anyway – but there’s obviously idle hands at Bend Studios and Bluepoint. Maybe they don’t have the specific expertise for a first person shooter, but Bluepoint has excelled in the past at remaking games, and with some guidance from Guerrilla to get the right feel, or Bungie who are pretty great at shooters themselves, this could be a good fit.</p>
<p>Sadly the obvious path is rarely the one Sony follows lately, but perhaps after being burned to the tune of hundreds of millions of dollars a cheaper, almost ready made F2P title could be just what they need.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>