<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 16:10:30 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Surprise! Descenders Next is out now for Xbox and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/21/surprise-descenders-next-is-out-now-for-xbox-and-pc/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/surprise-descenders-next-is-out-now-for-xbox-and-pc.1248861/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>No More Robots and RageSquid have announced that Descenders Next is out… now! The sequel to the downhill biking of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/descenders">Descenders</a> is available right now for PC and Xbox, and on<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/xbox-game-pass">&nbsp;Game Pass</a> for both systems.</p>
<p><iframe title="Descenders Next is OUT NOW!" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fE11hzKkErQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Where the original game was all about bikes, Descenders Next focuses in on snowboarding and mountainboarding. You’ll start by drifting through the white stuff, before getting onto the brown stuff, mastering snowboards first before having wheels attached to that plank of wood and relearning how this will handle.</p>
<p>Descenders Next already boasts as much content as the original Descenders, with full online multiplayer, multiple huge biomes, and tons of tricks and grinds to learn how to pull off. There’s still a blend of procedural generation and hand-crafted levels, but these now chain from one into the other, and the goal can be a to race to the finish line, pull of tricks and perfect landings, or go on scavenger hunts to explore the whole mountain.</p>
<p>Rounding out the experience is a drum and bass soundtrack from Monstercat.</p>

<p>Descenders was a huge hit for No More Robots and RageSquid, first launching for PC and Xbox One in 2019, before spreading to PS4 and Switch in 2020. With outright sales alongside stints in subscription services, there’s been over 35 million players of this game, and they’ll no doubt be hoping to capture that lightning in a bottle for a second time.</p>
<p>Originally announced last August, the team planned to roll from a demo back in February of this year to have their early access launch in April, but chose to postpone this after seeing tens of thousands of players try out the game and gathering a ton of valuable feedback and info. A few months on, and Descenders Next will hopefully be much better prepared to handle everything that players want from the game.</p>
<p><em>Source: press release</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/21/surprise-descenders-next-is-out-now-for-xbox-and-pc/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>