<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 02:32:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[007: First Light gets a March 2026 release date]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/03/007-first-light-gets-a-march-2026-release-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/007-first-light-gets-a-march-2026-release-date.1288062/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>IO Interactive has announced the release date for <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/007-first-light">007: First Light</a>, setting the game’s launch for 27th March 2026 across <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/playstation-5">PS5</a>, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/xbox-series-x">Xbox Series X|S</a>, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/nintendo-switch-2">Nintendo Switch 2</a> and PC.</p>
<p><iframe title="007 First Light – Gameplay Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Y1AHkgXCNjA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>The announcement came alongside the big gameplay reveal, with IOI sharing half an hour of gameplay snippets, cutting through a mission to intercept rogue agent 009 at a chess tournament, showcasing the game’s evolved stealth action gameplay, before leading into a high speed car chase and then deadly combat as Bond chases his target to a fleeing cargo plane. Would you believe that the plane doesn’t have a smooth take off and landing?</p>
<p>The studio revealed the ensemble cast that is taking on the roles of some truly iconic characters:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Patrick Gibson</strong> as James Bond</li>
<li><strong>Priyanga Burford</strong> as M</li>
<li><strong>Alastair Mackenzie</strong> as Q</li>
<li><strong>Kiera Lester</strong> as Miss Moneypenny</li>
<li><strong>Lennie James</strong> as Bond’s mentor, John Greenway</li>
<li><strong>Noemie Nakai</strong> as Miss Roth</li>
</ul>
<p>We had an early preview of the gameplay reveal back at Gamescom last month and had the opportunity to speak with Franchise Art Director Rasmus Poulsen. Here’s a little tidbit, as we discuss Bond’s visits to Q Lab and whether they’re more Desmon Llewelyn or Ben Wishaw. “We have quite a bit of humour everywhere, but it’s important to mention that it is, first and foremost, a reasonably dry British wit, because otherwise it doesn’t feel quite like it belongs. And, you know, you’ll get to a Q lab and you’ll get to understand how that relationship was formed in that surprising way, I would say, so look forward to that!”</p>

<p><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/03/007-first-light-preview-how-io-are-crafting-a-new-kind-of-bond-game/">Head here for our wider 007: First Light preview</a>, with insights on how they settled on James Bond’s look, brought cars, vehicles and high speed chases in alongside action set pieces and, of course, the more open stealth action style inherited from the Hitman franchise.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/03/007-first-light-gets-a-march-2026-release-date/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>