<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 14:36:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Portal gets full PS Plus cloud streaming, and you can even stream your own games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/05/playstation-portal-gets-full-ps-plus-cloud-streaming-and-you-can-even-stream-your-own-games/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-portal-gets-full-ps-plus-cloud-streaming-and-you-can-even-stream-your-own-games.1344349/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Close to one year on from the launch of the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/11/20/the-playstation-portal-is-finally-getting-ps-plus-cloud-streaming/">Cloud Streaming beta</a> for <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/playstation-portal">PlayStation Portal</a>, Sony has announced the official launch of this feature, as well as the debut of being able to stream your own games. All you need is a PS Portal and an active PlayStation Plus Premium subscription.</p>
<p>The update will arrive overnight tonight at 2AM on 6th November GMT, or 6PM 5th November on the US West Coast.</p>


<p>Cloud Streaming of your own games lets you stream from Sony’s servers instead of using Remote Play with your console. This has been shown to have some better performance, which seems daft in certain situations, but comes down to the server architecture having been optimised specifically for streaming. By incorporating your digitally owned games into this, it means titles such as Astro Bot, Borderlands 4, Final Fantasy VII Rebirth, Fortnite, Ghost of Yōtei, Grand Theft Auto V, and Resident Evil 4, which are not in the PS Plus library can be streamed.</p>
<p>The announcement notes that this can open up new multiplayer possibilities, such as having another player on your PS5, while you stream from the cloud. It also makes the experience of using the PS Portal away from home better and more reliable – no more remembering to leave your PS5 in standby or telling other family members not to use it.</p>
<p>For a full list of streamable games, visit <a href="http://playstation.com/ps5-game-cloud-streaming">here,</a> where Sony has constructed a really annoying layout with a search bar, instead of just making a list.</p>

<p>Beyond this, the system software of the PS Portal has been given an overhaul.</p>
<p>The refreshed UI presents three options when booting up – remote play, cloud streaming and a cloud streaming search – and cloud streaming now has a dedicated UI. There’s also 3D audio support for streamed games, a passcode lock, and a network status screen for finding a good connection. When you’re in a game, the in-game stores now work, there’s better accessibility options specifically for when streaming games, and game invitations arrive on a system level as well.</p>
<p>All around, this seems like a great update, so long as you have a PS Plus Premium subscription.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/11/05/cloud-streaming-officially-arrives-on-playstation-portal-today-with-new-support-for-digital-ps5-games-in-your-library/">PS Blog</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/05/playstation-portal-gets-full-ps-plus-cloud-streaming-and-you-can-even-stream-your-own-games/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam Deck can now download on the down low with new display-off mode]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/05/steam-deck-can-now-download-on-the-down-low-with-new-display-off-mode/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steam-deck-can-now-download-on-the-down-low-with-new-display-off-mode.1344232/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Valve has added a feature to the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/steam-deck">Steam Deck</a> that you might be surprised wasn’t there all along: Display-Off Downloads. Now, the console can download games with the screen off, entering a new low-power download mode before going to sleep upon completion.</p>
<p>This new mode is now in the Beta and Preview channels of SteamOS, and will be rolled out to all users eventually. At that point, it will be the default mode when the Steam Deck is plugged in to power, and can be enabled when on battery power manually under Settings &gt; Power.</p>


<p>If you’re downloading a game or updates at the time that you press the power button to turn off the Steam Deck, it will prompt if you’d like to continue downloading with the screen off. It will also enter this mode automatically after being idle for some time. While downloading, you’ll be able to check on downloads by waking the screen, and can fully wake or let it continue.</p>
<p>When using this with battery power, the Steam Deck will halt downloads and go to full sleep if the battery drops below 20%.</p>

<p>Display-off downloads are similar in concept to the standby mode downloads and updates that are possible on Xbox, PS5 and Switch, but with SteamOS being built on a branch of Linux, it’s much more like a PC in some of its workings. This is a good step closer to the console experience, when compared to needing to manually enable and enter more basic screen-off modes as with Windows-based handhelds, laptops and PCs.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1675200/view/771930569635267984?l=english">Steam</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/05/steam-deck-can-now-download-on-the-down-low-with-new-display-off-mode/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo makes the Switch 2 its “primary development focus”, as though it wasn’t already]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/05/nintendo-makes-the-switch-2-its-primary-development-focus/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-makes-the-switch-2-its-%E2%80%9Cprimary-development-focus%E2%80%9D-as-though-it-wasn%E2%80%99t-already.1344199/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Nintendo has confirmed that they are shifting to have the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/nintendo-switch-2">Nintendo Switch 2</a> be their “primary development focus” going forward, indicating that cross-gen game releases will become far from the norm after 2026.</p>
<p>The company plainly states that “Going forward, we will shift our primary development focus to Nintendo Switch 2 and expand our business around this new platform.”</p>


<p>It’s a small statement from Nintendo’s latest quarterly financial report, which saw the company announce that the Switch 2 has continued its record-setting launch and has <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/04/the-switch-2-sold-over-10-million-consoles-in-just-4-months/">already sold more than 10 million consoles after just four months</a> – selling faster than the original Switch, PS5 and PS4 through the same time span. With such rapid early momentum, it absolutely makes sense that Nintendo can focus more directly on the new generation of console.</p>
<p>This means that cross-gen games like <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/04/metroid-prime-4-beyond-switch-2-preview-worth-the-wait/">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</a> and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/14/pokemon-legends-z-a-review/">Pokémon Legends: Z-A</a> will remain rare and fleeting. Metroid Prime 4 has been in development for so long (and is a relative niche for Nintendo) that it makes sense for it still to receive a cross-gen release when it arrives in December, while Pokémon always needs to try and reach as large an audience as possible… but then enjoyed <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/24/pokemon-legends-z-a-has-hit-5-8-million-sales-and-half-of-them-are-on-switch-2/">around 50% of its launch sales on the newer system</a>.</p>
<p>2025 has already shown that Nintendo is all-in on the Nintendo Switch 2, launching with <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/12/mario-kart-world-review/">Mario Kart World</a> and with <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/16/donkey-kong-bananza-review/">Donkey Kong Bananza</a> following shortly afterwards. Through the rest of this year, we still have <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/kirby-air-riders">Kirby Air Riders</a> and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/metroid-prime-4">Metroid Prime 4</a> to release as well.</p>

<p>For 2026, it’s also very heavy on the Switch 2 exclusives, with Pokémon Pokopia, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/12/yoshi-and-the-mysterious-book-announced-for-switch-2/">Yoshi and the Mysterious Book</a>, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/10/splatoon-raiders-is-a-fresh-switch-2-exclusive-spinoff-and-theres-a-big-update-for-splatoon-3-too/">Splatoon Raiders</a>, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/12/mario-tennis-fever-swings-onto-switch-2-in-february/">Mario Tennis Fever</a> and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/12/fire-emblem-fortunes-weave-revealed-for-nintendo-switch-2/">Fire Emblem: Fortune’s Weave</a> all announced for next year. They’re also continuing to announce and release Switch 2 Edition upgrades for Switch games, with <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/30/animal-crossing-new-horizons-switch-2-edition-revealed/">Animal Crossing: New Horizons</a> and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/12/super-mario-bros-wonder-nintendo-switch-2-edition-is-coming-next-year/">Super Mario Wonder</a> both enhancing and expanding two big hits for the newer hardware.</p>
<p>That said, there are still some titles coming to original Switch, including Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream, Rhythm Heaven Groove, and Pokémon Champions – all games that benefit from as large a potential audience as possible.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/pdf/2025/251105e.pdf">Nintendo</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/05/nintendo-makes-the-switch-2-its-primary-development-focus/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>