<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 20:44:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age: The Veilguard will not get any expansions]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/11/04/dragon-age-the-veilguard-will-not-get-any-expansions/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-the-veilguard-will-not-get-any-expansions.1027245/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/11/04/dragon-age-the-veilguard-will-not-get-any-expansions/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Dragon Age: Inquisition was supported with no less than eight DLC packs but you will not be getting a single one for Dragon Age: The Veilguard. The news was confirmed in an interview with Rolling Stone who say Bioware have now moved all their staff on to working on the next Mass Effect game.</p>
<p>Dragon Age: The Veilguard – <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/06/dragon-age-the-veilguard-dreadwolf-single-player/">previously known as Dragon Age 4 and then as Dragon Age: Dreadwolf</a> – is the long-awaited return of one of BioWare’s most popular RPG series. The game is currently sitting at ratings of 70 for the PC version, 84 for the PS5 version, and 93 for the Xbox version over on <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/dragon-age-the-veilguard/">Metacritic,</a> our review is still in progress.</p>


<p>The next Mass Effect title was teased back on N7 Day, 7th November 2022, when Bioware said “Pre-production development has been proceeding very well. The team, comprised of Mass Effect franchise veterans as well as some amazing new additions to BioWare™, has grown steadily! They’ve been hard at work crafting new characters and locations that you’ll love, as well as revisiting many that you’ll remember.”</p>
<p>The game is set to follow on the from the original trilogy and will be a single player game.&nbsp; In the interview with Rolling Stone veteran Bioware creative director John Epler notes that while he likes multiplayer games, they are very hard to make.</p>
<p>“It’s possible to tell a strong story in a multiplayer game.<em>&nbsp;Final Fantasy XIV </em>does an excellent job,” he said. “Multiplayer also introduces some complications around world states. I make a giant choice in my world, and the world changes.” For games like <em>Dragon Age</em>, the consequences of a player’s choice are intended to impact the narrative moving forward, but for a multiplayer game, it isn’t quite as simple. For example, one player could choose to save a certain person from their fate while another could do the opposite.”</p>


<p>“It’s funny, because the games I play the most on my personal time are actually multiplayer games,” he says. “But when it comes to crafting these worlds and crafting the experiences, I love the focus that single-player can give you.”</p>
<p>With N7 day just round the corner, maybe we will get an update then.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming/dragon-age-the-veilguard-john-epler-interview-1235147001/">Rolling Stone</a> / <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/dragon-age-the-veilguard/">Metacritic</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Test Drive Unlimited Solar Crown players to get free Porsche and stickers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/11/04/test-drive-unlimited-solar-crown-porsche-stcikers-dlc-free/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/test-drive-unlimited-solar-crown-players-to-get-free-porsche-and-stickers.1027194/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/11/04/test-drive-unlimited-solar-crown-porsche-stcikers-dlc-free/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Nacon and studio KT Racing have announced&nbsp; free in-game items for those who purchased and played Test Drive Unlimited Solar Crown before the first major patch which was released on &nbsp;September 30th 2024.&nbsp; The goodies are compensation as the game suffered server issues when it launched with a reported 55% of players failing to log in to the game.</p>
<p>“NACON and studio KT Racing have decided to offer them two unique items: an exclusive special edition of the&nbsp;1986 Porsche 911 Carrera Coupe custom-built as an&nbsp;“Adventurer” edition, fully equipped for the island’s off-road roads, as well as a pack of 5 exclusive stickers for customizing their cars,” said Nacon in a press release.&nbsp; “This compensation will be offered to all players who played Test Drive Unlimited Solar Crown before the arrival of the first major patch, which was released on September 30. These items will be automatically added to players’ inventories in December, for the opening of Season 2.”</p>


<p>Tomorrow, Tuesday, November 5th, the second patch will be released. “This update primarily focuses on graphical enhancements for PS5,” comment Nacon. “The patch also optimizes game performance on PC and Xbox Series. Additionally, it includes network upgrades, improved peripheral compatibility, and numerous bug fixes.”</p>
<p>“We understand your frustration, given the difficulties that have been encountered during the launch of TDUSC. We are sorry for this situation and we want to acknowledge your concerns. We genuinely appreciate your patience and commitment to Test Drive Unlimited Solar Crown.”</p>

<p>In our <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/09/13/test-drive-unlimited-solar-crown-review/">Test Drive Unlimited Solar Crown review</a>,&nbsp; Stefan said, “After years and years of waiting, Test Drive Unlimited is back. Kind of. Solar Crown is an open world racer for gamers who don’t need constant gratification, but can be patient and work toward a key unlock and crowning car. It’s just a shame that the game at launch will require patience while KT Racing fix, improve and hopefully expand it to meet more of its potential.”</p>
<p><iframe title="Test Drive Unlimited Solar Crown | Launch Dev Diary &amp; Next Steps" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/k2I14V-HqOA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><em>Source: Press Release / <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1249970/view/4505380324428942357">Steam</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>