<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 06:32:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NBA 2K24 servers are being shut down today]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/01/nba-2k24-servers-are-being-shut-down-today/</link>
            <guid>1395265</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>It is the start of a new year which means one thing! That thing is the annual ceremony of an NBA 2K servers being switched off. From now on, January 1st 2026, all online functionality for NBA 2K24 has been switched off. That means no more multiplayer, MyCareer or MyTeam but modes that don’t require an internet connection like MyNBA and Play Now are still playable. NBA 2K24 was released on September 8th, 2023 and was removed from sale in October 2025.</p>
<p><iframe title="NBA 2K24 | Official Gameplay Trailer | 2K" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GITzbGIiNKg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>NBA 2K’s support page states, <em>“As of January 1, 2026, you’ll no longer be able to play multiplayer games or access any online game modes. MyCAREER and MyTEAM will no longer be available, and it will no longer be possible to earn Virtual Currency (VC). While you will still be able to enjoy Play Now, MyNBA, The W, and MyWNBA, any features that require a connection to 2K servers will be unavailable. This includes multiplayer, Online Leagues, and community sharing. We thank you for being a part of our community and hope you continue to enjoy&nbsp;NBA 2K!”</em></p>
<h2><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/09/17/nba-2k24-review/">NBA 2K24 Review</a></h2>
<p>In our NBA 2K24 review I wrote, <em>“Regardless of what this review says, NBA 2K24 will sell millions of copies, and generate millions of dollars through VC. That is because basketball fans who want to play a basketball game have nowhere else to go. The on court action is really good, but without competition to keep them honest, 2K’s monetisation has got out of hand and made modes like MyCareer near unplayable without extra investment from players.”</em></p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://support.nba2k.com/hc/en-us/articles/44273523230611-NBA-2K24-Server-Sunset">2K Support</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/01/nba-2k24-servers-are-being-shut-down-today/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>