<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 03:24:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dive into underwater horror Dark Mass, coming to PC, PS5, and Xbox Series XS]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/20/dive-into-underwater-horror-dark-mass-coming-to-pc-ps5-and-xbox-series-xs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dive-into-underwater-horror-dark-mass-coming-to-pc-ps5-and-xbox-series-xs.1140840/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/20/dive-into-underwater-horror-dark-mass-coming-to-pc-ps5-and-xbox-series-xs/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Developer Path Games has announced its next game and it is called Dark Mass. Much like its previous game Insomnis, Dark Mass is a first person horror title but it swaps a regular, land based mansion for a manor that is deep underwater in the middle of the sea. How did it get there? Well, that’s one of the mysteries. The announcement trailer gives a sense of what to expect in this unusual deep sea dive.</p>
<p><iframe title="Dark Mass - Announcement Trailer | 4K" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/j2sv9NAia24?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Dark Mass puts you in the role of deep sea explorer Alice who, along with her brother Reed, set off to to explore a ship wreck. However, they instead find the out of place manor that still retains much of its identity, despite being on the sea bed. Alice soon becomes trapped within the manor and has to solve its puzzle and avoid the horrors that still inhabit the house, including the monster Silas, who stalks Alice through the manor. Throughout the story, Alice maintains contact with Reed, who is on the boat, through a walkie talkie. Navigating through the manor will be slow at times as Alice’s movement is impacted by the deep sea currents. The story will have multiple choices with these leading to different endings.</p>
<p>A release date for Dark Mass is yet to be confirmed, but it is expected at some point this year.</p>
<p><em>Source: Press Release</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>