<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 15:09:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Octopath Traveler 0 is a HD-2D prequel coming to Switch & Switch 2 this year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/31/octopath-traveler-0-is-a-hd-2d-prequel-coming-to-switch-switch-2-this-year/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/octopath-traveler-0-is-a-hd-2d-prequel-coming-to-switch-switch-2-this-year.1258299/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Square Enix wasn’t content to reveal just one HD-2D game, and has also announced Octopath Traveler 0, a prequel to the title that originated this art style, which is coming to Nintendo Switch and Switch 2 on 4th December this year.</p>
<p><iframe title="OCTOPATH TRAVELER 0 – Announcement trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/klKrQZXDWkI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>“Embark on an adventure of your own creation,” reads the trailer blurb. “Start from zero in a quest of restoration and retribution! Confront powerful villains and rebuild your hometown in OCTOPATH TRAVELER 0 – a new entry in the HD-2D series.”</p>
<p>For the first time, you’ll be able to create your protagonist in this series, but will still be gathering a large party of fellows to journey with you.</p>
<p>There’s also a new town-building side to the game, which is glimpsed in just moments from the trailer, which could be really interesting.</p>

<p>We loved the last game in the series, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/02/17/octopath-traveler-2-review/">Octopath Traveler II</a>, with Reuben saying “Octopath Traveler II manages to improve on almost every aspect of its predecessor, whether they needed it or not. The exploration is deeper with more nooks and crannies to nose your way through. The combat is far more intricate, giving greater options to build your party and skillset, and a large degree of player choice. The visuals are absolutely beautiful, and the sound design is phenomenal once again. Honestly, Octopath Traveler II has basically negated the need to play the first title, and I cannot think of higher praise.”</p>
<p>Elsewhere, Square Enix also revealed <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/31/the-adventures-of-elliot-is-a-new-hd-2d-adventure-for-switch-2-and-theres-a-demo-out-today/">The Adventures of Elliot: The Millennium Tales</a>, a Switch 2 exclusive branch of the HD-2D visual style, embracing it for an action RPG.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/31/octopath-traveler-0-is-a-hd-2d-prequel-coming-to-switch-switch-2-this-year/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cronos: The New Dawn is coming out in September, and it’s also for Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/31/cronos-the-new-dawn-is-coming-out-in-september-and-its-also-for-switch-2/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cronos-the-new-dawn-is-coming-out-in-september-and-it%E2%80%99s-also-for-switch-2.1258212/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Bloober Team popped into the Nintendo Direct Partner Showcase to reveal that their upcoming sci-fi horror game Cronos: The New Dawn will be coming to <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/nintendo-switch-2">Nintendo Switch 2</a>, right alongside PS5, Xbox Series X|S and PC. And it’s coming out soon, with release now confirmed for 5th September.</p>
<p><iframe title="Cronos: The New Dawn – Nintendo Direct: Partner Showcase 7.31.2025" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/91BaLCOQa24?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/17/bloober-team-reveal-cronos-the-new-dawn/">Announced last October</a>, Cronos: The New Dawn’s takes place in a post-apocalyptic rendition of 1980s Poland. This is the home to a survival horror adventure with some hefty helpings of sci-fi and time travel. You’ll play as a time-hopping Traveller, going back through time rifts to try and extract people who didn’t survive the apocalypse. Some of the most notable inspirations include the Dead Space franchise and the movie Twelve Monkeys. The Traveller’s own suit takes its inspiration from older deep sea diving suits, alluding to the theme of diving through time to save people.</p>
<p>Bloober Team have really ramped up the trailers and reveals lately, posting a good 35-minute gameplay reveal alongside previews, just yesterday!</p>
<p><iframe title="Cronos: The New Dawn | 35-minute Gameplay" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UmgnABPqaoU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>




<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/31/cronos-the-new-dawn-is-coming-out-in-september-and-its-also-for-switch-2/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Go camping on Switch 2 with Chillin by the Fire today]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/31/go-camping-on-switch-2-with-chillin-by-the-fire-today/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/go-camping-on-switch-2-with-chillin-by-the-fire-today.1258206/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Chillin by the Fire has been revealed for <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/nintendo-switch-2">Nintendo Switch 2</a>, a new social experience that’s all about going camping, stoking your fire and hanging out with the faces of your friends.</p>
<p><iframe title="Chillin' by the Fire – Nintendo Direct: Partner Showcase 7.31.2025" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DKrZUZCDRaA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>You’ll have to construct your fire properly, chopping up wood and building a stack to set alight, and then ensuring that you add logs in a way that adds fuel, but still allows oxygen to circulate and build a roaring flame. Make sure you’re not adding wet logs, as well, and you can master getting a fire going in both rainy and snowy conditions.</p>
<p>Since you’ll need a little patience, you’ll be able to roast marshmallows and set off fireworks, but the real time sink will be playing with friends, who can appear as giant floating head bubbles, making use of the Switch 2 camera.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/31/go-camping-on-switch-2-with-chillin-by-the-fire-today/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment gets a new trailer, but no release date…]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/31/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-gets-a-new-trailer-but-no-release-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-gets-a-new-trailer-but-no-release-date%E2%80%A6.1258200/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Nintendo and Koei Tecmo have revealed that Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment, the musou spin-off prequel to <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/05/11/the-legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-review/">Tears of the Kingdom</a>, is coming to <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/nintendo-switch-2">Switch 2</a> this winter – no, they’re still not revealing the release date.</p>
<p><iframe title="Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment – A call to arms (Nintendo Switch 2)" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/03rjAKsUbNk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>The game will follow the narrative of The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom, which saw Zelda transported back in time to the distant past and the formation of Hyrule and the Imprisoning War.</p>
<p>The new trailer showcases plenty of the Musou action, with some team up powers while cutting through hordes of enemies, and more. It also ended with an intriguing teaser of a humanoid construct coming to life.</p>
<p>The last game in this spin-off series, Hyrule Warriors: Age of Calamity, told a prequel story to The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild, depicting the grand battle to try (and fail) to save Hyrule from the rising evil forces. When the main Zelda series has always been about delving into dungeons and defeating bosses one-by-one, it’s a great change of pace to see the huge wars between the massed forces of good and evil.</p>

<p>In <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2020/11/18/hyrule-warriors-age-of-calamity-review/">our review of that last game</a>, we said, “Age of Calamity is, for all intents and purposes, a prequel to Breath of the Wild. It might be a spin-off in a separate genre, but it’s clearly a labour of love, and the result is a thoroughly enjoyable romp through one of the most interesting periods of Hyrule. If the first game was a love letter to the Zelda series, this not only improves on this concept in every way, but stands as one of the best Zelda games, period.”</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/31/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-gets-a-new-trailer-but-no-release-date/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>