<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 10:22:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Forza Horizon 5 is coming to PS5 this spring]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/31/forza-horizon-5-is-coming-to-ps5-this-spring/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/forza-horizon-5-is-coming-to-ps5-this-spring.1096710/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/31/forza-horizon-5-is-coming-to-ps5-this-spring/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Another mainstay Xbox franchises is coming to PlayStation, With <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/forza-horizon-5">Forza Horizon 5</a> set to release for PS5 this spring.</p>
<p>The port is being developed by Panic Button in collaboration with Turn 10 Studios and Playground Games, and will be like-for-like in terms of content with all the previously released car pack, and the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2022/07/27/forza-horizon-5-hot-wheels-review/">Hot Wheels</a> and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/02/24/forza-horizon-5-rally-adventure-expansion-revealed/">Rally Adventure</a> expansions also available.</p>


<p>This follows on from comments by Xbox boss Phil Spencer, who said in the last few weeks that “To keep games off other platforms… it’s not a path for us.” This certainly tied in with <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/10/rumours-suggest-more-xbox-games-will-be-coming-to-ps5-and-switch/">the latest rumours</a> that had other core Xbox franchises like <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/halo-the-master-chief-collection">Halo</a>, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/gears-of-war-e-day">Gears of War</a> and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag-microsoft-flight-simulator">Microsoft Flight Simulator</a> potentially coming to PlayStation, and with Bethesda’s <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/23/doom-the-dark-ages-release-date-confirmed-for-may/">Doom: The Dark Ages</a> and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/02/05/rumours-grow-of-starfield-indiana-jones-more-xbox-games-coming-to-ps5/">Indiana Jones</a>, and Obsidian’s <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/13/the-outer-worlds-2-is-coming-to-ps5-as-well-as-pc-and-xbox-in-2025/">The Outer Worlds 2</a> already confirmed.</p>
<p><iframe title="Forza Horizon 5 Review (Xbox Series X in 4K 60fps)" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KEl0KBy5I-U?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Forza Horizon 5 is the latest in Playground Games’ spectacular open world arcade racing spin-off to the main Forza Motorsport series. Where previous games took us to Australia and the UK, Forza Horizon 5 takes players to a gorgeous approximation of Mexico, really showcasing the variety of environments that you can find in the country.</p>

<p>Originally released in late 2021 across Xbox Series X|S, Xbox One and PC, t<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2022/01/26/halo-infinite-20-million-players-forza-horizon-5-18-million-but-how-many-bought-the-games/">he game set records for Xbox Game Pass at the time</a>. It’s over three years old now, and has had countless updates, car packs and a pair of great expansions as well. PlayStation 5 owners are in for a treat when it arrives.</p>
<p>In our <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/11/04/forza-horizon-5-review-xbox-series-x/">Forza Horizon 5 review</a>, we scored the sequel a sublime 9 out of 10 with Dom saying, “Forza Horizon 5 continues the series’ legacy, usurping Forza Horizon 4 as the new pinnacle of open-world racing and as a graphical showcase for the new generation of Xbox console.”</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://forza.net/news/forza-horizon-5-comes-to-ps5">Forza.net</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>