<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 18:31:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No Rest for the Wicked co-op update comes in January with persistent realms, but you can play the beta now]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/21/no-rest-for-the-wicked-co-op-update-comes-in-january-with-persistent-realms-but-you-can-play-the-beta-now/</link>
            <guid>1389628</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Moon Studios has revealed what’s in store for their ambitious action RPG <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/no-rest-for-the-wicked">No Rest for the Wicked</a> and the addition of co-op multiplayer. The studio is forging a rather unique path compared to other top-down action RPGs and Soulslikes, with persistent realms you can share with other players.</p>
<p>The No Rest for the Wicked co-op update will arrive on 22nd January in full, but is <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1371980/view/496089445472142295">currently in an open beta on Steam</a>. <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1371980/view/496089445472142770">That beta has now been extended to conclude on 5th January</a>, so you can play all through the holiday.</p>
<p><iframe title="No Rest for the Wicked Together | Co-op update | Wicked Inside Showcase 4" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ayIqY6Sszcw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>So what’s the benefits and reason to Moon Studios’ approach? Well, as outlined in the latest dev diary, there’s a distinct lack of permanence to a multiplayer session in many Soulslikes, and shared online spaces in games like Diablo 4 and Destiny have little meaning to them, just other people running around. But there’s something special about having clanmates to hang out with in an MMO, and so No Rest for the Wicked is blending all of this together.</p>
<p>No Rest for the Wicked will let you convert any single player realm into a multiplayer one, making it a fully online and persistent instance of the game world. Within this you can have up to four players, and you can share this space fully with characters tied to the realm, or bring characters in from other realms. Being persistent, you don’t need a host player to be online, and so anyone can hop in, harvest materials, level up their character, buy property, and go to complete main quests.</p>

<p>That obviously means that you do need to have a trusting relationship with the other players in your realm. The video showcases some of the shenanigans you can get up to, as studio director Thomas Mahler buys up a ton of property through farming progress and then trying to flip the property to the others, and then those others getting a little bit of revenge.</p>
<p>For the more moment-to-moment action, Moon Studio also outline how you can really work together in play, having front line character, ranged builds and healers that can be great for tackling an imposing boss together. At the same time, enemy AI has been adapted to understand more about player positioning, able to react to flanking moves, or exhibiting some new attacks that you won’t see in single player.</p>
<p>For the game as a whole, vendors will now have fresh gear to sell cycling in and out of their shops. Enchantments have been overhauled and higher level items get better rolls – but you now have limited rerolls – while weapons can now deal crit damage, and have random Facets to provide different stats. Socketing gems will now give fixed improvements, but there’s now higher tier gems. Exhalting (a bit like prestiging an item) needs you to have completely maxed out your item first, boosting a random item in a particular category multiple times.</p>
<p>All enemies are now back-stabbable in combat (if you’re good enough), and bows have been enhanced with a new off-hand Quiver to introduce different arrow types (like blasting, explosive arrows).</p>
<p>Oh, and for the high difficulty sickos out there, the highest difficulty now has more enemies than before.</p>
<p>The game has come through a difficult year, with Moon Studios having to <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/11/moon-studios-is-now-self-publishing-no-rest-for-the-wicked-after-split-with-take-two/">split off from publisher Private Division and go it solo</a>, and with <a href="https://www.thegamer.com/moon-studios-no-rest-for-the-wicked-review-bomb-studio-closure/">Mahler having a weird moment on social media</a>. Since entering Early Access in early 2024, progress has also been steady as opposed to blistering, but with <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/30/the-breach-update-is-out-today-for-no-rest-for-the-wicked/">a big update earlier this year</a>, and now the imminent addition of multiplayer (which will certainly have been a mountain to overcome), the future for this game is rather encouraging.</p>
<p>No Rest for the Wicked is out now in Steam Early Access, with PS5 and Xbox Series X|S versions planned for when it’s good and ready.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ayIqY6Sszcw">YouTube</a>, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1371980/view/496089445472142295">Steam</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/21/no-rest-for-the-wicked-co-op-update-comes-in-january-with-persistent-realms-but-you-can-play-the-beta-now/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game of the Year 2025 – Best Original Soundtrack]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/21/game-of-the-year-2025-best-original-soundtrack/</link>
            <guid>1389610</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Music really has become a huge part of modern gaming, the best examples not just elevating the game as you play it, but sticking with you as the original compositions lodge themselves in your mind to emerge while you’re doing the dishes, waiting in line at the supermarket or other incongruous moments.</p>
<p>The difficulty with game music is just how varied it is. There’s sweeping orchestral scores, there’s jazzy chip tunes, there’s songs, there’s ambient music, regional influence and soundtracks that look to encompass hundreds of years of history.</p>
<p>For us, as we tried to consume as many soundtracks as we could this year, there were some clear standouts, but we had to pick one.</p>



<p>Of all the great video game music created this year, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/25/ghost-of-yotei-review/">Ghost of Yotei’s</a> really hits the high notes – this lacklustre pun absolutely intended. Composed by Toma Otowa, a multi-award-winning film and video game composer, the sweeping and beautiful compositions that accompany the player bring to life the world of Ghost of Yotei through a rich and culturally textured score.</p>

<p>What sets Tomo’s work apart for Ghost of Yotei is the attention to detail, seamlessly blending traditional Japanese instruments (like shamisen, shakuhachi, biwa, and Ainu instruments such as tonkori and mukkuri) with Western influences. There’s even a delightful smattering of spaghetti western-style elements to the score, a perfect fit for the revenge story of protagonist Atsu. Overall, a unique cultural fusion is blended, managing to complement the bombastic gore-soaked action whilst also providing the quiet melancholy that underpins the sorrow-tinged beats of Atsu’s emotional journey.</p>
<p><em>– Ade</em></p>
<h3>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 – Runner Up</h3>
<p>It’s rare that I listen to a game’s soundtrack when I’m not actively playing the game, but then again <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/05/clair-obscur-expedition-33-review/">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a> is a rare game. If you were to listen to the somber, melancholly of “Gustave” or the beautiful violins of “Firecamp – Sciel,” you might be surprised later when you hear “In Lumiere’s Name,” a tango for a battle with a mime, or “Is it a Gestral or a Volleyball?” which is at least as silly as it sounds. They could be from completely different games – though both French, obviously. Or perhaps the epic distorted guitars of “Une vie à peindre” would be more of a surprise?</p>
<p>Much like the rest it, the soundtrack of Expedition 33 is emotional, whimsical, silly, heavy, and French all at once. The soundtrack is as varied as it could possibly be, from slow, morosely beautiful, smaller tracks perfect for the dramatic brooding over the most recent unbelievable revelations, all the way up to the huge heavy hitting boss battles that really get your heart pounding when you need to try and keep focused on parrying and dodging. Frankly, it’s a delight all the way through. It’s clear that composer Lorien Testard poured a lot of love into this soundtrack and it shows as, truly, one of the best I’ve experienced ever.</p>
<p><em>– Gamoc</em></p>
<h3>Skate Story –&nbsp;Runner Up</h3>
<p>How do you soundtrack a game about a glass skateboarding demon on their way to eat the moon? If you’re Sam Eng and you’re making <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/08/skate-story-review-the-grind-of-a-lifetime/">Skate Story</a>, you draft in an entire indie band and let them loose on your gorgeous, existential exploration of the underworld. There’s a lot of leeway in what that might sound like, but with the neon, crystal-infused, ephemeral visuals, it made sense to bring electronica, synth, and a retro-modern outlook that speaks to the 1980s as much as it does the 2020s.</p>
<p>This is a true album too. Skate Story Vol.1 is an auditory journey that’s as essential as the game it soundtracks, and you’ll find yourself travelling back to the half-places and looming edifices of the demon’s journey as you sink ever further into Blood Cultures’ retro-pop.</p>
<p><em>– Dom</em></p>
<p><strong>Honourable Mentions</strong> (in alphabetical order)</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/31/europa-universalis-v-review/">Europa Universalis 5</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/27/fresh-tracks-review/">Fresh Tracks</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/10/south-of-midnight-review/">South of Midnight</a></strong></li>
</ul>
<p>That’s this weekend’s awards wrapped up. Join us again tomorrow for another gong, just not a musical one.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/21/game-of-the-year-2025-best-original-soundtrack/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>