<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 18:25:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ultimate Sheep Raccoon is a bike racing sequel to Ultimate Chicken Horse]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/11/ultimate-sheep-raccoon-is-a-bike-racing-sequel-to-ultimate-chicken-horse/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ultimate-sheep-raccoon-is-a-bike-racing-sequel-to-ultimate-chicken-horse.1058208/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/11/ultimate-sheep-raccoon-is-a-bike-racing-sequel-to-ultimate-chicken-horse/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Clear Endeavour Games has revealed Ultimate Sheep Raccoon, their bike racing party game successor to <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/ultimate-chicke-horse">Ultimate Chicken Horse</a> set to launch in 2025.</p>
<p><iframe title="Ultimate Sheep Raccoon Reveal Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/J4hC8GudgBU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Similar to Ultimate Chicken Horse, you’re all in a race to survive and reach the finish line of a level, replaying it multiple times to decide a winner… except that between each round players are able to lay deadly traps and modify the level, making it harder and harder to survive.&nbsp;Ultimate Sheep Raccoon, however, puts you all on bikes instead of having you platform around – it’s a bit more Trials-like in that regard, and you can earn bonus points for pulling off tricks.</p>
<p>Helping you survive will be power-ups, including jetpacks, parachutes to glide, bouncy mines to off your rivals, and more. Helping to make things utterly awful and hilarious are all of the traps and level parts, whether it’s adding rails, ramps and bouncy pads, or pendulums, spikes and laser-emitting TVs.</p>
<p>There’s returning characters in the form of Chicken, Horse, Sheep and Racoon, as well as a bunch of new barnyard animals… because this game support up to 8 players! There’s local, online and cross-platform multiplayer, so anyone and everyone can hop into the game together.</p>

<p>For now, though, the only confirmed platform is PC, and you can wishlist on Steam.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>