<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - thesixthaxis_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for thesixthaxis_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 11:09:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ludocene: the new app that reimagines game discovery]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/20/ludocene-the-new-app-that-reimagines-game-discovery/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ludocene-the-new-app-that-reimagines-game-discovery.1223772/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/20/ludocene-the-new-app-that-reimagines-game-discovery/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p><a href="https://www.ludocene.com/">Ludocene</a>, a new, self-styled dating app for video games, is aiming to tackle an age-old (albeit first world) problem. We’ve all been there, flicking through tatty, overstuffed CD wallets or irritably browsing digital storefronts, not really knowing what we want to play next. The unending influx of new releases doesn’t help with 19,000 titles being added to Steam alone in 2024. That sense of choice paralysis is only exacerbated further when you factor in the hoard of complimentary games shotgunned into players’ libraries on a monthly basis thanks to <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/playtstation-plus">PlayStation Plus</a>, <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/xbox-game-pass">Xbox Game Pass</a>, and other services such as <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/netflix">Netflix</a> and <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/apple-arcade">Apple Arcade</a>.</p>
<p><iframe title="Ludocene Kickstarter Video" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sRkvfG-1et8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Ludocene wants to cut through the noise in a way that’s personalised and playful. Currently in its testing stage, the innovative web app invites users to grab a seat at its virtual table, offering them a series of cards from its ginormous deck. Each card represents a video game, complete with a blurb, trailer, and even a handy store link should you want to make a purchase. Much like a dating app, Ludocene will ask you to keep cards or discard them, each swipe helping to narrow the results of its recommendation engine.</p>


<p>While storefronts such as Steam do a passable job of suggesting similar games to what you’ve been playing, it doesn’t account for changing tastes or the fact that sometimes we want to try something completely different from the game we’ve just finished. For instance, after wrapping up <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> and <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/assassins-creed-shadows">Assassin’s Creed Shadows</a>, I wanted to play something much shorter and less demanding.</p>

<p>So, I set about swiping and quickly landed on one of TSA’s all-time favourites, <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/journey">Journey</a>. Dropping it into the “Played Favourites” box prompted Ludocene to deal me similar cards such as <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/abzu">ABZU</a> and <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/the-pathless">The Pathless</a>, as well as games I’d seemingly forgotten about like Season: A Letter to the Future. I was also presented with more obscure indie titles like Two Falls, Webfishing, and Feather, and even upcoming releases, with Sword of the Sea being the top pick.</p>
<p><iframe title="Ludocene - Game Suggestions From People You Trust" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cdyh0Mc9TXg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Once you’re satisfied with the pool of cards you’ve curated you can save it and start a new “run” from scratch. This time around, instead of smaller, zen-like experiences I wanted to play an arcade racer on PS5; filtering out driving sims and Mario Kart clones I finally landed on Split/Second. While Ludocene is great for finding new and lesser known titles, it also encourages the rediscovery of games we might already own or have played in the past. Minutes later, I was drifting through collapsing cityscapes thanks to the game being part of Sony’s streamable PlayStation Plus classics catalogue. It would be great if Ludocene’s cards could indicate whether a game is currently available via subscription services though I imagine that curating an updated database of store links and updated prices is already suitably challenging.</p>
<p>With that said, there are special theme cards you can add to your deck that augment your results if, say, you want to specifically see games being offered as part of a Netflix subscription. There are expert cards too with Ludocene assembling an Avengers-like team of tastemakers from across the gaming industry. Given the current state of games journalism – with publications closing up shop and Google directing eyeballs towards sloppy AI summaries instead of actual articles – it’s great to feel a sense of connection with actual humans giving their honest opinions.</p>
<p>So, how do you get Ludocene? For instant access to a fully-functioning prototype, you can make a late pledge <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/ludocene">over on Kickstarter</a> with a wider release planned for September 2025.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What We Played – Raidou Remastered, Rematch & FBC: Firebreak]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/20/what-we-played-raidou-remastered-rematch-fbc-firebreak/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what-we-played-%E2%80%93-raidou-remastered-rematch-fbc-firebreak.1223757/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/20/what-we-played-raidou-remastered-rematch-fbc-firebreak/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>The release of a new console is then spent burning through as many of the launch titles as humanly possible. That’s even more true if you’re us, and the days and nights at TSA Towers have been spent blearily looking at the differences between docked and undocked performance, and trying out all our old games to see if they run better (they do!). I’m genuinely really happy to have a console that is a Switch but better, and it’s made a big jump towards what we expect from current gen consoles and handhelds. I’ve been playing a heap of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/17/rune-factory-guardians-of-azuma-is-an-amazing-experience-on-switch-2-but-its-not-perfect/">Rune Factory: Guardians of Azuma</a>, loads of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/18/street-fighter-6-year-12-fighters-edition-is-a-great-port-on-the-wrong-hardware/">Street Fighter 6</a>, a spot of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/19/hogwarts-legacy-on-switch-2-is-a-transfigurational-new-port/">Hogwarts Legacy</a> and plenty of family Mario Kart World. Me and my wife also embarked on a highly romantic playthrough of The Last of Us Remastered, as we approach our 15 year(!) wedding anniversary. That’s true love.</p>

<p>We’re going to start with <strong>Steve</strong> this week, who’s played a wide range of titles as he hid from the fiery ball in the sky. He tells us, “I cleared the lovely Symphonia on Game Pass (highly recommend for fans of Celeste et al), the clunky but nostalgic Warhammer Space Marine MasterCrafted, finished checking out Next Fest demos and inflated my ridiculous wishlist even more. I also started the excellent Alters (although only played the part I had already done in the demo last year). Finally I got deep into Metroid Zero Mission which is still an astonishingly good game – beginning a full series playthrough to take me up to the launch of Prime 4.”</p>
<p><strong>Miguel</strong> had a busy one, playing <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/19/tron-catalyst-review/">TRON Catalyst</a> for our review, Elden Ring: Nightrein, Synduality: Echo of Ada, and Girls Frontline 2: Exilium!</p>


<p><strong>Gamoc</strong> returned to Atomfall for its Wicked Isle DLC, continued on with Rebellion titles with Zombie Army VR, and then waggled his arms around in Maestro for review. That wasn’t all though, as he tell us, “There was also a bit of Balatro and, miraculously, a few hours of Fallout 4 on my severely under-equipped PC over the weekend. I forgot how awesome mods are and now I don’t want to go back to console.”</p>
<p><strong>Tuffcub&nbsp;</strong> has been wrapping up our upcoming review of Death Stranding 2, but has also been playing Destiny 2, presumably. And do you know what? I’ve downloaded it so I can play it too. I was appalled by the 180Gb install mind you, but the new expansion is free on PlayStation Plus.</p>
<p>Keen for a kick-about, <strong>Aran</strong> has been playing <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/19/rematch-review/">Rematch</a> for review, which has some really interesting ideas on how to handle video game football, and paired that with his old standby, The Witcher 3.</p>

<p><strong>Nic B</strong> has had a heck of a week, reviewing Raidou Remastered: The Mystery of the Soulless Army, Bravely Default: Flying Fairy HD Remaster, and Survival Kids. He’s also been playing through Split Fiction on the Switch 2 (review to come) and finished Mario Kart World. I think he’s probably exhausted, as he told us, “I have no intention of ever sleeping — I am going to go make another coffee, however…”</p>
<p><strong>Jim</strong> has been juggling a few very different games this week. First up was Nobunaga’s Ambition Awakening which he says, “just didn’t hook me in the same way previous instalments have done.” Looking to cross another game off his backlog, he booted up Ancestors: The Humankind Odyssey which didn’t start out well, “I initially found it equal parts dull and frustrating, leading me to wipe the game from my PS5. However, the following day I decided to reinstall and give it another shake. With the help of a few guides (the in-game onboarding is lacking) I’m starting to enjoy the game as my primal tribe of apes gradually learn to explore, communicate, and use tools. To cap it off, I’ve been playing Rematch – the new action footie game from Sifu developer, Sloclap.”</p>
<p><strong>Ade</strong> has been on holiday in the Lake District this week with the family, so that’s meant lots of Mario Kart 8 Deluxe and Rayman Legends on the Switch for evening gaming sessions after an epic walk or two! Sounds perfect!</p>
<p>Meanwhile, <strong>Reuben</strong> has been dealing with the world being a mess by playing a lot of games set ostensibly in post-apocalyptic worlds. He tells us, “I’ve been playing FUGA 3 (review coming shortly), Shin Megami Tensei IV and Stray. The last of which I have finished and didn’t overly enjoy all that much, but SMTIV is an incredible experience, if a little on the long side.”</p>

<p>And finally,&nbsp;<strong>Tef</strong> has been continuing his charge through the Switch 2’s library. This week’s seen Yakuza 0’s hefty cutscenes occupying him, plenty of back and forth to do our Hogwarts Legacy comparison (so he could use that punny headline he thought of weeks ago), and he’s pulling together patched game thoughts as well. Is that enough to do? Hell no! That’s why he’s been playing a bit of Remedy’s quirky co-op shooter spin-off, FBC: Firebreak. It’s an…. unusual game…</p>
<p><em>What about you? What have you played?</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>