<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - www.thesixthaxis.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/thesixthaxis_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for www.thesixthaxis.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 23:07:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil Requiem gets a new trailer, Leon returns to a famous location]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/12/resident-evil-requiem-gets-a-new-trailer-leon-returns-to-a-famous-location/</link>
            <guid>1434301</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Capcom are certainly doing a good of building hype for <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/resident-evil-9-requiem/">Resident Evil Requiem</a> and the latest trailer does just that.&nbsp; Grace Ashcroft and Leon S. Kennedy both feature, along with lots of action, including a return a location you may recognise!</p>
<p><iframe title="Resident Evil Requiem - 4th Trailer | PS5 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/u2jrHzua0jA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>We have had a hands on preview of Resident Evil Requiem <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/26/resident-evil-requiem-preview-action-and-horror-in-perfect-harmony/">which you can read here</a> and have also tried out the Switch 2 version, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/05/resident-evil-requiem-and-pragmata-both-show-what-the-switch-2-is-capable-of/">which you can read about here.</a></p>
<p>The ninth mainline Resident Evil game casts players as Grace Ashcroft who – as RE law dictates – finds herself embroiled in an apocalyptic scenario that has players running a gauntlet of jump scares as they peel back layers of a grander conspiracy. Without the series stalwarts at its heart, we’re getting back to much more horror than action of some entries.</p>
<p>As was eventually the case for Resident Evil Village, Requiem will feature both first person and third person gameplay from the off, looking to make the most of the RE Engine’s latest iteration.</p>

<p>Resident Evil Requiem is launching on 27th February 2026 for PS5, Xbox Series X|S and PC.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u2jrHzua0jA">YouTube</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/12/resident-evil-requiem-gets-a-new-trailer-leon-returns-to-a-famous-location/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kena: Scars of Kosmora revealed for this year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/12/kena-scars-of-kosmora-revealed-for-this-year/</link>
            <guid>1434298</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Sony’s State of Play has kicked off with a brand new game reveal.&nbsp;Kena: Scars of Kosmora is a sequel to 2021’s Kena: Bridge of Spirits and it is being by developed by the same team, Emberlab.</p>
<p><iframe title="Kena: Scars of Kosmora - Announce Trailer | PS5 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/12EQpTwn4lY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>As with all sequels we are promised a bigger and better game than it’s predecessor.</p>
<p><em>“Kena: Scars of Kosmora expands the action, adventure &amp; combat of its award-winning predecessor as the player traverses a vibrant island filled with buried secrets, wandering spirits, epic bosses, and distinct cultures.”</em></p>
<p><em>“Kena, now an accomplished Spirit Guide, travels to the mysterious island of Kosmora seeking a cure for her affliction and to reconnect with a friend from her past. There, she is confronted by a powerful corruption that fractures her staff. Needing it to survive, Kena must accept Kosmora’s forgotten and dangerous form of Spirit Guiding that manipulates the elements. On her journey, Kena discovers and nurtures memorable spirit companions – whose powers she will harness to solve puzzles and defeat enemies using new elemental abilities.”</em></p>

<p>Kena: Scars of Kosmora is coming to PlayStation 5 and PC in 2026.</p>
<p>We gave Kena: Bridge of Spirits <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/09/24/kena-bridge-of-spirits-review-ps5-ps4-pc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">8/10 in our review</a>. “Kena: Bridge of Spirits is a great palette cleanser, not just in terms of tone but the way it’s carefully designed. Well-paced and beautiful to behold with plenty to see and do, Ember Lab has well and truly captured the spirit of the 3D platformers many of us grew up adoring,” said Jim.</p>
<p><em><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=12EQpTwn4lY" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Source: YouTube</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/12/kena-scars-of-kosmora-revealed-for-this-year/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>