<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 22:07:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kick off Pokémon Day 2025 with this gorgeous short film]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/618887/dragonite-and-the-special-delivery-pokemon-day-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kick-off-pok%C3%A9mon-day-2025-with-this-gorgeous-short-film.1119951/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/618887/dragonite-and-the-special-delivery-pokemon-day-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/charles-pulliam-moore">Charles Pulliam-Moore</a> <span>is a reporter focusing on film, TV, and pop culture. Before The Verge, he wrote about comic books, labor, race, and more at io9 and Gizmodo for almost five years.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>It’s technically already Pokémon Day in Japan, and while we’re still a few hours away from <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/616289/pokemon-presents">this year’s big Pokémon Presents showcase</a>, there’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/pokemon/617216/oh-yes-wait-a-minute-mr-postmon">a new animated short film</a> out that right now feels like the perfect way to get pumped up for whatever surprises Nintendo has in store.</p><p>Many of the Pokémon Company’s animated projects outside of the mainline anime have been fun explorations of what people and their pokémon get up to besides battling. But director Maho Aoki’s <em>Dragonite and the Special Delivery</em> also feels like a reminder to thank your mail carriers for all the hard work they do. Produced by CoMix Wave Films — the studio behind <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/4/15/23678724/makoto-shinkai-suzume-interview"><em>Suzume</em></a>, <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/29/21113522/weathering-with-you-review-climate-change-makoto-shinkai">Weathering With You</a></em>, and <em><a href="https://www.polygon.com/2017/4/7/15209584/your-name-love">Your Name</a></em> — <em>Dragonite and the Special Delivery </em>tells the story of Hana (Riko Fukumoto), a young Paldean postal worker who dreams of becoming an expert deliveryperson.</p><p>While most deliverypeople get the chance to venture out into the world, as a letter sorter, Hana’s days are usually spent behind a desk with her partner Fuecoco. But when Hana happens to find an unaddressed letter from a young boy who is trying to wish his traveling father a happy birthday, she recognizes it as an opportunity to prove that she has what it takes to become one of the postal system’s greats like a certain friendly Dragonite.</p><p>The short spotlights how it takes all kinds of specialized human and pokémon labor to keep the inter-regional postal system running smoothly. Unsurprisingly, CoMix Wave’s take on the pokémon world is a visual delight that makes all of the short’s creatures look downright majestic regardless of whether they’re ordinary or legendary monsters. The short also features a sweeping shot of Kalos’ Lumiose City and quite a few pokémon capable of Mega Evolution.</p><div><p>Those details could be a nod to the location and mechanic <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/2/27/24083767/pokemon-legends-z-a-nintendo-switch-2025-launch-date">both returning in <em>Pokémon Legends: Z-A</em></a> (and Flygon<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/pokemon/comments/twzg0f/oc_why_did_flygons_mega_evolution_have_to_be/"> finally getting its due</a>), but we won’t know for sure until tomorrow morning.</p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>