<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:41:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2TB SSD upgrades for Steam Deck are surprisingly cheap]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/gadgets/822070/steam-deck-rog-ally-ssd-2tb-gaming-deal-sale</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/2tb-ssd-upgrades-for-steam-deck-are-surprisingly-cheap.1355926/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTU2Ng=="><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Cameron Faulkner</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is an editor covering deals and gaming hardware. He joined in 2018, and after a two-year stint at Polygon, he rejoined <em>The Verge</em> in May 2025.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Whether you have a Steam Deck handheld, or an Asus ROG Ally (the older, non-Xbox version), you might be considering an upgrade to its internal storage. I’m not talking about microSD cards, which are convenient, but slow. I’m talking about M.2 2230-size SSDs that are significantly faster at reading and writing data. If so, Prime members can run over to <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D61SDZD2?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">Amazon</a> to grab <strong>Crucial’s P310 2TB SSD </strong>while it’s $123.49. It’s just $2 more than its lowest price yet. 1TB SSDs in this form factor usually cost around $80 to $100, depending on the brand, so doubling the storage is a great value. Despite being available for months at around $150, it has recently sold at its original asking price of $239.99.</p><p>The process for upgrading your handheld’s SSD differs depending on the model, and in case you weren’t aware, it involves opening up your handheld. So there’s some challenge and inherent risks of damaging its internals with this process if you aren’t patient. If I was doing this process myself, I’d consult guides at iFixit. Even when equipped with the best guides, it’s possible you may not have the right tools to get the job done. If that’s the case, grabbing <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/aw/d/B0189YWOIO/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">iFixit’s basic 64-bit set for $39.99</a> should be a great companion for this and other tech tinker tasks.</p><div><p id="other-verge-approved-deals"><h2>Other Verge-approved deals</h2></p></div><div><ul><li><span>Last week, we covered an early Black Friday deal on <strong>Meta’s Quest 3S entry-level virtual reality headset</strong>. The 128GB model was $50 off ($249.99), and included a $50 gift card at Best Buy. It was a good value, though it’s over now. <a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8836598/type/dlg/https://www.costco.com/join-costco.html" rel="sponsored">Costco members</a> can score an even better deal on this model right now through November 17th. The 128GB model that includes a full year of Meta Horizon Plus is just $199.99 at <a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8836598/type/dlg/https://www.costco.com/p/-/meta-quest-3s-128gb-with-12-month-meta-horizon-subscription-bundle/4000385949" rel="sponsored">Costco</a>. The Quest 3S contains much of the same internal specs of the pricier Quest 3, but it lags behind in terms of optics and visual fidelity. However, it’s a huge step up compared to the Quest 2.</span></li></ul></div><div><ul><li><span>The <strong>second season of <em>Arcane</em></strong>, the beloved animated series based in the <em>League of Legends</em> universe, just got a nice discount on the 4K Blu-ray version. The gorgeous steelbook that contains four discs, packed with special features going beyond the show, fell from $46 to $37.14 at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Arcane-League-Legends-Limited-Steelbook/dp/B07GQ2XF1M/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">Amazon</a>. Considering that the cost of even one month of Netflix’s 4K service costs a whopping $24.99, get this version instead so you can watch this modern classic whenever you want.</span></li></ul></div><div><ul><li><span>A <a href="https://www.theverge.com/entertainment/820450/red-dead-revived">big, free current-gen update</a> is coming to <strong>Rockstar’s <em>Red Dead Redemption</em></strong> on December 2nd for the PlayStation 5 and Nintendo Switch 2. Thankfully, for those who don’t have the re-release that came out in 2023, you can save on physical editions now. <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0FPRNCXKB/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">Amazon</a> and <a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;mid=24348&amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fvideo-games%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fproducts%2Fred-dead-redemption-with-undead-nightmare-dlc---nintendo-switch%2F399170.html%2F" rel="sponsored">GameStop</a> each have the Switch version for $24.99, while the PS4 edition is the same price at <a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;mid=24348&amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fvideo-games%2Fplaystation-4%2Fproducts%2Fred-dead-redemption-with-undead-nightmare-dlc---playstation-4%2F399330.html" rel="sponsored">GameStop</a>. The game will feature enhanced visuals and better performance after the update. On the Switch 2, it’ll boast some surprising additions, like mouse support, DLSS, HDR, in addition to 60 frames per second gameplay.</span></li></ul></div><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTU2Ng=="><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Cameron Faulkner</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/gadgets/822070/steam-deck-rog-ally-ssd-2tb-gaming-deal-sale]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>