<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 20:28:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Antonblast is an out-of-control platformer with its heart in the ’90s]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/18/24344598/antonblast-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/antonblast-is-an-out-of-control-platformer-with-its-heart-in-the-%E2%80%9990s.1085910/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/18/24344598/antonblast-review<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Antonblast</em> is kind of like playing a zany Saturday morning cartoon. It’s brash, maximalist, and often, you’ll feel like you don’t actually understand what’s happening. Somehow, that chaos gels into something that actually makes sense — and, at times, is even calming.</p><p><em>Antonblast</em> just launched in 2024, but it looks like a long-lost side-scrolling platformer from the 16-bit era of the SNES or Sega Genesis. That’s not just due to the fantastic pixel art. There are fun touches like delightfully ’90s-era character designs and Mode 7-like effects, such as your character splatting against the screen when you die, that really make it feel like a missing classic of the era.</p><p>Summitsphere, <em>Antonblast</em>’s developer, describes the game as a “fast-paced explosive action platformer,” and that’s a good way to summarize how it actually feels to play. It’s sort of what would happen if you put <em>Wario</em>, <em>Sonic,</em> <em>Donkey Kong Country</em>, <em>Crash Bandicoot</em>, <em>The Ren &amp; Stimpy Show</em>, and <em>Rocko’s Modern Life</em> into a blender.</p><div><figcaption><em>Yes, there is grinding.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: Summitsphere</cite></p></div><p>As Anton or Annie, you’ll charge through various enemies and obstacles in your path, sometimes turning into a literal tornado of chaos, to retrieve Spirits (as in drinks) from a villainous Satan, who has stolen and scattered them throughout 12 different levels.</p><p>The levels usually have some kind of gimmick or theme that is explored with an almost Nintendo-like degree of precision. One level frequently turns your character into a pinball. Another features sections where you transform into a bouncing, explosive bomb. One of my favorites was a maze-like bathhouse that, compared to the rest of the game, was eerily quiet. And at the end of nearly every level, you’ll activate a switch that starts a timer and begins a frantic and thrilling run back to the entrance.</p><p>For the most part, <em>Antonblast</em> encourages you to build momentum, like a classic <em>Sonic</em> game. It’s easy to get into a flow state of surging forward, even when things can feel out of control because of how fast you’re going or the amount of stuff onscreen. As I got better at the game, I actually started to feel more chill when things got out of hand. The game was usually leading me in the right direction, and I learned to just accept that things were happening as they should.</p><div><figcaption><em>The boss fights are pretty wild.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: Summitsphere</cite></p></div><p>Occasionally, the game would have some tough platforming or annoyingly placed checkpoints that could take me out of the flow state — also like <em>Sonic</em>. Some of the bosses, which were often epic, screen-filling spectacles, could be frustratingly difficult. Fortunately, though, reloads are quick, which makes those frustrations a bit easier to deal with. The final level and boss are particularly challenging, but if you do get that far, trust me when I tell you that the payoff for seeing them through is worth it.</p><p>Like the ’90s-era cartoons that are its obvious inspirations, <em>Antonblast</em> can be a little loud and immature. There’s literally a button you can press just to have your character scream. But like the best of those shows, its creators clearly had fun making an over-the-top world, and they made it damn fun to play — even when I didn’t know what was going on.</p><p><small>Antonblast<em> is available now on Nintendo Switch and Steam.</em></small></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>