<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - www.theverge.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for www.theverge.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 15:26:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo keeps filling in the gaps]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/games/875986/nintendo-switch-2-release-schedule-mario-tennis-fever</link>
            <guid>1431052</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>When you buy a new Nintendo device, there are a few things you can expect: namely, some excellent <em>Super Mario</em>, <em>Pokémon</em>, and <em>Legend of Zelda</em> games, and maybe a great <em>Animal Crossing</em>, <em>Mario Kart</em>, or <em>Smash Bros</em>. The question mark has always been the <em>other</em> stuff. But with the Switch 2, it doesn’t seem like that will be a problem; its upcoming lineup already seems surprisingly strong.</p><p>There are a few reasons for this optimistic outlook. One is a more reliable output from the company’s seemingly smaller releases, like this week’s launch of <em>Mario Tennis Fever</em>. As with the rest of the series, <em>Fever</em> is to real tennis what <em>Mario Kart</em> is to real racing. Which is to say, it’s ridiculous, adding in all kinds of wacky power-ups and characters that turn it into a chaotic mess that is perfect for playing with friends.</p><p><em>Fever </em>is a robust package. In addition to the basic multiplayer tournaments, there’s a mode where you ascend a tower by taking on challenges, a motion control option that harkens back to the days of <em>Wii Sports</em>, and a single-player mode where Mario has to relearn all of his tennis skills after being turned into a baby.</p><div><p>This all makes <em>Fever</em> the exact kind of game that’s crucial for a platform like the Switch 2: It helps fill in the gaps between bigger releases. The current Switch 2 lineup for 2026 is made up of a similar tier of games, with titles including the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/819926/pokopia-extended-trailer-professor-tangrowth"><em>Pokémon</em> spinoff <em>Pokopia</em></a>, the cross-generation <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/870062/its-animal-crossing-for-sickos">life sim <em>Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream</em></a>, the adorable platformer <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YluJneE1bMo"><em>Yoshi and the Mysterious Book</em></a><em>,</em> and the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/777187/fire-emblem-fortunes-weave-annoucement-trailer">strategy game <em>Fire Emblem: Fortune’s Weave</em></a>.</p></div><div><p>New to this is Switch games being given significant upgrades for Nintendo’s newest hardware. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/863747/animal-crossing-new-horizons-update-3-0-switch-2-quality-of-life">The <em>Animal Crossing: New Horizons</em> community got a reinvigorating boost with the surprise 3.0 update for the game earlier this year</a>, and <em>Super Mario Bros. Wonder</em> is aiming to do something similar with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DVB3hZoOF0A">an upgrade in March</a>.</p></div><p>As Nintendo president Shuntaro Furukawa said during the company’s <a href="https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/pdf/2026/260204e.pdf">most recent earnings results</a>, these kinds of updates are particularly important now during the transitional period between the original Switch and its successor. “It is necessary to regularly release new titles to increase the installed base of new hardware,” he explained. “In addition, we believe it is very important to maintain touchpoints with consumers who are active on our gaming systems as the transition from Nintendo Switch to Nintendo Switch 2 unfolds over the next few years.”</p><p>The other key part to the company’s strategy is third-party support, which has always been an inconsistent part of the Nintendo experience. Despite some games that launched much later compared to other platforms, the original Switch did fairly well on that front, likely due to its overwhelming popularity, and the Switch 2 is headed in a similarly positive direction. Last week’s Nintendo Direct was filled with some of the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/874282/nintendo-direct-february-2026-fallout-ff7">biggest franchises in video games</a>: <em>Fallout</em>, <em>Final Fantasy</em>, <em>Elder Scrolls</em>, and <em>Resident Evil</em>, to name a few. Some of those are older games, of course — <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/11/9/9693246/fallout-4-review-ps4-xbox-pc">I originally reviewed <em>Fallout 4</em> more than a decade ago</a> — but <em>Resident Evil Requiem</em> will be launching on the Switch 2 at the same time as the PS5, Xbox, and PC, which is a good sign.</p><p>We know that there will be big Nintendo games coming eventually. The Switch 2’s first year already included the likes of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games-review/684518/mario-kart-world-review-nintendo-switch-2"><em>Mario Kart World</em></a>, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games-review/707704/donkey-kong-bananza-review-nintendo-switch-2"><em>Donkey Kong Bananza</em></a>, and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/835325/metroid-prime-4-review-nintendo-switch"><em>Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</em></a>. With the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/nintendo/618678/pokemon-presents-2025-all-the-biggest-news-and-trailers">annual</a> Pokémon Day happening later this month, it seems possible that the next mainline <em>Pokémon</em> game will be revealed soon as well. Obviously Mario and Zelda will come at some point; it’s been almost 10 years since <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/26/16552118/super-mario-odyssey-review-nintendo-switch"><em>Super Mario Odyssey</em></a>, the last all-new 3D entry in the series, while <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23718926/zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-review-nintendo-switch"><em>Tears of the Kingdom</em></a> launched three years ago.</p><p>In the past, that lack of clarity around the big franchises would be a cause for concern. But in the Switch 2 era, there’s enough other stuff to play, and that stuff is good enough, that Nintendo isn’t as beholden to the success of those blockbusters. You may buy a Nintendo console for <em>Mario</em> and <em>Zelda</em>, but games like <em>Mario Tennis Fever</em> are what make them platforms worth investing in.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTk3"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Andrew Webster</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/games/875986/nintendo-switch-2-release-schedule-mario-tennis-fever]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>