<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 22:05:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo of America boss Doug Bowser is retiring]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/786068/nintendo-of-america-president-doug-bowser-retirement</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-of-america-boss-doug-bowser-is-retiring.1309305/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTk3"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Andrew Webster</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is an entertainment editor covering streaming, virtual worlds, and every single Pokémon video game. Andrew joined The Verge in 2012, writing over 4,000 stories.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><div><p>One of Nintendo’s most recognizable names is stepping down. Today <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20250925384737/en/Doug-Bowser-Bids-Farewell-to-the-Mushroom-Kingdom">the company announced</a> that the aptly named Doug Bowser, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/21/18235073/nintendo-america-president-reggie-fils-aime-retirement-doug-bowser">who took over as president of Nintendo of America from Reggie Fils-Aimé in 2019</a>, will be retiring. He’ll stay on until the end of the year — December 31st, to be precise — and will be replaced by Devon Pritchard, who currently serves as executive vice president of NoA.</p></div><p>Bowser, who was in charge of sales and marketing before taking over the top job at NoA, was in the role for six years and oversaw a dramatic expansion for Nintendo, which included forays into theme parks and feature films, as well as <a href="https://www.theverge.com/nintendo/643277/nintendo-switch-2-price-tariffs-doug-bowser-interview">the recent launch of the Nintendo Switch 2</a>.</p><p>“One of my earliest video game experiences was playing the arcade version of Donkey Kong,” Bowser said in a statement. “Since that time, all things Nintendo have continued to be a passion for both me and my family. Leading Nintendo of America has been the honor of a lifetime, and I am proud of what our team has accomplished in both business results and the experiences we’ve created for consumers.”</p><p>In addition to promoting Pritchard, who has been with the company since 2006, Nintendo’s American arm will be adding Satoru Shibata as CEO. Shibata currently serves as managing executive officer and corporate director at Nintendo’s headquarters in Kyoto, and will continue on in both roles moving forward. In a statement about the moves, Pritchard said that “Doug has been a fantastic mentor, and I look forward to building on the incredible foundation he has helped establish.”</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTk3"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Andrew Webster</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/786068/nintendo-of-america-president-doug-bowser-retirement]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia is letting anyone use its AI voice animation tech]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/785981/nvidia-audio2face-ai-voice-animation-open-source</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nvidia-is-letting-anyone-use-its-ai-voice-animation-tech.1309302/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="__next"><p><a href="#content"><span>Skip to main content</span></a></p><nav aria-label="Sticky Nav"></nav><div><main id="content"><article><div><div><p>Nvidia is open sourcing Audio2Face, its AI tool that generates facial animations for 3D avatars based on audio input.</p></div><div><div><p>Nvidia is open sourcing Audio2Face, its AI tool that generates facial animations for 3D avatars based on audio input.</p><div><p><span><span>by</span> <!-- --> <span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"></span></span></p><p><span><time datetime="2025-09-25T21:16:23+00:00">Sep 25, 2025, 9:16 PM UTC</time></span></p></div></div><div><p><cite>Image: Cath Virginia / The Verge</cite></p></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTE2"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Emma Roth</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a news writer who covers the streaming wars, consumer tech, crypto, social media, and much more. Previously, she was a writer and editor at MUO.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Nvidia is <a href="https://developer.nvidia.com/blog/nvidia-open-sources-audio2face-animation-model/">open-sourcing Audio2Face</a>, its AI-powered tool that generates realistic facial animations for 3D avatars — all based on audio input. The change means developers can now use the tool and its underlying framework to create realistic 3D characters for their games and apps.</p><p>Nvidia’s <a href="https://docs.omniverse.nvidia.com/audio2face/latest/overview.html">Audio2Face</a> works by analyzing the “acoustic features” of a voice, allowing it to generate animation data that it maps to the 3D avatar’s facial expressions and lip movement. The company notes that developers can use the tool to create 3D characters for pre-scripted content, as well as for livestreams.</p><p>Some developers have already used Audio2Face in their games, including <em>Chernobylite 2: Exclusion Zone</em> creator Farm51, as well as the developers of <em>Alien: Rogue Incursion Evolved Edition.</em></p><p>In addition to open sourcing the Audio2Face models and software development kits, Nvidia is making the tool’s training frame available, allowing users to tweak its models for different use cases.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTE2"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Emma Roth</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><div><form><div><h2>The Verge Daily</h2><p><span>A free daily digest of the news that matters most.</span></p></div></form></div></div></article></main></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/785981/nvidia-audio2face-ai-voice-animation-open-source]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>