<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 23:45:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyber Monday is a great day to buy a 32-inch OLED gaming monitor]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/2/24311328/cyber-monday-oled-gaming-monitor-asus-alienware-msi-lg-deal-sale</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cyber-monday-is-a-great-day-to-buy-a-32-inch-oled-gaming-monitor.1050168/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/2/24311328/cyber-monday-oled-gaming-monitor-asus-alienware-msi-lg-deal-sale<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>If you mostly play games on PC and you’re in the market for a new monitor, there’s a glut of excellent OLED options with significant discounts for <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24309106/best-black-friday-deals-2024-tech-gadgets-cyber-monday">Cyber Monday</a>. Some of the best current models are 32-inch QD-OLED panels with 4K resolution, super-fast 240Hz refresh rate, and the necessary ports to take full advantage of those specs on both PC and consoles (DisplayPort 1.4 and HDMI 2.1, respectively).</p><p>Here’s the rundown on these excellent monitors from <a href="https://us-store.msi.com/Monitors/Gaming-Monitors/MAG-321UPX-QD-OLED?filter=139">MSI</a>, <a href="https://shop.asus.com/us/90lm09t0-b013b0-rog-swift-oled-pg32ucdm.html">Asus</a>, <a href="https://www.jdoqocy.com/click-8836598-14581062?sid=vergebfcm2024&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.lg.com%2Fus%2Fmonitors%2Flg-32gs95uv-w-gaming-monitor">LG</a>, <a href="https://www.kqzyfj.com/click-8836598-15850788?sid=vergebfcm2024&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.hp.com%2Fus-en%2Fshop%2Fpdp%2Fomen-transcend-315-inch-uhd-240hz-oled-gaming-monitor-omen-transcend-32">HP</a>, and <a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8836598/type/dlg/https://www.dell.com/en-us/shop/alienware-32-4k-qd-oled-gaming-monitor-aw3225qf/apd/210-blmq/monitors-monitor-accessories">Alienware</a> — each around the $900 range and saving you up to $450 on their normal prices. </p><div><ul><li>Dell’s <strong>Alienware AW3225QF</strong> is the sole curved option in this list, on sale for $899.99 ($300 off) at <a href="https://howl.link/o5x5d02jjy56l">Best Buy</a> and <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.anrdoezrs.net%2Fclick-8836598-12839518%3Fsid%3Dvergebfcm2024%26url%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Fwww.dell.com%252Fen-us%252Fshop%252Falienware-32-4k-qd-oled-gaming-monitor-aw3225qf%252Fapd%252F210-blmq%252Fmonitors-monitor-accessories">Dell</a>. Just like the others here, it supports 4K resolution (3840 x 2160, 16:9 aspect ratio) and up to 240Hz refresh. It also has DisplayPort, two HDMI 2.1 ports, and four USB ports (three USB-A and one USB-C 3.2 Gen 1).</li><li>The <strong>MSI Mag 321UPX QD-OLED</strong> is $799.99 ($200 off) at <a href="https://howl.link/jo2zwurmm1x74">Best Buy</a> and direct from <a href="https://us-store.msi.com/Monitors/Gaming-Monitors/MAG-321UPX-QD-OLED?filter=139">MSI</a>. It matches many of the same specs, but has a less expansive USB port selection (it has DisplayPort 1.4, 2x HDMI 2.1, and USB-C, but no USB-A ports).</li></ul></div><div><p>The MSI Mag 321UPX is a 32-inch flat gaming monitor using a QD-OLED panel for deep, contrasty black tones and excellent color. The 16:9 monitor supports 4K resolution and up to 240Hz refresh, with an equally speedy 0.03ms response time.</p></div><div><ul><li><strong>LG’s Ultragear 32GS95UE</strong> is selling for $949.99 ($450 off) at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/LG-%E2%80%8E32GS95UV-Ultragear-DisplayHDR-DisplayPort/dp/B0CV1Y7NLT?tag=theverge02-20">Amazon</a> and direct from <a href="https://www.kqzyfj.com/click-8836598-14581062?sid=vergebfcm2024&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.lg.com%2Fus%2Fmonitors%2Flg-32gs95uv-w-gaming-monitor">LG</a> — a new low that it just reached yesterday. The 32GS95UE isn’t the cheapest model here, even on sale, but it’s got the biggest discount. One of its unique qualities is the ability to switch from 4K at 240Hz to 1080p at 480Hz.</li><li>The 32-inch <strong>HP Omen Transcend</strong> matches many of the same core specs as the others above, but it also has KVM support for quick-switching of your peripherals from one device (like your personal desktop) to another (like your work laptop). It’s $999.99 ($300 off) at <a href="https://www.tkqlhce.com/click-8836598-15850788?sid=vergebfcm2024&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.hp.com%2Fus-en%2Fshop%2Fpdp%2Fomen-transcend-315-inch-uhd-240hz-oled-gaming-monitor-omen-transcend-32">HP</a> and <a href="https://howl.link/1xujxwtxdjvvo">Best Buy</a></li><li>The <strong>Asus ROG Swift</strong> <strong>PG32UCDM</strong> is $999.99 ($300 off) direct from <a href="https://shop.asus.com/us/90lm09t0-b013b0-rog-swift-oled-pg32ucdm.html">Asus</a> or backordered at <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1819714-REG%2Fasus_pg32ucdm_32_rog_swift_4k.html">B&amp;H Photo</a> with an expected arrival of December 9th. It’s the other outlier with that handy KVM support, and it also has a total of four USB ports (three USB-A and one USB-C).</li></ul></div><div><p>The Asus ROG Swift PG32UCDM 32-inch OLED supports 4K at up to 240Hz, and its generous port selection also offers KVM support for easily switching your peripherals between two devices.</p></div><p>Personally, I’d either save some money with the MSI or go for the convenience of the built-in KVM on the HP or Asus. They’re pricier, yes, but have you ever looked up prices of quality third-party KVM switches? It ain’t pretty. I’m also not partial to curved monitors, but if that’s your bag then the Alienware becomes the easy choice.</p><p>Feel free to share in the comments if you’re eyeing up any of these or own one yourself and have some thoughts.</p><div><form><div><h2>Verge Deals</h2><p> / <span>Sign up for Verge Deals to get deals on products we've tested sent to your inbox weekly.</span></p></div></form></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roblox tries to skirt app store fees by making Robux worth more on other platforms]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/2/24311337/roblox-robux-app-store-fees-worth-more-party</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/roblox-tries-to-skirt-app-store-fees-by-making-robux-worth-more-on-other-platforms.1050021/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/2/24311337/roblox-robux-app-store-fees-worth-more-party<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Roblox is now incentivizing users to buy its in-game currency, Robux, on platforms that won’t take app store fees. You can now get up to 25 percent more Robux if you purchase the currency through gift cards, on your computer, or on the web, <a href="https://devforum.roblox.com/t/users-can-enjoy-up-to-25-more-robux-on-computer-web-and-gift-cards/3275270">according to a developer forum post</a> from last week.</p><p>As for how that might look in practice, here’s some examples from the post:</p><div><blockquote><p>For example, users who purchase US $9.99 worth of Robux with a gift card, computer, or web would have originally received 800 Robux but will now receive 200 extra Robux or a total of 1000 Robux to spend on passes, in-experience items, and avatar items. Users who purchase a $10 gift card may now receive up to 1000 Robux when previously they would have received 800 Robux.</p></blockquote></div><div><figcaption><em>Roblox’s </em><a href="https://www.roblox.com/upgrades/robux"><em>Robux purchase page</em></a><em> also shows the additional Robux you’ll get by buying on your computer or the web.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: Roblox</cite></p></div><p>Roblox says this isn’t a holiday promotion. “We plan to keep this new pricing in place globally beyond the holiday season,” according to an FAQ in the post. And if you redeem a gift card on a computer or on the web that purchased before the change was announced, you’ll get the higher amount of Robux, too.</p><p>The company gave a very vague answer its own FAQ about why the change only applies to Robux purchased via gift cards, computer, and web:</p><div><blockquote><p><strong>Why is the new pricing only available for gift cards and on computer and web?</strong></p><p>We’re always looking for opportunities to share more with our community, on all platforms and we’ll keep you updated on channels where the opportunity becomes available.</p></blockquote></div><p>But it seems likely that Roblox wants users to buy Robux through those channels to avoid losing money to fees taken by app stores and game console stores. And Roblox isn’t the only company to do something like this; YouTube Premium <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/28/24166546/subscribing-to-stuff-from-your-iphone-is-a-waste-of-money">costs more</a> when you subscribe via the iOS app, for example.</p><p>Today, Roblox also announced its <a href="https://corp.roblox.com/newsroom/2024/12/join-the-party-on-roblox">new Party tool</a> to help users more easily hang out and communicate on the platform. Up to six people can be in a Party, though they only support text chat to start — voice chat will arrive in “the coming months.”</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>