<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 15:50:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia’s AI assistant on Windows now has plugins for Spotify, Twitch, and more]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/654221/nvidia-g-assist-plugins-spotify-twitch-apps</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nvidia%E2%80%99s-ai-assistant-on-windows-now-has-plugins-for-spotify-twitch-and-more.1171308/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/654221/nvidia-g-assist-plugins-spotify-twitch-apps<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/tom-warren">Tom Warren</a> <span>is a senior editor and author of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/notepad-microsoft-newsletter"><i>Notepad</i></a>, who has been covering all things Microsoft, PC, and tech for over 20 years.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Nvidia is updating its G-Assist AI assistant on Windows to take it beyond optimizing game and system settings. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/635155/nvidia-g-assist-ai-assistant-available-download">G-Assist originally launched last month</a> as a chatbot primarily focused on improving PC gaming, but it’s now getting plugin support so you can extend the AI assistant to control Spotify, check if a streamer is live on Twitch, and look at stock or weather updates.</p><p>The new ChatGPT-based <a href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/rtx-ai-garage-g-assist-plugin-builder/">G-Assist plugin builder</a> lets developers and enthusiasts create custom functionality for Nvidia’s AI assistant. G-Assist will be able to connect to external tools and use APIs to expand the capabilities of what Nvidia offers right now.</p><div><p>Nvidia has published <a href="https://github.com/NVIDIA/g-assist">sample plugins on GitHub</a> that can be compiled and used by G-Assist:</p></div><div><ul><li><span><strong>Spotify</strong> — hands-free music and volume control</span></li><li><span><strong>Google Gemini </strong>— allows G-Assist to invoke Gemini for cloud-based complex conversations</span></li><li><span><strong>Twitch</strong> — you can use this plugin to checks if a streamer is live with voice commands like, “Hey, Twitch, is [streamer] live?” </span></li><li><span><strong>Peripheral Controls</strong> — change RGB lighting or fan speed on <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nvidia.com%2Fen-us%2Fsoftware%2Fnvidia-app%2Fg-assist%2F" rel="noreferrer noopener sponsored" target="_blank">Logitech G, Corsair, MSI and Nanoleaf devices</a></span></li><li><span><strong>Stock Checker</strong> — provides real-time stock prices</span></li><li><span><strong>Weather Updates</strong> — provides current weather conditions in any city</span></li></ul></div><p>These plugins all run locally using a small language model on Nvidia’s RTX GPUs, and developers will also be able to share their own custom plugins through GitHub. G-Assist uses a local small language model that requires nearly 10GB of space for the assistant functions and voice capabilities. The AI assistant works on a variety of RTX 30-, 40-, and 50-series desktop GPUs, but you’ll need a card with at least 12GB of VRAM.</p><p>If you’re interested in trying out G-Assist or building a plugin, the app is available as an optional part of <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nvidia.com%2Fen-us%2Fsoftware%2Fnvidia-app%2F" rel="sponsored">Nvidia’s main app for Windows</a>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>