<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 21:18:30 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MultiVersus’ next season will be its last]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/604179/multiversus-final-season-shutdown</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/multiversus%E2%80%99-next-season-will-be-its-last.1097322/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/604179/multiversus-final-season-shutdown<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/emma-roth">Emma Roth</a> <span>is a news writer who covers the streaming wars, consumer tech, crypto, social media, and much more. Previously, she was a writer and editor at MUO.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p><em>MultiVersus</em> will go offline at the end of its next season, <a href="https://multiversus.com/en/news/multiversus-update">Warner Bros. Games announced on Friday</a>. The free-to-play brawler’s fifth and final season starts on February 4th and runs through May 30th, 2025, after which you’ll only be able to play against AI opponents or through local co-op. It will also no longer be available to download.</p><p>To gain access to the offline version of <em>MultiVersus</em>, you need to download the latest version of the game and log in during season five. From there, you’ll get a local save file connected to your PlayStation, Microsoft, Steam, or Epic Games account, “allowing you to enjoy the game offline with all earned and purchased content moving forward.​”</p><p>The <em>Super Smash Bros</em>.<em>-</em>like <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/7/26/23279073/multiversus-open-beta-wb-games-smash-bros"><em>MultiVersus</em> first launched in an open beta</a> in 2022, but it went offline in 2023 after its <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23603292/multiversus-player-count-base-free-play-wb-games">player count dropped</a>. It <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24097129/multiversus-release-date-warner-bros-games">relaunched in May 2024</a>, adding characters from across Warner Bros. Discovery’s intellectual property, like Samurai Jack, the Powerpuff Girls, and Beetlejuice. The fifth season will add the game’s final characters: Aquaman and the <em>Looney Tunes</em>’ Lola Bunny.</p><p><em>MultiVersus</em> is also ending in-game purchases starting today, which means you can no longer buy Gleamium. You can still use any remaining Gleamium or character tokens until the end of season five, however.</p><div><p>It’s been a pretty rough past few months for live service games like <em>MultiVersus</em>, as <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/4/24235163/concord-cancellation-live-service-games">Sony shut down <em>Concord</em></a> last year and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/16/24345575/sony-god-of-war-bluepoint-games-bend-games-canceled">canceled two unannounced live service projects</a>, while <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/3/24312584/ubisoft-xdefiant-shutting-down-refunds"><em>XDefiant</em> servers go offline in June</a>.</p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>