<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 22:28:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LG announces new UltraGear evo gaming monitors with AI upscaling]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/tech/850572/lg-announces-new-ultragear-evo-gaming-monitors-with-ai-upscaling</link>
            <guid>1393492</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6NjA5MzU0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Terrence O'Brien</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is the Verge’s weekend editor. He has over 18 years of experience, including 10 years as managing editor at Engadget.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>LG <a href="https://www.lgnewsroom.com/2025/12/lg-unveils-ultragear-evo-redefining-5k-gaming-with-worlds-first-ai-upscaling-technology/">unveiled</a> a whole new line of gaming monitors ahead of CES on Friday. The UltraGear evo line are all high-end monitors covering a range of technologies, but united by 5K resolution and AI upscaling.</p><p>The three flagships under the new branding are the 39GX950B, the 27GM950B, and the 52G930B. The first number in the model name indicates the size. The rest of the letters and numbers, well, I’m sure they mean something to someone.</p><p>The 39-inch <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/643183/lg-oled-ultragear-gx9-price">GX9</a> is an ultrawide 21:9 <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/29/24331748/lg-ultragear-gx9-bendable-oled-5k2k-monitors-specs">5K2K</a> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/844417/rog-strix-claims-it-made-the-first-5k-dual-mode-gaming-monitor">dual-mode</a> OLED screen. It can run at its full resolution at 165Hz, or jump to 330Hz for fast-twitch games at WFHD. The 27-inch GM9 uses “New” MiniLEDs, which promise to deliver brighter images compared to OLED, without the blooming often associated with MiniLEDs. Lastly, the 52-inch G9 is an absolutely massive curved display that delivers a 12:9 panoramic view at 240Hz in its native 5K2K resolution.</p><p>The GM9 model is particularly interesting since LG makes the panels for Apple’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/2/21161487/apple-mac-pro-display-xdr-review-6k-lcd-screen-price-features">Pro Display XDR</a>, and word is that the monitor is finally getting a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/apple-rumors/777791/whats-next-for-apple-iphone-17-m5-ipad-pro">long-overdue update</a> in the near future.</p><p>All three monitors will be on display at CES next month, but there’s no word on pricing or availability just yet.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6NjA5MzU0"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Terrence O'Brien</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/tech/850572/lg-announces-new-ultragear-evo-gaming-monitors-with-ai-upscaling]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The terrible Nintendo controller that helped make VR happen]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/podcast/850556/nintendo-power-glove-version-history</link>
            <guid>1393420</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6Mjc0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>David Pierce</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is editor-at-large and Vergecast co-host with over a decade of experience covering consumer tech. Previously, at Protocol, The Wall Street Journal, and Wired.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>The Nintendo Power Glove was not good. It’s important that you know that. The Power Glove was ambitious, impressive, even important — one of the very first mainstream devices that let you control a game using your body instead of just your thumbs — but it was not good. In some ways, its not-good-ness is a key part of the story.</p><p>The Power Glove showed up in the late 1980s, at a complicated time for the gaming industry, when Nintendo was a hugely powerful force for the future of fun. But the Power Glove wasn’t really even a Nintendo product. It started as a research lark, became a toy, and only wound up with Nintendo’s name on it after a particularly fateful pitch meeting. Thanks to a remarkable marketing campaign, and the feeling that VR often gives of simply being <em>the future</em>, the Power Glove wound up a reasonable (if brief) business success. And you can draw a line from the Glove to some other hugely successful Nintendo products — and maybe even to the whole VR industry as we know it.</p><p>On <a href="https://pod.link/1840983742">this episode of <em>Version History</em></a>, our chat show about old technology, we dig into the story of the Power Glove. It is, somehow, both very brief and very long. David Pierce, <em><a href="http://www.fandom.com/">Fandom’</a></em>s Chris Grant, and <em><a href="https://www.gamefile.news/">Game File</a></em>’s Stephen Totilo explore the projects that led to the Power Glove, the many (<em>many) </em>reasons it wasn’t a very good product, and the ways in which it changed the future anyway. They also attempt to set up a decades-old Glove and play games with it, which goes… poorly.</p><p>If you want to subscribe to <em>Version History, </em>there are two ways to get every episode as soon as it drops:</p><p>And if you want to know more about the Power Glove, whether you got to try it or not, here are some links to get you started:</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6Mjc0"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>David Pierce</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/podcast/850556/nintendo-power-glove-version-history]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft shuts down ‘Rainbow Six Siege’ servers following hack]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/850551/ubisoft-shuts-down-rainbow-six-siege-servers-following-hack</link>
            <guid>1393345</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6NjA5MzU0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Terrence O'Brien</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is the Verge’s weekend editor. He has over 18 years of experience, including 10 years as managing editor at Engadget.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Yesterday, Ubisoft <a href="https://x.com/Rainbow6Game/status/2004917731829948808">confirmed</a> that <em>Rainbow Six Siege</em> had been <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/massive-rainbow-six-siege-breach-gives-players-billions-of-credits/">compromised</a> and that it had <a href="https://x.com/Rainbow6Game/status/2004943312390926740">shut down</a> the game’s servers and marketplace while it resolved the issue. The hackers managed to <a href="https://x.com/kinggeorge/status/2004902566434668686">gain control</a> over a significant chunk of the game’s systems, including the ability to ban and unban users, sending <a href="https://x.com/ViTo_DEE91/status/2004910559884628290">custom messages</a> to ban ticker, unlocking all in-game items, and granting every player 2 billion R6 Credits and Renown.</p><p>Ubisoft sells R6 credits in its store, pricing 15,000 of them at $99.99. That means the actual cash value of 2 billion R6 credits is about $13.33 million.</p><p>Ubisoft made it clear that nobody would be punished for spending any credits they received. But, any transactions made after 11:ooAM UTC on Saturday (6AM ET) will be <a href="https://x.com/Rainbow6Game/status/2005018314431447283">rolled back</a> to avoid abuse. At the time of this writing, service had yet to be restored. We’ve reached out to Ubisoft for comment and will update if and when they respond.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6NjA5MzU0"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Terrence O'Brien</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/850551/ubisoft-shuts-down-rainbow-six-siege-servers-following-hack]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The best PS5 games from 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/games/846828/ps5-best-games-2025</link>
            <guid>1393273</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>In this new era of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/column/781303/microsoft-sony-playstation-xbox-future-of-gaming-console">console… inclusivity</a>? driven by <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/770311/playstation-game-helldivers-2-best-selling-game-on-xbox">Sony</a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/entertainment/809053/halo-playstation-xbox-multiplatform-strategy">mostly Microsoft</a> bringing their exclusives to other platforms, it’s getting harder to highlight games that make a singular console shine. Indeed, the top-performing games year after year on both PlayStation and Xbox are multiplatform releases, and often the best games of the year, like <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/843340/clair-obscur-expedition-33-wins-game-of-the-year">2025 GOTY winner</a> <em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em>, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/837245/expedition-33-was-the-most-popular-third-party-game-on-game-pass-this-year-rightly-so">similarly launch on most everything</a>. (Once again, like in all things, Nintendo is the exception.)</p><p>But while lists like this will probably disappear as we get deeper into the era of everything being an Xbox, Sony still seems committed to high-quality exclusives. Here are its best of 2025.</p><div><p><cite>Photo by Antonio G. Di Benedetto / The Verge</cite></p></div><div><p id="playstation-portal"><h2>PlayStation Portal</h2></p></div><p>As software exclusivity goes the way of Sega’s console business, console makers have other ways to attract consumers to their part of the video game ecosystem. For Microsoft, it’s Game Pass; for Sony in 2025, it’s the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24012547/sony-playstation-portal-handheld-remote-player-ps5-chiaki-review">PlayStation Portal</a>. This year, Sony launched an update for the Portal that <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/814078/playstation-portal-ps5-cloud-streaming">enables cloud streaming</a> and making the device a must-have for PlayStation households. For $200, roughly half the price of a PS5, you essentially get a second one, able to play select games without the need to stream them from the console. The list of streamable games isn’t comprehensive, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/ps5-game-cloud-streaming/?emcid=pa-co-520646&amp;gclsrc=aw.ds&amp;gad_source=1&amp;gad_campaignid=23305322396&amp;gbraid=0AAAAADc1uAa13odx4s8g3Bv1DboYIZ4Jc&amp;gclid=Cj0KCQiAo4TKBhDRARIsAGW29bf29vmveeci1sumQ-msyBQVI9oAT46bbjbhcjL5CHQlLVoyrOEre4caAuMnEALw_wcB">but there are over 2,000 of them</a>, and the ability to play them on the go is a literal game changer.</p><p>Get into a discussion with true <em>Final Fantasy</em> sickos about the top 10 games in the franchise, and you better have a lot of time and earplugs on your hands as everyone debates entries two through 10 — because No. 1, invariably, is <em>Final Fantasy Tactics</em>. Having finally played the game for the first time, taking advantage of the remaster Square Enix released this year, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/entertainment/783944/final-fantasy-tactics-remake-review-square-enix-playstation">I get it</a>. The best video games are often timeless while also able to speak to a specific moment, and <em>Tactics</em>’ story is and does exactly that.</p><p>But more than narrative, <em>Tactics</em>’ brilliance is also in its expansive job system that grants players a facsimile of godhood that’s so much fun to wield. The arithmetician class has the ability to cast any learned spell in the game instantly and without requiring mana. To offset the class’s ruinously slow speed, pair it with white mage to create the most diabolical unit in the history of strategy RPGs. Ramza Beoulve is just a guy trying to save the world, and <em>FFT</em> made me believe he can because I made his ragtag band of misfits into walking nuclear weapons.</p><div><p id="ghost-of-yotei"><h2><strong><em>Ghost of Yōtei</em></strong></h2></p></div><p>Sucker Punch’s sequel to <em>Ghost of Tsushima</em> plays things relatively safe. It doesn’t change things up dramatically but instead polishes the experience. Which means the experience isn’t all that different from its predecessor — that means lush landscapes to explore, lots of combat techniques to learn, and, uh, plenty of hot springs to bathe in — but everything feels more finely tuned this time around. That’s especially true of the game’s tale of revenge, which is both more gripping than the original and also gives the open-world experience some much-needed structure.</p><p>The original <em>Death Stranding</em> was so weird that half of the fun was just wrapping your head around the experience. I’m not sure I really understood it until I was almost done (if at all). The sequel is still plenty weird, but because it builds off of the previous game, it’s also much easier to understand from the get-go. It’s still a delivery simulator where you trek across a postapocalyptic landscape to get goods and people where they’re needed. But now the setting has shifted to Australia, which means there are new environmental elements to deal with — hello, sandstorms — along with a whole new cast of weirdo characters to meet, played by everyone from Elle Fanning to George Miller.</p><p>But don’t worry; the story is still as inscrutable as ever.</p><p>Bennett Foddy sure made you feel the “walking” part of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/638179/baby-steps-preview-ps5-steam">this elaborate walking simulator</a>. In <em>Baby Steps</em>, your job is to walk, and you do that by controlling every move involved in taking a step, down to the fine motor details. What results is a hilarious examination of human psychology, emotional maturity, and a newfound appreciation for just how hard it is to ambulate a body with nothing more than DualSense trigger buttons.</p><p>When <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/817997/lumines-arise-review-ps5-steam"><em>Lumines Arise</em></a> was first announced, I made the mistake of asking, “Oh, is it a series or something?”, unfamiliar with <em>Lumines</em>’ days as a PSP powerhouse. My elders have never let me live that down, so I thought I’d see for myself what the game is.</p><p><em>Lumines Arise</em> is<em> Evil Dr. Tetris Effect Mean Bean Machine</em>. <em>Mean Bean Machine</em> in that the game is played by globbing together matching blocks in two-by-two configurations. It’s part <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/18/18099272/tetris-effect-perfect-game-red-dead-redemption-2-modern-games-overwhelming"><em>Tetris Effect</em></a> because the game has an incredible synth / pop-house soundtrack that’s synced to the action, creating a full-body puzzle-playing experience. And evil in that the game is hard as shit. My skills as a <em>Tetris </em>player, limited though they are, just do not transfer to <em>Lumines Arise</em>. But! There is a flow state I can reach. Throughout playing, the shapes of the blocks will change from blocks, to eggs, to clocks, whatever, and I’ve found some patterns are easier to group than others. It’s interesting and fun to figure out what shapes make the game easier for me and which ones are impossible to configure.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTAy"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Ash Parrish</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/games/846828/ps5-best-games-2025]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>