<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 15:57:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donkey Kong Bananza is coming to the Switch 2 in July]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/641537/donkey-kong-bananza-nintendo-switch-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/donkey-kong-bananza-is-coming-to-the-switch-2-in-july.1152582/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/641537/donkey-kong-bananza-nintendo-switch-2<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/jay-peters">Jay Peters</a> <span>is a news editor covering technology, gaming, and more. He joined The Verge in 2019 after nearly two years at Techmeme.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Nintendo is releasing a new 3D <em>Donkey Kong</em> game that will be an exclusive for the Nintendo Switch 2. The game, <em>Donkey Kong Bananza</em>, will release on July 17th, which is a little more than a month after the June 5th launch of the Switch 2.</p><p><em>Bananza</em> is a 3D platformer that gives DK a new look that’s seemingly inspired by his appearance in <em>The Super Mario Bros. Movie</em>. “Explore a vast underground world—by smashing your way through it!” according to the description of Nintendo’s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mIddsPkdX9U">YouTube trailer for the game</a>. “Bash, throw, and climb through just about anything in DK’s brand-new 3D platforming action-adventure game!”</p><p>In the trailer, you can see DK scaling walls like a super-powered Link from <em>Breath of the Wild</em>, picking up and tossing rocks to smash through enemies and walls, and digging into the ground with his fists. There also looks to be old-school 2D sections and mine cart rides.</p><p>The game looks full of energy — DK and various characters in the trailer are really expressive and fun. It’s a shame it won’t launch at the same time as the Switch 2, but at least we won’t have to wait too much longer after the system releases to play the game.</p><p><strong>Related:</strong></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment hits the Switch 2 this winter]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/638770/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-hits-the-switch-2-this-winter.1152579/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/638770/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/charles-pulliam-moore">Charles Pulliam-Moore</a> <span>is a reporter focusing on film, TV, and pop culture. Before The Verge, he wrote about comic books, labor, race, and more at io9 and Gizmodo for almost five years.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>It wouldn’t be a new Nintendo console without a big <em>Zelda</em> release, and the franchise’s next entry is sending the princess to war.</p><p>During <a href="https://www.theverge.com/nintendo/638604/nintendo-switch-2-direct-news-trailers-stream">today’s Switch 2 Direct,</a> Nintendo announced the forthcoming arrival of <em>Age of Imprison</em>ment, a new installment of Koei Tecmo’s <em>Zelda-</em>inspired <em>Hyrule Warriors </em>series. Like <a href="https://www.theverge.com/21572264/hyrule-warriors-age-of-calamity-review-nintendo-switch-zelda-botw-prequel"><em>Hyrule Warrior</em>s: <em>Age of Calamity</em></a>, <em>Age of Imprisonment</em> is another prequel whose story connects directly with the larger tale unfolding in <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/3/2/14787082/the-legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-review">Breath of the Wild</a> </em>and <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/23718926/zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-review-nintendo-switch">Tears of the Kingdom</a></em>. But this time around, the game looks even farther back into the past to focus on the battle Princess Zelda fought alongside King Rauru against Ganondorf.</p><p>A brief trailer for the game highlighted how <em>Age of Imprisonment </em>will allow you to play as Zelda and Rauru as you fight against hordes of Hylian monsters. Nintendo didn’t reveal much about the new game’s plot, but announced that it’s set for release this winter.</p><p>The <em>Zelda </em>franchise played a key role in the original Switch’s success. <em>Breath of the Wild</em>, which was also one of the last Wii U titles, quickly became one of the handheld console’s bestselling games and a critical darling that kicked off a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/3/2/14787082/the-legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-review">new era of open-world gaming</a>. The Switch gave Nintendo a chance to double down on <em>Zelda</em> spinoffs like the <em>Hyrule Warriors </em>series and <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/13/18677194/cadence-of-hyrule-crypt-of-the-necrodancer-zelda-nintendo-hands-on-release-date-e3-2019">Cadence of Hyrule</a></em>.</p><div><p>The company kept its <em>Zelda </em>momentum going with updated versions of classics like <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/19/20871958/legend-of-zelda-links-awakening-review-nintendo-switch-updates-graphics">Link’s Awakening</a></em> and <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/22576029/legend-of-zelda-skyward-sword-hd-review-nintendo-switch">Skyward Sword</a></em>. And even though the first Switch was nearing the end of its life cycle, Nintendo pushed the series even further into the future with <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/23718926/zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-review-nintendo-switch">Tears of the Kingdom</a> </em>and <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24253919/the-legend-of-zelda-echoes-of-wisdom-review-nintendo-switch">Echoes of Wisdom</a></em>. The way <em>Zelda </em>flourished on the Switch is undoubtedly part of why the franchise is being <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/638133/legend-of-zelda-movie-premiere-date-2027">adapted into a live-action movie</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/video-of-legend-of-zelda-producer-eiji-aonuma-at-universal-studios-pulled-offline">seemingly getting the theme park treatment</a>. And now we know a bit more about how the princess’s legend will continue with the Switch 2.</p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>