<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:29:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Netflix Games is getting its first MMO]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/632526/spirit-crossing-netflix-games-mmo-spry-fox</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/netflix-games-is-getting-its-first-mmo.1139391/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/632526/spirit-crossing-netflix-games-mmo-spry-fox<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/ash-parrish">Ash Parrish</a> <span>is a reporter who covers the business, culture, and communities of video games, with a focus on marginalized gamers and the quirky, horny culture of video game communities.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Netflix just announced <em>Spirit Crossing</em> during a press event at GDC 2025. Spirit Crossing represents a first for Netflix, becoming the service’s first MMO offering. It was developed by Spry Fox, one of Netflix’s in-house game studios, and will launch sometime later this year.</p><p><em>Spirit Crossing</em> is described in the press release as a “cozy MMO.” Its launch trailer certainly gives off typical “cozy” game vibes with cute creatures, pastel colors, and chill music that wouldn’t be out of place in a Lo-fi Girl stream. The game will feature customizable housing and neighborhoods for players, open-world exploration, and lots of crafting. Spry Fox is known for several cozy-style games including <em>Cozy Grove </em>and its Netflix-exclusive sequel <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/23/24163281/cozy-grove-camp-spirit-release-date-netflix-gaming">Cozy Grove: Camp Spirit</a></em>. Netflix acquired the studio in 2022 as a part of its gaming initiative.</p><p>While the streaming platform has proven it’s serious about its games offering by continuing to bring third-party titles to the service in addition to its own first-party games, it is not immune to the same forces wrecking the games industry at large. Last year, the company <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/22/24276700/netflix-gaming-studio-closure-blue">shut down one of its studios</a> which was reportedly working on what would have been the first in-house developed AAA title.</p><p>Players interested in <em>Spirit Crossing</em> can sign up for the closed alpha playtest <a href="https://projectfriendship.spryfox.com/">here</a>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>