<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 14:49:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiegogo is getting acquired by Gamefound, a board game crowdfunding company]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/712733/indiegogo-acquired-gamefound-crowdfunding</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiegogo-is-getting-acquired-by-gamefound-a-board-game-crowdfunding-company.1252218/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/jay-peters">Jay Peters</a> <span>is a news editor covering technology, gaming, and more. He joined The Verge in 2019 after nearly two years at Techmeme.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Indiegogo is being acquired by the board game crowdfunding platform Gamefound, which plans on “integrating Indiegogo’s global community of 38 million members with Gamefound’s state-of-the-art crowdfunding technology,” the <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/gamefound-acquires-indiegogo-a-groundbreaking-leap-forward-for-global-creativity-and-creator-empowerment-302511967.html">companies announced this morning</a>.</p><p>Gamefound has built “the best tech in crowdfunding, hands down,” Indiegogo CEO Julie dePontbriand tells <em>The Verge</em>. “By joining forces, we’re aligning with the strongest platform out there — so we can bring the very best tools, features, and experience to our creators.” Gamefound has become a huge player in crowdfunding for tabletop games, with six of the top 10 tabletop campaigns last year, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/analysis/520142/gamefound-top-10-biggest-board-game-crowdfund-campaigns">according to <em>Polygon</em></a>.</p><p>The threat of Trump’s tariffs mean that now is a potentially vulnerable time for the tabletop industry, as many board game makers rely on <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/643173/trump-tariffs-steve-jackson-board-game-industry">manufacturing in China</a>. (A group of tabletop game makers filed <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/656074/trump-tariffs-lawsuit-tabletop-game-companies-stonemaier-princess-awesome">a lawsuit in April</a> in an attempt to stop them.) While the current status of the tariffs <a href="https://www.npr.org/2025/07/09/nx-s1-5460936/trump-tariffs-economy-china-policy">remains fluid</a>, people are still backing games. Per dePontbriand: “Gamefound hasn’t seen a drop in US backer activity or overall campaign funding.”</p><p>As part of the acquisition, Indiegogo will change its pricing to be in line with Gamefound’s, which is “a flat 5 percent fee” and “no additional fees for any promotional placements” on Indiegogo and its newsletters, dePontbriand says. That change will be going into effect “immediately.”</p><p>Indiegogo will also follow Gamefound’s tipping policy, which gives 100 percent of tips directly to a creator “outside of the checkout flow,” dePontbriand says. This change is in the works, and “we’ll provide an update on timing as soon as possible.”</p><p>Both platforms will continue to exist separately, though Gamefound campaigns will be featured on both Gamefound and Indiegogo “for added exposure,” per the press release.</p><p>dePontbriand says she will remain the CEO of Indiegogo, while Gamefound CEO Marcin Świerkot will “take on the role of Group CEO.”</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTIz"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Jay Peters</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/712733/indiegogo-acquired-gamefound-crowdfunding]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>