<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 14:26:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mario Kart World launches exclusively with the Nintendo Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/634632/mario-kart-nintendo-switch-2-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mario-kart-world-launches-exclusively-with-the-nintendo-switch-2.1152237/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/634632/mario-kart-nintendo-switch-2-trailer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>We knew a <em>Mario Kart </em>game was coming to the Switch 2, and now Nintendo has finally shared some real details in its <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DXUmjX7DsP8">latest Nintendo Direct</a>. It’s called <em>Mario Kart World</em>, and it will be a day-one Switch 2 exclusive when the console launches on June 5th. <em>Mario Kart World</em> features an open-world mode, in-game atmospheric effects that depend on “the time of day and weather conditions,” and up to 24 drivers per race. After the Direct, Nintendo announced a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/634603/nintendo-switch-2-price-release-date-details">$499.99 launch day Switch 2 bundle</a> that includes a download code for <em>Mario Kart World</em>. The company plans to share more about the game in a Nintendo Direct scheduled for April 17th at 6AM PT / 9AM ET.</p><p><em>Mario Kart World</em>’s open-world mode is called “Free Roam,” and it’ll sound familiar to <em>Forza Horizon </em>5 players, letting users drive on or off-road around the world, “take scenic drives with friends, and take photos together at different locations.” There’s also a “Knock-out Tour” mode that lets you do a cross-country <em>Cannonball Run</em>-style checkpoint race.</p><p>Nintendo showed off some new gameplay mechanics, like abilities to grind on rails and power lines or wall jump, as well as new vehicles like boats and snowmobiles. Other shots showed what looked like on-the-fly character customization. Characters that appeared in the trailer included standards like Mario and Wario, as well as new ones to the mainline series like the cow from Moo Moo Meadows in <em>Mario Kart 64.</em></p><p><em>Mario Kart</em> was <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/16/24337198/switch-2-mario-kart-nintendo">the one new game teased</a> during <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/16/23872810/nintendo-switch-2-next-generation-console-features-trailer">the initial Switch 2 reveal event in January</a>. And it makes a lot of sense as a debut title for the platform, as the kart racing series has arguably become Nintendo’s most popular franchise. <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/11/1/23941695/mario-kart-8-deluxe-wave-6-dlc-tracks-release-date-characters">Mario Kart 8 Deluxe</a></em> is the bestselling Switch game to date, and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/5/15/5714102/mario-kart-8-review">its predecessor</a> holds the same title for the Wii U. Meanwhile, <em>Mario Kart 7</em> was the top-selling 3DS game, <em>Mario Kart Wii</em> was second only to <em>Wii Sports</em> on that platform, and <em>Mario Kart DS</em> sat just behind <em>Nintendogs</em> to claim third place on the handheld.</p><p>Today’s reveal was part of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/16/24236766/nintendo-switch-2-games-direct-date-time">a Nintendo Direct event</a> aimed at sharing more hard details about both the Switch 2 and its initial lineup of games.</p><p><em>Developing…</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 arrives on June 5th]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/634603/nintendo-switch-2-price-release-date-details</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-arrives-on-june-5th.1152234/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/634603/nintendo-switch-2-price-release-date-details<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>After <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/16/24344718/nintendo-switch-2-specs-date-price-launch-games-mario-kart">a reveal that was light on details</a>, Nintendo has finally announced key information about the Switch 2: most notably, when it will launch. The Switch 2 will be available on June 5th, priced starting at $449.99. A separate bundle with the new <em>Mario Kart World</em> game will also be available for $499.99.</p><p>The Switch 2 be available for preorder in North America from select retailers on April 9th. The console will come bundled with Joy-Con 2 controllers, the Switch 2 dock, a HDMI cable, a USB-C charging cable, and Switch 2 AC adapter.</p><p>Nintendo has also revealed <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/630264/nintendo-switch-2-specs-details-performance">more hardware details about the Switch 2</a> today during its dedicated stream. The Switch 2 will ship with a 1080p screen capable of 120Hz, a 4K dock that upscales games for your TV, and Joy-Con 2 controllers that can work like a mouse. It also has 256GB of internal storage, up from 32GB on the original Switch.</p><p>The follow-up to the Switch boasts a larger 7.9-inch screen and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/16/24343722/switch-2-joy-cons-details-magnets-drift-nintendo">redesigned Joy-Con controllers</a>, along with new games like the next <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/634632/mario-kart-nintendo-switch-2-trailer"><em>Mario Kart World</em> game</a> that launches exclusively on the Switch 2 on June 5th. <em>Mario Kart World </em>features an open-world mode, in-game atmospheric effects that depend on “the time of day and weather conditions,” and up to 24 drivers per race.</p><div><p>Nintendo also announced a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/641352/nintendo-switch-2-camera-launch">Switch 2 camera</a> for video chats, a new <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/637833/nintendo-switch-2-pro-controller-details">Switch 2 Pro Controller</a> with customizable rear buttons, and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/24339906/nintendo-switch-2-gamecube-nso">GameCube games for the Switch 2</a>. Nintendo is also upgrading the Switch’s best <em>Zelda </em>games with <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/641365/nintendo-zelda-botw-totk-switch-2-edition-announced">Switch 2 Editions</a>.</p></div><div><p>Its predecessor, the original Switch, has been a defining success for Nintendo <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/3/1/14772530/nintendo-switch-review-zelda-breath-of-the-wild">since its launch in 2017</a>. The console has sold more than 150 million units to date, putting it within spitting distance of platforms like the Nintendo DS (155 million) and PlayStation 2 (160 million). For that reason, the last few months have still seen a number of notable releases for the original Switch, including <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24253919/the-legend-of-zelda-echoes-of-wisdom-review-nintendo-switch">The Legend of Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom</a></em> and <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/games-review/629964/xenoblade-chronicles-x-definitive-edition-review-nintendo-switch">Xenoblade Chronicles X: Definitive Edition</a></em>. Just last week <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/636750/nintendo-switch-march-2025-direct">Nintendo held <em>another</em> Direct presentation focused on games for the original Switch</a>.</p></div><p><em><strong>Update, April 2nd</strong>: Article updated with Switch 2 pricing and preorder information.</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 specs: 1080p 120Hz display, 4K dock, mouse mode, and more]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/630264/nintendo-switch-2-specs-details-performance</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-specs-1080p-120hz-display-4k-dock-mouse-mode-and-more.1152231/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/630264/nintendo-switch-2-specs-details-performance<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><div><p>Nintendo has finally shared many of the key specs about the Nintendo Switch 2 as part of its <a href="https://www.theverge.com/nintendo/638604/nintendo-switch-2-direct-news-trailers-stream">Switch 2-focused Direct</a>, and said the system <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/634603/nintendo-switch-2-price-release-date-details">will launch on June 5th</a>.</p></div><p>The device has a 7.9-inch screen, but it’s still 13.99mm thick, like the first Switch. The LCD screen has a 1080p resolution and supports HDR and up to a 120fps refresh rate. The Joy-Con controllers are bigger, too, and as hinted at, they can be used similarly to a mouse. (Though a footnote says that mouse mode will only work with compatible games.) And they stay connected to the Switch 2 via magnets.</p><p>It has 256GB of internal storage, up from 32GB on the first Switch. As shown in the Switch 2’s initial reveal trailer, it also has two USB-C ports for connecting accessories and for charging. When using the dock, you can play games at up to 4K resolution at 60fps. The dock also has a fan to keep the system cool.</p><p>The new “C” button can also be used to activate a chat menu that lets you access controls like muting your voice during the Discord-like “GameChat” calls. To help users better understand the features of the Switch 2, Nintendo will also release a <em>Nintendo Switch 2 Welcome Tour</em> paid digital game that will be available on launch day.</p><p>The game cards for the Switch 2 will be red, a change from the black cards for the original Switch. The system also supports microSD Express cards, but original microSD cards for the Switch are not compatible.</p><p>There’s a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/637833/nintendo-switch-2-pro-controller-details">new Pro Controller, too</a>, which has new rear buttons, a headphone jack, and the C button.</p><p>Nintendo will also let players share compatible games locally with a new feature called GameShare.</p><p>Nintendo officially revealed the Nintendo Switch 2 <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/16/23872810/nintendo-switch-2-next-generation-console-features-trailer">in a brief video in January</a>. In the video, arguably the only “spec” that Nintendo stated was that the console would be backward-compatible with <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/16/24343666/nintendo-switch-2-cartridge-backwards-compatibility">original Switch carts</a>. But, from the video, it was apparent that the Switch 2 was <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/16/24345191/nintendo-switch-2-bigger-screen">a bigger device</a> with an extra port on top of the console. You could also see that it had a new way to connect to Joy-Con controllers; instead of sliding on and off, they snapped to the sides. That video also showed that the controllers could slide around a surface, similar to the way a mouse does, and snap into accessories.</p><p>In the initial Switch 2 announcement, Nintendo also revealed that the dock had a more rounded shape than the one included with the first Switch.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>