<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 14:44:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AMD’s Ryzen 7 9800X3D gaming CPU arrives on November 7th for $479]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/31/24284453/amd-ryzen-7-9800x3d-release-date-pricing</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amd%E2%80%99s-ryzen-7-9800x3d-gaming-cpu-arrives-on-november-7th-for-479.1024143/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/31/24284453/amd-ryzen-7-9800x3d-release-date-pricing<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>After <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/21/24273397/amd-ryzen-x3d-processor-zen-5-release-date">bizarrely teasing</a> a 9000-series X3D announcement last week, AMD is making it official  today that the Ryzen 7 9800X3D will be available on November 7th. Priced at $479, the 9800X3D is a direct successor to the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/4/5/23668320/amd-ryzen-7-7800x3d-review-cpu-processor-benchmark-test">best gaming CPU on the market</a> right now, the Ryzen 7 7800X3D. There’s a lot to be excited about with this next-generation X3D chip, too.</p><p>AMD is increasing the base clock speed up to 4.7GHz on the 9800X3D, with a max boost of 5.2GHz. Combined with an increase to a 120-watt TDP, this may well help improve productivity workloads — something the X3D chips have always fallen behind their non-X3D counterparts on.</p><div><figcaption><em>AMD claims its 9800X3D is on average 8 percent faster than the 7800X3D.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: AMD</cite></p></div><p>The 9800X3D is really focused on gaming, though. AMD is calling it “the world’s best gaming processor,” and promising an 8 percent uplift in average FPS over the 7800X3D. Those gains are thanks to the Zen 5 architecture and a second generation of 3D V-Cache technology. </p><p>AMD even claims the 9800X3D will be up to 20 percent better than Intel’s latest Core Ultra 9 285K in gaming. In a <a href="https://x.com/JackMHuynh/status/1851970613604126789">video announcement</a>, AMD computing and graphics boss Jack Huynh reveals that “in many games such as <em>Far Cry 6</em> and <em>Cyberpunk 2077</em> we are more than 40 percent faster.”</p><p>The 9800X3D is also the first X3D processor to be fully unlocked, allowing enthusiasts and gamers to overclock it and squeeze more performance out of their systems. AMD is launching the Ryzen 7 9800X3D on November 7th, priced at $479.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A meditative take on sudoku that changes with the weather]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/31/24283527/puzzmo-weather-memoku</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-meditative-take-on-sudoku-that-changes-with-the-weather.1024053/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/31/24283527/puzzmo-weather-memoku<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The Weather Network can be a very useful website, but that’s mostly true when the weather is bad. So when the company began collaborating with <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/12/4/23984103/puzzmo-acquired-hearst-zach-gage">the Hearst-owned</a> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23929222/puzzmo-newspaper-games-crossword-zach-gage">puzzle platform Puzzmo</a>, it had a specific goal: to get people coming to the site even when it’s nice out. “Why would you check the weather on a sunny day?” veteran game designer Zach Gage remembers asking himself. Eventually, the Puzzmo team came up with an answer in the form of <a href="http://puzzmo.com/+/weather"><em>Weather Memoku</em></a>, an extremely chill game that combines elements of memory, sudoku, and, well, the weather.</p><p>“A very important idea was: can we change checking the weather from being a thing you check off your to-do list, to being a chance to take a moment for yourself?” explains Gage.</p><p>The game takes place on a 6 x 6 grid, and the goal is to flip over tiles to find matches, much like in a classic game of memory. The twist is that it also follows the rules of sudoku. This means that each of the six symbols appears in each row and column only once, turning <em>Weather Memoku</em> from a pure guessing game to one with a bit of strategy. It’s also incredibly charming, with symbols that change based on the weather. There are cute little frogs on a rainy day and penguins when it snows out. When you complete the puzzle — which will probably take a minute or two — you’re presented with your score in addition to an hourly weather report. You can also share this, much like your <em>Wordle</em> score.</p><p>According to Gage, who previously <a href="https://www.theverge.com/21334116/good-sudoku-iphone-ipad-app-game-zach-gage">developed the sudoku app <em>Good Sudoku</em></a>, <em>Weather Memoku</em> is meant to be an iteration of what he calls “arcade sudoku,” which is basically the standard way of playing without using high-level strategies. <em>Weather Memoku</em> takes the same core gameplay — looking at a grid to figure out where things belong — and streamlines it even further. “Being wrong is part of the game,” Gage explains. “In this game, if you don’t know something and you guess, you can tap anywhere and now you have a new piece of information and your board has changed. It really feels like an interesting evolution of arcade sudoku.”</p><p>That streamlined nature is important for what the game is meant to be. <em>Weather Memoku</em> is a fun way to learn a piece of information, but it’s also designed to feel like “a little meditation” that would make you want to keep coming back to the site each day, much like a crossword puzzle or sudoku challenge. “You can have this meditative experience and then when you’re done, you actually have the weather,” says Gage. “You’ve left with a tangible piece of information that’s valuable to you.”</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>