<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:32:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghost of Yōtei studio Sucker Punch is getting new leadership]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/845573/sony-playstation-sucker-punch-leadership</link>
            <guid>1385092</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTIz"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Jay Peters</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a senior reporter covering technology, gaming, and more. He joined The Verge in 2019 after nearly two years at Techmeme.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Sucker Punch Productions, the PlayStation studio behind games like <em>Ghost of Yōtei</em> and the <em>Infamous</em> and <em>Sly Cooper</em> series, will be headed up by Jason Connell and Adrian Bentley starting January 1st, <a href="https://sonyinteractive.com/en/news/blog/the-next-chapter-of-sucker-punch/">Sony announced on Tuesday</a>. Studio co-founder Brian Fleming is stepping down and will be “passing Sucker Punch studio leadership on to a new generation.”</p><p>Connell recently served as co-creative director on the <em>Ghost</em> franchise — I spoke to him earlier this year about <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/789026/ghost-of-yotei-cinematic-modes-kurosawa-miike-watanabe"><em>Ghost of Yōtei</em>’s cinematic modes</a>. Bentley has been the studio’s technical director, leading Sucker Punch’s engineering and production teams.</p><p>“As Sucker Punch moves forward under Jason and Adrian’s leadership, the team remains dedicated to crafting new adventures that capture the imagination of players everywhere,” Sony says. Ahead of the transition, Fleming has “worked closely with PlayStation Studios to ensure that Sucker Punch was in the best hands moving forward with a strong foundation for the studio’s continued success.”</p><p>Fleming, on LinkedIn, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/brian-fleming-8445b31a_sucker-punch-productions-co-founder-brian-activity-7406746502825660416-cRm9?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;rcm=ACoAAAIV1iYBHi7OPybalzIKilWBO4bTY5vJb8c">says that</a> “I really don’t know what’s next” and that he’s going to stay at Sucker Punch through April to help with the transition.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTIz"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Jay Peters</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/845573/sony-playstation-sucker-punch-leadership]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft’s free update brings better Bluetooth to your Xbox Wireless Headset]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/games/845491/microsoft-xbox-wireless-headset-bluetooth-le-free-update</link>
            <guid>1385089</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="__next"><p><a href="#content"><span>Skip to main content</span></a></p><nav aria-label="Sticky Nav"></nav><div><main id="content"><div><article><div><div><p>﻿If you’ve got the 2024 version, anyhow.</p></div><div><div><p>﻿If you’ve got the 2024 version, anyhow.</p><div><p><span><span>by</span> <!-- --> <span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"></span></span></p><p><span><time datetime="2025-12-16T17:43:57+00:00">Dec 16, 2025, 5:43 PM UTC</time></span></p></div></div><div><p><cite>Photo by Cameron Faulkner / The Verge</cite></p></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MzQz"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Sean Hollister</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a senior editor and founding member of The Verge who covers gadgets, games, and toys. He spent 15 years editing the likes of CNET, Gizmodo, and Engadget.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>My favorite kind of update is the one that gives my gadgets entirely new features and specs for free — and Microsoft is <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/12/16/xbox-december-2025-update-mobile-app-updates-audio-support/?ocid=Announce_soc_omc_xbo_tw_Link_lrn_12.16.1#:~:text=Today%2C%20we%E2%80%99re%20excited%20to%20share%20a%20new%20firmware%20update">unleashing one of those today</a> by bringing Bluetooth Low Energy (LE) Audio to its 2024 Xbox Wireless Headset, which unlocks a lot of those new features!</p><p>It could bring better battery life, lower latency, and perhaps most importantly, palatable voice chat when paired with <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/843010/xbox-ally-x-sleep-battery-drain-two-months-later">Microsoft’s “Xbox” handhelds</a> like the Xbox Ally and Xbox Ally X. (The older Bluetooth Classic mode requires more bandwidth than Bluetooth LE, so you typically see a big drop in audio quality with Bluetooth Classic when you try to add two-way voice communication to your audio stream.)</p><p>Microsoft actually branded that “don’t drop audio quality” idea back in August, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/766569/microsoft-windows-11-bluetooth-super-wideband-stereo-le-audio-voice-feature">calling it “super wideband stereo,”</a> and any Bluetooth LE headset should be able to get you it in Windows 11 now. And, Bluetooth LE should also get you <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/811795/microsoft-windows-11-bluetooth-le-shared-audio-headsets">Microsoft’s new shared audio Insider Preview feature</a> so your PC can stream audio to two sets of headphones (or headphones and speakers) at once. Super wideband isn’t ready for Xbox Ally quite yet though, it seems: “Coming soon to ROG Xbox Ally and ROG Xbox Ally X,” reads the blog.</p><div><p>Yes, it’s only for the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/22/24276564/microsoft-xbox-wireless-headset-update-release-date-price-features">2024 refreshed version of the headset</a>, not <a href="https://www.theverge.com/22325883/microsoft-xbox-wireless-headset-gaming-series-x-s-pc-windows-10-review">the original 2021 version</a>, but it’s quite the update for free. Maybe it’ll take some of the sting out of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/659430/microsoft-xbox-console-controller-game-price-increases-worldwide">Microsoft’s price hike on these headsets</a>; originally $99, they’ve cost $119 since May. (It may also help cement the idea that the next Xbox is probably a PC.)</p></div><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MzQz"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Sean Hollister</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><div><form><div><h2>The Verge Daily</h2><p><span>A free daily digest of the news that matters most.</span></p></div></form></div></div></article></div></main></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/games/845491/microsoft-xbox-wireless-headset-bluetooth-le-free-update]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[An iconic joystick from the Commodore 64 era is returning]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/845447/retro-games-the-quickshot-ii-joystick-controller-commodore-64</link>
            <guid>1385023</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTYw"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Andrew Liszewski</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a senior reporter who’s been covering and reviewing the latest gadgets and tech since 2006, but has loved all things electronic since he was a kid.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Retro Games, a company known for its <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/11/24034344/atari-400-mini-release-date-price">upgraded revivals of iconic ‘80s and ‘90s era computers</a>, including the Commodore 64 and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/11/22619622/amiga-500-mini-announced-games-price-release-date">Amiga</a>, has announced that it’s bringing back another accessory from the same era. If you grew up gaming before the NES hit the US, you were probably using (or drooling over) the Quickshot II. Now, you can get <a href="https://retrogames.biz/products/thequickshot-ii/?ref=retrododo.com">a recreation of the popular controller</a> for £29.99, or around $40. It is expected to be available starting on January 30th, 2026.</p><p>The new version of the Quickshot II, created through a partnership between Retro Games and Plaion Replai, carries forward the aviation-inspired joystick design that was frequently used in controllers before Nintendo’s first console helped popularize gamepads. Its ergonomics may look a little outdated now, but the Quickshot II’s large contoured handle was more comfortable than previous versions, and it introduced a trigger alongside its top-mounted button, replicating the controls found on many arcade machines at the time.</p><p>This revamped Quickshot II looks nearly identical to the original, but with the addition of six more buttons on its base that can be remapped to accommodate modern titles, although the controller is probably best suited for playing simpler retro titles. The joystick now features a “floating ball-joint design” for smoother movement, but still relies on microswitches for detecting inputs.</p><p>The original version’s now-antiquated DE-9 connector has been replaced with USB and plug-and-play compatibility with PCs and consoles, but two retro features have been preserved. There’s still a switch on the base to temporarily activate an auto-fire mode, and on the underside of the Quickshot II you’ll find suction cups to keep it securely perched on a desk, even during intense gaming sessions.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTYw"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Andrew Liszewski</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/845447/retro-games-the-quickshot-ii-joystick-controller-commodore-64]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>