<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - www.theverge.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for www.theverge.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 16:26:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil Requiem is the best of both terrifying worlds]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/entertainment/883947/resident-evil-requiem-review-ps5-xbox-switch-2</link>
            <guid>1445971</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Resident Evil has always been a strange creature: Like many of its most notable monsters, it has shifted and evolved into various forms. From its blocky days of tank-controlled Z-list actors to first-person fright fests, the franchise’s identity is not so much tied to genre as theme: zombies, viruses, very ugly monsters. Now, with <em>Requiem</em>, we have its first proper chimera, mixing the first-person horror of the latest installments with the fan-favorite action of <em>Resident Evil 4</em>.</p><p>Along with this are two playable characters that embody these two very different styles, with beloved Leon S. Kennedy returning as a middle-aged action hero alongside newcomer Grace Ashcroft. The pair come together for a <em>Resident Evil</em> that seamlessly shifts between tone and view to create yet another terrifying evolution for the franchise.</p><p><em>Requiem</em> sees Grace, an FBI analyst, investigating a series of strange murders. All the victims are survivors of the 1998 <a href="https://residentevil.fandom.com/wiki/Raccoon_City_Destruction_Incident">Raccoon City Incident</a>, the inciting event that’s central to much of <em>Resident Evil</em>’s history. Grace’s section begins in 2026 in a burnt-down hotel encased in a rainy urban environment, which reminded me of the cold, wet horror of David Fincher’s <em>Seven</em>. She navigates the dark hotel, armed only with a flashlight, before realizing she is not, in fact, alone. She soon finds herself in the hands of the main villain, Dr. Victor Gideon.</p><p>The game lets you swap between first- and third-person views, but also recommends a particular view for each character. Much like the two previous entries, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/1/23/14353714/resident-evil-7-biohazard-review-ps4-xbox-one-pc"><em>Biohazard</em></a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/22420738/resident-evil-village-review-playstation-xbox-pc"><em>Village</em></a>, Grace’s section is designed with a first-person viewpoint in mind. With her limited ammo and inventory space, low health, and tiny frame, Grace is this game’s unprepared horror protagonist, surrounded by enemies who can often kill her in one or two hits. Grace has to prioritize hiding, using one-off but powerful weapons and gadgets, and fleeing. Playing this in first-person helps articulate her vulnerability.</p><p>Soon I was controlling Leon (who looks much worse for wear since his last appearance in <em>Resident Evil 6</em>, a game everyone, including me, pretends does not exist). Leon arrives near the hotel after Grace, and he’s soon killing zombies in the middle of a public street, giving chase to Gideon. It is rather unnerving watching Dr. Gideon shoot needles into innocent passersby as he escapes, quickly creating zombies. Leon’s sections are much like <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23642938/resident-evil-4-remake-review-xbox-ps5-steam"><em>Resident Evil 4</em></a>: third-person action, with melee prompts and a new ax weapon. Despite being in his 50s, Leon remains an efficient killing machine: As with his abilities in <em>Resident Evil 4</em>, Leon has melee and instant kills, with incredible animations and satisfying gore gushing from successful takedowns. There has never been this much gore caused by a <em>Resident Evil</em> protagonist; it’s glorious to watch him paint rooms red.</p><p>It’s remarkable how seamlessly the game shifts between perspectives. If you have ever watched videos showing <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gWR11Ck_oZM">what first-person games look like from a third-person</a> perspective, you will know things are… different. For example, when Grace opens a creepy cupboard, the game wants to show you a disgusting mass with ooze. The animation for her arms, the angle you view it from, and more will differ if you’re watching it from a first or third-person perspective. Incredibly, <em>Requiem</em> has achieved this fidelity for both angles at any time. It’s truly masterful work by Capcom.</p><p>There is no optional character switching, however. You will simply find yourself playing Grace or Leon based on where you are in the story. For example, after playing as Grace for an hour, navigating very creepy hallways and avoiding a large monstrosity known only as the girl, she ends up being saved by Leon. The game then cuts back to show how Leon got the point of saving her. Later, when Grace is separated from Leon, you take over as Leon and give her covering fire from a sniper’s nest.</p><p>You cannot predict when you will play as either character, but most of the first half of the game is in the shoes of Grace, with Leon’s sections notably shorter; by the time I crossed the halfway mark, the game put Grace on the back burner for a very long time.</p><p>The mashup works surprisingly well, as it feels like the style of play reflects the characters and their particular story. Leon just could never be afraid, underprepared, or ill-suited to the horror around him by this stage in his story. Even with his bare hands, he is a formidable fighter, and remains the lovable weirdo from <em>Resident Evil 4.</em> His sections are refined, tight combat sequences; at one point you can even block a rocket with an ax.</p><p>Grace is another story. Despite being an FBI analyst, she looks like a very small teenager. While I appreciate that her being unprepared adds to the horror, nothing portrayed her as a criminal analyst or FBI agent. Indeed, her being a lonely college student would have made more sense, as nothing in any part of the story demonstrated any abilities. Her backstory, which I won’t spoil here, is also underwhelming, and discovering why she is so important to the all-powerful villains left me rolling my eyes. While she felt good to play and embodied vulnerability, her constant sniveling and delivering lines with a whimper became very jarring. Thankfully she shows some growth toward the end of the game.</p><p>The environments and scenarios are also wonderfully varied, throwing you from a creepy hospital-like area to the bombed-out remains of Raccoon City Police Department — also known as Leon’s origin story. It was quite emotional returning, as the original <em>Resident Evil 2 </em>was the first big-budget game I got in the 2000s. Leon and I were somewhat aligned in taking a breath before opening those doors. I chuckled as 50-year-old Leon commented on puzzles and items he dealt with nearly 30 years ago, which returning players will appreciate.</p><p>The series’ enemies have also continued to evolve beyond just the shambling undead. My favorites were the new partially sentient zombies who retain some semblance of humanity — a cook keeps chopping decaying meat in the kitchen, a cleaner keeps rubbing a stained mirror and bashing her face, a hotel guest nursing a hangover keeps turning a light on and off. Grace can use these tics to her advantage when trying to escape them; for example, with the light-switcher zombie, you can turn on a light farther down a corridor to get him to move.</p><p>Leon and Grace’s journey centers around what they believe is tracking down the last strain of the zombie virus that upended the world. I can safely say that the ending I got was one of the most satisfying conclusions to any <em>Resident Evil</em> game — and <em>Requiem</em> is a fitting name. This newest installment brings together two of the franchise’s heavy hitters — <em>Resident Evil 4</em> and the first-person horror of <em>Biohazard</em> and <em>Village</em> — and at just under 11 hours, it doesn’t overstay its welcome, either.</p><p>Over the years, <em>Resident Evil</em> has shown that it can be many different types of horror — and <em>Requiem</em> proves that the series can pull it all off in one single experience.</p><p><sub>Resident Evil Requiem<em> launches on February 27th on the PS5, Xbox, Switch 2, and PC.</em></sub></p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTAwNTg="><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Tauriq Moosa</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/entertainment/883947/resident-evil-requiem-review-ps5-xbox-switch-2]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil Requiem is still scary as hell on the Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/games/883965/resident-evil-requiem-nintendo-switch-2-performance</link>
            <guid>1445968</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>It took me a while to recover from the first big scare in <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/entertainment/883947/resident-evil-requiem-review-ps5-xbox-switch-2">Resident Evil Requiem</a></em>. There I was, hunched over with a screen inches from my face and headphones in my ears, when a gigantic woman began chasing me through a dimly lit hallway intent on, well, eating me. It was a heart-racing sequence, and when I finally got to a save room I had to put the game down for a few minutes. It was an early indication that <em>Requiem </em>was a great game, and further evidence that the Switch 2 is becoming a welcome home for third-party titles.</p><p>Since <a href="https://www.theverge.com/nintendo/686603/nintendo-switch-2-review">Nintendo’s latest console launched last June</a>, there have been few chances to see how it directly stacks up to other platforms. The successful <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/704560/tony-hawks-pro-skater-3-4-nintendo-switch-2-comparison">cross-platform launch of <em>Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater 3+4</em></a> was a good early sign for the Switch 2, but <em>Requiem</em> might be the best test so far. It’s a blockbuster action-horror game launching simultaneously across the Switch 2, PS5, Xbox, and PC. And while there are certainly some compromises on Nintendo’s platform, <em>Requiem</em> is a surprisingly solid experience on the Switch 2.</p><p><em>Requiem</em> brings together two different types of <em>Resident Evil</em> games: <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23642938/resident-evil-4-remake-review-xbox-ps5-steam">the fast-paced action of <em>Resident Evil 4</em></a> and the more visceral first-person terror of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/1/23/14353714/resident-evil-7-biohazard-review-ps4-xbox-one-pc"><em>Biohazard</em></a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/22420738/resident-evil-village-review-playstation-xbox-pc"><em>Village</em></a>. Those two sides are represented through two playable characters. <em>RE4</em> hunk Leon returns as a grizzled action hero, while newcomer Grace is a more hapless FBI agent who does a lot of running and hiding. Impressively, you can seamlessly swap between viewpoints at any point, letting you experience Grace’s scares in first person or help Leon wield a chainsaw in third person (or vice versa).</p><p>On a purely functional level, I haven’t had any issues with the game on the Switch 2. There haven’t been any noticeable slowdowns or hitches, aside from one time when the corpse of a zombie butcher disappeared briefly, which gave me a scare thinking he’d come back to life after a tense shootout. But there’s been nothing game-breaking, and that’s been true in both portable and TV modes.</p><p>The main compromise, of course, is visual. <em>Requiem</em> on the Switch 2 simply does not look as good as it does on PC or the other consoles. There are a lot of blurry textures, particularly when you get up close to objects or walls, and things overall just don’t look as sharp or clear as they do on, say, a PS5. It’s especially noticeable in first-person mode when you’re up closer to objects and characters. I also spotted some wonky hair physics, with hair occasionally deciding to defy the laws of gravity and float whichever way it wanted. Again, none of these are game-breaking issues, but they do cut into the tension <em>Requiem</em> works so hard to build.</p><p>This is a busy week for <em>Resident Evil</em> fans who also own a Switch 2. In addition to <em>Requiem</em>, Capcom has released belated ports of <em>Biohazard</em> and <em>Village</em>. And while these are older games, my experience was much the same. I played through the beginning area of <em>Biohazard</em> again for the first time in nearly a decade — which I regret, because it is so freaking scary — and it similarly performed well but was plagued by fuzzy textures and impossible floating hair.</p><p>Honestly, that’s about the best-case scenario for ports like these. We all know the Switch 2 is underpowered compared to its direct competitors, so a game like <em>Requiem</em> is always going to feel hamstrung in some way. A port of <em>Requiem</em> that’s good enough, even if it’s not the best version of the game, goes a long way to helping Nintendo continue to flesh out the Switch 2’s library, which has <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/875986/nintendo-switch-2-release-schedule-mario-tennis-fever">grown steadily in both size and quality</a> despite a notable lack of major first-party titles from Nintendo. And let’s not forget the fact that what you lose in visual splendor you make up for in portability.</p><p><em>Requiem</em> is a good sign for the Switch 2’s viability as a platform for major third-party games, but an even better sign would be seeing releases like this more frequently. We won’t have to wait too long to see the next big test: Capcom’s sci-fi action game <em>Pragmata</em> launches across most major platforms, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/874282/nintendo-direct-february-2026-fallout-ff7">Switch 2 included</a>, in April. I can’t wait to see how hair floats in space.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTk3"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Andrew Webster</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/games/883965/resident-evil-requiem-nintendo-switch-2-performance]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>