<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 15:36:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Champions gets right to the fights]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/620196/pokemon-champions-online-pokemon-battles-nintendo-switch-mobile</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-champions-gets-right-to-the-fights.1120542/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/620196/pokemon-champions-online-pokemon-battles-nintendo-switch-mobile<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/ash-parrish">Ash Parrish</a> <span>is a reporter who covers the business, culture, and communities of video games, with a focus on marginalized gamers and the quirky, horny culture of video game communities.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>To celebrate the day when Pikachu pika’d his way into our hearts and minds almost <em>30 years ago</em>, The Pokémon Company held a Pokémon Presents showcase highlighting what games and experiences to expect in the coming months. There were updates on <em>Pokémon Legends: Z-A</em>, a new season of <em>Pokémon Concierge</em>, and a totally new multiplayer gameplay: <em>Pokémon Champions</em>.</p><p>While the reveal was light on the specifics,<em> Champions</em> appears to a game focused solely on battling. Players will be able to import their pokémon from <em>Pokémon Scarlet</em> or <em>Violet</em>, Pokémon Home, and other games into<em> Champions</em> to use in battles against players around the world. There are restrictions, however, on the pokémon you can use. The fine print says that not every pokémon available in Home and elsewhere will be available in <em>Champions</em> and those obtained in <em>Champions</em> cannot be ported back to Home.</p><p>It seems like <em>Champions</em> is a gamified version of the online battle simulators competitive <em>Pokémon</em> players use to test team composition and monster builds. The Pokémon Company was specific in that the game is coming to “the Nintendo Switch family of systems,” indicating this game might make an appearance on the forthcoming Switch 2. It’s also coming to Android and iOS.</p><p><em>Pokémon</em> is a very malleable franchise, able to fit a wide variety of game genres that The Pokémon Company seems keen to experiment with. There was <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/3/18/11259028/pokken-tournament-review-nintendo-wii-i"><em>Pokken Tournament</em></a> for the fighting game community, <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/23/22590249/pokemon-unite-nintendo-switch-hands-on-esports">Pokémon UNITE</a></em> for the MOBA fans, all the casual co-op and 1v1 experiences in the mainline games, and so much more. (Anybody remember <em>Pokémon Conquest</em>, the strategy RPG that was essentially Pikachu meets <em>Nobunaga’s Ambition</em>?) With <em>Pokémon Champions</em>, The Pokémon Company has found yet another way to reach gamers outside of its core games.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>