<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 06:44:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony is making a Horizon MMO — here’s all the details]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/819657/horizon-steel-frontiers-mmo-sony-ncsoft-playstation</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-is-making-a-horizon-mmo-%E2%80%94-here%E2%80%99s-all-the-details.1352032/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>The rumored MMO <a href="https://www.mmorpg.com/editorials/ncsoft-teases-mystery-mmorpg-at-g-star-could-it-be-the-horizon-project-2000136544">set in Sony’s post-apocalyptic <em>Horizon</em> universe</a> is real. We spilled details about the game before it was revealed based on an announcement video we saw, and that video has been officially posted — and more has been shared about the title, too.</p><p>The new game is called <em>Horizon Steel Frontiers</em>, and Sony and the Korean video game company NCSoft are working on the cross platform title together for PC, iOS, and Android. It will be free to play, <a href="https://hsf.plaync.com/en-us/conts/teaser#platform">according to the game’s website</a>. Based on the more than 10-minute announcement video, which features a mix of cinematic and pre-alpha gameplay footage as well as developer interviews, the game will focus strongly on fighting the <em>Horizon</em> series’ giant mechanical beasts and being able to do so with other people.</p><p>Sony and a PR company representing NCSoft didn’t immediately reply to a request for comment. <em>The Verge</em> initially spotted promotional art for <em>Steel Frontiers</em> on a website used to share game assets that media and influencers are approved to use. The art was posted early ahead of the <a href="https://sonyinteractive.com/en/press-releases/2025/ncsoft-unveils-horizon-steel-frontiers/">official announcement</a> at the G-Star 2025 event in Korea. The website we viewed also included a link to a Google Drive with open access that contained the video.</p><p>Footage from the announcement video shows players taking on beasts as well as navigating through lush natural environments and looming metal buildings you might be familiar with if you’ve played the <em>Horizon</em> games.</p><section tabindex="-1" aria-label="carousel"><p><strong>1<!-- -->/<!-- -->6</strong><span><figcaption><em>A gallery of pre-alpha footage of </em>Horizon Steel Frontiers<em> from a video seen by </em>The Verge <em>before the game’s announcement.</em></figcaption></span></p></section><p>“<em>Horizon Steel Frontiers</em> is a full-fledged MMORPG that NCSoft has built specifically for mobile,” Jan-Bart van Beek, studio director at PlayStation’s Guerilla Games, says in the video. “With <em>Steel Frontiers</em>, you can step into this world anywhere, anytime. Players take on the role of machine hunters, chasing opportunity in a region called the Deathlands. This is inspired by Arizona and New Mexico. You’re sharing the frontier with thousands of other players, sometimes working together to take down machines and other times competing with rival tribes or fighting over resources, and that mix of cooperation and competition creates moments that you could never script.”</p><div><p><figcaption><em>Pre-alpha footage of </em>Horizon Steel Frontiers<em> from a video seen by </em>The Verge <em>before the game’s announcement.</em></figcaption></p></div><p>“The core concept of <em>Horizon Steel Frontiers</em> can be summed up in one phrase: the thrill of taking down colossal machines,” executive producer Sung-Gu Lee says in the video. “Hunting massive machines was one of the greatest appeals of the original <em>Horizon</em> series. And now, we’re expanding that experience into the world of MMORPGs.” Lee says there will be new mechanics for fighting the machines, like picking up dropped weapons from beasts and carrying them on a mount to use in later fights. As part of the full announcement, the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@HorizonSteelFrontiers"><em>Horizon Steel Frontiers</em> YouTube channel</a> posted a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9qwAulK6db4">gameplay trailer</a> featuring fights against beasts in the game.</p><p>The announcement video also highlights the game’s character customization features — in <em>Steel Frontiers</em>, instead of playing as Aloy, who has been the series protagonist so far, you’ll be able to make your own character.</p><div><p><figcaption><em>Pre-alpha footage of </em>Horizon Steel Frontiers<em> from a video seen by </em>The Verge <em>before the game’s announcement.</em></figcaption></p></div><p>Sony and NCSoft haven’t shared a release date, but Lee says in the announcement video that the team is working to make the game available “as soon as possible.”</p><p><em><strong>Update, November 13th</strong>: Added details from the official reveal.</em></p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTIz"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Jay Peters</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/819657/horizon-steel-frontiers-mmo-sony-ncsoft-playstation]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>