<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 14:35:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghost of Yōtei is exactly the kind of game PlayStation needs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/games/784888/ghost-of-yotei-review-ps5</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ghost-of-y%C5%8Dtei-is-exactly-the-kind-of-game-playstation-needs.1308561/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Things have been weird for PlayStation of late. After years spent cultivating an image akin to the HBO of video games through single-player franchises like <em>The Last of Us</em>, <em>God of War</em>, and <em>Horizon Zero Dawn</em>, the company shifted focus, jumping on the live-service bandwagon to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/4/24235163/concord-cancellation-live-service-games">mostly disastrous effect</a>. Aside from <a href="https://www.theverge.com/22929852/horizon-forbidden-west-ps5-review">a few standouts</a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24035730/the-last-of-us-part-2-remastered-review-ps5">a number of remasters</a>, those beloved single-player games have slowed to a trickle: which is what makes <em>Ghost of Yōtei</em> so notable. Like <a href="https://www.theverge.com/21323144/ghost-of-tsushima-review-ps4-game-developer-samurai">its predecessor <em>Ghost of Tsushima</em></a>, it’s an attempt by studio Sucker Punch to merge the freedom of an open-world game with the style and drama of a classic samurai movie. More importantly, it’s exactly the kind of game that PlayStation needs more of.</p><p><em>Yōtei </em>isn’t a direct sequel, but rather a follow-up that tells a new story. This time around, you play as Atsu, whose family was killed when she was young by a group of outlaws known as the Yōtei Six. After barely surviving, she left her island home of Ezo and spent 16 years training to become a warrior capable of getting revenge. When she arrives on the island at the outset of the game, she has a very clear goal: to kill each of the Yōtei Six and then, ultimately, herself. She has each of their names written on a piece of fabric and plans to mark them off with blood after each kill. It’s both badass and unsettling.</p><p>What’s great about this setup is that it keeps the experience focused on that core theme of revenge. Like <em>Tsushima</em>, <em>Yōtei</em> doesn’t deviate too much from the typical open-world action game, and so it can feel very familiar at times. But with this idea of hunting down targets, there’s a flexibility as you approach each of the six in almost whatever order you choose. And most of what you’re doing, whether it’s looking for clues at a local tavern or learning a new weapon technique, contributes to this goal. You never lose the sense of the fact that you’re out for revenge, even when you’re dabbling in side quests. Over time, the people of Ezo start calling you <em>onryō</em>, a vengeful spirit, and that’s really how Atsu feels.</p><div><p><cite>Image: Sony Interactive Entertainment</cite></p></div><p>This structure makes <em>Yōtei</em> feel surprisingly fresh, despite that it’s not all that different from its predecessor otherwise. Many of the changes are subtle refinements. For one thing, the leap to the PS5 means the game looks incredible, and <em>Yōtei</em> takes advantage of that with some stunning set-pieces. The epic samurai duels take place in burning buildings, rain-drenched mountaintops, and fields of snow covered in golden leaves. It’s the kind of game where it’s hard not to constantly stop and take screenshots — which is very easy, as you can jump into photo mode with a single button press.</p><p><em>Yōtei</em> also has much more interesting side quests. They really vary in tone and gameplay; some involve an investigative element, as you seek out shrines in hard-to-reach areas to unlock new skills, while others are just plain funny, like an evolving series of quests about a hapless would-be samurai who is desperate to defeat Atsu. At one point, I even befriended a bear. It reminded me a lot of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/5/12/8586515/witcher-3-wild-hunt-review-ps4-xbox-one-game"><em>The Witcher 3</em></a>, where even seemingly simple stories proved to be deeper and more interesting, often with a haunting twist (the friendly bear story takes a <em>very</em> dark turn).</p><p>One element that separates the <em>Ghost</em> games from other, more bombastic open worlds is their moments of calm and reflection. As with the previous game, Atsu can seek out hot springs to relax and think back on her adventures, and there are new elements like cooking and playing a shamisen by the fire that have a similarly cozy vibe. At almost any point in the game, you can camp to replenish your spirit and cook some food, and other characters will often stop by your campsite for a chat. Given how bloody and violent the rest of the experience is, these moments of respite are very welcome.</p><div><p><cite>Image: Sony Interactive Entertainment</cite></p></div><p><em>Yōtei </em>is largely an improvement from its predecessor, in terms of both structure and story. But because the two games are so similar, <em>Yōtei</em> naturally shares some of the same flaws, which mostly stem from the sometimes incongruous mix of open-world action and the tone of a classic samurai flick. Combat is the biggest offender. When you’re fighting a few enemies — or just one of the more powerful foes — the swordplay is incredible, forcing you to be patient and strategic as you decide when to parry or attack and what kind of weapon to wield. But often, the game devolves into huge battles where the nuances of the combat get lost, and I found myself button-mashing my way to victory.</p><p>Worse still is that these battles can get in the way of the more laid-back exploration. As Atsu gains notoriety by killing her enemies, bounty hunters and other outlaws start seeking her out. Often, I would find myself repeatedly attacked by these would-be samurai while I was just trying to ride to my next destination. It became tedious and actively discouraged me from exploring the landscape, because I didn’t want to get tied up in another pointless conflict.</p><p>Mostly, though, <em>Yōtei </em>smooths out many of the issues of its predecessor, while rearranging itself to sharply focus on its epic tale of revenge. Atsu’s quest starts out violently straightforward, but things naturally become more complicated along the way thanks to some genuinely surprising twists that I won’t spoil for you. That combination of refined gameplay and cinematic story is exactly what PlayStation owners have come to expect, and <em>Ghost of Yōtei </em>shows that Sony can still pull it off. Which is good news, because <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/784746/playstation-state-of-play-september-2025-news-trailers">the pendulum appears to be swinging back to these kinds of games</a>.</p><p><sub>Ghost of Yōtei <em>launches on the PS5 on October 2nd.</em></sub></p><p><span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/784888/ghost-of-yotei-review-ps5#comments"><span>0<!-- --> <!-- -->Comments</span></a></span></p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTk3"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Andrew Webster</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/games/784888/ghost-of-yotei-review-ps5]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Remedy has a big FBC: Firebreak update aimed at turning things around]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/entertainment/784967/remedy-fbc-firebreak-update</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/remedy-has-a-big-fbc-firebreak-update-aimed-at-turning-things-around.1308558/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p>It’ll be available on all platforms on September 29th.</p></div><div><div><p>It’ll be available on all platforms on September 29th.</p><div><p><span><span>by</span> <!-- --> <span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"></span></span></p><p><span><time datetime="2025-09-25T13:00:00+00:00">Sep 25, 2025, 1:00 PM UTC</time></span></p></div></div><div><p><cite>Image: Remedy Entertainment</cite></p></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTk3"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Andrew Webster</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is an entertainment editor covering streaming, virtual worlds, and every single Pokémon video game. Andrew joined The Verge in 2012, writing over 4,000 stories.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Things haven’t started out so well for <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/665752/fbc-firebreak-preview-interview-remedy-control-ps5-xbox">FBC: Firebreak</a></em>, Remedy’s multiplayer spinoff of its <em>Control</em> universe. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games-review/689333/fbc-firebreak-review-xbox-ps5-steam">When it launched in June</a> there were complaints about repetitive gameplay and a lack of Remedy-style narrative flourishes. In a launch week update, <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/games/2272540/announcements/detail/536605349656920275">the studio admitted</a> that “Several things have gone well. Clearly, not everything has.” Now Remedy has detailed a major, free update that aims to fix some of those problems.</p><p>It’s called “Breakpoint” and it’s launching on all platforms on September 29th. According to Remedy, “this update is more than just new content — it’s a refresh of how the core game is played.”</p><p>First up is a revamp of the job board, which is now known as the crisis board. Here’s how Remedy explains the change:</p><div><blockquote><p>The new Crisis Board replaces the old Job Board and presents curated Crises to play, making FBC: Firebreak feel more dynamic, less predictable, and closer to its first-responder fantasy.</p><p>At any given time, 4-6 Crises are active globally, ranging from full runs to shorter Jobs or Corrupted Jobs, each with randomized rewards, objectives, and length. The Crisis Board refreshes every 30 minutes.</p><p>Crises in Zones 1-2 have streamlined requirements and can occasionally swap in unique Alternative Objectives for added variety. The Quick Reinforce feature lets you jump into active runs to help other teams.</p></blockquote></div><p>And to deal with the lack-of-variety issue, <em>Firebreak </em>is getting five new enemy types, six new weapons (three grenades, three heavy weapons), and a total of 27 gun mods to add further customization. Perhaps most notable is a new mission called “Outbreak,” in which “a Mold infestation creates unique challenges, enemies, and a dangerous new condition.”</p><div><p>There are a handful of other changes to the experience. Yesterday <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.steampowered.com%2Fnews%2Fapp%2F2272540%3Femclan%3D103582791474781150%26emgid%3D530984095140809424" rel="sponsored">Remedy detailed more simplified economy and progression systems</a>, and the studio says the onboarding has been improved as well with, among other things, a new tutorial level.</p></div><p>Whether or not these changes are enough remains to be seen, but the studio has further changes planned as well. An update in November will add a new game mode and cross-platform voice chat, and a third major update is expected in March. “We hope that these changes and additions make <em>FBC: Firebreak </em>more welcoming to new players while deepening the challenge and customization for veterans,” Remedy says.</p><p><span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/entertainment/784967/remedy-fbc-firebreak-update#comments"><span>0<!-- --> <!-- -->Comments</span></a></span></p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTk3"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Andrew Webster</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><div><form><div><h2>The Verge Daily</h2><p><span>A free daily digest of the news that matters most.</span></p></div></form></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/entertainment/784967/remedy-fbc-firebreak-update]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>