<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 23:57:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here’s a new trailer for the ambitious survival game from PUBG’s creator]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/620988/playerunknown-productions-prologue-go-wayback-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/here%E2%80%99s-a-new-trailer-for-the-ambitious-survival-game-from-pubg%E2%80%99s-creator.1121097/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/620988/playerunknown-productions-prologue-go-wayback-trailer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/jay-peters">Jay Peters</a> <span>is a news editor covering technology, gaming, and more. He joined The Verge in 2019 after nearly two years at Techmeme.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>PlayerUnknown Productions, the studio from <em>PUBG</em> creator Brendan Greene (aka PlayerUnknown), has shared a gameplay trailer for <em>Prologue: Go Wayback!</em>, a single-player survival game that’s launching in early access on Steam this year.</p><p>The studio <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/5/24313965/pubg-brendan-playerunknown-greene-new-games-krafton">previously shared</a> that the game would be built with “machine-learning-driven terrain generation technology,” and in this new trailer, you can see some gorgeous, wooded areas on display. In the game, you’ll also have to deal with various types of weather, including pouring rain and heavy snow. The point of the game, according to a fact sheet, is to explore and survive so that you can find a weather station to call for help.</p><p><em>Prologue</em> is just one of three games in the works from PlayerUnknown Productions. The “ultimate project,” dubbed <em>Project Artemis</em>, is going to be “a massive multiplayer sandbox experience” that builds on the technology featured in <em>Prologue</em> and a tech demo, <em>Preface: Undiscovered World</em>, that’s <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.steampowered.com%2Fapp%2F2820060%2FPreface_Undiscovered_World%2F" rel="sponsored">available on Steam</a>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>