<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 15:58:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft adds Steam games to its Xbox PC app on Windows]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/690967/microsoft-xbox-app-windows-steam-games-aggregated-library-support-beta</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-adds-steam-games-to-its-xbox-pc-app-on-windows.1225869/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="__next"><p><a href="#content"><span>Skip to main content</span></a></p><nav aria-label="Sticky Nav"></nav><div><main id="content"><article><div><div><div><p><span><ul><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news">News</a></li></ul></span></p></div><div><p>Xbox Insiders get access to Microsoft’s new aggregated gaming library this week.</p></div></div><div><div><p>Xbox Insiders get access to Microsoft’s new aggregated gaming library this week.</p><div><p><span><time datetime="2025-06-23T15:00:00+00:00">Jun 23, 2025, 3:00 PM UTC</time></span></p></div></div><div><p><cite>Image: Cath Virginia / The Verge</cite></p></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/tom-warren">Tom Warren</a> <span>is a senior editor and author of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/notepad-microsoft-newsletter"><i>Notepad</i></a>, who has been covering all things Microsoft, PC, and tech for over 20 years.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Microsoft is starting to test its new aggregated gaming library in its Xbox PC app on Windows. Xbox Insiders will now be able to see their Steam and Battle.net games all within the Xbox app this week — making it a single launcher for most installed PC games.</p><p>This new consolidated library will roll out to the Xbox app later this year, as well as new devices like the ROG Xbox Ally handhelds. It’s part of Microsoft’s efforts to make the Xbox app on Windows <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318799/microsoft-xbox-app-new-games-homescreen">the home of PC gaming</a> and compete with Steam and SteamOS by <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/682011/microsoft-windows-xbox-pc-combination-features-rog-xbox-ally-devices">combining Windows and Xbox</a>.</p><p>“When a player installs a game from a supported PC storefront, it will automatically appear in ‘My library’ within the Xbox PC app, as well as the ‘Most recent’ list of titles in the sidebar — making it easier than ever to jump back into your games,“ <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/06/23/xbox-insiders-aggregated-gaming-library-is-coming-to-the-xbox-pc-app/">explains Manisha Oza</a>, product manager of the Xbox platform. Microsoft says support for additional PC storefronts will roll out over time.</p><p>If you want to try out the new aggregated library in the Xbox app on Windows, you can simply download the <a href="https://apps.microsoft.com/detail/9PLDPG46G47Z?hl=en-us&amp;gl=GB&amp;ocid=pdpshare">Xbox Insider Hub</a> on PC and join the PC gaming preview. You can also manage the visibility of games by hiding any PC storefront in the Library &amp; Extensions section of the Xbox app settings.</p></div></div><div><form><div><h2>Installer</h2><p><span>A weekly newsletter by David Pierce designed to tell you everything you need to download, watch, read, listen to, and explore that fits in The Verge’s universe.</span></p></div></form></div></div></article></main></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/690967/microsoft-xbox-app-windows-steam-games-aggregated-library-support-beta]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>