<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 19:07:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals gets Wolverine, Black Widow, and more in the latest trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/30/24309516/marvel-rivals-gets-wolverine-black-widow-and-more-in-the-latest-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-gets-wolverine-black-widow-and-more-in-the-latest-trailer.1048689/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/30/24309516/marvel-rivals-gets-wolverine-black-widow-and-more-in-the-latest-trailer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><article id="content"><div><div><h2>Marvel Rivals gets Wolverine, Black Widow, and more in the latest trailer</h2><p><span><span> / </span><h2>Marvel revealed the final five characters for Rivals ahead of its December 6th debut.</h2></span></p></div><div><p><span>By</span> <span><span></span> <span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/wes-davis">Wes Davis</a></span><span>, <span>a weekend editor who covers the latest in tech and entertainment. He has written news, reviews, and more as a tech journalist since 2020.</span></span></span></p><p><time datetime="2024-11-30T17:13:04.460Z"> <!-- -->Nov 30, 2024, 5:13 PM UTC</time></p><div><h2>Share this story</h2></div></div></div><div><div><p>With a new <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-b0veB7q9P4"><em>Marvel Rivals </em>trailer</a>, Marvel has revealed that Wolverine, Black Widow, Iron Fist, Squirrel Girl, and Cloak and Dagger will all be part of its upcoming 6 v 6 hero shooter<em>. </em>The company says in an <a href="https://www.marvel.com/articles/games/marvel-rivals-launch-trailer-features-chrissy-costanza-from-against-the-current">announcement</a> that each of them will be “fully revealed” in one trailer per day leading up to its December 6th launch.</p><p>The trailer hints at some of the attacks the characters will have, including a Hulk / Wolverine team-up that involves the big green guy flinging Marvel’s furry short king at their adversaries. Some other paired attacks show up, like Squirrel Girl catching a Spider-Man web ball and apparently turning it into an exploding slingshot projectile, or Black Window and Hawkeye firing side-by-side. </p><p>Marvel also took the wraps off a new map called Kyntar: Symbiotic Surface in a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X-CFFxqFNRo">separate video</a> published on Thursday. Here’s the synopsis from Marvel’s announcement: </p><div><blockquote><p>The awakening Knull has cast a shadow over the Panther God Bast. In response, Shuri sends the Guardians of the Galaxy to Klyntar to seek out a solution to this looming threat. After the Milano crashes on Klyntar, the Guardians bump into Venom. The two sides have different opinions on how to defeat Knull: Venom, having extracted the Knull Essence from a controlled symbiote, argues for caution due to its volatile nature and the risk of harming the planet’s symbiotes. With Knull still dormant, Venom prefers to wait until they can harness this power safely. On the other hand, the Guardians, tasked by Shuri, are eager to immediately neutralize Knull’s influence over the gods including Bast. At an impasse, they decide to go their separate ways.</p></blockquote></div><p><em>Marvel Rivals </em>is coming to PS5, Xbox Series X / S, and PC (via Steam and the Epic Games Store) on December 6th. Ahead of that, the Marvel Games team is holding an AMA on December 4th at 10PM ET on the game’s <a href="https://www.discord.gg/marvelrivals">official Discord</a>.</p></div><div><p>Most Popular</p><p>Most Popular</p><ol><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24307545/black-friday-2024-best-deals-tech-gadgets-cyber-monday-gift-ideas"><h2>The best Black Friday tech&nbsp;deals&nbsp;we’ve found</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/26/24303161/amazon-influencers-lawsuit-copyright-clean-aesthetic-girl-sydney-nicole-gifford-alyssa-sheil"><h2>Bad influence</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24306534/black-friday-2024-streaming-best-deals-max-hulu-peacock-paramount-plus-cyber-monday"><h2>Max, Hulu, and Paramount Plus are all heavily discounted for Black Friday</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/29/24308746/meta-10-billion-global-subsea-cable-project"><h2>Meta is building the ‘mother of all’ subsea cables</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/29/24308950/hyundai-ioniq-5-n-review-price-specs-photos"><h2>Hyundai Ioniq 5 N review: fake shifting, real fun</h2></a><hr></li></ol></div></div></article></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You can still score a PlayStation 5 for as low as $374 for Black Friday]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/30/24308967/black-friday-2024-playstation-5-ps5-slim-digital-edition-disc-cyber-monday</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/you-can-still-score-a-playstation-5-for-as-low-as-374-for-black-friday.1048572/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/30/24308967/black-friday-2024-playstation-5-ps5-slim-digital-edition-disc-cyber-monday<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Sony and other game makers are running all kinds of Black Friday sales right now, allowing you to save on games, consoles, and plenty of accessories. However, one of the better offers still available is on the latest<strong> PlayStation 5 Digital Edition</strong>, which is on sale at <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSony-PlayStation-5-PS5-Digital-Console-Slim%2F5113183757">Walmart</a>, <a href="https://howl.link/ow8vdkonq4ogj">Best Buy</a>, and Sony’s <a href="https://direct.playstation.com/en-us/buy-consoles/playstation5-digital-edition-console-model-group-slim">PlayStation Direct storefront</a> for an all-time low of $374 ($75 off). It’s also available at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/PlayStation%C2%AE5-Digital-slim-PlayStation-5/dp/B0DJHG2VVS?tag=theverge02-20">Amazon</a> as part of a <em>Fortnite</em> bundle that includes some in-game cosmetics and other freebies.</p><p>Alternatively, if you prefer your console to come with its disc drive (instead of having to potentially add one later), you can get a <strong>disc-ready PS5</strong> for $424 (regularly $499) at <a href="https://howl.link/a96z6zpacc2ax">Best Buy</a>, <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSony-PlayStation-5-PS5-Disc-Console-Slim%2F5113183756">Walmart</a>, <a href="https://direct.playstation.com/en-us/buy-consoles/playstation5-console-model-group-slim">PlayStation Direct</a>, and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/PlayStation%C2%AE5-Digital-slim-PlayStation-5/dp/B0DJHF6Q9Z?th=1&amp;tag=theverge02-20">Amazon</a> (in that same <em>Fortnite</em> bundle). <a href="https://direct.playstation.com/en-us/">According to Sony’s listing</a>, the ongoing promo should last through the holidays. So, while you may have time to mull it over, there’s no guarantee your preferred retailer (or the one you collect rewards points from) will have it in stock the whole time.</p><div><p>The PlayStation 5 Digital doesn’t come with a disc drive, but you can buy one separately if you later decide you want one. The console otherwise plays all of the same games as the version equipped with a disc drive.</p></div><div><p>Sony’s new standard PlayStation 5 includes a removable disc drive, dual front-facing USB-C ports, 1TB of storage, and a slightly smaller and lighter design.</p></div><p>The PS5 has been with us for more than four years now, so it’s built up an expansive lineup of 4K-capable games and now offers a little something for everyone. It may not seem as special now that the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/reviews/24289319/ps5-pro-review">PS5 Pro</a> is out, but at this discounted price, the PS5 “slim” is almost half the cost of a $699 Pro (and even with the Pro, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/10/24240906/sony-ps5-pro-disc-drive-separate-price">you don’t get a disc drive</a>).</p><p>The regular PS5s may not have the same level of graphical performance as the Pro, but in the end, they all play the same games. And if you’re not the type to notice or care about the tiniest of details when it comes to resolution, frame rate, or extras like raytraced lighting,  the difference between a PS5 and PS5 Pro may not be very stark.</p><div><form><div><h2>Verge Deals</h2><p> / <span>Sign up for Verge Deals to get deals on products we've tested sent to your inbox weekly.</span></p></div></form></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>