<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 13:59:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GeoGuessr is coming to Steam after 12 years in your browser]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/636201/geoguessr-steam-browser-game-early-access</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/geoguessr-is-coming-to-steam-after-12-years-in-your-browser.1145037/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/636201/geoguessr-steam-browser-game-early-access<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/dominic-preston">Dominic Preston</a> <span>is a news editor with over a decade’s experience in journalism. He previously worked at <em>Android Police</em> and <em>Tech Advisor</em>.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>12-year-old browser game GeoGuessr is getting a belated port to PC, with a new listing for the game now in the Steam Store. Despite its age, GeoGuessr will launch in Early Access when it goes on sale some time in April 2025.</p><p>GeoGuessr <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/5/12/4323978/geoguessr-map-game-google-street-view-exploration">first launched in 2013</a>, and tasks players with figuring out their coordinates after being dropped into a random Google Street View location. Over the years it’s developed an <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/21/22846869/geoguessr-competitive-esport-reddit-geowizard-google-street-view">unlikely competitive esports scene</a>, which the Steam edition looks to capitalize on, with a focus on competitive modes and ranked play.</p><p>The <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.steampowered.com%2Fapp%2F3478870%2FGeoGuessr_Steam_Edition%2F" rel="sponsored">Steam listing</a> explains that the game will remain in Early Access “for at least six months,” while the developers add “new game modes, maps, and competitive features.” At launch it will support ranked Solo Duels and unranked Team Duels, including <a href="https://x.com/geoguessr/status/1904516547806150715">cross-play with the browser version</a>.</p><p>What we don’t know is exactly when in April GeoGuessr will launch on Steam, or how much it will cost. While the game’s browser version was initially free, it now only allows you to make three guesses per day before requiring a <a href="https://www.geoguessr.com/pro">paid subscription</a>, starting from $2.49 per month. GeoGuessr’s iOS and Android apps are locked behind the $2.99 Pro Unlimited plan, but the Steam app will require a new account that will not be synced with existing Geoguessr accounts, so may have its own pricing structure.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PS5 owners really want to play Xbox games, as Microsoft tops Sony’s preorder charts]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/636178/microsoft-playstation-store-ps5-xbox-games-preorder-chart</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ps5-owners-really-want-to-play-xbox-games-as-microsoft-tops-sony%E2%80%99s-preorder-charts.1145010/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/636178/microsoft-playstation-store-ps5-xbox-games-preorder-chart<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/tom-warren">Tom Warren</a> <span>is a senior editor and author of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/notepad-microsoft-newsletter"><i>Notepad</i></a>, who has been covering all things Microsoft, PC, and tech for over 20 years.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>If you’re looking for some solid evidence that Microsoft’s strategy to bring Xbox games to PS5 is seeing some early success, look no further than Sony’s own PlayStation Store today. The top preordered games in the <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/category/3bf499d7-7acf-4931-97dd-2667494ee2c9/1">US PlayStation Store</a> are <em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</em> and <em>Forza Horizon 5</em>, with the $99.99 premium versions of both games proving the most popular.</p><p><a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-is-topping-the-pre-order-charts-on-the-playstation-store-with-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-and-forza-horizon-5.1144932/">Resetera</a> posters have noticed it’s the same story in the <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-ca/category/3bf499d7-7acf-4931-97dd-2667494ee2c9/1">Canadian</a> PlayStation Store and across a variety of European stores, including <a href="https://store.playstation.com/fr-fr/category/3bf499d7-7acf-4931-97dd-2667494ee2c9/1">France</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/de-de/category/3bf499d7-7acf-4931-97dd-2667494ee2c9/1">Germany</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/it-it/category/3bf499d7-7acf-4931-97dd-2667494ee2c9/1">Italy</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/es-es/category/3bf499d7-7acf-4931-97dd-2667494ee2c9/1">Spain</a>, and the <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-gb/category/3bf499d7-7acf-4931-97dd-2667494ee2c9/1">UK</a>. Microsoft-owned Bethesda <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/610817/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-ps5-release-date">announced earlier this week</a> that <em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</em> will debut on PS5 on April 17th, with the premium version providing two days of early access starting April 15th. <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/620993/forzas-on-ps5s-horizon">Forza Horizon 5</a></em> is also coming to Sony’s rival console on April 29th.</p><p>Microsoft may have timed these two games perfectly for the PS5, amid a slow point for Sony’s own game studios, but the software maker has seen success with its earlier Xbox titles on PS5, too. <em>Sea of Thieves</em> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/2/21/24079090/hi-fi-rush-ps5-xbox-release-date">debuted on PS5</a> in April last year and <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/06/13/playstation-store-may-2024s-top-downloads/">Sony revealed</a> it was the top seller across the US, Canada, and EU markets a month later. It remained in Sony’s top downloads list for nearly six months.</p><p>Microsoft’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/2/12/24067370/microsoft-xbox-playstation-switch-games-future-hardware">Xbox everywhere strategy</a> — which I’ve been covering closely in <a href="https://www.theverge.com/notepad-microsoft-newsletter">my <em>Notepad </em>newsletter</a> over the past year — is clearly doing well on PS5, and I’d expect to see more titles land on Sony’s console throughout 2025 and beyond. Microsoft is also preparing a similar list of Xbox games for Nintendo’s Switch 2, with <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-launch-plans/">reports suggesting</a> the next-gen console will launch in June with third-party games to follow later this year.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>