<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 15:01:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghosts in the Kinect]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/games/638490/microsoft-kinect-ghost-hunting</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ghosts-in-the-kinect.1149165/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/games/638490/microsoft-kinect-ghost-hunting<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Billy Tolley swings a Microsoft Kinect around an abandoned room in sudden, jittery movements. “Whoa!” he says. “Dude, it was so creepy.” On the display, we see an anomaly of arrows, spheres, and red lines that disappears almost as soon as it arrives. For Tolley and Zak Bagans, two members of the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yG17LDeGs14">Ghost Adventures</a> YouTube channel, this is enough to suggest they should leave the building. Because for this team and other similar enthusiasts, that seemingly innocuous blotter of white arrows means something more terrifying: a glimpse at specters and phantoms invisible to the human eye. </p><p>Fifteen years after its release, just about the only people still buying the Microsoft Kinect are ghost hunters like Tolley and Bagans. Though the body-tracking camera, which <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/25/16542870/microsoft-kinect-dead-stop-manufacturing">was discontinued in 2017</a>, started as a gaming peripheral, it also enjoyed a spirited afterlife <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2011/12/6/2616242/kinect-hacks">outside of video games</a>. But in 2025, its most notable application is helping paranormal investigators, like the Ghost Adventures team, in their attempts at documenting the afterlife.</p><p>The Kinect’s ability to convert the data from its body-tracking sensors into an on-screen skeletal dummy delights these investigators, who allege the figures it shows in empty space are, in fact, skeletons of the spooky, scary variety. Looking at it in use — the Kinect is particularly popular with ghost-hunting YouTubers — it’s certainly producing results, showing human-like figures where there are none. The question is: why?</p><p>With the help of ghost hunters and those familiar with how the Kinect actually works, <em>The Verge</em> set out to understand why the perhaps most misbegotten gaming peripheral has gained such a strong foothold in the search for the paranormal.</p><p>Part of the reason is purely technical. “The Kinect’s popularity as a depth camera for ghost hunting stems from its ability to detect depth and create stick-figure representations of humanoid shapes, making it easier to identify potential human-like forms, even if faint or translucent,” says Sam Ashford, founder of ghost-hunting equipment store <a href="https://www.spiritshack.co.uk/about-us/">SpiritShack</a>.</p><p>This is made possible by the first-generation Kinect’s structured light system. By projecting a grid of infrared dots into an environment — even a dark one — and reading the resulting pattern, the Kinect can detect deformations in the projection and, through a machine-learning algorithm, discern human limbs within those deformations. The Kinect then converts that data into a visual representation of a stick figure, which, in its previous life, was pumped back into games like <em>Dance Central</em> and <em>Kinect Sports</em>.</p><div><p>The Kinect isn’t always seeing what it thinks it is</p></div><p>When it was released in 2010, the first-gen Kinect was cutting-edge technology: a high-powered, robust, and lightweight depth camera that condensed what would usually retail upward of $6,000 into a $150 peripheral. Today, you can find a Kinect on eBay for around $20. Ghost hunters, however, typically mount it to a carry handle and a tablet and upsell it for around $400-600, rebranded as a “structured light sensor” (SLS) camera. “The user will direct the camera to a certain point of the room where they believe activity to be present,” says Andy Bailey, founder of a gear shop for ghost hunters called <a href="https://www.infraready.co.uk/">Infraready</a>. “The subject area will be absent of human beings. However, the camera will often calculate and display the presence of a skeletal image.”</p><p>Though this is often touted as proof we’re all bound for an eternity haunting aging hotels and abandoned prisons, Bailey urges caution, telling would-be ghost hunters that the cameras are best paired with other equipment to “provide an additional layer of supporting evidence.” For this, Ghost Hunters Equipment, the retail arm of haunted tour operator <a href="https://ghostaugustine.com/">Ghost Augustine</a> recommends that “EMF readings, temperature, baseline readings, and all of that are essential when considering authentication of paranormal activity.”</p><p>That’s because the Kinect isn’t always seeing what it thinks it is. But what <em>is</em> it actually seeing? Did Microsoft, while trying to break into a motion-control market monopolized by the Nintendo Wii, accidentally create a conduit through which we might glimpse the afterlife? Sadly, no.</p><div><p><cite>Photo by Joe Raedle/Getty Images</cite></p></div><p>The Kinect is actually a straightforward piece of hardware. It is trained to recognize the human body, and assumes that it’s always looking at one — because that’s what it’s designed to do. Whatever you show it, whether human or humanoid or something entirely different, it will try and discern human anatomy. If the Kinect is not 100 percent sure of its position, it might even look like the figure it displays is moving. “We may recognise the face of Jesus in a piece of toast or an elephant in a rock formation,” says Jon Wood, <a href="https://jonwoodscience.com/">a science performer</a> who has a show devoted to examining ghost hunting equipment. “Our brains are trying to make sense of the randomness.” The Kinect does much the same, except it cannot overrule its hunches. </p><p>That suits ghost hunters just fine, of course: the Kinect’s habit of finding human shapes where there are none is a crowd-pleaser. The Kinect, deployed in dark rooms bathed in infrared light from cameras and torches, wobbling in the hands of excitable ghost hunters as it tries to read a precise grid of infrared points, is almost guaranteed to show them what they want to see.</p><p>Much of ghost hunting depends on ambiguity. If you’re searching for proof of something, be it the afterlife or not, logic suggests you’d want tools that can provide the clearest results, the better to cement the veracity of that proof. Ghost hunters, however, prefer technology that will produce results of any kind: murky recordings on 2000s voice recorders that might be mistaken for voices, low-resolution videos haunted by shadowy artifacts, and any cheap equipment that can call into question the existence of dust (sorry, <a href="https://www.spiritshack.co.uk/blog/ghost-hunting/what-are-orbs-and-what-do-orbs-mean/?srsltid=AfmBOop0q1b5vRMlNWw7sKVl1DCra20mlKMdO0a4-hpSqFJWqCsj1Scz"><em>spirit</em> <em>orbs</em></a>) — bonus points if battery life is temperamental.</p><p>“I’ve watched ghost hunters use two different devices for measuring electromagnetic fields (EMF),” Wood says. “One would be an accurate and expensive Trifled TF2, that never moves unless it actually encounters an electrical field. The other would be a £15 [$18], no-brand, ‘KII’ device with five lights that go berserk when someone so much as sneezes. Which one was more popular, do you think?”</p><div><p>Glitches aren’t tolerated — they’re <em>encouraged</em></p></div><p>Given the notoriously unreliable skeletal tracking of the Kinect — most non-gaming applications bypass the Kinect’s default SDKs, preferring to process its raw data by other, less error-prone, means — it would be stranger if it <em>didn’t </em>see figures every time it’s deployed. But that’s the point. Like so much technology ghost hunters use, the Kinect’s flaws aren’t bugs or glitches. They’re not tolerated — they’re <em>encouraged</em>.</p><p>“If a person pays good money to enjoy a ghost hunt, what are they after?” Wood asks. “They prime themselves for a ‘spooky encounter’ and open up to the suggestion of anything being ‘evidence of a ghost’ — they want to find a ghost, so they make sure they do.”</p><p>If it were just the skeletal tracking that ghost hunters were after, better options are now possible with a simple color image. But improved methodology wouldn’t return the false-positives that maintain belief, and so skeletal tracking from 2010 is preferred. None of this is likely to move the needle for those who believe towards something more skeptical. But we <em>do </em>know why the Kinect (or SLS) returns the results it does, and we <em>know </em>it’s not ghosts.</p><p>That said, even if its results are erroneous, maybe the Kinect’s new lease on afterlife isn’t a bad thing. Much as ghosts supposedly patrol the same paths over and over until interrupted by ghost hunters, perhaps it’s fitting that the Kinect will continue forevermore to track human bodies — even if the bodies aren’t really there.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Shadows lives up to the series’ name]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/games/637717/assassins-creed-shadows-stealth-assassinations</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-shadows-lives-up-to-the-series%E2%80%99-name.1148763/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/games/637717/assassins-creed-shadows-stealth-assassinations<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>I realized quite late in <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/games-review/631744/assassins-creed-shadows-review-ubisoft">Assassin’s Creed Shadows</a></em> that being this version of a shinobi is hard — but it was precisely the precision the game demanded that made it all the more rewarding.</p><p>With <em>Shadows</em>, the <em>Assassin’s Creed</em> franchise has achieved both its most impressive stealth and assassination mechanics. At its best, <em>Shadows</em> evokes games like <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/11/23/13719322/dishonored-2-immersive-sim-serious-game-melodrama">Arkane’s <em>Dishonored</em> series</a>, mixing emergent action with an artful blend of skills and scenarios. While not nearly at the level of sophistication as those games, I nevertheless had moments that left me breathless from what I could achieve. These put me more in the space of immersive simulated assassination games than the most recent, chest-thumping<em> Assassin’s Creed</em> games.</p><p>Here’s an example. In Ubisoft’s open-world third-person action game, I was faced with a group of about 10 men in a dark cave, all of whom turned out to be targets I’d been hunting for ages. They were all part of one group, who I’d been carefully taking down individually — one leading me to the next. Now, after tracking one, it turned out he and his remaining colleagues had decided to hold a meeting. Together. With their guards. I hadn’t planned this, but now I either had to leave or use this opportunity to finish the job in one lethal swoop.</p><p>Importantly, my character, the shinobi Naoe, was not without her own tricks to balance the overwhelming odds. First, she wasn’t alone. In <em>Shadows</em>, you organically recruit allies throughout your massive revenge quest. You can summon them at a moment’s notice to assist you in any scenario: from a barefisted fighter monk to a giggling, creepy teenage poisoner. Having “upgraded” my poisoner, her poison bomb put three enemies to sleep immediately. Her upgrades also meant anyone who came to investigate fell under the same spell. I began by summoning said poisoner to take out several of the targets and guards.</p><p>Second, Naoe herself has skills that verge on magical, such as slowing down time while moving at normal speed — again, reminiscent of <em>Dishonored</em> or Arkane’s other big hitter, <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22671207/deathloop-review-ps5-pc">Deathloop</a></em>. Using this skill immediately after my poisoner allowed me to throw several deadly kunai at guards’ heads and move closer to the actual targets for a slick close-up double assassination.</p><p>All of this happened within less than 20 seconds. And voila! All the targets and their guards were down.</p><p>Never had I felt more like an assassin in <em>Assassin’s Creed</em>. It surprised me, given that I have been playing the franchise since the first game. But this moment made me realize that I had never had to be this clever before in these games, or had access to such a variety of complementary skills, tools, and abilities. Even the more recent trilogy of “reboots” — <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/4/16414638/assassins-creed-origins-ancient-egypt-hands-on-open-world-exploration"><em>Origins</em></a>, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/1/17921552/assassins-creed-odyssey-review-ps4-xbox-pc"><em>Odyssey</em></a>, and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/12/21319059/assassins-creed-valhalla-hands-on-preview-pc-xbox-one-ps4-gameplay-ubisoft-rpg"><em>Valhalla</em></a> — did not feature such variety and complementary actions. While the lovable goofball protagonists of those games develop god-like abilities, most were centered around combat rather than stealth. The last expansion of <em>Valhalla</em>, for example, literally saw you play a god, Odin, battling through the Norse realms to save his son, Baldur.</p><p>Now, with <em><em>Shadows</em></em>, Ubisoft has managed to balance both action and stealth, allowing you to play as the shinobi Naoe and the lethal mountain samurai Yasuke. It’s Naoe’s stealth, in particular, that has left me impressed. <em>Shadows</em> creates multiple scenarios that require planning for your shinobi. While Naoe moves like dark silk on a night wind and can instantly assassinate multiple targets, she can die quickly. Yet, she will often face large set pieces with upward of 20–30 enemies patrolling an area.</p><p>The game places huge rewards in, for example, giant, heavily guarded castles. Walking in the front gate is almost never an option. But Naoe can climb overhanging trees, find cracks in walls, and swim in via aqueducts. Once inside, she can use “eagle vision” to see through walls and tag enemies. <em>Shadows </em>removes the flying companion from the previous three games, which acted like a military drone to provide air reconnaissance.</p><p>Now, it’s entirely within the limited confines of Naoe’s vision — but that’s not necessarily limiting. If used properly, Naoe can never be surprised and can plan the order of assassination such that no one ever realizes she has infiltrated. For example, if one guard is patrolling, it could be easier to take him out, rather than his colleagues who are stationed, since he may spot you moving.</p><p>The size of these places turns this into a murdery puzzle. If I take Guard A out, I have access to Guards B and C. However, Guard D is watching Guard A, etc. Without realizing it, you have to create an assassination Rube Goldberg machine, taking one out, then another, timing it and using different abilities, recruits, and so on. It takes some time to get through these giant castles, but you’re rewarded with some of the best weapons and armor in the game. And if you’re caught, you are hunted for a while, making traversal a hazard. In previous entries, stealth was largely optional and functional but unremarkable. There was also no real penalty for being spotted that those godlike protagonists couldn’t easily silence.</p><p>Similarly, the other playable character, the samurai Yasuke, requires careful consideration, despite being a moving mountain. He doesn’t have eagle vision. He is made for loud lethality; even his instant assassinations sever heads and limbs. This creates its own thoughtful play since you need to carefully move and work your way through these large set pieces, ideally without drawing attention.</p><p>Yasuke’s advantage is that he can use a huge bow to take enemies out instantly from a distance — unlike Naoe, who has to be close. This speaks to the give-and-take theme central to the game’s mechanics. But Yasuke can more easily and quickly end alerts, making his style of murder puzzle less clean but easier to recover from should things go awry.</p><p>I did not expect <em>Shadows</em> to place so much work and thought into its assassinations, which is obviously amusing given the name of the franchise. Having played this series since its inception, I was struck by the emphasis on clean, thoughtful assassinations — not only within scripted contexts, but in the open world itself.</p><p>After years of trending toward bombastic action, <em>Shadows</em> points toward a future where <em>Assassin’s Creed</em> continues to live up to its name — and hopefully creates scenarios to make players feel like the titular leads, rather than god-like warriors.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>