<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 01:48:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here’s your very first look at The Witcher 4]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/12/24320092/the-witcher-4-trailer-game-awards-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/here%E2%80%99s-your-very-first-look-at-the-witcher-4.1059801/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/12/24320092/the-witcher-4-trailer-game-awards-2024<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="__next"><p><a href="#content">Skip to main content</a></p><div><main><article id="content"><div><div><h2>Here’s your very first look at The Witcher 4</h2><p><span><span> / </span><h2>The game got a surprise unveiling at The Game Awards.</h2></span></p></div><div><p><span>By</span> <span><span></span> <span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/andrew-webster">Andrew Webster</a></span><span>, <span>an entertainment editor covering streaming, virtual worlds, and every single Pokémon video game. Andrew joined The Verge in 2012, writing over 4,000 stories.</span></span></span></p><p><time datetime="2024-12-13T01:25:12.335Z"> <!-- -->Dec 13, 2024, 1:25 AM UTC</time></p><div><h2>Share this story</h2></div></div></div><div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>The 2024 edition of The Game Awards started with a bang — the very first look at the next <em>Witcher</em> game. It’s called <em>The Witcher 4</em>, and was revealed via a lengthy cinematic trailer that starred Ciri in place of Geralt, who led the original trilogy. There aren’t many details yet, but CD Projekt Red says that in the new game “Ciri takes center stage as the protagonist, embarking on her own journey to become a professional monster slayer.” It will be a single-player, open-world RPG.</p><p>It doesn’t sound like the trailer will necessarily be representative of the final game, however. Here’s how CD Projekt Red explains it:</p><div><blockquote><p>In the nearly six-minute trailer, viewers were introduced to Ciri, the adopted daughter of Geralt of Rivia, as she takes on a witcher contract in a remote village that has been terrorized for generations by a fearsome monster demanding human sacrifices. Framed as a short, self-contained&nbsp;<em>Witcher</em>&nbsp;story, the trailer showcases Ciri’s new abilities and tools, including a chain and advanced magic powers.</p><p>At the heart of the trailer is Ciri’s perspective as an outsider to the village. As the villagers say goodbye to one of their own — a young girl they are preparing for a traditional ritual sacrifice — Ciri chooses to intervene. Aiming to slay the beast and save the girl at the same time, Ciri finds herself at odds with the prejudices and superstitions of the people she tries to protect, leading her to confront a painful witcher lesson: that monsters come in all forms.</p></blockquote></div><p>We’ve known for some time that <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/10/4/23387206/cyberpunk-witcher-new-games-cd-projekt-red-cdpr-franchise-hadar-multiplayer">CD Projekt Red was working on a follow up</a> to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/12/12/23505545/the-witcher-3-next-gen-update-ps5-xbox-pc-hands-on"><em>The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt</em></a>, which is meant to kick off a new saga for the fantasy franchise. In November <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/26/24306590/the-witcher-keeps-on-witching">the studio revealed</a> that the game, previously codenamed “Polaris,” was in the “full-scale production phase” of development.” It’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/10/26/23424463/witcher-remake-cd-projekt-red-unreal-engine-5">being built using Unreal Engine 5</a>, which the studio shifted to following the troubled launch of <em>Cyberpunk 2077</em>. When it comes to the cinematics shown off today, the studio says that “the cinematic trailer is pre-rendered in a custom build of Unreal Engine 5 on an unannounced NVIDIA GeForce RTX GPU.”</p><p>No word yet on platforms or release timing.</p></div><div><p>Most Popular</p><p>Most Popular</p><ol><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318444/google-gemini-2-0-flash-ai-model"><h2>Google launched Gemini 2.0, its new AI model for practically everything</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/12/24319585/youtube-tv-2024-subscription-price-increase-82-99"><h2>YouTube TV’s monthly cost soars to $82.99</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/12/24318840/ios-18-2-apple-intelligence-chatgpt-genmoji-image-playground"><h2>With iOS 18.2, Apple completes its AI starter kit</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/12/24319498/pokemon-tcg-pocket-mythical-island-release-date"><h2>Pokémon TCG Pocket’s new expansion drops next week</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/12/24319528/google-android-xr-samsung-project-moohan-smart-glasses"><h2>I saw Google’s plan to put Android on your face</h2></a><hr></li></ol></div></div></article></main><div><h2>More from this stream<!-- --> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24319637/the-game-awards-2024-trailers-annoucements">The Game Awards 2024: all of the biggest trailers and announcements</a></h2><ul><li><h3><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/12/24320097/elden-ring-sequel-nightreign-the-game-awards-trailer">FromSoftware debuts a new Elden Ring game</a></h3><p><time datetime="2024-12-13T01:44:49.236Z"> <!-- -->Dec 13, 2024, 1:44 AM UTC</time></p></li><li><h3><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/12/24320105/some-outer-worlds-2-gameplay">Some Outer Worlds 2 gameplay.</a></h3><p><time datetime="2024-12-13T01:40:40.894Z"> <!-- -->Dec 13, 2024, 1:40 AM UTC</time></p></li><li><h3><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/12/24320078/fumito-ueda-is-back">Fumito Ueda is back.</a></h3><p><time datetime="2024-12-13T01:34:14.383Z"> <!-- -->Dec 13, 2024, 1:34 AM UTC</time></p></li><li><h3><a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/2024/12/12/24320102/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-formerly-a-ps5-timed-exclusive-is-coming-to-pc">Final Fantasy VII Rebirth, formerly a PS5 timed exclusive, is coming to PC.</a></h3><p><time datetime="2024-12-13T01:31:07.654Z"> <!-- -->Dec 13, 2024, 1:31 AM UTC</time></p></li></ul><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24319637/the-game-awards-2024-trailers-annoucements">See all <!-- -->13<!-- --> stories</a> </div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia will host its first full LAN party in over a decade, and you’re invited]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/12/24320009/nvidia-lan-party-comeback-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nvidia-will-host-its-first-full-lan-party-in-over-a-decade-and-you%E2%80%99re-invited.1059684/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/12/24320009/nvidia-lan-party-comeback-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>It’s been 13 years since Nvidia hosted <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@NVIDIA/search?query=geforce%20lan%206">its last LAN party</a>, inviting hundreds of people to physically haul their gaming PCs onto a decommissioned aircraft carrier and jack them in for networked gaming bliss. Now, the GeForce LAN is finally coming back — and you’re theoretically invited, should you manage to reserve one of the 400 available spaces <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nvidia.com%2Fen-us%2Fgeforce%2Fgeforce-lan-50%2F">right here</a> on December 16th at 6AM PT / 9AM ET.</p><p><a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nvidia.com%2Fen-us%2Fgeforce%2Fgeforce-lan-50%2F">The GeForce LAN 50</a> will run January 4th through January 6th, 2025 in Las Vegas, Nevada, with satellite events in Berlin, Taipei, and Beijing, and it promises to be a “online &amp; in-person 50 hour gaming marathon” with contests, tournaments, raffles, and swag. </p><p>It’ll kick off 4:30PM PT on January 4th, and you’ll need to provide a fully refundable $125 deposit to sign up. Nvidia tells me those 400 slots are for everyday gamers, and do not count the influencers who may also show up.</p><p>If you can’t or don’t want to make it, Nvidia says it’ll offer one small set of rewards online — if you stream <em>Diablo IV</em>,&nbsp;<em>The Elder Scrolls Online</em>,&nbsp;<em>Fallout 76</em>,&nbsp;<em>The Finals</em>, or<em>&nbsp;WoW</em>&nbsp;from its GeForce Now cloud gaming service “continuously for 50 minutes,” there’ll be some kind of in-game reward. Nvidia will also be offering prizes in a marketing celebration <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nvidia.com%2Fen-us%2Fgeforce%2Fgeforce-greats%2F">it’s calling “GeForce Greats”.</a></p><p>The LAN party is happening right before <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/7/24264418/nvidia-ces-2025-keynote-rtx-5090-rumors">Nvidia’s CES 2025 keynote in Las Vegas</a>, where we’re expecting the company to announce the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/9/24266052/nvidia-rtx-5070-ces-rumor-specs">RTX 5090, RTX 5080, and possibly the RTX 5070</a> as well, and the fact that this is the “GeForce LAN 50” is probably a tease for those 50-series cards — the last LAN that Nvidia hosted was the “GeForce LAN 6,” not “GeForce LAN 49” or anything like that. </p><p>Starting in 2004, the GPU company began to host major LAN parties almost every year until it stopped in 2011. Here’s one of my minor claims to nerd fame: I helped set <a href="https://www.techpowerup.com/69990/lan-party-at-nvision-08-sets-world-record">a Guinness World Record for the largest, longest LAN party</a> at one in 2008.</p><div><figcaption><em>Record scratch, freeze frame, yep that’s me (on the left)...</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: Sean Hollister</cite></p></div><p>That Nvidia LAN wasn’t held on an aircraft carrier, but rather the San Jose Convention Center, as part an event that Nvidia called “NVISION 08.” The company never held another NVISION, but it rebooted its event the very next year, at the very same location, as the GPU Technology Conference (GTC). <a href="https://nvidia.custhelp.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/19/~/getting-nvidia-to-sponsor-a-lan-party%2Fevent">There was a time</a> Nvidia would sponsor third-party LANs as well. </p><p>Apparently Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang has a soft spot for LANs, making <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/nvidia/comments/18e879x/mr_jensen_huang_came_to_a_nvidia_lan_party_in/">a surprise visit to a small one</a> in Vietnam last year. While gamers have largely moved online for multiplayer games, the LAN party subculture has been getting a bit of nostalgic attention as of late — there’s <a href="https://www.amazon.com/LAN-Party-Inside-Multiplayer-Revolution/dp/0500026955?tag=theverge02-20">even a coffee table book now</a> documenting the era.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>