<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 15:07:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox 360 consoles can now be hacked with just a USB key]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/631102/xbox-360-hack-homebrew-badupdate-exploit-usb</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-360-consoles-can-now-be-hacked-with-just-a-usb-key.1136679/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/631102/xbox-360-hack-homebrew-badupdate-exploit-usb<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/tom-warren">Tom Warren</a> <span>is a senior editor and author of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/notepad-microsoft-newsletter"><i>Notepad</i></a>, who has been covering all things Microsoft, PC, and tech for over 20 years.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Xbox 360 modders have discovered a new way to get homebrew apps and games running on the console. A new software-only exploit known as <a href="https://github.com/grimdoomer/Xbox360BadUpdate">BadUpdate</a> allows you to use a USB key to hack past Microsoft’s Hypervisor protections and run unsigned code and games.</p><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IUK__yGXmds">Modern Vintage Gamer has tested</a> BadUpdate and found that you don’t even have to open up your Xbox 360 console to get it running. Unlike the RGH or JTAG exploits for the Xbox 360, this BadUpdate method just requires a USB key. If you have the time and patience to get this running successfully, you’ll be able to run the Xbox 360 homebrew store which includes games, apps, emulators, utilities, and even custom dashboards.</p><p>There are some limitations, though. If you want to take advantage of BadUpdate then you’ll also need to manually patch every executable you want to run on your Xbox 360. Modern Vintage Gamer says the exploit isn’t always reliable either, or takes some time to pull off. As this exploits Microsoft’s custom Hypervisor on the Xb0x 360, you’ll also need to run this exploit every single time you boot up the console.</p><p>You’ll just need a USB key, the exploit code, and a trial version of <em>Rock Band Blitz</em> that helps enable the bypass. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IUK__yGXmds">Modern Vintage Gamer walks through</a> all the steps in his detailed YouTube video, and there’s a brief guide on the <a href="https://github.com/grimdoomer/Xbox360BadUpdate">GitHub repository</a> that houses this software-only exploit.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roblox’s new AI model can generate 3D objects]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/630977/roblox-cube-3d-objects-mesh-ai-text-prompt</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/roblox%E2%80%99s-new-ai-model-can-generate-3d-objects.1136649/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/630977/roblox-cube-3d-objects-mesh-ai-text-prompt<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/jay-peters">Jay Peters</a> <span>is a news editor covering technology, gaming, and more. He joined The Verge in 2019 after nearly two years at Techmeme.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Roblox is launching and open-sourcing Cube 3D, the first version of its foundational AI model for generating 3D objects.</p><p>“With Cube, we intend to make 3D creation more efficient,” Roblox says <a href="https://corp.roblox.com/newsroom/2025/03/introducing-roblox-cube">in a press release</a>. “With 3D mesh generation, developers can quickly explore new creative directions and increase their productivity by deciding rapidly which to move forward with.”</p><p>The model is trained on 3D objects, as Roblox explains in its press release:</p><div><blockquote><p>To achieve this, we’ve taken inspiration from state-of-the-art models trained on text tokens (or sets of characters) so they can predict the next token to form a sentence. Our innovation builds on the same core idea. We’ve built the ability to tokenize 3D objects and understand shapes as tokens and trained Cube 3D to predict the next shape token to build a complete 3D object.</p></blockquote></div><p>The actual data used to train the model includes “a combination of licensed and publicly available datasets, as well as experience data from the Roblox ecosystem,” spokesperson Samantha Spielman tells <em>The Verge</em>.</p><p>Down the line, Cube 3D will be able to generate objects using images as inputs, too. “It will ultimately be a multimodal model, trained on text, images, video, and other types of input – and will integrate with our existing AI creation tools,” according to Roblox.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Discord is plugging directly into games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/630823/discord-social-directly-games-sdk</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/discord-is-plugging-directly-into-games.1136595/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/630823/discord-social-directly-games-sdk<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/jay-peters">Jay Peters</a> <span>is a news editor covering technology, gaming, and more. He joined The Verge in 2019 after nearly two years at Techmeme.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Discord is launching a way for developers to directly integrate the platform’s social features into their games.</p><p>The new Social SDK, announced today, will let developers that use it offer “friends lists, cross-platform messaging, voice and more for all players — with or without a Discord account,” <a href="http://www.discord.com/blog/announcing-discord-social-sdk-to-power-game-comms">according to a press release</a>. You’ll also be able to send invites to your friends while you’re in a game.</p><p>As the company says, you don’t have to have a Discord account to use the in-game Discord features, but “account linking is available for those who wish to connect their in-game experience to their Discord account for an even more engaging experience.”</p><p>Currently, the SDK is “compatible with C++, both Unreal Engine and Unity, and supports Windows 11+ and macOS,” according to Discord. Console and mobile support is “coming soon.” Developers including Theorycraft Games, Facepunch Studios, 1047 Games, Scopely, Mainframe Industries, Elodie Games, and Tencent Games are already using it, Discord says.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The OneXSugar asks: what if Nintendo Switch could transform into Nintendo DS?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/631005/qualcomm-snapdragon-g3-gen-3-onexsugar-handheld-ayaneo-pocket</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-onexsugar-asks-what-if-nintendo-switch-could-transform-into-nintendo-ds.1136592/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/631005/qualcomm-snapdragon-g3-gen-3-onexsugar-handheld-ayaneo-pocket<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>The picture above <em>does not</em> contain two different gaming handhelds. Instead, this halo device for Qualcomm’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/631188/three-new-snapdragon-gs">just-announced Snapdragon G3 Gen 3 gaming chips</a> — which I’ll tell you about in a sec — is a <em>single</em> transforming device with swing out gamepads and screens. It’s called the OneXPlayer OneXSugar, and it’s one of the most delightfully gadgety gaming gadgets I’ve seen.</p><p>Hold it horizontally like a Nintendo Switch or Steam Deck, flip out its secondary screen, then <em>rotate</em> its twin hinged gamepads for a more squared-off Nintendo DS-like experience:</p><div id=":R6bdber6:"><div><p><figcaption>GIF by The Verge / OneXPlayer</figcaption></p></div><div><p><cite>GIF by The Verge / OneXPlayer</cite></p></div></div><p>If you listen closely, you can almost hear the emulation community jumping for joy at the idea of two different aspect ratio screens joined at the hip. Me, I’m busy imagining the satisfying and/or horrifying sounds it might make as its triple joints swing into action!</p><p>We know little more than what you can glean from the pictures and animations, but here are the key bits:</p><div><ul><li><span>It’s from the same boutique Chinese gadget maker behind <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/21/24161887/onexplayer-x1-mini-handheld-gaming-pc-ssd">the three-in-one X1 and X1 Mini</a> that I told you about last spring.</span></li><li><span>OneXPlayer plans to put it on preorder this May.</span></li><li><span>It’s an Android device with Qualcomm’s just-announced Snapdragon G3 Gen 3 processor inside, rather than an AMD-toting Windows gaming handheld.</span></li></ul></div><p>Before you get your hopes up, the OneXPlayer OneXSugar is unlikely to become a machine aimed at Windows games too. For one thing, we’re looking at nice but modest gains of 30 percent more CPU performance and 28 percent more GPU performance <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/8/23/23840895/qualcomm-g3x-snapdragon-gen-2-g2-g1-gaming-handheld-chips">than the Snapdragon G3x Gen 2</a> announced in 2023. It doesn’t contain the Oryon CPU core that powers both Qualcomm’s Snapdragon 8 Elite for phones or its Snapdragon X Elite for laptops, nor the Adreno X1 or Adreno 830 GPUs that respectively feature in those chips.</p><p>And while Qualcomm Snapdragon gaming lead Micah Knapp told journalists that the company might launch support for other operating systems “over time,” it’s “really focused on the Android side” as of today. That’s because China is such a huge market for Android gaming, the company hints. “The perspective that Android gaming isn’t popular is a very region-centric perspective,” Qualcomm spokesperson Sascha Segan says when I ask.</p><p>That China interest is certainly helping produce some incredible looking devices. When Qualcomm first announced its last handheld gaming chips, the best it could show off <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/8/23/23840895/qualcomm-g3x-snapdragon-gen-2-g2-g1-gaming-handheld-chips">was a dull batarang-shaped reference design</a>. Today, in addition to the OneXSugar, it’s got the sleek metal-bodied Ayaneo Pocket S2, an Ayaneo Gaming Pad, and additionally two new Retroid Pocket devices on its new lower-tier chips, the Snapdragon G2 Gen 2 and G1 Gen 2.</p><p>Here’s that Pocket S2:</p><p>Knapp tells me that his company doesn’t need to subsidize the development of Qualcomm handhelds, either. “To be blunt, most of them are coming to us to build platforms on their own,” he says. “People have accepted this is where things are going to happen, and now they’re just aggressively moving into the space,” he says.</p><p>Of the two lower-tier chips, the G2 Gen 2 claims significant gains of 2.3x the CPU performance and 3.8x the GPU performance of a Snapdragon G2 Gen 1, though I’m not aware of any particular handhelds shipping with that earlier chip, and neither Qualcomm nor Retroid have released images of its next horizontal handheld. The G1 Gen 2 boasts 80 percent greater CPU performance than G1 Gen 1, and a 25 percent faster GPU.</p><p>The Ayaneo Pocket S2 should be coming this month, the Retroid Pocket PR Classic should be up for preorder this month, and the Ayaneo Gaming Pad should be coming this May.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>