<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 13:44:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Royal Shakespeare Company is turning Macbeth into a neo-noir game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/23/24349938/royal-shakespeare-company-macbeth-game-lili</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-royal-shakespeare-company-is-turning-macbeth-into-a-neo-noir-game.1089543/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/23/24349938/royal-shakespeare-company-macbeth-game-lili<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p><em>Macbeth</em>, William Shakespeare’s iconic play, is being reimagined as an interactive video game with a neo-noir vibe — and it’s being developed in part by the Royal Shakespeare Company. The game, titled <em>Lili</em>, is a “screen life thriller video game” where you’ll have access to a modern-day Lady Macbeth’s personal devices, according to a press release.</p><p>“Players will be immersed in a stylized, neo-noir vision of modern Iran, where surveillance and authoritarianism are part of daily life,” the release says. “The gameplay will feature a blend of live-action cinema within an interactive game format, giving players the chance to immerse themselves in the world of Lady Macbeth and make choices that influence her destiny.” It sounds kind of like a version of <em>Macbeth</em> inspired by Sam Barlow’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/23/20828666/telling-lies-review-steam-iphone-sam-barlow-interactive-thriller-her-story">interactive</a> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/9/24031558/immortality-is-coming-to-ps5">thrillers</a>.</p><p>The Royal Shakespeare Company is making the game in collaboration with iNK Stories, a New York-based indie studio and publisher that also made <em>1979 Revolution: Black Friday</em>. It stars Zar Amir as “Lady Macbeth (Lili),” per the press release.</p><p><em>Lili</em> is set to release “later in 2025.”</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>