<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 09:32:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo wants you to join its next mysterious Switch Online playtest]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/709530/nintendo-switch-online-playtest-program-july-august-invitations-application</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-wants-you-to-join-its-next-mysterious-switch-online-playtest.1246845/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Late last year, Nintendo hosted a mysterious Switch Online playtest, and on Thursday, the company announced that it would be doing another test as part of the “Nintendo Switch Online: Playtest Program” and that it will be opening applications soon. This second round will be a test of the “same service” as before.</p><p>Last time, Nintendo asked participants not to share details about the playtest, but leaks <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/21/24275596/nintendo-switch-online-beta-playtest-program-leak-mmo">appeared anyway</a> indicating that the test was for some kind of MMO-style game.</p><p>Applications for this next playtest will be open to users 18 or older with an active Nintendo Switch Online + Expansion Pack as of Thursday at 6PM ET <em>and</em> with a Nintendo Account registered in Japan, United States, United Kingdom, France, Germany, Italy, Spain, Canada, Brazil, or Mexico. Users can apply as individuals or as a group of up to four people “if everyone in the group meets the Application Qualifications,” according to Nintendo.</p><p>You can prepare your application <a href="https://playtest-p.nintendo.com/en-us">on Nintendo’s website</a> from Friday, July 18th at 6PM ET to Monday, July 21st at 10:59AM ET.</p><p>You can actually submit your application from Monday, July 21st at 11AM ET to Wednesday, July 23rd at 10:59AM ET, though Nintendo says applications will be accepted “on a first-come, first-served basis.”</p><p>Nintendo expects to accept “as many as 40,000 participants worldwide,” a big jump from the 10,000 participants allowed for <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/9/24266478/nintendo-switch-online-invite-application-beta-playtest">the October test</a>. If you participated in that playtest, you can participate in this next one, too, <a href="https://x.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1945971033330102298">Nintendo says</a>.</p><p>The playtest itself will run from Monday, July 28th at 9PM ET to Sunday, August 10th at 8:59PM ET.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/709530/nintendo-switch-online-playtest-program-july-august-invitations-application]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>