<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 12:13:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo says invites for its own Switch 2 sales may arrive after launch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/655159/my-nintendo-store-switch-2-invites</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-says-invites-for-its-own-switch-2-sales-may-arrive-after-launch.1172232/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/655159/my-nintendo-store-switch-2-invites<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/jay-peters">Jay Peters</a> <span>is a news editor covering technology, gaming, and more. He joined The Verge in 2019 after nearly two years at Techmeme.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>In a recent update to <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nintendo.com%2Fus%2Fgaming-systems%2Fswitch-2%2Fhow-to-buy%2F" rel="sponsored">its website</a> about its direct sales program for the Switch 2, Nintendo says that due to “the very high demand” for the console, “delivery by June 5 is not guaranteed” and that “your invitation email may arrive after the Nintendo Switch 2 launch.”</p><p>Nintendo has already said that the initial invitations for eligible registrations on its My Nintendo Store website would go out on May 8th. The requirements to be eligible are <a href="https://www.theverge.com/nintendo/641559/nintendo-switch-2-preorder-gameplay-requirements">quite strict</a>, seemingly to thwart scalpers.</p><p>But now, as it did <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/654213/nintendo-switch-2-demand-japan-preorders-sales">for Japan yesterday</a>, the company is signaling that US demand for consoles through its own store is quite high. If you were banking on getting a Switch 2 through the platform, you might want to be prepared to potentially wait.</p><p>In its update, Nintendo suggests visiting “our participating retail partners,” but the preorders that have happened so far, which kicked off at 12AM ET on Thursday at Best Buy, Target, and Walmart, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/654571/nintendo-switch-2-preorders-issues-problems">have been messy</a>.</p><p>Ahead of those preorders, the list of retail partners on Nintendo’s website included Best Buy, Target, Walmart, and GameStop. As I write this, only GameStop, which opens online preorders at 11AM ET on Thursday, has a logo on the page.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>