<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 08:51:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This watch has Pong and Missile Command instead of apps]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/632077/atari-2600-my-play-watch-pong-centipede-missile-command-super-breakout</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-watch-has-pong-and-missile-command-instead-of-apps.1138386/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/632077/atari-2600-my-play-watch-pong-centipede-missile-command-super-breakout<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/andrew-liszewski">Andrew Liszewski</a> <span>is a senior reporter who’s been covering and reviewing the latest gadgets and tech since 2011, but has loved all things electronic since he was a kid.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Atari is now selling a smartwatch that prioritizes fun over functionality. The watch’s user interface can be customized with Atari 2600-themed artwork and sound effects. But pushing it squarely into impulse purchase territory is the watch’s ability to play <em>Centipede</em>, <em>Pong</em>, <em>Super Breakout</em>, and <em>Missile Command</em> using the touchscreen or the watch’s crown dial functioning as a paddle controller.</p><p>Instead of trying to compete with the Apple Watch’s capabilities, the <a href="https://atari.com/products/atari-2600-my-play-watch-smartwatch">Atari 2600 My Play Watch</a> targets longtime gamers nostalgic enough for the consoles of their youth to spend $79.99 on an elaborately themed fitness tracker. The watch is available for preorder now through Atari’s online store and is expected to ship by June 10th, 2025.</p><div><p>If the Atari 2600 My Play Watch feels familiar, it’s because it’s actually based on the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/25/24254312/space-invaders-my-play-watch-taito-kickstarter">Space Invaders My Play Watch</a> that launched last September through a <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/f84/space-invaderstm-my-play-watch?ref=hodqsx">Kickstarter crowdfunding campaign</a>. Its limited smartwatch capabilities are <a href="https://www.myplaywatch.com/">nearly identical to that previous version</a>, including swappable watch faces and fitness tracking capabilities like step tracking, calories burned, and a heart rate monitor.</p></div><p>There’s still no Bluetooth or Wi-fi connectivity. So, while the Atari 2600 My Play Watch won’t pester you with notifications from your smartphone, you won’t be able to expand its capabilities by downloading apps or new games.</p><p>There are a few upgrades on the Atari 2600 My Play Watch. Its 2.02-inch touchscreen is slightly larger than the 1.86-inch screen on the Space Invaders watch, it has a beefier and more industrial-looking metal case, and there’s now a button located beneath its crown dial. It also comes with three swappable bands featuring retro graphic designs, although Atari says they will only be available for a limited time.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>