<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 08:27:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AMD’s new RX 9060 XT looks set to challenge Nvidia’s RTX 5060]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/670285/amd-radeon-rx-9060-xt-announcement-computex</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amd%E2%80%99s-new-rx-9060-xt-looks-set-to-challenge-nvidia%E2%80%99s-rtx-5060.1194750/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/670285/amd-radeon-rx-9060-xt-announcement-computex<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/tom-warren">Tom Warren</a> <span>is a senior editor and author of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/notepad-microsoft-newsletter"><i>Notepad</i></a>, who has been covering all things Microsoft, PC, and tech for over 20 years.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>AMD is officially announcing its Radeon RX 9060 XT GPU at Computex today. Like the number implies, this graphics card will challenge Nvidia’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/661807/nvidia-rtx-5060-cards-laptops-release-date-price">recently released RTX 5060</a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/648705/nvidias-rtx-5060-ti-gpu-pricing-release-date">RTX 5060 Ti</a>, with AMD offering models with 8GB or 16GB of VRAM. AMD is launching both models on June 5th, with the 8GB variant priced at $299, with the 16GB version priced at $349.</p><p>AMD is following Nvidia’s controversial choice to ship a modern GPU with just 8GB of VRAM in the year 2025. The 8GB of VRAM debate has been raging for months now, particularly because of the latest games that can be very demanding on the memory side. AMD is following in Nvidia’s footsteps, though, so it’ll be interesting to see what reviewers make of both cards in this important part of the market.</p><p>The RX 9060 XT will ship with 32 RDNA 4 compute units, a boost clock of 3.13GHz, and support for DisplayPort 2.1a and HDMI 2.1b. The total board power is between 150 watts and 182 watts, depending on the model. AMD claims its 16GB version of the RX 9060 XT will be around 6 percent faster than Nvidia’s RTX 5060 Ti at 1440p resolution, based on 40 games that AMD has tested itself.</p><p>We’re still waiting to hear how the RTX 5060 stacks up, because oddly, Nvidia launched its latest 50-series GPU yesterday without any reviews available. The GPU maker had reportedly prevented reviewers from obtaining the necessary driver to test the RTX 5060 ahead of the release date, presumably because it’s worried about the paltry 8GB of VRAM spec.</p><p>While the 8GB of VRAM choice for both Nvidia and AMD is controversial, Nvidia has managed to spark a further wave of outrage from PC gaming YouTubers over <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/669538/we-will-not-play-those-games">comments it has made to Gamers Nexus</a>. In a 22-minute video, Gamers Nexus <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AiekGcwaIho">discusses the pressure from Nvidia</a> to include Multi Frame Generation (MFG) in benchmarks against competitor cards that don’t have a similar feature. Gamers Nexus (GN) alleges that Nvidia has even implied that it would revoke access to interview Nvidia engineers unless the channel discussed MFG more.</p><p><em><strong>Update, May 21st</strong>: Article updated with pricing and release date information that AMD didn’t share with The Verge ahead of its press conference.</em></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite is back on US iPhones again]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/661290/fortnite-ios-iphone-epic-games-back-apple-app-store</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-is-back-on-us-iphones-again.1194666/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/661290/fortnite-ios-iphone-epic-games-back-apple-app-store<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p><em>Fortnite</em> is once again available on the iOS App Store in the US, <a href="https://x.com/Fortnite/status/1924949632628523199">according to Epic Games</a>. You can get it from <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/fortnite/id6483539426">the App Store here</a>. Epic says it has returned to the Epic Games Store and AltStore as well.</p><p>Apple kicked <em>Fortnite</em> off the App Store <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/13/21366438/apple-fortnite-ios-app-store-violations-epic-payments">nearly five years ago</a> after Epic Games added its own in-app payment system to the game, which violated Apple’s rules. But after a major court ruling in <em>Epic Games v. Apple</em> that <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/659246/apple-epic-app-store-judge-ruling-control">forced Apple</a> to not take fees from purchases made outside of apps, the game is available to play on US iPhones once again.</p><p>Shortly after the big ruling hit, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/659271/fortnite-ios-apple-app-store-us-return">CEO Tim Sweeney said</a> that Epic planned to bring back <em>Fortnite</em> to iOS in the US. He also made a “peace proposal:” “If Apple extends the court’s friction-free, Apple-tax-free framework worldwide, we’ll return <em>Fortnite</em> to the App Store worldwide and drop current and future litigation on the topic.“</p><div><p>On May 9th, it <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/664245/epic-submitted-fortnite-to-apple">submitted the app to Apple</a>. Ahead of that, Sweeney said that Epic would use <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/661237/epic-games-fortnite-apple-us-ios-app-store-eu-account">its Sweden developer account</a> to submit the game to the US App Store.</p></div><p>Late last week, Epic said that Apple had blocked <em>Fortnite’s</em> return to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/668232/fortnite-ios-unavailable-worldwide-apple-epic">the App Store</a>, and the game also became unavailable on other alternative app stores in the EU. However, Apple said that it had “asked that Epic Sweden resubmit the app update without including the US storefront of the App Store so as not to impact <em>Fortnite</em> in other geographies” and that “we did not take any action to remove the live version of <em>Fortnite</em> from alternative distribution marketplaces.”</p><p>Epic asked the judge in the <em>Epic v. Apple</em> case to order Apple to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/669047/epic-fortnite-filing-apple-app-store-review-order">review its <em>Fortnite</em> submission</a> on May 16th. Yesterday, the judge said <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/669676/apple-is-fully-capable-of-resolving-this-issue-without-further-briefing-or-a-hearing">in a filing</a> that Apple is “fully capable of resolving this issue without further briefing or a hearing,” and that if a resolution wasn’t reached, the Apple official who “is personally responsible for ensuring compliance” would have to appear at a hearing next Tuesday.</p><p>However, shortly after <em>Fortnite</em> returned to the App Store on Tuesday, Epic and Apple <a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/25949416-joint-notice/">filed a joint notice</a> saying that they have “resolved all issues” from Epic’s May 16th filing. Apple didn’t immediately reply to a request for comment.</p><p>Epic also recently rolled out a new promotion to encourage players to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/659655/epic-games-store-revenue-share-webshops-apple-in-app-purchases">use its payment systems</a>: if you use Epic’s system in <em>Fortnite</em>, <em>Rocket League</em>, or <em>Fall Guys</em> on PC, iOS, Android, and the web, the company will give you 20 percent back in Epic Rewards that can be used for other purchases in its games or on the Epic Games Store.</p><p>In the iOS version of <em>Fortnite</em> that was released on Tuesday, the app shows you that 20 percent bonus when you pick which payment system you want to use to buy V-Bucks.</p><div><p>The company launched a new <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/659347/fortnite-star-wars-galactic-battle-season-battle-pass"><em>Star Wars</em>-themed season</a> for <em>Fortnite</em> on May 2nd.</p></div><p>If you get the app from the App Store, it will be a small initial download, and after you actually open the app, it will download the rest of the game. For a colleague, that additional download was 12.95GB.</p><p><em><strong>Update, May 20th</strong>: Added details of Epic and Apple’s joint notice.</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lost in Cult’s new Editions publishing label focuses on art and indie games preservation]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/671051/lost-in-cult-editions-physical-game-releases</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lost-in-cult%E2%80%99s-new-editions-publishing-label-focuses-on-art-and-indie-games-preservation.1194567/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/671051/lost-in-cult-editions-physical-game-releases<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/cameron-faulkner">Cameron Faulkner</a> <span>is an editor covering deals and commerce. He joined in 2018, and served as commerce editor at Polygon until May 2025.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Editions is the name of a new game publishing label launched by <a href="https://www.lostincult.co.uk/">Lost in Cult</a>, the same company known for making gorgeous books about video games, like <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/663177/go-deep-down-the-animal-well"><em>Outer Wilds: Design Works</em>.</a> The new label’s aim is to preserve indie games, including some that haven’t been released on physical media before, and to celebrate their artistic contributions to the medium by including plenty of extra goodies. Notably, Lost in Cult is working with DoesItPlay? to validate its titles before they’re released. The group specializes in game preservation, ensuring that games can be run from the physical media they’re stored on without the need for a download or an internet connection.</p><p>The focus on elegantly preserving these titles is similar to what we’ve seen from Limited Run Games, while Editions’ focus on indie games reminds me of the Criterion Collection’s approach. Each game included in the Editions lineup will come with a fold-out poster, a sticker, a numbered authenticity card, a 40-page essay and developer interview, and gorgeous cover art, along with the game itself. The first three games to launch under the label include <em>Immortality</em>, <em>The Excavation of Hob’s Barrow</em>, and <em>Thank Goodness You’re Here</em>. Editions plans to announce a new game every month, starting in July.</p><p>Each of the three games is <a href="https://www.lostincult.co.uk/">available to preorder</a> through the Lost in Cult site starting at £59.99, with the option to choose between Nintendo Switch and PlayStation 5 editions when applicable. PS5 owners can opt to buy the entire first run of Editions games at a discounted price, containing <em>Immortality </em>and <em>Thank Goodness You’re Here</em>, and they’ll get a third (as of yet, unannounced) Editions title when it launches in July. Lost in Cult is asking for patience with shipments, which may take up to six months. But if they’re as good as the books, the wait will be worth it.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>