<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 19:19:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony will only ‘occasionally’ offer PS4 games on PlayStation Plus starting next year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/601940/sony-playstation-plus-ps4-games-occasionally</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-will-only-%E2%80%98occasionally%E2%80%99-offer-ps4-games-on-playstation-plus-starting-next-year.1095078/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/601940/sony-playstation-plus-ps4-games-occasionally<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/jay-peters">Jay Peters</a> <span>is a news editor who writes about technology, video games, and virtual worlds. He’s submitted several accepted emoji proposals to the Unicode Consortium.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Sony <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/01/29/playstation-plus-monthly-games-for-february-payday-3-high-on-life-pac-man-world-re-pac/">announced Wednesday</a> that it will change to “occasionally” including PS4 games as a PlayStation Plus benefit starting in January 2026. You’ll still have access to any of the monthly PS4 games you’ve already redeemed to your account after that date, however, and you can still play PS4 games that are available on the PlayStation Plus Game Catalog until they leave the catalog.</p><p>After January 2026, Sony also says that it “may still provide titles that can be playable on both PS4 and PS5 consoles after this date.” But in general, it seems like the company is shifting its focus more fully to PS5.</p><p>As part of its blog post announcing the change, Sony also revealed that <em>Payday 3</em>, <em>High on Life</em>, and <em>Pac-Man World Re-Pac </em>will be February’s redeemable games for PlayStation Plus users.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation is dropping its PSN account requirement for some PC games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/601909/playstation-is-dropping-its-account-linking-requirement-for-some-pc-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-is-dropping-its-psn-account-requirement-for-some-pc-games.1095075/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/601909/playstation-is-dropping-its-account-linking-requirement-for-some-pc-games<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/jay-peters">Jay Peters</a> <span>is a news editor who writes about technology, video games, and virtual worlds. He’s submitted several accepted emoji proposals to the Unicode Consortium.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Sony announced Wednesday that you won’t need to log in to a PlayStation Network account to play four of its single-player games on PC: <em>Marvel’s Spider-Man 2</em> (which comes out tomorrow), <em>The Last of Us Part II Remastered </em>(which launches on April 3rd), <em>God of War Ragnarök</em>, and <em>Horizon Zero Dawn Remastered</em>.</p><p>However, to incentivize you to still sign in with a PSN account while playing those games, Sony says that it will “soon” be adding “in-game content unlocks” like outfits and resources. You can see the full list of bonuses in <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/01/29/new-in-game-content-incentives-coming-to-playstation-games-on-pc/">Sony’s blog post about the news</a>. Sony also says that using a PSN account gives you benefits like “trophies and friend management.”</p><p>Sony’s PSN account requirement for some of its PC games hasn’t been a popular one. Backlash to the requirement for <em>Helldivers 2</em> led Sony to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24150327/sony-helldivers-2-review-bombing-psn-login">reverse the decision</a> after the game was review bombed on Steam.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>