<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 11:18:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony is giving PS Plus members extra days following PSN’s big outage]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/609132/sony-playstation-plus-psn-outage</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-is-giving-ps-plus-members-extra-days-following-psn%E2%80%99s-big-outage.1104507/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/609132/sony-playstation-plus-psn-outage<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="__next"><p><a href="#content"><span>Skip to main content</span></a></p><nav aria-label="Sticky Nav"></nav><div><main id="content"><article><div><div><div><p><span><ul><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news">News</a></li></ul></span></p></div><div><p>PlayStation Plus subscribers will get an extra five days of service added to their accounts.</p></div></div><div><div><p>PlayStation Plus subscribers will get an extra five days of service added to their accounts.</p></div><div><p><cite>﻿Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge</cite></p></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/wes-davis">Wes Davis</a> <span>is a weekend editor who covers the latest in tech and entertainment. He has written news, reviews, and more as a tech journalist since 2020.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Following the huge PlayStation Network (PSN) outage <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/608946/playstation-network-down-outage">that ended yesterday</a>, Sony is giving an automatic five extra days of service to PlayStation Plus subscribers, <a href="https://x.com/AskPlayStation/status/1888454556125708758">according to a post</a> from the official Ask PlayStation support account on X.</p><p>“Network services have fully recovered from an operational issue,” the company wrote in the post. “We apologize for the inconvenience and thank the community for their patience.” Sony didn’t offer further specifics.</p><p>The outage lasted about a full day, with the first indications of problems seemingly cropping up around 6PM ET Friday. Sony <a href="https://x.com/AskPlayStation/status/1888376843255824475">posted</a> that service had been restored just before 7PM ET Saturday.</p><p>During the outage, players had issues with things like logging into accounts, visiting the PlayStation Store, or launching games. For my colleague, Jay Peters, the outage meant he couldn’t log into <em>Fortnite</em> or see his trophies, but his digital copy of <em>Final Fantasy VII Rebirth </em>launched like normal.</p></div></div><div><form><div><h2>Installer</h2><p><span>A weekly newsletter by David Pierce designed to tell you everything you need to download, watch, read, listen to, and explore that fits in The Verge’s universe.</span></p></div></form></div></div></article></main></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>