<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 04:45:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Razer Blade 16 is even thinner this year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24335984/razer-blade-16-laptop-thin-ryzen-amd-cpu-nvidia-gpu-240-hz-oled-display</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-razer-blade-16-is-even-thinner-this-year.1075614/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24335984/razer-blade-16-laptop-thin-ryzen-amd-cpu-nvidia-gpu-240-hz-oled-display<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="__next"><p><a href="#content">Skip to main content</a></p><div><main><article id="content"><div><div><h2>The Razer Blade 16 is even thinner this year</h2><p><span><span> / </span><h2>The latest 16-inch Razer laptop is over 30 percent thinner than its predecessor.</h2></span></p></div><div><div><p><span>By</span> <span><span></span> <span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/wes-davis">Wes Davis</a></span><span>, <span>a weekend editor who covers the latest in tech and entertainment. He has written news, reviews, and more as a tech journalist since 2020.</span></span></span></p><p>Photography by Antonio G. Di Benedetto / The Verge</p></div><p><time datetime="2025-01-07T04:00:00.000Z"> <!-- -->Jan 7, 2025, 4:00 AM UTC</time></p><div><h2>Share this story</h2></div></div></div><div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Razer announced it’s overhauling the Razer Blade 16 inside and out. In addition to a new CPU and GPU, the Blade 16 is now thinner overall than the outgoing 2024 model and comes with a few tweaks to its audio system and keyboard. </p><p>The new Blade 16 comes with up to a Ryzen AI 9 HX 370 CPU and a “next-gen Nvidia<strong> </strong>GPU.” The company also bumped its speaker array from four to six speakers, while the display carries over the 240Hz OLED <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/4/24024217/razer-gaming-laptop-updates-blade-16-18-oled-4k-ces">introduced to the line last year</a>. This is the first time Razer has put an AMD processor in the Blade 16.</p><p>Razer says it’s packing all of that into a chassis that’s over 30 percent thinner than last year’s model at just 0.59 inches — or 14.9 millimeters — thick<strong> </strong>in the front and 0.69 inches (17.4mm) in the back, not including the feet. For reference, the 16-inch MacBook Pro M4 is 0.61 inches (15.5mm) thick, including feet. The new Razer Blade&nbsp;is also deeper than last year’s model, measuring 250.5mm front to back, versus 244mm for the 2024 Blade 16. Despite all of that, Razer says it increased the travel of its keyboard keys from 1mm to 1.5mm. And there’s now a Copilot key, of course.</p><p>That thinness may come at a cost: the new Blade 16 has a 90Wh battery that it says can charge to 80 percent in about 45 minutes. The fast charging may come in handy; the larger 95.2Wh battery in the Blade 16 we <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23588660/razer-blade-16-2023-review-specs-features-design">reviewed in 2023</a> already felt like it wasn’t up to the task. That review unit was also a hot laptop. Razer says it’s using a new thermal gel that covers more interior surface area than the 2023 model.</p><div><div><p><figcaption><em>The 2025 model (top) vs. the thicker 2024 model (bottom).</em></figcaption></p></div><div><figcaption><em>2024 (left) vs. 2025 (right).</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Photo by Antonio G. Di Benedetto / The Verge</cite></p></div></div><p>The AMD chip it’s using might help things, though. When <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24324299/asus-rog-zephyrus-g16-2024-gaming-laptop-review-amd-strix-point">we tested an Asus ROG Zephyrus G16 with that Ryzen AI 9 HX 370 CPU</a> against the same laptop with an Intel Core Ultra 9 185H, the AMD version ran for three hours longer in non-gaming tasks and put out slightly less heat, though Asus puts a much lower power draw cap on its gaming laptops than Razer does. Naturally, we won’t know how any of that affects the new Blade 16 until we have one in hand to test. </p><p>The 2025 Razer Blade 16 is due out in the first quarter of this year. Razer didn’t announce pricing, but you can bet it won’t be cheap.</p><div tabindex="0" aria-label="Zoom" role="button"><p>1<!-- -->/<!-- -->10</p><div><figcaption><em>The new Razer Blade 16.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: Razer</cite></p></div></div></div><div><p>Most Popular</p><p>Most Popular</p><ol><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/4/24307731/ces-2025-tvs-gaming-smart-home-wearables-news"><h2>CES 2025: all the news, gadgets, and surprises</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24325799/dell-pro-max-premium-plus-ces-laptop-pc-rebrand-announcement"><h2>Dell kills the XPS brand</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/5/24336154/samsung-the-frame-pro-features-specs"><h2>Samsung announces The Frame Pro: could this be the perfect TV?</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24337117/microsoft-bing-search-results-google-design-trick"><h2>Microsoft is using Bing to trick people into thinking they’re on Google</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/5/24334030/halliday-smart-glasses-ai-tiny-display-frame-availability-price-ces"><h2>These smart glasses have a tiny little screen hidden in the frame</h2></a><hr></li></ol></div></div></article></main><div><h2>More from this stream<!-- --> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/4/24307731/ces-2025-tvs-gaming-smart-home-wearables-news">CES 2025: all the news, gadgets, and surprises</a></h2><ul><li><h3><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24335238/msi-gaming-laptops-cyborg-stealth-raider-vector-nvidia-rtx-intel-amd-ces">MSI’s 2025 gaming laptops have the latest from Nvidia, Intel, and AMD — plus lots of RGB</a></h3><p><time datetime="2025-01-07T04:00:00.000Z"> <!-- -->Jan 7, 2025, 4:00 AM UTC</time></p></li><li><h3><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24335564/alienware-27-inch-4k-240hz-oled-price-date">Alienware’s 27-inch 4K 240Hz OLED monitor is only a couple months away</a></h3><p><time datetime="2025-01-07T04:00:00.000Z"> <!-- -->Jan 7, 2025, 4:00 AM UTC</time></p></li><li><h3><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24335027/msi-titan-18-dragon-edition-norse-myth-gaming-laptop-ces-price-specs">The Titan Dragon Edition is MSI’s latest all-out gaming laptop</a></h3><p><time datetime="2025-01-07T04:00:00.000Z"> <!-- -->Jan 7, 2025, 4:00 AM UTC</time></p></li><li><h3><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24332341/alienware-area-51-16-18-rgb-laptop-price-specs-ces">Alienware’s new Area-51 laptops have light-up trackpads and fans</a></h3><p><time datetime="2025-01-07T04:00:00.000Z"> <!-- -->Jan 7, 2025, 4:00 AM UTC</time></p></li></ul><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/4/24307731/ces-2025-tvs-gaming-smart-home-wearables-news">See all <!-- -->177<!-- --> stories</a> </div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HP put Google TV inside a gaming monitor]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24335320/hp-omen-32x-smart-gaming-monitor-g2-specs-ces-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hp-put-google-tv-inside-a-gaming-monitor.1075611/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24335320/hp-omen-32x-smart-gaming-monitor-g2-specs-ces-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>HP is jumping into the smart monitor space with the Omen 32x, a gaming monitor that doubles as a streaming device running Google TV.&nbsp;It’ll ship this April for $749.99, the company announced at CES 2025.</p><p>The HP Omen 32x Smart Gaming Monitor has a 31.5-inch 4K IPS display with a 144Hz refresh rate, 1ms response time, 400 nit peak brightness, and DisplayHDR 400 with Dolby Vision. The panel covers 95 percent of the Display P3 and 99 percent of the sRGB color gamuts, and it has support for G-Sync and FreeSync Premium. For video inputs, it has one DisplayPort 1.4 port and two HDMI 2.1 ports, plus a 65W USB-C Power Delivery port with alt mode support for DisplayPort. It also has two USB-A 2.0 ports for peripherals, 3.5mm for audio (plus four built-in 3W speakers), and even an ethernet jack.</p><p>The hardware specs don’t jump off the page compared to other gaming monitors in its class, but the Google TV integration sets it apart. You’ll find it familiar if you’ve used a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/6/24214471/google-chromecast-line-discontinued">Chromecast</a>, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/6/24214055/google-tv-streamer-features-price-matter-thread">Google TV Streamer</a>, or select <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/3/1/23619895/sony-2023-tv-lineup-bravia-xr-features">TVs from Sony</a>, Hisense, and the like. It delivers recommendations based on your watch history, and you can use Google Assistant voice commands to search for specific content within its deep library of apps as it pulls options from all available sources. You can also cast content from supported mobile apps. Most other smart monitors, like <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/12/31/24020920/lg-myview-4k-smart-monitor-display-tv-webos">LG’s MyView line</a> and the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/5/24/23735566/samsung-smart-monitor-2023-m80c-m70c-m50c-tv">Samsung M series</a>, use their own custom operating systems, and most of them are more focused on productivity than gaming.</p><p>The Omen 32x also has some unique tricks we haven’t seen before, such as native support for streaming your screen to four platforms — including Twitch, YouTube, and Instagram — simultaneously with no additional hardware. It can stream up to two webcam sources in addition to what’s on your screen. You can also mirror your Android-based smartphone to the display and use it in desktop mode within a multiview window while you’re gaming. HP even built in wireless KVM functionality, allowing you to operate everything using the same keyboard and mouse.</p><div><figcaption><em>HP’s 2025 G2 monitors, like the pictured Omen 34c G2, have a minimum 180Hz refresh rate.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: HP</cite></p></div><p>HP is also updating its mainstream G2 line of monitors for 2025, including the $479.99 Omen 34c G2, a 34-inch WQHD curved ultrawide (21:9) display with FreeSync Premium, DisplayHDR 400, and a 4,000:1 contrast ratio. We’re also getting new 27-inch 16:9 options in the 1080p Omen 27 G2 for $249.99 in May, the QHD Omen 27q G2 for $299.99 in April, and the QHD 27qs G2 for $449.99 in June. </p><p>All will benefit from factory color calibration for the first time, and the former three will support boosted refresh rates up to 180Hz. The 27qs G2, however, is distinguished as the only monitor in the G2 lineup with an IPS Black display and the first ever with a 280Hz refresh rate. IPS Black displays are said to offer higher contrast ratios (2,000:1 on the 27qs G2) and better color accuracy than ordinary IPS panels.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Titan Dragon Edition is MSI’s latest all-out gaming laptop]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24335027/msi-titan-18-dragon-edition-norse-myth-gaming-laptop-ces-price-specs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-titan-dragon-edition-is-msi%E2%80%99s-latest-all-out-gaming-laptop.1075605/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24335027/msi-titan-18-dragon-edition-norse-myth-gaming-laptop-ces-price-specs<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Lots of gaming laptops go for maximum performance with maximum RGB showiness, but nothing goes harder than MSI’s Titan. The company announced its Titan 18 HX laptop at CES 2025. It’s an 18-inch behemoth with an illuminated touchpad, Intel’s Core Arrow Lake processor, and Nvidia’s new RTX 50-series GPU for a starting price of around $5,000. </p><p>But is that really outrageous enough?</p><p>It’d be much wilder to also release a fully unhinged Titan adorned with dragon designs and runes inspired by Norse mythology. And that’s exactly what MSI is doing with its Titan 18 HX Dragon Edition Norse Myth. It has the innards of the standard Titan, complete with a new dedicated heat pipe cooler just for its PCIe Gen5 SSD to maximize transfer speeds, and it adds a massive etching of a hand-drawn dragon head to its lid as well as a 3D-printed dragon coin under glass within the palm rest. Now we’re talking.</p><div><p><figcaption><em>According to MSI, those Norse runes on the lid mean “Dragon Edition.”</em></figcaption></p></div><p>We’re still awaiting pricing information, but spec-wise, this thing is roaring. It packs an Intel Core Ultra 9 285HX CPU, Nvidia RTX 5090 GPU with 24GB of GDDR7 VRAM, up to 96GB of DDR5 RAM, one slot of Gen5 NVMe M.2 storage, and three extra slots of Gen4 SSD storage.</p><p>It has an 18-inch 4K Mini LED screen capable of 3840 x 2400 (16:10) resolution at 120Hz refresh, a six-speaker audio setup (two of which are woofers), Wi-Fi 7, Bluetooth 5.4, Cherry mechanical keyboard switches with per-key RGB illumination, a 99.9Wh battery, and a power adapter capable of delivering 400-freaking-watts. </p><p>For I/O, you get two Thunderbolt 5 USB-C ports, three USB-A 3.2 Gen 2 ports, HDMI 2.1, gigabit ethernet, and a full-size SD card slot. This whole fire-breathing magnesium alloy package weighs in at a <em>hefty</em> 3.6 kg / 7.94 lbs, but it’s somehow not as heavy as <a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/24096382">Alienware’s boat anchor of a new 18-inch Area-51 laptop</a>.</p><div tabindex="0" aria-label="Zoom" role="button"><p>1<!-- -->/<!-- -->6</p><p><figcaption><em>The inlaid dragon medallion has some nice detail work within it.</em></figcaption></p></div><p>MSI has done Dragon Edition laptops before, but compared to previous incarnations, the new Titan Dragon Edition looks <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22227970/msi-ge76-raider-dragon-edition-ge66-tiamat-gaming-laptop-nvidia-rtx-3000-series">more fierce</a> and actually less garish — just <a href="https://www.msi.com/Laptop/GT70_Dragon_Edition/Specification">look at this old thing</a>. And true worshippers of Bahamut or Baal (or take your pick) may be able to get their draconic Titans in an accessory bundle with a matching mouse, keychain, and colorful desk pad when it launches in March.</p><div><figcaption><em>A glimpse at what some of MSI’s Dragon Edition bundle accessories may look like.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: MSI</cite></p></div><p><em>Photography by Antonio G. Di Benedetto / The Verge</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alienware’s new Area-51 laptops have light-up trackpads and fans]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24332341/alienware-area-51-16-18-rgb-laptop-price-specs-ces</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/alienware%E2%80%99s-new-area-51-laptops-have-light-up-trackpads-and-fans.1075602/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24332341/alienware-area-51-16-18-rgb-laptop-price-specs-ces<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Alienware is bringing back its Area-51 computer line, and its new flagship laptops are much showier than the secretive air base they’re named after. The bombastic, UFO-like Area-51 laptops are paired with a range of top-flight specs featuring Intel Arrow Lake CPUs and next-gen Nvidia GPUs — coming in two sizes: big (16-inch) and bigger (18-inch). They’ll start at a pricey $3,199 when select configurations launch by the end of Q1 2025, with an entry-level $1,999 model and other configs coming later.</p><p>Unlike last year’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/8/24026555/dell-alienware-m16-r2-ces-2024-gaming-laptop">M16 R2</a>, which trimmed down the protruding butt found on many Alienware laptops, the Area-51 has a full-on dump truck for a rear. And this protrusion, where all its ports are located, even lights up with a soft, supple glow of RGB illumination. The Area-51’s RGB light show extends to per-key keyboard illumination, a light-up trackpad, and lit case fans. The light-up fans are visible through the intake holes on the top deck as well as a seethrough Gorilla Glass panel on the underside, also showing off some of the laptop’s innards.</p><div><p><figcaption><em>The teal case color has a bit of a shimmer in the right light.</em></figcaption></p></div><p>The Area-51 duo will rely on their RGB lighting for their splashiest pops of color, as both sizes of Alienware laptops come in just one chassis color, called liquid teal. The anodized finish is said to take inspiration from the aurora borealis, looking nearly charcoal black in a dimly lit room until its lid or underside shows a slight shimmer of iridescence when the light catches it.</p><p>Housed within that aluminum chassis, the Area-51 sports some high-end specs. It can be outfitted with up to an Intel Core Ultra 9 275HX CPU, Nvidia’s new 50-series GPUs, up to 64GB of dual-channel DDR5 RAM, and up to 2TB NVMe PCIe Gen5 SSD. Powering all of that in each the 16-inch and 18-inch laptops is a sizable 96Wh battery. Alienware doesn’t list any battery life estimates in the Area-51’s tech specs. We’ve asked how many hours of use people should expect when unplugged and haven’t yet heard back. </p><p>The Area-51 duo use a new thermal architecture to keep all this hot hardware cool, and Alienware claims it moves up to 37 percent more airflow while running 15 percent quieter than the older Alienware X16 R2 from 2024. All those specs and improved thermals sound nice on paper, but keep in mind, these new Area-51 models are hefty laptops. Remember that older X16 R2 laptop that Alienware compares them to? The X16 R2 weighs six pounds. At 7.6 pounds, the new 16-inch Area-51 weighs about as much as the average American newborn baby, and the 18-inch is even heavier at nearly 10 pounds.</p><div><div><p><figcaption><em>The seethrough glass panel on the bottom has some alien-like glyphs.</em></figcaption></p></div><div><p><figcaption><em>That absolute unit of a derriere offers lots of I/O.</em></figcaption></p></div></div><p>Tipping the scales like that, the Area-51 laptops don’t feel like just a resurrection of Alienware’s flagship brand name but a throwback to older, basically immobile desktop replacement laptops. That does come with some benefits, like a plethora of rear-mounted ports including HDMI 2.1, 2.5 gigabit ethernet (RJ-45), three USB Type-A 3.2 Gen 1 5Gbps ports, two Thunderbolt 5 / USB-C ports, and a headphone jack and full-size SD card slot on the side. </p><p>The big drawback here is that the displays also feel a little retro, since the laptops use older IPS display tech. Both machines have 2560 x 1600 QHD panels with 3ms response time and up to 300Hz refresh (240Hz on the 16-inch), but there’s no fancy tandem OLED or anything of the sort like Alienware’s parent company Dell put in its upcoming <a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/24092096">Pro Premium laptop</a>. If you want OLED displays from Alienware, you’ll instead have to check out its <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23011794/alienware-aw3423dw-review-qd-oled-curved-gaming-pc-monitor">gaming monitors</a> — of which, it announced a new 27-inch 4K QD-OLED at CES 2025 as well as some <a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/24099606">Area-51 and Aurora prebuilt desktops. </a></p><p><em> Photography by Antonio G. Di Benedetto / The Verge</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HP’s Omen Max 16 is its most powerful gaming laptop yet]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24332194/hp-omen-max-16-elitebook-x-flip-g1i-zbook-ultra-14-g1a</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hp%E2%80%99s-omen-max-16-is-its-most-powerful-gaming-laptop-yet.1075599/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24332194/hp-omen-max-16-elitebook-x-flip-g1i-zbook-ultra-14-g1a<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>HP is announcing an updated lineup of notebooks at CES that includes new EliteBooks, a new Ryzen AI-powered ZBook workstation, and a fresh 16-inch Omen Max gaming laptop that can spin its fan in reverse to help clear out dust from its vents.</p><p>The Omen Max 16 could surely benefit from a cooling system that doesn’t get mucked up too quickly, considering it will come with next-gen Nvidia GeForce RTX graphics and a choice of Intel Core Ultra 9 or Ryzen AI 9 HX processors. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/23/24328561/hp-omen-max-leak-shows-off-another-nvidia-50-series-laptop">A leak in December suggested</a> the Omen will be one of the first devices to feature the RTX 5080 mobile GPU . HP also says the laptop is the first to use a “hybrid cryo compound” and a vapor chamber to improve thermals.</p><div><div><figcaption><em>You can get the Max in black or white.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: HP</cite></p></div><div><figcaption><em>The Omen Max 16’s fan can spin in reverse to help clear out dust.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: HP</cite></p></div></div><p>The laptop has Omen AI software that automatically adjusts system and game settings for the best performance and can pair instantly with HP’s HyperX gaming peripherals. HP’s Omen has also earned Microsoft Copilot Plus PC designation.</p><p>Of course, no gaming laptop is complete without RGB and accessories. The Omen Max 16 has a light bar on the front of its metal body (black or white) that can reflect off your desk, and you can control the colors using Omen Light Studio software. HP’s HyperX brand is also launching an incredibly modular Pulsefire Saga Pro gaming mouse that lets you swap out buttons and body components to your liking.</p><div><figcaption><em>HyperX Pulsefire Saga Pro modular gaming mouse.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Photo by Antonio G. Di Benedetto / The Verge</cite></p></div><p>HP <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/20/24160524/hp-omnibook-elitebook-ai-pc-laptop-surface-event">streamlined its computer lineup in May 2024</a>, letting go of the Pavilions and the Envys in favor of Omni and Elite laptop and desktop lines that correspond to consumer and business devices, respectively. Today, the company announced the EliteBook Ultra G1i, the Intel version of the laptop that launched in 2024 with Qualcomm chips. And the EliteBook X and convertible X Flip, which launched with AMD chips last year, now have Intel G1i versions as well.</p><p>You can configure EliteBooks with privacy screens, which makes it harder for onlookers to see what you’re doing while you work in public.</p><div tabindex="0" aria-label="Zoom" role="button"><p>1<!-- -->/<!-- -->7</p><div><figcaption><em>EliteBook X and X Flip.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Photo by Antonio G. Di Benedetto / The Verge</cite></p></div></div><p>Finally, HP updated its 14-inch workstation laptop with the new ZBook Ultra 14 G1a, this time with a thinner profile and without the <a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8836598/type/dlg/https://www.hp.com/us-en/workstations/zbook-firefly.html">Firefly</a> name. This ZBook ships with Ryzen AI Max Pro series chips designed to tear through Solidworks, 3DS Max, and AutoCAD work with up to 96GB shared graphics memory and up to 128GB of RAM. HP calls it the “world’s most powerful 14-inch mobile workstation.”</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia announces DLSS 4 with Multi Frame Generation]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24337402/nvidia-dlss-4-upscaling-announcement-ces-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nvidia-announces-dlss-4-with-multi-frame-generation.1075584/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24337402/nvidia-dlss-4-upscaling-announcement-ces-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Nvidia is revealing a big upgrade to its Deep Learning Super Sampling (DLSS) technology today. <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nvidia.com%2Fen-us%2Fgeforce%2Fnews%2Fdlss4-multi-frame-generation-ai-innovations%2F">DLSS 4</a> will include new neural rendering capabilities that, on systems with <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24337396/nvidia-rtx-5080-5090-5070-ti-5070-price-release-date">the new RTX 50 Series GPUs</a>, can do Multi Frame Generation, generating “up to three additional frames per traditionally rendered frame, working in unison with the complete suite of DLSS technologies to multiply frame rates by up to 8X over traditional brute-force rendering.”</p><p>According to Nvidia, that’s a big enough upgrade to make 4K 240fps, fully ray-traced gaming possible. Also, in an upgrade that will work on all GeForce RTX GPUs, DLSS games with Ray Reconstruction, Super Resolution, and DLAA&nbsp;can be updated to new transformer AI models that use the same tech as AI tools like ChatGPT, which it says is a first for the graphics industry.</p><p>Nvidia says its new frame generation model is 40 percent faster and uses 30 percent less VRAM than the old one. By replacing the old Convolutional Neural Networks with its new transformer model, the claim is that generated pixels will have less ghosting, more detail, and more stability in a scene for a clearer picture overall. </p><p>Nvidia is promising <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nvidia.com%2Fen-us%2Fgeforce%2Fnews%2Fdlss4-multi-frame-generation-ray-tracing-rtx-games%2F">there will be 75 games and apps that support Multi Frame Generation on day zero</a>, with <em>Alan Wake 2, Cyberpunk 2077, Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</em>, and <em>Star Wars Outlaws </em>supporting it when RTX 50 Series GPUs launch at the end of January, while “over 50 games” will have support for the new transformer-based DLSS features that can run on all GeForce RTX hardware.</p><p>We will want to see how the new frame generation tech affects latency, but Nvidia also announced Reflex 2 with Frame Warp technology, which it says can cut latency by up to 75 percent:</p><div><blockquote><p>As a frame is being rendered by the GPU, the CPU calculates the camera position of the next frame in the pipeline, based on the latest mouse or controller input. Frame Warp samples the new camera position from the CPU, and warps the frame just rendered by the GPU to this newer camera position. The warp is conducted as late as possible, just before the rendered frame is sent to the display, ensuring the most recent mouse input is reflected on screen.</p></blockquote></div><p>Nvidia’s figures show Reflex 2 cutting latency from 27ms with Reflex 1 to just 14ms in testing with<em> The Finals</em>. It says the tech is “coming soon” to both <em>The Finals </em>and <em>Valorant</em> for gamers with 50 Series GPUs first, before it’s available on other RTX hardware.</p><p>For games and apps that don’t have updates available immediately but have DLSS support, the updated drivers and Nvidia app have new DLSS Override switches. Users can force Multi Frame Generation on the new GPUs when frame generation is already turned on in the game, rendering based on the latest models when DLSS is turned on in the fame, and using updated Super Resolution rendering when that feature is turned on in the game.</p><p>Here’s a slide showing which DLSS 4 features are available on which series of RTX GPUs:</p><p>DLSS 4 arrives more than two years after <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/9/20/23362990/nvidia-dlss-3-0-demonstration-ada-lovelace-graphics-cards-upscaling-technology">Nvidia introduced DLSS 3</a> with Frame Generation to boost performance in a variety of games. Nvidia then introduced DLSS 3.5 in August 2023 with an AI-powered Ray Reconstruction technique to improve the quality of ray tracing and introduce path tracing (full ray tracing) in select titles. In August last year, <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nvidia.com%2Fen-gb%2Fgeforce%2Fnews%2Fnvidia-rtx-games-engines-apps%2F">Nvidia revealed</a> it now has more than 600 games and applications with RTX support.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia announces next-gen RTX 5090 and RTX 5080 GPUs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24337396/nvidia-rtx-5080-5090-5070-ti-5070-price-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nvidia-announces-next-gen-rtx-5090-and-rtx-5080-gpus.1075572/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24337396/nvidia-rtx-5080-5090-5070-ti-5070-price-release-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Nvidia is officially <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nvidia.com%2Fen-gb%2Fgeforce%2Fnews%2Frtx-50-series-graphics-cards-gpu-laptop-announcements%2F">announcing its RTX 50-series</a> GPUs today. After months of leaks and rumors, the next-generation RTX Blackwell GPUs are now official, and there are four of them on the way. </p><p>Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang revealed the RTX 50-series GPUs during a CES keynote this evening, announcing a $1,999 RTX 5090, a $999 RTX 5080, a $749 RTX 5070 Ti, and a $549 RTX 5070. Nvidia’s new RTX 5090 and RTX 5080 GPUs will both be available on January 30th, with the RTX 5070 Ti and RTX 5070 to follow in February.</p><div><figcaption><em>Nvidia’s RTX 5090 GPU is surprisingly small.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: Nvidia</cite></p></div><p>The RTX 50-series GPUs include a new design for the Founders Edition, with just two double flow-through fans, a 3D vapor chamber, and GDDR7 memory. All of the RTX 50-series cards are PCIe Gen 5 and include DisplayPort 2.1b connectors to drive displays up to 8K and 165Hz. </p><p>Surprisingly, the <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nvidia.com%2Fen-gb%2Fgeforce%2Fgraphics-cards%2F50-series%2Frtx-5090%2F">RTX 5090 Founders Edition</a> will be a two-slot GPU and will be capable of fitting inside small form factor PCs — a big departure from the size of the RTX 4090. The RTX 5090 has 32GB of GDDR7, a memory bandwidth of 1,792GB/sec, and a massive 21,760 CUDA cores. </p><p>This all adds up to a GPU that Nvidia says will be two times faster than the RTX 4090, thanks to DLSS 4 and the Blackwell architecture. But it will come at a cost of power consumption, as Nvidia says the RTX 5090 will have a total graphics power of 575 watts and a recommended PSU requirement of 1000 watts. That’s 125 watts more than the RTX 4090, but hopefully the RTX 5090 will be a lot more power efficient so that you’ll rarely be using the full 575 watts.</p><p>Nvidia demonstrated <em>Cyberpunk 2077</em> running on an RTX 5090 with DLSS 4 at 238fps compared to 106fps on an RTX 4090 with DLSS 3.5. Both GPUs are running the game with full ray tracing enabled.</p><p><a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nvidia.com%2Fen-gb%2Fgeforce%2Fgraphics-cards%2F50-series%2Frtx-5080%2F">The RTX 5080</a> is designed to be twice as fast as the RTX 4080 and will include 16GB of GDDR7 memory, a memory bandwidth of 960GB/sec, and 10,752 CUDA cores. The RTX 5080 will have a total graphics power of 360 watts and Nvidia is recommending a 850-watt power supply. Nvidia is promising big performance gains with the RTX 5080 over the previous RTX 4080 model as a result of these specs.</p><div><figcaption><em>RTX 5090 performance.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: Nvidia</cite></p></div><div><figcaption><em>Nvidia’s RTX 5080 performance promises.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: Nvidia</cite></p></div><p>Nvidia is also launching an <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nvidia.com%2Fen-gb%2Fgeforce%2Fgraphics-cards%2F50-series%2Frtx-5070-family%2F">RTX 5070 Ti</a> and <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nvidia.com%2Fen-gb%2Fgeforce%2Fgraphics-cards%2F50-series%2Frtx-5070-family%2F">RTX 5070</a>. The RTX 5070 Ti includes 16GB of GDDR7 memory, a memory bandwidth of 896GB/s, and 8,960 CUDA cores. The RTX 5070 has 12GB of GDDR7, a memory bandwidth of 672 GB/sec, and 6,144 CUDA cores. The RTX 5070 Ti will have a total graphics power of 300 watts and require a 750-watt PSU, while the RTX 5070 has a total graphics power of 250 watts and only needs a 650-watt PSU.</p><p>Nvidia says the RTX 5070 Ti will be 2x faster than the RTX 4070 Ti, and the RTX 5070 should be twice as fast as the RTX 4070. Huang even claimed on stage at CES that the RTX 5070 will deliver “RTX 4090 performance at $549,” but this will undoubtedly be because of DLSS 4 improvements and not pure rasterization performance.</p><p>Nvidia is also bringing its RTX 50-series to laptops, with the RTX 5090 laptop GPU debuting with 24GB of GDDR7 memory. The RTX 5080 laptop GPU will ship with 16GB of GDDR7 memory, the RTX 5070 Ti with 12GB of GDDR7 memory, and the RTX 5070 with just 8GB of GDDR7 memory. RTX 50-series laptops will be available starting in March from a variety of PC makers.</p><div><figcaption><em>RTX 50-series laptops are coming in March.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: Nvidia</cite></p></div><p>Huang demonstrated Nvidia’s RTX Blackwell GPUs with a real-time rendering demo at the beginning of the company’s CES keynote today. The demo included new RTX Neural Materials, RTX Neural Faces, text to animation, and even DLSS 4. “The new generation of DLSS can generate beyond frames, it can predict the future,” says Huang. “We used GeForce to enable AI, and now AI is revolutionizing GeForce.”</p><p>Nvidia’s new RTX Neural Shaders can be used to compress textures in games, while RTX Neural Faces aim to improve face quality using generative AI. The next generation of DLSS includes Multi Frame Generation, which generates up to three additional frames per traditional frame and can multiply frame rates by up to 8x over traditional rendering, according to Nvidia.</p><p>DLSS 4 also includes a real-time application of transformers to improve image quality, reduce ghosting, and add higher detail in motion. The DLSS 4 upgrade will even work on existing RTX GPUs, as features have been upgraded to the new transformer AI models. You can <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24337402/nvidia-dlss-4-upscaling-announcement-ces-2025">read more about DLSS 4 right here</a>.</p><p>Nvidia’s RTX 50-series announcement comes more than two years after the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/9/20/23362653/nvidia-rtx-4080-4090-price-release-date">RTX 4090 and RTX 4080 were announced</a>, based on Nvidia’s Ada Lovelace architecture. Nvidia’s RTX 40-series of GPUs focused on improving ray tracing with Deep Learning Super Sampling (DLSS)  version 3, and the RTX 4090 delivered some <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23398201/nvidia-rtx-4090-review-test-benchmark">truly impressive performance gains</a> over the previous RTX 3090 GPU.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Last of Us season 2 will premiere in April]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24337876/last-of-us-season-two-release-date-hbo-max-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-last-of-us-season-2-will-premiere-in-april.1075521/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24337876/last-of-us-season-two-release-date-hbo-max-announced<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p><em>The Last of Us </em>will return to HBO and Max this April. Series creative director, Neil Druckmann, announced the premiere of the show’s second season onstage at CES this evening alongside a short teaser for the new season. A specific premiere date wasn’t given.</p><p>The show’s first season <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23636850/the-last-of-us-season-1-tlou-hbo-ps5-game-reviews-interviews">wrapped up in March 2023</a>, so it’ll be more than two years between seasons by the time the new one debuts. <em>The Last of Us</em>’ first season was very well-received —&nbsp;particularly for a video game adaptation —&nbsp;so expectations are high for the show’s return.</p><p>This season is supposed to cover a portion of the second game, with the full story being split across two or more seasons, according to <a href="https://deadline.com/2024/06/the-last-of-us-season-2-episode-count-season-4-roadmap-1235945923/">an interview last year</a> with the show’s creators. “We don’t think that we’re going to be able to tell the story even within two seasons [2 and 3] because we’re taking our time and go down interesting pathways which we did a little bit in Season 1 too,” showrunner Craig Mazin told <em>Deadline</em>.</p><p>Alongside the return of <em>The Last of Us</em>, Sony also announced plans to bring several other PlayStation titles to the screen. <em>Ghost of Tsushima</em> is being adapted into an anime series, and both <em>Horizon Zero Dawn </em>and <em>Helldivers 2 </em>are being <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24337875/sony-playstation-horizon-zero-dawn-helldivers-2-ghosts-of-tsushima-movie-tv-show">made into films</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony’s Xyn is a prototype VR headset for making 3D games and movies]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24337597/sony-xyn-vr-headset-prototype-3d-games-movies</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony%E2%80%99s-xyn-is-a-prototype-vr-headset-for-making-3d-games-and-movies.1075488/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24337597/sony-xyn-vr-headset-prototype-3d-games-movies<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Sony is launching the Xyn (pronounced <em>zin</em>), an “extended reality” headset for creating 3D objects for films, animation, and games. The device, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/8/24030930/sony-vr-spatial-smart-control-ring-ces">which Sony first teased at CES last year</a>, will come with 4K OLED displays, video passthrough, and support for third-party design, modeling, and production software.</p><p>Based on the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WPBmlGIiAOE&amp;embeds_referring_euri=https%3A%2F%2Fvoxmedia.stories.usechorus.com%2F&amp;source_ve_path=MjM4NTE">video shared by Sony</a>, it looks like wearers will be able to flip up the headset when they’re not using it. It doesn’t appear to come with the ring and pointer that Sony showed off last year, though.</p><p>Alongside the headset, Sony revealed Xyn Motion Studio, an accompanying Windows app that supports up to 12 Mocopi sensors, its <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/6/30/23780187/sony-mocopi-motion-capture-vr-avatar-us-price-release">wireless motion-tracking system</a> that V-Tubers and other creators often use to control virtual avatars. The software comes with motion-editing features, allowing creators to trim and merge motions, as well as adjust time and position.</p><p>There’s also a prototype of a “spatial capture solution,” which is supposed to transform images of real objects and spaces into “photorealistic” 3D computer-generated assets using Sony’s algorithm. One year out from Sony’s initial teaser, and details are still pretty slim on what exactly this headset will be capable of, aside from viewing and interacting with 3D objects.</p><p>Sony is planning to release its Xyn Motion Studio software in late March 2025, but there still isn’t any word on the availability or pricing of its headset.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The best stuff we’ve seen at CES so far]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24337606/ces-2025-smart-home-tv-cameras-power-bank-robot-smart-glasses</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-best-stuff-we%E2%80%99ve-seen-at-ces-so-far.1075437/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24337606/ces-2025-smart-home-tv-cameras-power-bank-robot-smart-glasses<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The show floor of the biggest tech event of the year hasn’t even opened yet, but CES 2025 has already delivered a long list of new gadgets, tech, concepts, and AI-powered devices tempting you to upgrade. </p><p>It’s a lot to keep up with, so we’ll help you catch up. Below are some of the standout gadgets of the show so far. Of course, there’s still a lot more out there and a lot more to go. You can catch up on all of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/4/24307731/ces-2025-tvs-gaming-smart-home-wearables-news/archives/5"><em>The Verge’s</em> coverage of the show here</a>.</p><p><h3><a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@verge/video/7456477347454307630">Roborock Saros Z70</a></h3></p><div><p><cite>Photo by Owen Grove / The Verge</cite></p></div><p>The ability for most robovacs to thoroughly clean a floor can be stymied by random objects left lying on the ground. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/5/24332998/roborock-saros-z70-robot-vacuum-omnigrip-arm">Roborock’s new Saros Z70’s solution to that problem</a> is an articulated five-axis robot arm called the OmniGrip that can pick up after its owners and move obstacles out of its way. It’s limited to smaller items like socks, tissues, or anything weighing less than 300 grams, but the company plans to eventually expand what it can grasp. Pricing isn’t known, but Roborock says the Saros Z70 will be available by June 2025.</p><p><h3><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/5/24336154/samsung-the-frame-pro-features-specs">Samsung The Frame Pro TV</a></h3></p><div><p><cite>Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge</cite></p></div><p>Samsung’s The Frame TV appealed to many consumers with an aesthetically pleasing design and the ability to camouflage itself as a piece of art in a home’s decor. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/5/24336154/samsung-the-frame-pro-features-specs">The Frame Pro further expands the TV’s appeal</a> to more discerning TV viewers with a variation on Mini LED display technology, the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/4/4/23009799/samsung-the-frame-2022-preview-matte-display-artwork">matte finish introduced in 2022</a>, and a wireless connection to its breakout box so all you need to hide is a power cord.</p><p><h3><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/5/24334030/halliday-smart-glasses-ai-tiny-display-frame-availability-price-ces">Halliday smart glasses</a></h3></p><p>With the success of the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23922425/ray-ban-meta-smart-glasses-review">Meta Ray-Bans</a>, it’s no surprise that several companies are debuting smart glasses at CES 2025. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/5/24334030/halliday-smart-glasses-ai-tiny-display-frame-availability-price-ces">Halliday’s new enhanced specs</a>, which are expected to ship “by the end of Q1 2025” and cost between $399 and $499, are differentiated with the addition of a small screen on the frame. The “DigiWindow” appears as a 3.5-inch private display in the upper-right corner of your vision and is controlled using voice commands, an interface on the frame, or a smart ring with an integrated trackpad.</p><p><h3><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24334913/dell-32-plus-monitor-head-tracking-beamforming-audio-ces-2025">Dell 32 Plus 4K QD-OLED monitor</a></h3></p><div><p><cite>Photo by Antonio G. Di Benedetto / The Verge</cite></p></div><p>Dell’s new <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24334913/dell-32-plus-monitor-head-tracking-beamforming-audio-ces-2025">32-inch 4K OLED display uses an infrared sensor and five speakers</a> located below the screen to track your head and beam sound directly to your ears. The feature eliminates the need to keep your head positioned in a sweet spot for optimal sound, and it could be ideal for gamers who are constantly moving around in the heat of battle. The monitor also features a 120Hz refresh rate, a 0.03ms response time, and will launch in the US on May 22nd, 2025, for $799.99.</p><p><h3><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24337124/bird-buddy-wonder-petal-camera-track-plants-insects-ces-2025">Wonder plant and insect camera</a></h3></p><p>Bird Buddy is moving on to smaller flying creatures of the outdoors. The company behind the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/1/4/23528786/bird-buddy-hummingbird-feeder-ai-camera">stylish smart bird feeders</a> is introducing a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24337124/bird-buddy-wonder-petal-camera-track-plants-insects-ces-2025">playfully designed camera</a> for tracking your plants and the insect visitors that stop by them. You’ll be able to view a livestream from your phone, while an optional solar panel can keep the 4K camera running. It’s supposed to launch on Kickstarter this spring.</p><p><h3><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/5/24325152/yukai-engineering-mirumi-robot-ces">Mirumi</a></h3></p><p>Mirumi is a robot that you might actually want to own. It’s a furry, bashful companion bot that clings to a bag and looks adorable. It doesn’t have AI tricks and doesn’t even make noise. Like my colleague Owen Grove said <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@verge/video/7456601160565263658?embed_source=121374463%2C121468991%2C121439635%2C121433650%2C121404359%2C121477481%2C121351166%2C121487028%2C73226838%2C121331973%2C120811592%2C120810756%2C121494655%3Bnull%3Bembed_blank&amp;refer=embed&amp;referer_url=www.theverge.com%2F2025%2F1%2F5%2F24325152%2Fyukai-engineering-mirumi-robot-ces&amp;referer_video_id=7456601160565263658">in a video</a>: “It’s just a cute fuzzy thing. What more do you want?” It will be available through a crowdfunding campaign that’s set to launch in mid-2025.</p><p><h3><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24335423/acer-handheld-gaming-pc-nitro-blaze-8-11-specs-price">Acer Nitro Blaze 11</a></h3></p><p>How big is <em>too</em> big for a handheld gaming machine? The answer might be <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24335423/acer-handheld-gaming-pc-nitro-blaze-8-11-specs-price">Acer’s new Nitro Blaze 11 featuring a beefy 10.95-inch 144 Hz WQXGA touch display</a> that makes it look like you’re holding a small monitor instead of a portable console. It’s powered by an&nbsp;AMD Ryzen 8040HS processor, 16GB of RAM, and has detachable controllers with Hall effect joysticks. It’s also got a built-in kickstand so you don’t have to strain your arms by always playing it handheld. It will be available starting in Q2 2025 and start at $1,099.99.</p><p><h3><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/5/24335612/belkin-stage-powergrip-battery-pack-camera-grip-stand">Belkin Stage PowerGrip</a></h3></p><p>Your smartphone may take great pictures, but it lacks the refined ergonomics of a traditional camera. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/5/24335612/belkin-stage-powergrip-battery-pack-camera-grip-stand">Belkin’s new Stage PowerGrip</a> addresses that issue and battery anxiety. It’s a MagSafe power bank with a 10,000mAh battery, a retractable USB-C cable, and a design that adds a camera-like grip to the iPhone. It’s even got a physical shutter button that works with the iOS camera app over Bluetooth and a small LCD screen on the front showing the battery’s remaining charge. Pricing and availability haven’t been announced, but the PowerGrip will come in several color options.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>