<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 22:09:51 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo’s new amiibo might be getting a price hike]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/652885/nintendo-switch-2-amiibo-price-increase</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo%E2%80%99s-new-amiibo-might-be-getting-a-price-hike.1169802/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/652885/nintendo-switch-2-amiibo-price-increase<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/emma-roth">Emma Roth</a> <span>is a news writer who covers the streaming wars, consumer tech, crypto, social media, and much more. Previously, she was a writer and editor at MUO.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Nintendo’s soon-to-be-released amiibo just went up in price <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fbrowse%2Fswitch-2-hardware-and-software%2F0%2F0%3F_refineresult%3Dtrue%26_be_shelf_id%3D7433688%26search_sort%3D100%26facet%3Dshelf_id%253A7433688%26povid%3Dets_switch2_pov%26nrtv_cid%3Dwrdc7ik0tek3t%26clickid%3DVEUwSBxtZxycW%253Aa19cxNAycYUksUeMRNIQMKUc0%26irgwc%3D1%26sourceid%3Dimp_VEUwSBxtZxycW%253Aa19cxNAycYUksUeMRNIQMKUc0%26veh%3Daff%26wmlspartner%3Dimp_376373%26affiliates_ad_id%3D565706%26campaign_id%3D9383%26sharedid%3D" rel="sponsored">at Walmart</a>, <a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;mid=24348&amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fnintendo-switch-amiibo%3Fsrule%3Drelease-date-descending" rel="sponsored">GameStop</a>, and <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/482924/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fsearchpage.jsp%3F_dyncharset%3DUTF-8%26browsedCategory%3Dpcmcat306400050032%26id%3Dpcat17071%26iht%3Dn%26ks%3D960%26list%3Dy%26qp%3Dplatformcompatibilitymv_facet%253DCompatible%2520Platform~Nintendo%2520Switch%25202%26sc%3DGlobal%26st%3Dcategoryid%2524pcmcat306400050032%26type%3Dpage%26usc%3DAll%2520Categories" rel="sponsored">Best Buy</a> in the US. The three retailers have increased the price of <em>Street Fighter 6</em> amiibo from $29.99 to $39.99, while the new <em>Legend of Zelda</em> amiibo have gone from $19.99 to $29.99, as reported <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/04/walmart-joins-gamestop-with-higher-amiibo-price-listings-for-switch-2-us">earlier by <em>Nintendo Life</em></a>.</p><p>Nintendo’s upcoming amiibo, which include <em>Street Fighter</em>’s Luke, Jamie, and Kimberly, along with <em>The Legend of Zelda</em>’s Riju, Sidon, Yunobo, and Tulin, are set to arrive with <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/634603/nintendo-switch-2-price-release-date-details">the Switch 2 on June 5th</a>.</p><p>Though Nintendo announced last week that it isn’t increasing the price of the $449.99 console, that isn’t the case for its accessories. The Switch 2 Joy-Con, Pro Controller, and the Switch 2 camera <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/643616/nintendo-switch-2-us-preorders-date">all went up in price last week</a>, around the same time some users started noticing the amiibo price hike at GameStop. <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:knj5sw5al3sukl6vhkpi7637/post/3lndgszmdtm2d?ref_src=embed&amp;ref_url=https%253A%252F%252Fwww.nintendolife.com%252Fnews%252F2025%252F04%252Fwalmart-joins-gamestop-with-higher-amiibo-price-listings-for-switch-2-us">Walmart</a> and Best Buy only seem to have adjusted the prices on Monday.</p><p><em>The Verge</em> reached out to Nintendo with a request for more information, but didn’t immediately hear back. The Switch 2 and its amiibo will be available for preorder on April 24th.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Boy clone maker Anbernic suspends all shipments to US]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/652797/anbernic-suspend-shipments-tariffs-us-china</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/game-boy-clone-maker-anbernic-suspends-all-shipments-to-us.1169775/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/652797/anbernic-suspend-shipments-tariffs-us-china<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/sean-hollister">Sean Hollister</a> <span>is a senior editor and founding member of The Verge who covers gadgets, games, and toys. He spent 15 years editing the likes of CNET, Gizmodo, and Engadget.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><div><p>How much will <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/650556/temu-shein-us-price-increase-tariffs">Trump’s threatened 245 percent tariffs</a> truly impact Chinese goods and the prices we pay in the US? Some Chinese companies aren’t waiting to see. Anbernic, which makes <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/630797/a-game-boy-for-pirates-titw">excellent and controversial Nintendo Game Boy clones</a>, is already suspending US shipments indefinitely.</p></div><p>“Due to changes in U.S. tariff policies, we will be suspending all orders shipping from China to the United States starting today,” <a href="https://anbernic.com/pages/shipping-policy">writes Anbernic.</a> “We strongly recommend prioritizing products shipped from our U.S. warehouse, which are currently not affected by import duties and can be purchased with confidence.”</p><p>No, Anbernic didn’t set up a brand-new US warehouse in response to tariffs — it’s been an option on its storefront for some time. Generally, Anbernic begins by drop-shipping each new handheld from China directly to buyers’ homes after they’re introduced, then stockpiles additional units in US warehouses for faster ship times. Anbernic lets buyers pick which warehouse they prefer on its checkout page.</p><p>As of last week, Anbernic had <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ANBERNIC/comments/1k1ikq0/is_it_safe_to_order_from_anbernic_at_this_point/#lightbox">already begun suggesting</a> that US buyers pick its US warehouse because “orders shipped to the United States may be subject to high customs duties,” asking customers to “take this potential risk into account when making your purchase decisions.”</p><p>But now, the company is suspending those shipments entirely — similarly to how acclaimed retro game scaler maker <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/651007/retrotink-us-shipments-suspended-trump-tariffs">RetroTINK suspended shipments not just because of tariffs</a>, but “due to lack of guidance on how tariffs will be collected.” I checked: while you can still add a Anbernic handheld to your US cart from a Chinese warehouse, the company offers plenty of warnings and won’t let you purchase it from there.</p><p>One reason for Anbernic’s popularity is that its retro handhelds are cheap, typically around $70 for the newest models. (Some also do an excellent job emulating the look and feel of classic Nintendo handhelds, as you can see in my videos above and below.) But those low prices are now completely under threat by Trump’s tariffs and the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/642601/donald-trump-tariffs-de-minimis-shein-temu">removal of the de minimis exemption for cheap Chinese goods</a>. It’s not clear if or how companies like Anbernic could afford to resume shipments, should those tariffs actually take hold.</p><p>For the time being, Anbernic handhelds are also still available in the US via third-party sellers like Amazon — which I’ve always found surprising given that those ones typically come with Nintendo, Sega and Sony ROMs.</p><div><p><a href="https://retrohandhelds.gg/tariffs/"><em>Retro Handhelds</em> has a handy regularly updated page</a> keeping track of handheld tariffs; so far, Anbernic is the only one to suspend US shipments entirely.</p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony shows off the PS5 Pro’s liquid metal updates]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/652556/ps5-pro-teardown-liquid-metal-cooling-changes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-shows-off-the-ps5-pro%E2%80%99s-liquid-metal-updates.1169685/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/652556/ps5-pro-teardown-liquid-metal-cooling-changes<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><div><p><span><ul><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news">News</a></li></ul></span></p></div><div><p>New grooves may address complaints of liquid metal leaking in the standard PS5.</p></div></div><div><div><p>New grooves may address complaints of liquid metal leaking in the standard PS5.</p><div><p><span><time datetime="2025-04-21T18:06:34+00:00">Apr 21, 2025, 6:06 PM UTC</time></span></p></div></div><div><p><cite>Photo: Vjeran Pavic / The Verge</cite></p></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/wes-davis">Wes Davis</a> <span>is a weekend editor who covers the latest in tech and entertainment. He has written news, reviews, and more as a tech journalist since 2020.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Sony has <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/04/21/playstation-5-pro-teardown-an-inside-look-at-the-most-advanced-playstation-console-to-date/">published a new teardown</a> of the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/626952/sony-fsr-4-upscaler-coming-to-ps5-pro-reimplementation">PlayStation 5 Pro</a>, highlighting improvements that it made to the cooling apparatus of the machine. They include tweaks to the PS5’s liquid metal cooling design aimed to give the console “more stable” cooling. </p><p>The changes follow unproven claims that the liquid metal used in the first PS5 can leak and damage the console. Some sites even recommended against keeping the PS5 vertical after a repair shop owner and YouTuber was <a href="https://wololo.net/2023/01/05/youre-killing-your-ps5-by-using-it-vertically-due-to-a-design-flaw-by-sony-according-to-hardware-experts/">partially misquoted</a> by jailbreak site Wololo.net. Wololo <a href="https://wololo.net/2023/01/07/ps5-liquid-metal-issues-thecod3r-addresses-some-questions-in-new-video/">later followed up</a>, saying its original story contained a “critical misunderstanding” — ultimately, it doesn’t seem like this was ever a widespread issue.</p><p>Even so, Sony writes that it changed the design for the PS5 Pro, quoting Shinya Tsuchida, PS5 Pro Mechanical Design Lead:</p><div><blockquote><p>We spent quite some time conducting research on insulation when we were designing the original PS5. The basic structure remains the same in the PS5 Pro, but we made some improvements by adding fine grooves where the liquid metal is applied, so that the cooling effect is more stable. When we were doing research for the original PS5, we anticipated that semiconductors would continue to advance and become much denser, so we believed liquid metal technology would become crucial. It turns out we were right, and it was integral when designing the PS5 Pro.</p></blockquote></div><p>The rest of the blog post and its images may be familiar to you if you already saw <a href="https://www.ifixit.com/News/105278/ps5-pro-teardown-is-a-battery-hatch-this-years-hottest-repair-trend">iFixit’s teardown</a> of Sony’s very expensive console, in which it noted that the inside of the PS5 Pro contains more thermal management than electronics.</p><p>Some of that includes a larger cooling fan that the company says has redesigned fan blades, including “smaller blades in between” them. The blog also explains why it’s so hard to see the traces on the PS5 Pro’s motherboard: the board hides extra electrical layers beneath, to speed up memory access.</p></div></div><div><form><div><h2>Installer</h2><p><span>A weekly newsletter by David Pierce designed to tell you everything you need to download, watch, read, listen to, and explore that fits in The Verge’s universe.</span></p></div></form></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>