<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 22:38:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silksong: all of the updates about the Hollow Knight sequel]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/769489/hollow-knight-silksong-news-updates</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/silksong-all-of-the-updates-about-the-hollow-knight-sequel.1286952/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section><p>After years of development and pent-up anticipation from fans, <em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em>, the full sequel to the indie classic <em>Hollow Knight</em>, will finally be released <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/680636/hollow-knight-silksong-release-date-trailer">on September 4th</a>. It will <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/768524/hollow-knight-silksong-pricing-release-timing">cost $19.99</a> and include new zones, more than 200 enemies, over 40 bosses, and an orchestral score from the composer of the first game.</p><p><em>Silksong</em> was first announced <a href="https://www.teamcherry.com.au/blog/hollow-knight-silksong-revealed">in 2019</a>, two years after the release of <em>Hollow Knight</em>, but developers Team Cherry have stayed pretty quiet about the sequel in the years since — even after a planned launch window was announced <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/6/12/22175400/hollow-knight-silksong-sequel-xbox-game-pass-trailer">in 2022</a>, which was followed by <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/5/9/23717855/hollow-knight-silksong-delayed">a delay</a> months later. In an interview <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2025-08-21/why-silksong-team-cherry-s-sequel-to-hollow-knight-took-so-long-to-make">with <em>Bloomberg</em></a>, Team Cherry co-founders Ari Gibson and William Pellen said that the game was “never stuck”; instead, the small team working on <em>Silksong</em> was just taking its time.</p><p>Team Cherry announced <em>Silksong</em>’s release date just two weeks ahead of the game’s launch. The game is launching on PC, Nintendo Switch, Xbox, and PlayStation.</p><p>Here’s all of our coverage of <em>Silksong</em>.</p></section><section id="updates-section"><ul><li id="dmcyOnBvc3Q6NzY4NTI0" role="article"><h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/768524/hollow-knight-silksong-pricing-release-timing">Silksong is only $19.99</a></h2><div><p><em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em>, Team Cherry’s sequel to <em>Hollow Knight</em> that has been in development for seven years, is <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/680636/hollow-knight-silksong-release-date-trailer">releasing later this week</a> for just $19.99. <em>Silksong</em>’s highly-anticipated launch on September 4th comes with a modest $5 bump over <em>Hollow Knight</em>’s original $14.99 price tag.</p><p>While Team Cherry could have charged more for <em>Silksong</em>, it’s essentially pricing it the same as the original when you factor in inflation over the past eight years. The team revealed seven years ago that it kept the <em>Hollow Knight</em> pricing low to ensure as many people played it as possible. “$15 US is actually quite a bit of money for many people, especially in other countries than the US,” explained Team Cherry cofounder Ari Gibson in a 2018 <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NintendoSwitch/comments/8swt8n/comment/e12wtcy/">Reddit post</a>. “Ultimately, our main interest is that as many people as possible play our games, and we want to price them such that players can do so.”</p><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/768524/hollow-knight-silksong-pricing-release-timing">Read Article &gt;</a></p></div></li><li id="dmcyOnBvc3Q6NzY0MzQ2" role="article"><h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/764346/hollow-knight-silksong-indie-game-delays-cloverpit-faeland-aeterna-lucis">Silksong is out soon, and indie games are getting out of the way</a></h2><div><p>Yesterday, <em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em> developers Team Cherry announced a September 4th release date for the long-awaited game, and indie developers are announcing delays to get out of the way of the launch. <em>Silksong</em> is a full sequel to the excellent <em>Hollow Knight</em> and is currently the most wishlisted game on Steam, so it’s likely going to be very popular when it’s finally available.</p><p>Panik Arcade, which was set to release its “hellish gambling roguelike” <em>CloverPit</em> on September 3rd, has pushed the game’s launch to September 26th. “We poured our hearts into our little game so of course we want to give it the best possible shot,” <a rel="sponsored" href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.steampowered.com%2Fnews%2Fapp%2F3314790%2Fview%2F520848458437886253">Panik Arcade says</a>. “We hope you can understand — we’ll use the extra time of course to polish the game even further and we hope for your support at launch either way.”</p><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/764346/hollow-knight-silksong-indie-game-delays-cloverpit-faeland-aeterna-lucis">Read Article &gt;</a></p></div></li><li role="article"><div><p>A Silksong September.</p><p><strong>Dicebot:</strong></p><div><blockquote><p>Woohoo! Release day announced! Can’t wait for them to tell us the year.</p></blockquote></div><p>Get the day’s best comment and more in my free newsletter, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/newsletters"><em>The Verge Daily</em></a>.</p></div></li><li id="dmcyOnBvc3Q6NjgwNjM2" role="article"><h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/680636/hollow-knight-silksong-release-date-trailer">Silksong finally launches in September</a></h2><div><p><em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em>, the full sequel to <em>Hollow Knight</em> that has been in development for years, will be released on September 4th. The news was revealed as part of a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6XGeJwsUP9c">“special announcement”</a> video that debuted on Thursday.</p><p>In <em>Silksong</em>, you play as Hornet, a character that appeared in the original <em>Hollow Knight</em>. The game, which will be released for Nintendo Switch, PlayStation, Xbox, and PC, features a new kingdom with new areas to explore and new enemies and bosses to fight.</p><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/680636/hollow-knight-silksong-release-date-trailer">Read Article &gt;</a></p></div></li><li role="article"><div><p>“Silksong is real.”</p><p>The game is “100 percent” launching in 2025, according to Geoff Keighley at Opening Night Live. Onstage, he showed off some <a href="https://x.com/summergamefest/status/1957866774965154193">brief footage of the game</a>. More news about the game is coming <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/761451/hollow-knight-silksong-special-announcement-youtube">on Thursday.</a></p></div></li><li id="dmcyOnBvc3Q6NzYxNDUx" role="article"><h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/761451/hollow-knight-silksong-special-announcement-youtube">Get ready for Silksong’s ‘special announcement’ on Thursday</a></h2></li><li role="article"></li><li role="article"><div><p>Silksong will also be at Nintendo’s Gamescom booth.</p></div></li><li id="dmcyOnBvc3Q6NzE0NDkw" role="article"><h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/714490/xbox-gamescom-silksong-playable-demo-xbox-ally-handheld">Xbox&nbsp;will let you play Silksong at Gamescom in August</a></h2><div><p>Microsoft will let Gamescom attendees play a demo of the long-awaited <em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em> on the new <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/682011/microsoft-windows-xbox-pc-combination-features-rog-xbox-ally-devices">ROG Xbox Ally handhelds</a>. It’s part of more than 20 titles that <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/07/28/xbox-gamescom-2025/">will be available</a> at the Xbox booth at Gamescom, including a new theater experience to demonstrate <em>The Outer Worlds 2</em>.</p><p><em>Silksong </em>will be available to play on the new Xbox Ally devices at Gamescom, just months after Xbox president Sarah Bond <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/682390/silksong-spotted">revealed in June</a> that <em>Silksong</em> will be available “at launch and in Game Pass” when Asus’ new handhelds launch later this year.</p><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/714490/xbox-gamescom-silksong-playable-demo-xbox-ally-handheld">Read Article &gt;</a></p></div></li><li role="article"><div><p>Silksong spotted!</p><p>Xbox showed off some footage of the long-awaited <em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em> on the new <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/682011/microsoft-windows-xbox-pc-combination-features-rog-xbox-ally-devices">ROG Xbox Ally handheld</a>. But we still don’t have a specific release date for the game: all Xbox president Sarah Bond said is that the game will be available “at launch and in Game Pass when the Ally releases later this year.”</p></div></li><li id="dmcyOnBvc3Q6NjEwNzY2" role="article"><h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/610766/hollow-knight-silksong-release-date-trailer">Hollow Knight: Silksong is launching in 2025</a></h2><div><p><em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em>, the long-awaited sequel to <em>Hollow Knight</em>, has a new release year window: 2025, as revealed in a very brief clip during today’s Nintendo Switch 2 Direct.</p><p><em>Silksong</em> was first announced for Windows, Mac, Linux, and the Nintendo Switch in 2019. It was originally intended to be DLC for <em>Hollow Knight</em>, but <a href="https://www.teamcherry.com.au/blog/hollow-knight-silksong-revealed">according to developers Team Cherry</a>, “it quickly became too large and too unique to stay a DLC, as initially planned.” The game will take place in a new kingdom, with new moves and new weapons at your disposal as well as new enemies to take on.</p><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/610766/hollow-knight-silksong-release-date-trailer">Read Article &gt;</a></p></div></li><li role="article"><div><p>Time to get your hopes up about a Silksong release date.</p><p>If <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24132202/nintendo-indie-world-april-2024">Nintendo’s recent showcase</a> didn’t satisfy your need for indie game news, here comes Microsoft. The company just announced that its next ID@Xbox Digital Showcase will take place on April 29th, and will feature “another batch of hotly anticipated indies.” Of course, there’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/6/12/22175400/hollow-knight-silksong-sequel-xbox-game-pass-trailer">one specific game</a> we’ll all be looking out for.</p></div></li><li role="article"><div><p>Is the Silksong release date in the room with us right now?</p></div></li><li id="dmcyOnBvc3Q6NjYxNDg=" role="article"><h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/5/9/23717855/hollow-knight-silksong-delayed">Hollow Knight: Silksong has been delayed</a></h2><div><p>We’ll be waiting a little while longer for <em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em>. The years-in-the-making sequel to the excellent <em>Hollow Knight</em> was supposed to release within 12 months <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/6/12/23164968/xbox-bethesda-games-showcase-2022-activision-blizzard">of the 2022 Xbox June showcase</a>, but a representative for the game said Tuesday evening that the title will be missing that release window.</p><p>“We had planned to release in the 1st half of 2023, but development is still continuing,” Matthew Griffin, who works on marketing and publishing for the game, <a href="https://twitter.com/griffinmatta/status/1656106351184199680">posted on Twitter</a>. “We’re excited by how the game is shaping up, and it’s gotten quite big, so we want to take the time to make the game as good as we can. Expect more details from us once we get closer to release.”</p><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/5/9/23717855/hollow-knight-silksong-delayed">Read Article &gt;</a></p></div></li><li role="article"></li><li role="article"><div><p>Silksong when?</p><p>Nintendo is hosting its next Indie World showcase on Wednesday at 12PM ET / 9AM PT, and I’ll be <a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/news/hollow-knight-fans-rejoice-as-crumb-of-silksong-news-is-released-but-theres-still-no-release-date">putting on my clown makeup</a> in hopes of a <em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em> release date announcement. In June, Microsoft said the game would be released <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/6/12/22175400/hollow-knight-silksong-sequel-xbox-game-pass-trailer">within 12 months</a>, so maybe it’s almost time?</p></div></li><li id="dmcyOnBvc3Q6ODgxMDk=" role="article"><h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/9/16/23356667/hollow-knight-silksong-playstation-ps5-ps4-still-no-release-date">Hollow Knight: Silksong is coming to PlayStation, too</a></h2><div><p><em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em>, the long-awaited sequel to the indie action-platformer <em>Hollow Knight</em>, will be coming to PS5 and PS4, according to a Friday tweet from <a href="https://twitter.com/PlayStation/status/1570797280063627264">the official PlayStation Twitter account</a>.</p><p>We already knew the game was coming to Nintendo Switch, Xbox, and PC, so it’s good to hear that it will be available on PlayStation, too. But for those of us who have been desperate news about a concrete release date (like me), we still don’t know that; PlayStation only confirmed that the game would be coming to its consoles, not when.</p><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/9/16/23356667/hollow-knight-silksong-playstation-ps5-ps4-still-no-release-date">Read Article &gt;</a></p></div></li><li id="dmcyOnBvc3Q6OTYzNDA=" role="article"><h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/6/12/22175400/hollow-knight-silksong-sequel-xbox-game-pass-trailer">Hollow Knight: Silksong is coming to Xbox, and it will be out within the next year</a></h2><div><p><em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em>, the sequel to the 2017 indie side-scrolling action platformer <em>Hollow Knight</em>, is coming to Xbox, Microsoft announced during the Xbox and Bethesda Showcase on Sunday. It will be available on Xbox Game Pass the day it’s released.</p><p>While there’s no official release date, Xbox exec Sarah Bond said during the showcase that all of the games shown during the event will be available in the next 12 months. The official Xbox Twitter account <a href="https://twitter.com/Xbox/status/1536035818275487746">confirmed that timeline</a>, so we at least have a window of time for when we can expect the game.</p><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/6/12/22175400/hollow-knight-silksong-sequel-xbox-game-pass-trailer">Read Article &gt;</a></p></div></li></ul></section></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/769489/hollow-knight-silksong-news-updates]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft gave Perfect Dark’s developers a chance to save the game — after it was already canceled]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/769372/microsoft-perfect-dark-revival-take-two-deal</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-gave-perfect-dark%E2%80%99s-developers-a-chance-to-save-the-game-%E2%80%94-after-it-was-already-canceled.1286850/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MzQz"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Sean Hollister</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a senior editor and founding member of The Verge who covers gadgets, games, and toys. He spent 15 years editing the likes of CNET, Gizmodo, and Engadget.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><div><p>In July, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/697125/microsoft-xbox-layoffs-2025">Microsoft’s sweeping layoffs hit Xbox hard</a>, and shuttered the entire game studio that was building <em>Perfect Dark</em>. Officially, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/696877/xbox-perfect-dark-everwild-cancelled-the-initiative-layoffs">the game was canceled</a>. But unofficially, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-09-02/-perfect-dark-developer-lays-off-staff-after-funding-deal-falls-through">reports <em>Bloomberg</em>’s Jason Schreier</a>, Microsoft gave <em>Perfect Dark</em>’s other set of developers — <em>Tomb Raider</em> studio Crystal Dynamics<em> — </em>a chance to revive the game.</p></div><p>Here’s where it gets potentially confusing: Microsoft doesn’t own Crystal Dynamics — that studio belongs to the Embracer Group, which <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/630234/embracer-group-aftermath-saber-matt-karch-stephen-totilo">has had</a> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/23/24163110/embracer-laid-off-more-employees-than-riot-games-entire-workforce">many</a> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/3/28/24114402/embracer-selling-gearbox-borderlands-developer-take-two">troubles</a> of its own. So Embracer was trying to cut a deal with <em>yet another</em> publisher, the giant Take-Two, to buy, fund, and publish the game. But, Schreier reports:</p><div><blockquote><p>the talks collapsed at least in part because the companies involved were unable to come to terms over long-term ownership of the <em>Perfect Dark</em> franchise, said the people, who requested anonymity because they were not authorized to speak about sensitive negotiations.</p></blockquote></div><p>When that deal fell through, it reportedly led to the new round of layoffs at Crystal Dynamics <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/crystal-dynamics-lays-off-more-following-perfect-dark-cancelation">that <em>IGN</em> reported last week</a>, and Schreier writes that Crystal Dynamics has now “fully” abandoned the game.</p><p>Seems Microsoft didn’t want to give up the rights to <em>Perfect Dark</em>, which it presumably obtained when it bought Rare in 2002. (For the uninitiated, <em>Perfect Dark</em> was a spiritual successor to Rare’s hit <em>Goldeneye 007</em> on the Nintendo 64, a game that itself went many decades without a revival because of <a href="https://licensinginternational.org/news/mgm-and-eon-productions-partner-with-nintendo-and-microsoft-to-bring-iconic-goldeneye-007-video-game-to-a-new-generation-of-gamers/">a complicated licensing situation</a>.) That feels like a crummy reason for the game to stay canceled, but we don’t know the details.</p><div><p>Microsoft <em>was</em> able to broker a previous deal to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/12/24218424/hifi-rush-studio-tango-gameworks-saved-krafton-microsoft">save <em>Hi-Fi Rush </em>developer Tango Gameworks by selling it to <em>PUBG</em> giant Krafton</a>, but it was under a lot of pressure there. <em>Hi-Fi Rush</em> had already been released, had <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/8/24152137/xbox-hi-fi-rush-tango-gameworks-matt-booty">become a “break out hit” that won “prestige and awards”</a>, and gamers were pissed that Microsoft had rewarded its developers with layoffs.</p></div><p><span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/769372/microsoft-perfect-dark-revival-take-two-deal#comments">6<!-- --> <!-- -->Comments</a></span></p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MzQz"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Sean Hollister</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><div><form><div><h2>The Verge Daily</h2><p><span>A free daily digest of the news that matters most.</span></p></div></form></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/769372/microsoft-perfect-dark-revival-take-two-deal]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>