<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 14:52:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Playstation is holding its State of Play summer showcase this week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/669527/playstation-state-of-play-summer-2025-ps5</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-is-holding-its-state-of-play-summer-showcase-this-week.1205595/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/669527/playstation-state-of-play-summer-2025-ps5<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/ash-parrish">Ash Parrish</a> <span>is a reporter who covers the business, culture, and communities of video games, with a focus on marginalized gamers and the quirky, horny culture of video game communities.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Sony has announced it will hold a <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/06/03/state-of-play-returns-june-4/">summer State of Play presentation</a> on Wednesday, June 4th, making this first week of June an all-timer for the video game industry. Not only do we have the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/nintendo/674887/nintendo-new-era-switch-2-next-gen">Switch 2 launching this week</a>, but all the video game showcases are dropping at once, because while E3 is a thing of the past, we still need an excuse to party.</p><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/675716/summer-game-fest-might-have-a-lot-of-games">Summer Game Fest</a>, affectionately (or not) known as Keigh-3, kicks off Friday, June 6th. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/645779/xboxs-next-major-games-showcase-streams-in-june">Xbox</a> will host its showcase on Sunday, June 8th. Epic has its State of Unreal <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/677653/epic-games-unreal-fest-2025-orlando-news-announcements">going on right now</a>. And now PlayStation will join the slate of summer programming with its own showcase on <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/playstation">Twitch</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/PlayStation">YouTube</a> starting at 5PM ET / 2PM PT.</p><p>According to the announcement, we can expect a 40-minute livestream featuring updates on forthcoming PlayStation 5 titles and possibly a few surprises. The biggest game that seems possibly set to make an appearance is <em>Death Stranding 2: On The Beach </em>from Metal Gear Solid maestro Hideo Kojima. Sucker Punch’s <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/654227/ghost-of-yotei-ps5-release-date-trailer">Ghosts of Yotei</a></em> will also likely get a brief update, whetting the appetite of those waiting on its October 2nd release date.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>