<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 11:53:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia invests $5 billion into Intel to jointly develop PC and data center chips]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/780792/nvidia-intel-investment-pc-chips-data-center</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nvidia-invests-5-billion-into-intel-to-jointly-develop-pc-and-data-center-chips.1301256/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTY0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Tom Warren</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a senior editor and author of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/notepad-microsoft-newsletter"><i>Notepad</i></a>, who has been covering all things Microsoft, PC, and tech for over 20 years.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Nvidia is throwing Intel a $5 billion life raft, just weeks after similar stakes from the US government and SoftBank. <a href="https://nvidianews.nvidia.com/news/nvidia-and-intel-to-develop-ai-infrastructure-and-personal-computing-products">Nvidia is investing</a> $5 billion in Intel common stock in a collaboration that will see the pair “jointly develop multiple generations of custom data center and PC products.”</p><p>Nvidia says Intel will help build “x86 system-on-chips (SoCs) that integrate Nvidia RTX GPU chiplets.” These chips will power a “wide range” of PCs, by closely integrating Intel’s CPUs with Nvidia’s GPUs. Intel and Nvidia already have a close partnership on many gaming laptops, but combining both on a single SoC is a big step further.</p><div><p>It will help Intel and Nvidia better compete with AMD, which has been gaining ground on Intel with its <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/6/24288948/amd-ryzen-7-9800x3d-review-cpu-processor-benchmark-test?showComments=1">impressive gaming desktop CPUs</a> and a wide variety of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/2/24168951/amd-ryzen-ai-9-300-series-hx-laptop-processors">AI laptop processors</a>. It also raises further questions about the future of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24337345/intel-discrete-gpu-ces-2025">Intel’s Arc graphics card business</a>, especially if the company is now relying on Nvidia’s GPU expertise.</p></div><p>Nvidia and Intel will also work together on connecting both their architectures via Nvidia’s NVLink communications link system that’s used in data centers to link GPUs together. “Intel will build Nvidia-custom x86 CPUs that Nvidia will integrate into its AI infrastructure platforms and offer to the market,” says Nvidia.</p><p>“This collaboration tightly couples Nvidia’s AI and accelerated computing stack with Intel’s CPUs and the vast x86 ecosystem — a fusion of two world-class platforms,” says Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang. “Together, we will expand our ecosystems and lay the foundation for the next era of computing.”</p><p>The US government agreed to take an around <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/764480/intel-donald-trump-lip-bu-tan-deal">10 percent stake in Intel last month</a>, valued at $8.9 billion. SoftBank is also investing $2 billion into Intel, as the struggling chipmaker has been pulling back on spending and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/713388/intel-q2-2025-leave-germany-poland-costa-rica">laying off thousands</a> of workers.</p><p>Intel’s stock price jumped 28 percent in pre-market trading after Nvidia’s announcement.</p><p><span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/780792/nvidia-intel-investment-pc-chips-data-center#comments"><span>0<!-- --> <!-- -->Comments</span></a></span></p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTY0"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Tom Warren</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/780792/nvidia-intel-investment-pc-chips-data-center]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>