<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 07:21:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vergil is out for blood in the latest trailer for Netflix’s Devil May Cry series]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/trailers/627307/devil-may-cry-netflix-vergil</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/vergil-is-out-for-blood-in-the-latest-trailer-for-netflix%E2%80%99s-devil-may-cry-series.1131846/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/trailers/627307/devil-may-cry-netflix-vergil<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/charles-pulliam-moore">Charles Pulliam-Moore</a> <span>is a reporter focusing on film, TV, and pop culture. Before The Verge, he wrote about comic books, labor, race, and more at io9 and Gizmodo for almost five years.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><div><p>Ahead of the debut of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/19/24249440/devil-may-cry-show-netflix-date-trailer">its new <em>Devil May Cry </em>adaptation</a> next month, Netflix has released <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OlEqHXRrcpc&amp;ab_channel=Netflix">yet another trailer</a> to get you acquainted with some of the characters who will be gunning for Dante.</p></div><p>In the new trailer it appears there are two different armies dead set on destroying demon hunter Dante (Johnny Yong Bosch) because of his connections to the supernatural world. Dante already has his hands full with the demon White Rabbit (Hoon Lee) and his goons threatening to raze an entire city if their demands aren’t met.</p><p>But to make matters even more complicated, human soldiers like Lady (Scout Taylor-Compton) see Dante as a threat due to the demon blood running through his veins. </p><p>Despite Dante’s insistence that he isn’t a monster, all of the high-flying, Studio Mir-produced acrobatics he pulls off definitely make it seem like he’s got some demonic heritage in the mix. And the look on Dante’s face when his twin brother Vergil (Robbie Daymond) shows up makes it pretty clear that he’s hiding something rather explosive about himself. The trailer makes clear that Netflix’s <em>Devil May Cry </em>is going to be feature elements from the franchise’s games like <em>Dante’s Awakening </em>as well as its official manga (where White Rabbit made his first appearance.) And hopefully, that means the series will feel like more than a one-to-one adaptation when it debuts on April 3rd.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>