<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 18:29:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon studio’s action RPG Beast of Reincarnation launches in 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/682371/beast-of-reincarnation-game-freak-xbox-games-showcase-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-studio%E2%80%99s-action-rpg-beast-of-reincarnation-launches-in-2026.1212243/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/682371/beast-of-reincarnation-game-freak-xbox-games-showcase-trailer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/jay-peters">Jay Peters</a> <span>is a news editor covering technology, gaming, and more. He joined The Verge in 2019 after nearly two years at Techmeme.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Game Freak, perhaps best known for its work on the <em>Pokémon</em> franchise, is working on a new action RPG called <em>Beast of Reincarnation</em> that will launch sometime in 2026. It’s coming to PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X / S.</p><p>In the game, you play as Emma, who will be accompanied by a canine friend. “Survive a journey across an ominous, ever-changing world where dangerous forests can erupt in the wasteland,” according to the description from <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=L-qZiMPsNz0">a new trailer</a> shown at the Xbox Games Showcase 2025. “As Emma and Koo push deeper into the unknown, their bond strengthens—and with it, strange powers bloom.”</p><p>The description also says the RPG is built around “demanding, technical combat,” and based on the trailer, that sure appears to be the case — it looks thrilling.</p><p><em>Beast of Reincarnation</em> was originally announced <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23716737/game-freak-developer-project-bloom-game">as <em>Project Bloom</em></a>, according to an emailed press release. The game was previously set to be published by Take-Two’s Private Division label, but Take-Two sold that label <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/6/24289932/take-two-private-division-publisher-sale">last year</a>. <em>Beast of Reincarnation</em> is now being published by Fictions.</p><p><em>Update, June 8th: Added what platforms the game will be available on and confirmation that the game is what was once known as </em>Project Bloom<em>.</em></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>