<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 07:54:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Netflix’s cloud plans include co-op and party games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/23/24350690/netflix-cloud-gaming-plans-co-op-party-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/netflix%E2%80%99s-cloud-plans-include-co-op-and-party-games.1090764/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/23/24350690/netflix-cloud-gaming-plans-co-op-party-games<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Netflix plans to offer couch co-op and party games that it will stream over the cloud to TVs, co-CEO Greg Peters said as part of the company’s Q4 2024 earnings announcements this week. The company has offered cloud gaming as a beta to a “subset” of subscribers <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/10/16/23919517/netflix-game-streaming-beta-tvs-us">since 2023</a>, so this news from Peters indicates that the company is going to continue to invest in it.</p><p>Peters didn’t say exactly when the co-op and party games might be available. But he did say that “we think of this as a successor to family board game night or an evolution of what the game show on TV used to be.”</p><p>Netflix will also continue to focus on “more narrative games based on Netflix IP” — Peters says those games are “consistent fan favorites and we’ve got a lot in the library to work with there.”</p><div><h3>Related</h3><ul><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24171526/netflix-games-too-hot-too-handle-interactive-fiction">The future of Netflix games could look like reality TV</a></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/10/16/23919517/netflix-game-streaming-beta-tvs-us">Netflix tests streaming games to US TVs to take on PlayStation and Xbox</a></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gamers are already using Nvidia’s DLSS 4 tech in Cyberpunk 2077]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/23/24350558/nvidia-dlss-4-frame-generation-cyberpunk-2077-transformer-graphics-update-patch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gamers-are-already-using-nvidia%E2%80%99s-dlss-4-tech-in-cyberpunk-2077.1090698/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/23/24350558/nvidia-dlss-4-frame-generation-cyberpunk-2077-transformer-graphics-update-patch<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><article id="content"><div><div><h2>Gamers are already using Nvidia’s DLSS 4 tech in Cyberpunk 2077</h2><p><span><span> / </span><h2>CD Projekt Red’s patch 2.21 makes Cyberpunk the first DLSS 4-compatible game.</h2></span></p></div><div><p><span>By</span> <span><span></span> <span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/antonio-g-di-benedetto">Antonio G. Di Benedetto</a></span><span>, <span>a reviewer covering laptops and the occasional gadget. He spent over 15 years in the photography industry before joining The Verge as a deals writer in 2021.</span></span></span></p><p><time datetime="2025-01-23T22:41:13.654Z"> <!-- -->Jan 23, 2025, 10:41 PM UTC</time></p><div><h2>Share this story</h2></div><p>If you buy something from a Verge link, Vox Media may earn a commission.<!-- --> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/ethics-statement">See our ethics statement.</a></p></div></div><div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>You may have to wait until January 30th to buy Nvidia’s new RTX 5090 graphics card, but owners of last-gen Nvidia 40-series GPUs can already download and install <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24337402/nvidia-dlss-4-upscaling-announcement-ces-2025">DLSS 4 Multi Frame Generation</a> software via the Nvidia app. And if you want a compatible, graphically-intense game to test DLSS 4 out, <em>Cyberpunk 2077</em>’s newly-launched <a href="https://www.cyberpunk.net/en/news/51296/patch-2-21">patch 2.21</a> adds support for it.</p><p>Here’s the important info from CD Projekt Red’s changelog for patch 2.21 about DLSS 4:</p><div><blockquote><p>Added support for DLSS 4 with Multi Frame Generation for GeForce RTX 50 Series graphics cards, which boosts FPS by using AI to generate up to three times per traditionally rendered frame – enabled with GeForce RTX 50 Series on January 30th. DLSS 4 also introduces faster single Frame Generation with reduced memory usage for RTX 50 and 40 Series. Additionally, you can now choose between the CNN model or the new Transformer model for DLSS Ray Reconstruction, DLSS Super Resolution, and DLAA on all GeForce RTX graphics cards today. The new Transformer model enhances stability, lighting, and detail in motion.</p></blockquote></div><p>People on the <em>Cyberpunk 2077</em> subreddit are already trying out DLSS 4’s improved single Frame Generation on their 40-series cards and <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/nvidia/comments/1i811by/cyberpunk_2077_patch_221/">sharing their results</a>. One user <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/nvidia/comments/1i811by/comment/m8pgk39/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">posted a variety of screenshots</a> with comparison sliders that show a side-by-side between the older <a href="https://developer.nvidia.com/discover/convolutional-neural-network">Convolutional Neural Network</a> (CNN) model and the new <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nvidia.com%2Fen-us%2Fgeforce%2Fnews%2Fdlss4-multi-frame-generation-ai-innovations%2F%23%3A~%3Atext%3DThe%2520New%2520Transformer%2520Model%2520%252D%2520Image%2520Quality%2520Improvements%2520For%2520All%2520GeForce%2520RTX%2520Gamers">Transformer model</a> in DLSS 4 with full path tracing on their RTX 4070 Super at QHD resolution. It may not be night-and-day differences when frozen in screenshots, but looking closely reveals improvements like better clothing textures and cleaned up facial details, all without taking any significant hit to framerates.</p><p>The real star of the DLSS 4 show may be incredibly high framerates via Multi Frame Generation on the new 50-series cards, but getting graphical improvements for free on older cards is an impressive flex of Nvidia’s new tech. It’s not every day you can download better performance.</p><p>But just as 50-series early adopters will have to wait for more developers to implement Multi Frame Generation beyond the approximate 75 titles at launch, 40-series users may also have to be patient to see more DLSS 4-compatible updates.</p></div><div><p>Most Popular</p><p>Most Popular</p><ol><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/22/24349499/nfl-patriots-bluesky-accounts-not-allowed-x-meta-threads"><h2>NFL teams can’t use Bluesky</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/23/24340743/star-trek-section-31-review-paramount-plus"><h2>Star Trek: Section 31 is firing on all cylinders</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/22/24349416/google-gemini-virtual-assistant-samsung-siri-alexa"><h2>Google’s Gemini is already winning the next-gen assistant wars</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/23/24349619/nvidia-rtx-5090-review-test-benchmark"><h2>Nvidia GeForce RTX 5090 review: a new king of 4K is here</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/22/24349329/youtube-premium-test-multiple-new-experimental-features"><h2>YouTube Premium gets more experimental features that can now be tested all at once</h2></a><hr></li></ol></div></div></article></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>