<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 08:55:30 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Confirmed: Nintendo’s Switch 2 can work with existing docks and webcams after replacing their firmware]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/nintendo/701381/confirmed-nintendos-switch-2-can-work-with-existing-docks-and-webcams-after-replacing-their-firmware</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/confirmed-nintendo%E2%80%99s-switch-2-can-work-with-existing-docks-and-webcams-after-replacing-their-firmware.1238862/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Over the last two weeks, I’ve sought to uncover why the Nintendo Switch 2 didn’t work with a host of USB-C accessories that worked perfectly fine with other devices, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/report/695915/switch-2-usb-c-third-party-docks-dont-work-authentication-encryption">including third-party docks</a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/report/693182/nintendo-switch-2-webcam-mystery-1080p-480p-uvc-iso-bulk-ugreen-elgato">some of the best-reviewed webcams</a>. But today, I have first-hand confirmation that existing gadgets <em>can</em> work — as long as their manufacturers issue the right firmware updates, and as long as Nintendo doesn’t break compatibility from here on out.</p><p>You shouldn’t necessarily need to buy a brand-new gadget to plug a TV or video glasses into your Nintendo Switch 2. Three manufacturers have already proven that firmware updates are enough for now, and hopefully more will follow!</p><p>The existing gadgets I just successfully tested are: the <strong>AverMedia Elite Go GC313 Pro</strong> and <strong>AverMedia Core Go GC313</strong> compact charger docks, the <strong>Elgato Facecam MK.2 </strong>webcam, and the <strong>Viture Pro Mobile Dock</strong> for the company’s AR glasses.</p><p>None of them worked with the Nintendo Switch 2 at launch, but each now has firmware updates available, and I was able to get them all working in my own home — and maybe, set a few more things straight about Switch 2 compatibility.</p><div><p id="elgato"><h2>Elgato</h2></p></div><p><strong>The story:</strong> Elgato was one of the very first companies to promise it would update some non-working webcams to work with the Switch 2, and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/report/693182/nintendo-switch-2-webcam-mystery-1080p-480p-uvc-iso-bulk-ugreen-elgato">provided its own theories to <em>The Verge</em></a> on why they didn’t work on day one. The company won’t formally release its firmware updates for the Facecam MK2 and Facecam Neo till the end of July, but it sent us an early copy so I could show you video proof!</p><p>Here, follow along with me as I install and test it for the very first time:</p><p>(Sorry, I’m not allowed to share the early firmware update files.)</p><p><strong>What we learned: </strong>Elgato originally claimed the primary reason its cameras didn’t work was that the Nintendo Switch 2 requires cameras to advertise a low-resolution 480p video mode, even if that’s not the mode the Switch 2 winds up using. Sure enough: <a href="https://answers.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/forum/all/how-to-use-and-install-usbview/e66494f9-05ce-439e-bcbe-c074b36d4272">the USBView tool</a> shows me that the Facecam MK2 now makes 480p the default video streaming mode that a USB host device (like the Switch 2) will see before anything else.</p><p>Also: Remember when Ugreen told us that cameras wouldn’t work with Switch 2 if they used the HID (human interface device) protocol? Weirdly, it seems Elgato actually <em>added</em> some HID references in its latest firmware. <a href="https://www.diffchecker.com/S0k5VI8i/">Here’s the diff</a> if you want to peek.</p><div><p id="avermedia"><h2>AverMedia</h2></p></div><div><p><cite>Photo by Sean Hollister / The Verge</cite></p></div><p><strong>The story:</strong> I’d never even heard of these 100W GaN compact charging docks, the $130 GC313 Pro and the $90 GC313 — but it now appears they’re the first and only portable docks for the Switch 2! (The Pro also doubles as a 1080p60 USB capture card, if you’re wondering about the price delta.) The company has <a href="https://www.avermedia.com/NS2-compatibility-status">a whole page dedicated to Switch 2 compatibility firmware updates</a>, mostly for its video capture devices, but also these portable docks, as well as <a href="https://www.amazon.com/AVerMedia-Charging-Screen-Mirroring-Capture/dp/B0DBSND34P?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">a more traditional standing dock</a> if you don’t mind plugging your Switch in upside-down.</p><p><strong>What we learned</strong>: The firmware update was quick to install and the HDMI connection totally works — probably because AverMedia’s dock is now using the exact same proprietary commands that we see Nintendo’s official dock using. (<a href="https://www.theverge.com/report/695915/switch-2-usb-c-third-party-docks-dont-work-authentication-encryption">Once again</a>, I pulled out a USB-C PD analyzer to check. Before the update, AverMedia’s dock didn’t speak Nintendo’s language and was quickly rejected; after the update, it did.)</p><p>AverMedia’s dock didn’t work quite as reliably as the official dock in my early tests. It doesn’t always connect the first time I plug it in, and there’s also a short delay. Also note: the GC313 only seems to support vanilla 4K60 output with no HDR or VRR.</p><p>As you’ll read below, video glasses maker Viture has a firmware update that makes its gadgets compatible with Switch 2 — but <em>takes away</em> compatibility with the original Nintendo Switch. But I tested the AverMedia dock working with <em>both</em> generations of Switch, and Viture says it’ll do the same in future.</p><div><p id="viture"><h2>Viture</h2></p></div><p><strong>The story</strong>: This $130 dock is a battery pack that can power your handheld or phone, while routing its video to Viture’s USB-C video glasses or a USB-C monitor. (The HDMI port is for input, not output to a TV.) <a href="https://academy.viture.com/mobile_dock/update">With a firmware update</a>, it gains support for Switch 2, but breaks support for the original Switch unless you downgrade afterwards. A future update will support both, though, Viture co-founder Emily Wang tells <em>The Verge</em>.</p><p><strong>What we learned</strong>: Viture shipped me its dock pre-updated, so I didn’t test before-and-after. But with the update, it totally works — after a bit of a delay, which seems to stem from some miscommunication between Viture’s gadgets and the Switch 2, if I’m reading the USB-C PD traffic right. But after that miscommunication, I can see the Viture dock sends the exact same proprietary commands as Nintendo’s official dock.</p><p>One of the things we’d heard early on is that Switch 2 docking stations need to offer 20 volts of power for the Switch 2 to kick into TV mode — even though the handheld only actually uses 15 volts. But the Viture dock only advertises a maximum of 15 volts at 1.34 amps (20 watts in total), and yet Viture got video output working anyhow.</p><div><p id="what-happens-next"><h2>What happens next?</h2></p></div><p>We know these third-party docks are working with the Switch 2 as of today, and we expect more are on the way.</p><p>(One I didn’t get to test is <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/switch2/comments/1lrs7mh/hagibis_switch_2_dock_hdmi_cable_for_only_20/">this Hagabis</a>, which fits the entire HDMI adapter into a cable instead of a dock — beware that <a href="https://hagibis.bbscloud.com/info/38597196f50d47b0a523a002dd8590ba?csr=1">the firmware update</a> only official works with the 8K version <strong>which is black</strong>, <em>not white or red and blue </em>and keeps going out of stock.)</p><p>But we don’t know if Nintendo will move to block these accessories with firmware updates of its own. Today, it appears that each of these docks can fool the Switch 2 into thinking they’re the official dock by emulating its commands, but several manufacturers admit that could lead to a game of cat-and-mouse where they have to issue new firmware updates to keep up with Nintendo.</p><p>“Similar to what Antank shared with you, it’s true that we may need to provide firmware updates if Nintendo changes its protocol specifications,” Viture tells<em> The Verge. </em></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/nintendo/701381/confirmed-nintendos-switch-2-can-work-with-existing-docks-and-webcams-after-replacing-their-firmware]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The best Prime Day deals on games, hardware, and accessories]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/tech/698696/amazon-prime-day-best-gaming-deals-controllers-headsets-accessories-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-best-prime-day-deals-on-games-hardware-and-accessories.1238838/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><div><p><span><ul><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/tech">Tech</a></li></ul></span></p></div><div><p>You can currently save on games, controllers, headsets, hard drives, laptops, and more.</p></div></div><div><p>You can currently save on games, controllers, headsets, hard drives, laptops, and more.</p><div><p><span><time datetime="2025-07-08T22:00:00+00:00">Jul 8, 2025, 10:00 PM UTC</time></span></p></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/brandt-ranj">Brandt Ranj</a> <span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/brandt-ranj">Brandt Ranj</a> is a commerce reporter for <em>The Verge </em>writing about the best deals and gadgets. He previously wrote for <em>Business Insider, Rolling Stone, </em><em>Futurism, </em>and <em>Popular Science.</em></span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/tech/696641/amazon-prime-day-best-tech-deals-2025">Amazon Prime Day</a> is the perfect time to score incredible deals on games to fill your backlog, as well as essential accessories like controllers, headsets, and storage expansion for your next-gen console. Combing through thousands of deals to find the ones actually worth your time is tedious, though, which is why we’ve done the heavy lifting and collected the best ones here.</p><p>A ton of great games are on sale, including <em>Star Wars Outlaws</em>, which is currently on sale for $41 off at Amazon for both the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Star-Wars-Outlaws-Limited-Exclusive-PlayStation/dp/B0D187PJHJ?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">Xbox Series X / S</a> and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Star-Wars-Outlaws-Limited-Exclusive-PlayStation/dp/B0D187PJHJ?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">PlayStation 5</a>. Nintendo hardly ever discounts its first-party games, so we’re pleased to see <em>Splatoon 3</em> going for $39.99 ($20 off) at <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/482924/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fsplatoon-3-nintendo-switch-oled-model-nintendo-switch-nintendo-switch-lite-digital%2F6499368.p%3FskuId%3D6499368&amp;subId2=[vg0707awD][696641][][][][][][][][][]" rel="sponsored">Best Buy</a> and <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSplatoon-3-Nintendo-Switch-Physical-U-S-Version%2F578169735&amp;subId2=[vg0707awD][696641][][][][][][][][][]" rel="sponsored">Walmart</a>. You can also pick up <em>Pikmin 4</em> — an underrated gem of the last console generation — for $39.99 ($20 off) at <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/482924/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fpikmin-4-nintendo-switch-oled-model-nintendo-switch-nintendo-switch-lite%2F6535552.p%3FskuId%3D6535552&amp;subId2=[vg0707awD][696641][][][][][][][][][]" rel="sponsored">Best Buy.</a></p><p>Hardware discounts are exceedingly rare these days, but if you’re looking to upgrade from a previous-gen console or have been tempted by a gaming PC handheld, your patience has been rewarded. The Asus ROG Ally is $200 off at <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/482924/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Frog-ally-7-120hz-fhd-1080p-gaming-handheld-amd-ryzen-z1-extreme-processor-512gb-windows%2F6542964.p%3FskuId%3D6542964&amp;subId2=[vg0707awD][696641][][][][][][][][][]" rel="sponsored">Best Buy</a> with a Ryzen Z1 Extreme processor and 512GB of storage. If you’re curious about virtual reality headsets, don’t skip the $50 discount on the Meta Quest 3S at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DDK1WM9K?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">Amazon</a>.</p><div><nav><h2>In this article</h2><ul><li><a href="#best-video-game-deals">Best video game deals</a></li><li><a href="#best-gaming-hardware-deals">Best gaming hardware deals</a></li><li><a href="#best-gaming-laptop-deals">Best gaming laptop deals</a></li><li><a href="#best-controller-deals">Best controller deals</a></li><li><a href="#best-headset-deals">Best headset deals</a></li><li><a href="#best-storage-deals">Best storage deals</a></li><li><a href="#best-board-game-deals">Best board game deals</a></li><li><a href="#other-miscellaneous-gaming-deals">Other miscellaneous gaming deals </a></li></ul></nav></div><div><p id="best-video-game-deals"><h2>Best video game deals</h2></p></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->28</span></p><div><p><em>Star Wars Outlaws</em> is an original open-world adventure set in the vast universe of the iconic film series. It stars Kay Vess, a protagonist looking to steal from criminal overlords to gain her freedom. A <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/21/24302318/star-wars-outlaws-lando-dlc-steam-launch-stealth-update">new expansion featuring Lando Calrissian</a> recently launched, alongside an update that improves stealth and some of the game’s most glaring issues. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24230628/star-wars-outlaws-review-ps5-xbox-pc">Read our review</a>.</p></div></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->45</span></p><div><p>Princess Zelda’s first solo adventure as a playable character tasks her with saving her people, including Link, who have been taken away through mysterious rifts. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24253919/the-legend-of-zelda-echoes-of-wisdom-review-nintendo-switch">Read our review</a>.</p></div></div><div><ul><li><span>Ubisoft’s latest <em>Assassin’s Creed</em> game, <em><strong>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</strong></em>, has been given a small but welcome price cut. Thanks to Prime Day, you can pick up the open-world game set in feudal Japan for either the Xbox Series X or PS5 for $47.49 (originally $69.99) at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D47WTKPM?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">Amazon</a>. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/637717/assassins-creed-shadows-stealth-assassinations">Read our review</a>.</span></li><li><span>If you want to know why <em>Armored Core</em> fans were overjoyed in 2023, it’s because that’s when <em><strong>Armored Core VI: Fires of Rubicon</strong></em> launched. The fast, relentlessly challenging third-person action game is a treat for the senses (and a punishment to your reflexes), and the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BX4KZ5PJ?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">PS5</a> / <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BX4GQZLB/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">Xbox</a> versions are down to just $19.99 (about $10 off) at Amazon for Prime Day. This matches the game’s previous low, but it remains a fantastic deal if you missed out last time.</span></li><li><span>Bloober Team knocked it out of the park with its remake of <em><strong>Silent Hill 2</strong></em> on the PS5. Thankfully, if you scoffed at its original $69.99 price tag, you can currently pick it up for $39.99 ($30 off) at <a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CMC3C3Z9?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">Amazon</a> and <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/482924/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fsilent-hill-2-playstation-5%2F6567007.p%3FskuId%3D6567007" rel="sponsored">Best Buy</a>. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/26/24279276/survival-horror-silent-hill-2-fear-the-spotlight">Read our review</a>.</span></li></ul></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->38</span></p><div><p><em>Alan Wake 2 </em>is the culmination of everything Remedy Entertainment has been building toward. The inventive third-person survival game is both horrifying and strange, with dual campaigns that are more than a little meta. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23934662/alan-wake-2-review-ps5-xbox-pc">Read our original review</a>.</p></div></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->35</span></p><div><p><em>Split Fiction </em>is an excellent, cooperative sci-fi game in which two players must traverse completely different worlds simultaneously, while relying on new powers to help them progress through each stage. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games-review/623660/split-fiction-review-hazelight-studios-it-takes-two">Read our review</a>.</p></div></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->25</span></p><div><p>The latest mainline <em>Final Fantasy</em> game is a bombastic rollercoaster of an RPG infused with a dose of <em>Game of Thrones</em> medieval intrigue and gritty violence. It’s also quite the cinematic spectacle of the PS5’s graphical prowess. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23767669/final-fantasy-xvi-review-ps5">Read our review.</a></p></div></div><div><ul><li><span>There are few games out there with more heart and soul (and pure silliness) than <em><strong>Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii</strong></em>. The latest game in the long-running <em>Yakuza</em>-turned-<em>Like a Dragon</em> franchise is on sale for the PS5 for $39.99 ($20 off) at <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/482924/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Flike-a-dragon-pirate-yakuza-in-hawaii-standard-edition-playstation-5%2F6602641.p%3FskuId%3D6602641" rel="sponsored">Best Buy</a> and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Like-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-Standard-PlayStation/dp/B0DHLPSVJT/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">Amazon</a>.</span></li><li><span>One of the best-looking Switch 2 games is <strong><em>Splatoon 3</em></strong>, which recently got an update that makes the game run better on the new console. If you’ve always wanted to give this one a try, pick up a digital or physical copy at <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/482924/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fsplatoon-3-nintendo-switch-oled-model-nintendo-switch-nintendo-switch-lite-digital%2F6499368.p%3FskuId%3D6499368&amp;subId2=[vg0707awD][696641][][][][][][][][][]" rel="noreferrer noopener sponsored" target="_blank">Best Buy</a> for $39.99 or <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSplatoon-3-Nintendo-Switch-Physical-U-S-Version%2F578169735&amp;subId2=[vg0707awD][696641][][][][][][][][][]" rel="noreferrer noopener sponsored" target="_blank">Walmart</a> for $49.50 (typically $59.99). <a href="https://www.theverge.com/nintendo/686128/splatoon-3-switch-2-update-overview">Read about the Switch 2 update</a>.</span></li><li><span>Not enough people are still talking about <em><strong>Pikmin 4</strong></em>, the latest entry in Nintendo’s chill (yet often chaotic) exploration game. You navigate through environments, collect and command Pikmin with different elemental abilities and weaknesses, and try to save fellow space cadets from strange happenings. All the while, you’re trying to find Captain Olimar, the protagonist of the original <em>Pikmin</em> game. It matches its lowest price of $39.99 on digital or physical at <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/482924/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fpikmin-4-nintendo-switch-oled-model-nintendo-switch-nintendo-switch-lite%2F6535552.p%3FskuId%3D6535552&amp;subId2=[vg0707awD][696641][][][][][][][][][]" rel="noreferrer noopener sponsored" target="_blank">Best Buy</a>. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23799072/pikmin-4-review-nintendo-switch">Read our review</a>.</span></li><li><span><em><strong>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II</strong></em> is a cinematic, open-world JRPG that takes place in 15th-century Bohemia. You traverse the world as part of a revenge story to avenge your murdered parents, crossing paths with peasants, kings, and everyone in between while learning how to be a blacksmith and hunt to help you survive. Right now, you can pick it up at Amazon for either the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0D2FGZ3HF/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">PS5</a> or <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0D2DW9FJK/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">Xbox</a> for $39.99 ($30 off) — its lowest price to date.</span></li></ul></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->15</span></p><div><p>The newest <em>Dragon Age </em>title is a narrative masterstroke, where every decision you can make feels like it can impact the rest of your adventure. The biggest problem may be determining which path to take. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24307786/dragon-age-the-veilguard-full-review">Read our review</a>.</p></div></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->40</span></p><div><p>The middle game in a three-part trilogy, <em>Final Fantasy VII Rebirth</em> continues the reimagining of the classic PS1 RPG with modern visuals, an expansive open world, new gameplay elements, and even better character development than the original. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24079544/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-review-ps5">Read our review</a>.</p></div></div><div><p id="best-gaming-hardware-deals"><h2>Best gaming hardware deals</h2></p></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->249</span></p><div><p>If you bought a Meta Quest 2, you’re a prime candidate for the Quest 3S. It’s a faster, more comfortable VR headset that runs the same chipset as the pricier Quest 3. While its screen resolution hasn’t improved, nearly everything else about the hardware has. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24340948/meta-quest-3s-vr-headset-review">Read our review</a>.</p></div></div><div><ul><li><span>If you read <a href="https://www.theverge.com/reviews/617613/lenovo-legion-go-s-review-feels-good-plays-bad">our review</a> of the Windows-flavored <strong>Lenovo Legion Go S</strong>, we made it clear that its high $729.99 price was one of its biggest flaws. It has other issues, such as the current state of gaming on a Windows handheld and its underpowered Ryzen Z2 Go processor, but the 32GB RAM / 1TB storage model is worth considering at its discounted price of $499.99 ($230 off) at <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/482924/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Flegion-go-s-8-120hz-gaming-handheld-amd-ryzen-z2-go-windowsos-32-gb-with-1-tb-ssd-windows%2F6612958.p%3F" rel="sponsored">Best Buy</a>. That’s a huge discount.</span></li></ul></div><div><p id="best-gaming-laptop-deals"><h2>Best gaming laptop deals</h2></p></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->650</span></p><div><p>The Victus 15 is a popular, budget-friendly gaming laptop that now comes with RTX 4050 graphics, more RAM, and an improved 144Hz screen.</p></div></div><div><ul><li><span>The <strong>Asus ROG Strix G16</strong>, a stripped-down version of the Strix Scar featured in our buying guide, is on sale at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/ASUS-ROG-Strix-Gaming-Laptop/dp/B0DZZWMB2L?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">Amazon</a> for $1,274.99 ($225 off). It has an Nvidia RTX 5060 GPU, Intel Raptor Lake Core i7 14650HX processor, 16GB of RAM, and 1TB SSD.</span></li><li><span>If you prefer the <strong>ROG Strix G16</strong> with a little more power, the model with an <strong>RTX 5070 Ti </strong>is $1,999.99 ($400 off) at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/ASUS-Gaming-Laptop-Nebula-Display/dp/B0DW1X5YCQ?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">Amazon</a>, and with an even higher-end <strong>RTX 5080</strong> it’s $2,399.99 ($500 off) at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/ASUS-Strix-Gaming-Laptop-Nebula/dp/B0DW1FVPK8?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">Amazon</a>.</span></li><li><span>There are also a couple of deals on lower-cost <strong>Asus TUF gaming laptops</strong> with last-gen graphics. The <strong>Asus TUF A14 with RTX 4050</strong> graphics is $899.99 ($300 off) <a href="https://www.amazon.com/ASUS-Gaming-Copilot-Laptop-WQXGA/dp/B0DZQHB8S5/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">Amazon</a>. It’s got an AMD Ryzen 7 AI CPU, 16GB of RAM, and 512GB SSD — all housed in a portable 14-inch chassis. The larger 16-inch <strong>Asus TUF F16 with RTX 4050</strong> is $849.99 ($250 off) at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/ASUS-Gaming-Laptop-144Hz-IPS-Level/dp/B0F2JMX6RG?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">Amazon</a>. It’s configured with an Intel Core 5 210H (Raptor Lake) CPU, 16GB of RAM, and 512GB SSD.</span></li></ul></div><div><p id="best-controller-deals"><h2>Best controller deals</h2></p></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->45</span></p><div><p>Gamesir’s Cyclone 2 is a wireless controller compatible with iOS, Android, PC, the Steam Deck, and the Nintendo Switch. It has Hall effect triggers, motion control and vibration (Switch only), and comes with a charging dock.</p></div></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->100</span></p><div><p>The Razer Kishi Ultra is a wired gaming controller that works with Android and iOS devices, as well as select iPad models. The controller has Hall effect triggers, reprogrammable buttons, haptic feedback, and a USB-C port for passthrough charging.</p></div></div><div><ul><li><span>The version of <strong>8BitDo’s Ultimate 2 wireless controller</strong> that works with Android and Windows (including the Steam Deck) is down to $47.99 (originally $59.99) at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Ultimate-Wireless-Controller-Joysticks-Switchable-Smartphone/dp/B0DR8V899R?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">Amazon</a>. Aside from not being able to connect to Nintendo consoles, it’s identical in terms of features to the pricier, made-for-Switch edition.</span></li><li><span><strong>Amazon’s Luna Controller </strong>is on sale for $39.99 ($30 off) at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Amazon-Luna-Controller/dp/B07P989QTJ/?tag=theverge02-20&amp;ascsubtag=__vg0707awD__696641__________________&amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="noreferrer noopener sponsored" target="_blank">Amazon</a>, which matches its best price to date. Although it was built primarily for Amazon’s cloud-gaming service, the gamepad offers support for both Bluetooth and USB-C connectivity, making it compatible with Android phones, Apple products, Fire TV devices, and PCs. It also integrates with Alexa, allowing you to issue voice commands directly through the controller when paired with a Fire TV device.</span></li></ul></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->56</span></p><div><p>For something cheaper — and in some ways better — than Nintendo’s official Pro controller, there’s 8BitDo’s Ultimate 2, which works with the original Switch and Switch 2. It features TMR joysticks with trigger switches for adjusting the feel, as well as vibration and motion control support.</p></div></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->19</span></p><div><p>PowerA’s Enhanced Wired Controller for Nintendo Switch comes in dozens of designs featuring iconic video game characters. It has a pair of remappable rear buttons, 3.5mm headphone jack, and includes a 10-foot long USB cable.</p></div></div><div><p id="best-headset-deals"><h2>Best headset deals</h2></p></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->48</span></p><div><p>The InZone H3 is the wired (3.5mm / USB-A) model in Sony’s latest lineup of gaming headsets, which are compatible with both PlayStation and PC. You can customize the sound profile of InZone headsets with the InZone companion app and Sony’s Spatial Sound Personalizer.</p></div></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->150</span></p><div><p>The BlackShark V2 Pro is a wireless gaming headset that’s compatible with the Xbox Series S / X, PS5, PC, and the Nintendo Switch. It has a flexible, wideband mic, noise-isolating ear cups, and 70 hours of battery life. Its volume dial also lets you adjust the audio mix between your game and chat mid-game without needing to open an app.</p></div></div><div><p id="best-storage-deals"><h2>Best storage deals</h2></p></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->123</span></p><div><p>Seagate’s Storage Expansion Card is as fast as the Xbox’s internal storage, comes in 1TB, 2TB, and 4TB sizes, and fits into a proprietary slot without any cables.</p></div></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->105</span></p><div><p>SanDisk’s 1TB microSD Card can increase the Nintendo Switch’s internal storage by over 30x, and its design features an iconic symbol from <em>The Legend of Zelda</em> series.</p></div></div><div><ul><li><span>Do you have a Steam Deck, an Asus ROG Ally, or a similar handheld PC that can accommodate an M.2 2230-sized SSD? <strong>Western Digital’s 1TB SN770M</strong> is down to $84.99 ($55 off) at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CHJXHVZM?tag=theverge02-20&amp;ascsubtag=__vg0707awD__696641__________________&amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">Amazon</a>, down slightly from its previous low of $89.99. Keep in mind that installation procedures vary in terms of steps and complexity depending on the gaming handheld you own.</span></li></ul></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->95</span></p><div><p>Western Digital’s SN850X is a high speed NVME SSD with read speeds up to 7,300Mbps and write speeds up to 6,8000 Mbps. This model has a heatsink, which makes it compatible with the PlayStation 5.</p></div></div><div><p id="best-board-game-deals"><h2>Best board game deals</h2></p></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->19</span></p><div><p>A strategy card game in which players compete to build Renaissance Europe’s most lucrative and prestigious jewelry business.</p></div></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->19</span></p><div><p>Azul is a game in which you arrange patterned tiles in order to create the most beautiful tapestry possible. Arranging tiles in a strategic sequence will help you build your score while limiting your opponents’ ability to grow theirs.</p></div></div><div><ul><li><span><strong>Ticket to Ride</strong> is another classic board game that’s down to $24.99 (about $25 off) at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Days-Wonder-DO7201-Ticket-Ride/dp/0975277324/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">Amazon</a>. That’s one of the better prices we’ve seen on the cutthroat card game, which challenges you to build the longest locomotive route across classic America before your other tycoon opponents.</span></li><li><span>The 6th Edition of <strong>Catan</strong> is currently on sale at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/CATAN-Board-Game-Discovery-Civilization/dp/B0DYK1ZH2D/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">Amazon</a> for the first time ever, where you can grab it for $41.99 ($8 off). If you’ve never played before, Catan has you strategically collect and trade resources with fellow players while you figure out how to build out your civilization to take over the board. The latest edition has updated artwork to commemorate the game’s 13th anniversary.</span></li><li><span>You can gauge how well you know your friends and family by playing <strong>Codenames, </strong>which is on sale at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Czech-Games-00031CGE-Codenames/dp/B014Q1XX9S/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored" target="_blank">Amazon</a> right now for $14.99 ($10 off), the best price of the year. You only get to say one word associated with multiple tiles on the board, and your teammates have to figure out which ones you’re talking about. If you’re too vague, your teammates may guess incorrectly, giving the other side an edge.</span></li></ul></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->40</span></p><div><p>The latest <em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons Player</em>’s <em>Handbook</em> teaches you about 12 core classes, 48 subclasses, and helps you construct your story with 16 backgrounds and 75 feats. With a bit of help, you’ll be DMing your own original campaigns in no time.</p></div></div><div><ul><li><span><strong>Happy Salmon</strong> is on sale for just $9.49 (about $4 off) at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09KKJMR4L/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="noreferrer noopener sponsored" target="_blank">Amazon</a>. It’s one of the best icebreakers at social gatherings, for both adults and parents alike, and it takes just minutes to learn and play this card game. Up to eight players can get in on the action, which gets you out of your seats and has you doing fun stuff like giving each other high-fives and “fish bumps.”</span></li></ul></div><div><p id="other-miscellaneous-gaming-deals"><h2>Other miscellaneous gaming deals</h2></p></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->70</span></p><div><p>SteelSeries’ Aerox 3 is a lightweight, water-resistant wireless mouse with six programmable buttons, 200 hours of battery life, and three RGB zones.</p></div></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->133</span></p><div><p>The G Pro X Superlight 2 is Logitech’s lightest and most advanced mouse to date. It features a 32,000 DPI Hero 2 sensor and 4kHz polling rate, as well as support for USB-C charging and Logitech’s Powerplay mouse mat.</p></div></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->450</span></p><div><p>The Xreal One aren’t the most affordable augmented-reality glasses available, but they are some of the best for displaying movies and games on the go. You can connect them via USB-C to your smartphone, tablet, or handheld gaming PC.</p></div></div><div><form><div><h2>Verge Deals</h2><p><span>Sign up for Verge Deals to get deals on products we’ve tested sent to your inbox weekly.</span></p></div></form></div></div></div><div><form><div><h2>Verge Deals</h2><p><span>Sign up for Verge Deals to get deals on products we’ve tested sent to your inbox weekly.</span></p></div></form></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/tech/698696/amazon-prime-day-best-gaming-deals-controllers-headsets-accessories-2025]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>