<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 04:04:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Informer has officially returned]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/635915/game-informer-return-gunzilla-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/game-informer-has-officially-returned.1144758/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/635915/game-informer-return-gunzilla-games<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/emma-roth">Emma Roth</a> <span>is a news writer who covers the streaming wars, consumer tech, crypto, social media, and much more. Previously, she was a writer and editor at MUO.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p><em>Game Informer</em> is back, and so is its entire staff. On Tuesday, editor-in-chief Matt Miller <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/letter-from-the-editor/2025/03/25/game-informer-is-back">announced that Gunzilla Games</a> has acquired the rights to the gaming magazine, helping to bring the site and its archives back online.</p><div><p>GameStop, which previously owned <em>Game Informer</em>, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/2/24212016/game-informer-shutting-down-layoffs-gamestop">shut down the beloved magazine</a> last August and laid off its entire staff after a more than 30-year run. The team <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/632610/game-informer-returning-gamestop">teased a comeback last week</a>, and has already <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2025/03/24/every-review-from-game-informers-hiatus">published a series</a> of new reviews for titles released during the magazine’s hiatus, along with a belated list of the <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2025/03/20/game-informers-belated-top-10-games-of-2024-awards">best games of 2024</a>.</p></div><p>Its new owners, Gunzilla Games, is a game developer based in Europe that’s currently working on a battle royale title called <em>Off the Grid</em>. Miller says the magazine will continue operating as an independent editorial outlet under a new entity called Game Informer, Inc. “Our intent is to continue to focus on highlighting the coolest games, celebrating the history and legacy of the gaming industry, and shining a spotlight on the creators and players who are charting its future,” Miller says.</p><p>In addition to bringing back its website, <em>Game Informer</em> plans to resurrect its print magazine, too, with “new membership and subscription benefits.” Though <em>Game Informer</em> currently isn’t offering a subscription just yet, you can sign up for an <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/subscribe">account on its website</a> to receive updates, as well as gain access to the magazine’s archive. <em>Game Informer</em> will continue updating its site with news, reviews, previews, features, event coverage, and more starting today.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>