<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 04:55:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Take-Two is selling its indie games label Private Division]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/6/24289932/take-two-private-division-publisher-sale</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/take-two-is-selling-its-indie-games-label-private-division.1029330/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/6/24289932/take-two-private-division-publisher-sale<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><article id="content"><div><div><div><h2>Take-Two is selling its indie games label Private Division</h2><p><span><span> / </span><h2>The label behind games such as The Outer Worlds and Kerbal Space Program 2 has been sold to an unknown buyer.</h2></span></p></div><div><p><span>By</span> <span><span></span> <span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/umar-shakir">Umar Shakir</a></span><span>, <span>a news writer fond of the electric vehicle lifestyle and things that plug in via USB-C. He spent over 15 years in IT support before joining The Verge. </span></span></span></p><p><time datetime="2024-11-06T23:52:13.420Z"> <!-- -->Nov 6, 2024, 11:52 PM UTC</time></p><div><h2>Share this story</h2></div></div></div><div><figure><span><span></span></span><div><figcaption>Pokemon<em> developer Game Freak’s unreleased </em>Project Bloom<em> game is included in the sale.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: Private Division</cite></p></div></figure></div></div><div><div><p>Take-Two Interactive is selling off its indie games label Private Division, which published titles such as <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/12/20959758/the-outer-worlds-obsidian-fallout-series-hero-narrative-xbox-one-ps4-pc"><em>The Outer Worlds</em></a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/22915054/olliolli-world-review-switch-ps5-xbox-pc"><em>OlliOlli World</em></a>, following <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/take-two-is-quietly-killing-private-division">rumors over the summer</a> that Take-Two laid off most of Private Division’s staff.</p><p>Take-Two did not disclose the buyer of Private Division or how much they paid. In an emailed statement to <em>The Verge</em>, Take-Two spokesperson Alan Lewis wrote:</p><div><blockquote><p><em>We recently made the strategic decision to sell our Private Division label to focus our resources on growing our core and mobile businesses for the long-term. As part of this transaction, the buyer purchased our rights to substantially all of Private Division’s live and unreleased titles. </em></p><p><em>Take-Two will continue to support No Rest for the Wicked, which launched in Early Access on PC in April. We are grateful for the contributions that the Private Division team has made to our company and are confident that they will continue to achieve success in their new home.</em></p></blockquote></div><div><p><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-11-06/take-two-sells-video-game-label-private-division-for-undisclosed-sum">According to <em>Bloomberg</em></a>, the label has been plagued by “a string of flops, including K<em>erbal Space Program 2</em>, which was full of bugs and panned by fans.” Private Division games, including the upcoming <em>The Lord of the Rings</em> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24137113/tales-of-the-shire-trailer-private-division-weta-workshop">farm simulator <em>Tales of the Shire</em></a>, as well as <em>Pokémon</em> developer Game Freak’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23716737/game-freak-developer-project-bloom-game">untitled game known as <em>Project Bloom</em></a>, will move over to the new buyer. However, Private Divison’s buyer <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23990860/no-rest-for-the-wicked-trailer-announce-moon-studios">won’t get the rights to <em>No Rest for the Wicked</em></a><em>.</em></p></div><p>Take-Two CEO Strauss Zelnick told <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/zelnick-on-private-division-sale-those-projects-were-smaller-were-in-the-business-of-big-hits"><em>GamesIndustry.biz</em></a><em> </em>that the buyer would be named soon and said, “The team of Private Division did a great job supporting independent developers and, almost to a one, every project they supported did well. However, the scale of those projects was, candidly, on the smaller side, and we’re in the business of making great big hits,” like the upcoming <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23987993/gta-6-news-trailers-rockstar-games"><em>Grand Theft Auto VI</em></a>.</p></div><div><p>Most Popular</p><p>Most Popular</p><ol><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/reviews/24289319/ps5-pro-review"><h2>PS5 Pro review: how close is your TV?</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/6/24289768/openai-chat-chatgpt-sam-altman-hubspot"><h2>Did OpenAI just spend more than $10 million on a URL?</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/6/24289674/nintendo-switch-2-next-generation-backward-compatibility"><h2>Nintendo’s next generation is off to a great start</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/5/24288836/elon-musk-top-20-diablo-4-players-the-pit"><h2>Elon Musk’s ‘top 20’ Diablo IV claim is as real as his self-driving cars</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/5/24284745/switch-2-backward-compatibility-nintendo-online-preservation"><h2>Nintendo says the Switch successor will be compatible with Switch games</h2></a><hr></li></ol></div></div></article></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft’s new emulator could bring more games to Windows on Arm]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/6/24289844/microsoft-windows-on-arm-emulator-prism-update</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft%E2%80%99s-new-emulator-could-bring-more-games-to-windows-on-arm.1029312/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/6/24289844/microsoft-windows-on-arm-emulator-prism-update<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p>Microsoft is testing a big Windows on Arm update to let more x64 software and games run under Prism emulation on <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/26/24186432/microsoft-windows-on-arm-qualcomm-copilot-plus-pcs-prism-emulator">Copilot Plus PC with Qualcomm’s Snapdragon X Elite</a> or X Plus processors. The capability comes as part of the <a href="https://blogs.windows.com/windows-insider/2024/11/06/announcing-windows-11-insider-preview-build-27744-canary-channel/">Windows 11 Insider Preview&nbsp;Build 27744</a>, rolling out to testers in the Canary Channel.</p></div><p>This way, Qualcomm’s new chips can run more kinds of apps that don’t have native ARM64 versions and, until now, weren’t usable with emulation. It could even enable <a href="https://hothardware.com/news/new-windows-build-avx-on-sdxe">games that use AVX2, like <em>Starfield</em></a> and <em>Helldivers 2, </em>to work on Windows on Arm.</p><p>With this update, Microsoft’s emulator will open up support for 64-bit x86 software to use processor extensions like AVX, AVX2, BMI, FMA, and F16C. However, it says 32-bit software still won’t be able to detect the new emulator support, so some programs still might have trouble.</p><p>While many apps, including Photoshop, Hulu, and Chrome, already have native ARM64 versions for Windows, others require emulation, and some still won’t work at all. According to Microsoft, the new emulator is already enabled “in limited use” on retail PCs, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/5/24214172/adobe-premiere-pro-is-available-on-snapdragon-x-elite-laptops">allowing Premiere Pro 25 to run on Arm</a> — after it was initially blocked — while Adobe works on a native version.</p><p><em><strong>Correction, November 6th: </strong>A previous version of the article incorrectly stated Blender needed to be emulated. It now has an ARM64 version.</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roblox is banning kids from ‘social hangout’ spaces]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/6/24289837/roblox-banning-preteens-social-hangout-spaces</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/roblox-is-banning-kids-from-%E2%80%98social-hangout%E2%80%99-spaces.1029255/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/6/24289837/roblox-banning-preteens-social-hangout-spaces<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Roblox is going to block kids from accessing certain types of experiences following reports alleging that the platform has enabled child abuse.</p><p>One new measure will stop kids under 13 from accessing experiences with “certain types of interactive features,” Roblox says <a href="https://devforum.roblox.com/t/updating-experience-guideline-policies-to-keep-our-younger-users-safe/3249079">in a post on its developer forum</a>. Those include “social hangouts,” where the primary purpose is to communicate with others over text or voice chat, and “free-form 2D user creation” experiences, where players can do things like draw on a chalkboard or whiteboard. This change goes into effect beginning November 18th.</p><p>Another change stops kids under 13 from playing, searching for, or being able to discover unrated experiences. This change goes into effect after December 3rd. If a creator wants to let a player under 13 access their game, they will have to complete a questionnaire and make sure that all of the information regarding their experience meets Roblox’s requirements for its current All Ages or 9 plus ratings. Roblox says it will start enforcing those requirements “next year.”</p><p>There have been multiple <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/8/24265145/roblox-hindenburg-reseach-dau-child-safety-short-seller-report">recent stories</a> about Roblox’ allegedly poor protections for children, including <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/features/2024-roblox-pedophile-problem/?srnd=undefined">a <em>Bloomberg</em> article</a> titled “Roblox’s Pedophile Problem.” In October, the company announced <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/23/24277992/roblox-pre-teen-children-parent-accounts-default-settings">changes for pre-teen users</a> and a new type of account to let parents manage their kids on Roblox.</p><p>“We’re constantly strengthening our safety systems and policies — we shipped over 30 improvements this year and we have more to come,” spokesperson Juliet Chaitin-Lefcourt says in a statement to <em>The Verge</em>. “As a company that’s transparent with our community of developers, we needed to share key information about the upcoming changes prior to launch. The&nbsp;DevForum&nbsp;has all the information on the upcoming changes that we’re sharing at this time. It’s important to know that at Roblox, we’re constantly innovating Safety and we’ll never STOP.”&nbsp;(Emphasis Chaitin-Lefcourt’s.)</p><p><em><strong>Update, November 6th</strong>: Added statement from Roblox.</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>