<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 21:21:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel’s WWII action game has been delayed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/games/666270/marvel-1943-rise-of-hydra-delayed-2026</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel%E2%80%99s-wwii-action-game-has-been-delayed.1188477/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/games/666270/marvel-1943-rise-of-hydra-delayed-2026<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/ash-parrish">Ash Parrish</a> <span>is a reporter who covers the business, culture, and communities of video games, with a focus on marginalized gamers and the quirky, horny culture of video game communities.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p><em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24106470/1943-rise-of-hydra-marvel-game-trailer-amy-hennig">Marvel 1943: Rise of Hydra</a></em>, the new Marvel action-adventure game, has been delayed. The game was originally slated to release this year but Skydance New Media, the studio developing the game, has announced it will instead come out some time in early 2026. </p><div><p>“Taking this additional time will allow us to add more polish,” Skydance <a href="https://x.com/SkydanceGames/status/1922275645402337325">wrote of the delay on their X account</a>. </p></div><div><p><em>Marvel 1943</em> was first teaseed in 2021 as the first project under Skydance New Media, a new gaming initiative spearheaded by parent company studio Skydance Media known for films like <em>Mission: Impossible – Dead Reckoning</em>. Skydance appointed former Naughty Dog creative director and <em>Uncharted </em>writer Amy Hennig <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/18/20971217/amy-hennig-skydance-media-studio-streaming-platforms">to lead the studio</a>. </p><p>It’s billed as an action-adventure game taking place in World War II featuring multiple playable characters including Captain America, Black Panther (T’Challa’s grandfather Azzuri), Gabriel Jones (a member of Captain America’s Howling Commandos team,) and Nanali, a Wakandan spy. We have one brief trailer from the game, released during last year’s state of Unreal address but no other details. Skydance New Media is <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/4/19/23031936/star-wars-amy-hennig-naughty-dog-skydance-new-media">also working on a <em>Star Wars</em> game.</a></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>