<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 19:56:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Three months later, S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2 is the glorious pain in the ass its makers intended]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/games-review/614336/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyl-update-patches</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/three-months-later-s-t-a-l-k-e-r-2-is-the-glorious-pain-in-the-ass-its-makers-intended.1112523/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/games-review/614336/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyl-update-patches<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>When <em>S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2: Heart of Chornobyl </em>was released in November<em>, </em>it was clearly not yet the game its developers, GSC Game World, wanted it to be. Sure, this imagining of the Zone was fabulously moody, a desolate and bleak expanse of bog, scrubland, abandoned warehouses, and pallid vistas. For all the ways it was transportive and evocative, it did not yet feel truly alive. The Zone was, dare I say, a little too quiet, lacking the kind of brilliant emergent moments (like three-way skirmishes between stalkers, more stalkers, and roving packs of mutant dogs) that have previously defined the franchise. I ended my <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/20/24300652/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyl-review">review</a> wondering whether the game would, and indeed could, become the very best “shining” version of itself. </p><p>Three months on, with two major and five smaller patches under its belt, I’m thrilled to report that the game is close to becoming exactly that. To cut a long story short, the enemy AI in combat situations is vastly improved, A-Life 2.0 (the more expansive AI system that gives the game its thrillingly unpredictable sense of life) is practically purring, and I’m now encountering far fewer of the immersion-breaking bugs (like floating and disembodied heads)<em>. S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2</em> was admittedly no <em>Cyberpunk 2077</em> disaster at launch. That said, the work done by its Kyiv and Prague-based developers, who have labored throughout the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/12/arts/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyl-ukraine-war.html">Russia-Ukraine war</a>, is nothing short of remarkable.</p><p>Last night, while traipsing through the overgrowth to complete a mission in the Malachite region, I was spotted by stalkers from a rival faction. I retreated back into the vehicle station that I’d just passed through, taking cover behind a steel gate. I poked my rifle around the metal panel, leaning to my left as bullets whizzed past my head, catching a glimpse of the masked stalkers attempting to flank me. They threw grenades, pinning me back. I downed one of them, and the other went to heal him. As he crouched down to administer a med kit, I headshotted him, a fearsome crack whipping through the air. Of course, I unceremoniously looted both bodies moments later.</p><p>Improved enemy AI clearly has a massive impact on gameplay. It also changes how the Zone feels. Where, previously, the architecture felt ghostly — blown-out, post-Soviet wreckage that was slowly being reclaimed by nature — now, it is the perfect site for cat-and-mouse shootouts. Fear not, the Zone is still haunting, but the adrenaline-pumping, hardcore firefights that were such a standout feature of <a href="https://youtu.be/0ZqMt74hO6U">prerelease trailers</a> are now very much a reality in the game. It adds up to a 64-kilometer-squared open-world playspace that feels even more dangerous; you’re locked into a battle with the landscape itself and the much smarter humans that stalk it. </p><p>In the latest patch released last Thursday, there are a whopping <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.steampowered.com%2Fnews%2Fapp%2F1643320%2Fview%2F579378232238800945" rel="sponsored">1,700 improvements</a>, ranging from small balancing tweaks like radiation levels to what seem like pretty substantial changes, including “level design, and terrain improvements for multiple locations and regions.” Your flashlight now casts shadows on objects, and stealth has been improved (although, truth be told, it’s still pretty wonky). Maybe my favorite detail is that NPCs don’t just heal their fallen allies; they now loot the corpses of downed enemies. Turns out, these NPCs have just as little shame as me. Another small detail that subtly enhances the game’s already wonderful atmosphere: thanks, I think, to the improved A-Life 2.0, NPC stalkers now more regularly gather at campfires, even those in the wilderness outside of major hub areas. </p><p>I don’t want to tacitly endorse developers releasing games in borderline unfinished states. The examples, unfortunately, have been <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/after-2042s-disastrous-launch-what-next-for-battlefield">piling</a> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/5/26/23738863/gollum-developers-apology-negative-reviews-lotr">up</a> in recent years. But you can’t deny the achievements of GSC Game World. In early December, creative director Mariia Grygorovych reflected on the game’s rocky launch. “It’s not perfect, we need to fix everything,” she <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/delaying-stalker-2-again-not-an-option-studio-says-team-worked-until-it-was-broken-by-marathon-development">said</a>. “But it’s a game! It’s a game with soul, with feelings there, with love there!”</p><p>Grygorovych is right, and now it’s easier than ever to appreciate all that love and soul. For sure, it’s an odd and uncompromising love, the kind that’s content to let the player cower in a shed while a blood-red radiation storm whirs above them; the kind that also takes pride in first-person animations of protagonist Skif wolfing down delicious cured sausage. These types of moments feed into a wider tapestry of action that does not go easy on the player — indeed, it goes out of its way to make life miserable for them. </p><p>This type of friction has always been the major selling point of the <em>S.T.A.L.K.E.R.</em> franchise. It’s what makes the series appeal to such a specific type of video game fetishist. Now, that friction manifests in many more of the ways the developers intended. <em>S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2.</em> is no tribute act to past glories: three months on from launch, it finally feels as if it was worth the wait. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Magic: The Gathering’s Final Fantasy sets will tell the stories of the games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/614519/magic-the-gathering-final-fantasy-commander-sets</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/magic-the-gathering%E2%80%99s-final-fantasy-sets-will-tell-the-stories-of-the-games.1112424/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/614519/magic-the-gathering-final-fantasy-commander-sets<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/ash-parrish">Ash Parrish</a> <span>is a reporter who covers the business, culture, and communities of video games, with a focus on marginalized gamers and the quirky, horny culture of video game communities.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p><em>Magic: The Gathering</em> has revealed a look at its forthcoming <a href="https://www.polygon.com/mtg-magic-the-gathering/470491/final-fantasy-art-reveal-universes-beyond-standard-legal-announcement"><em>Final Fantasy</em>-themed set</a>. In <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-final-fantasy-commander-deck-reveal-spoilers">an interview with <em>IGN</em></a>, senior game designer Daniel Holt talked about the collaboration and this initial look, which focuses on four major character cards and their associated pre-constructed Commander decks.</p><p>The revealed cards include Terra from <em>Final Fantasy VI</em>, Tidus from <em>Final Fantasy X</em>, Y’shtola from (<a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/the-critically-acclaimed-mmorpg">critically acclaimed MMORPG</a>)<em> <em>Final Fantasy XIV</em></em>, and of course, Cloud from <em>Final Fantasy VII</em>. What’s interesting about these Commander decks is that instead of being constructed to simply support a single powerful card (known as the Commander), each deck’s mechanics and cards are designed to tell the story of a specific<em> Final Fantasy</em> game.</p><section tabindex="-1" aria-label="carousel"><p><strong>1<!-- -->/<!-- -->5</strong><span><cite>Image: Magic: The Gathering</cite></span></p></section><p>Since the back half of <em>Final Fantasy VI</em> is all about rebuilding the world Kefka destroyed, its associated deck is all about returning creatures from the graveyard to the battlefield, for example. Cloud’s deck is all about equipment — you gotta have the right materia for the job, right? <em>Magic</em> has always been really good with how it marries the story of a set to gameplay mechanics, and seeing that applied to<em> Final Fantasy</em> is really cool. </p><p>In the <em>IGN</em> interview, Holt assured fans that even though these Commander decks are focused on only four games, the rest of the Standard-legal set will feature cards that represent all 16 mainline <em>Final Fantasy</em> games.</p><p>You can see previews for some of those cards’ artwork on the set’s official website <a href="https://magic.wizards.com/en/products/final-fantasy">here</a>. There will be even more cards revealed during an <a href="https://x.com/wizards_magic/status/1891549077654954031">official <em>MT</em>G x <em>Final Fantasy</em> livestream</a> taking place on February 18th at 1PM ET.</p><div><p>The full set launches on June 13th and will feature artwork from <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2012/10/15/3506952/final-fantasy-designer-on-breaking-creative-boundaries-and-wearing">famed <em>Final Fantasy </em>artist Yoshitaka Amano</a>.</p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>