<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 21:48:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WB Games’ best PC titles are in this $12 Humble bundle]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/tech/720211/humble-bundle-wb-games-deal-sale</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wb-games%E2%80%99-best-pc-titles-are-in-this-12-humble-bundle.1263918/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="__next"><p><a href="#content"><span>Skip to main content</span></a></p><nav aria-label="Sticky Nav"></nav><div><main id="content"><article><div><div><h2>WB Games’ best PC titles are in this $12 Humble bundle</h2><p>The bundle includes <em>Batman: Arkham City, Middle-earth: Shadow of Mordor</em>, as well as early 2024’s <em>Suicide Squad</em>.</p></div><div><p>The bundle includes <em>Batman: Arkham City, Middle-earth: Shadow of Mordor</em>, as well as early 2024’s <em>Suicide Squad</em>.</p><div><p><span><span>by</span> <!-- --> <span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"></span></span></p><p><span><time datetime="2025-08-06T20:39:51+00:00">Aug 6, 2025, 8:39 PM UTC</time></span></p></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6Njg3NzE5"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Brandon Russell</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a commerce writer covering deals and buying guides. Previously, he was a freelance writer for Popular Mechanics, Men’s Health, and Esquire.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/619293/warner-bros-games-wonder-woman-canceled-studios-shut-down">The future of Warner Bros. Games is unclear</a>, as it shut down several studios and canceled anticipated games earlier this year. But there’s no arguing that the company’s back catalog of titles is full of gems, many of which are in Humble’s great $12 bundle. Through August 27th, you can jump on this unbeatable deal that gets you <a rel="sponsored" href="https://humblebundleinc.sjv.io/c/482924/2091208/25796?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.humblebundle.com%2Fgames%2Fwb-play-legends">16 WB Games titles on Steam for just $12</a>, with proceeds going to the <a href="https://www.raidenscience.org/">Raiden Science Foundation</a>.</p></div><p>This bittersweet bundle features an array of licensed and original open-world titles, fighting games, and first-person shooters from WB Games’ studios — most of which have either fallen from grace in recent years, or have been shut down. The standout for me is <em>Middle-earth: Shadow of Mordor</em>, Monolith’s third-person action game that features the excellent Nemesis System, a mechanic that allows enemies to remember and react to players. For instance, if an enemy kills you in battle, that enemy will get stronger and remember your last encounter, making fights feel more personal.</p><p>Other highlights include <em>Batman: Arkham City</em>, <em>Batman: Arkham Asylum</em>, and the oft-overlooked <em>Mad Max</em>. There’s a lot of fun to be had with other games in the bundle too, like <em>Mortal Kombat 11</em>, <em>Mortal Kombat XL, Middle-earth: Shadow of War, and Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League, </em>among others. In most cases, you’ll be getting the most content-complete versions of the games with purchase.</p><div><form><div><h2>Verge Deals</h2><p><span>Sign up for Verge Deals to get deals on products we’ve tested sent to your inbox weekly.</span></p></div></form></div><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6Njg3NzE5"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Brandon Russell</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><div><form><div><h2>Verge Deals</h2><p><span>Sign up for Verge Deals to get deals on products we’ve tested sent to your inbox weekly.</span></p></div></form></div></div></article></main></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/tech/720211/humble-bundle-wb-games-deal-sale]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Jurassic Park islands and dinos are coming to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/720070/orbx-universal-jurassic-world-park-dinosaurs-microsoft-flight-simulator-2-024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-jurassic-park-islands-and-dinos-are-coming-to-microsoft-flight-simulator-2024.1263792/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTYw"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Andrew Liszewski</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a senior reporter who’s been covering and reviewing the latest gadgets and tech since 2006, but has loved all things electronic since he was a kid.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p><em>Jurassic World: Archipelago</em> is a <a href="https://orbxstudios.com/jwarchipelago/overview/">new expansion pack</a> for <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/19/24248947/microsoft-flight-simulator-2024-cloud-release-date"><em>Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024</em></a> that lets aspiring pilots explore the five islands of the fictional Cinco Muertes Archipelago featured in the <em>Jurassic Park</em> and <em>Jurassic World</em> movies. Created by Australian developer Orbx that’s <a href="https://orbxdirect.com/">known for its flight sim add-ons</a>, the expansion lets you visit many locations from the films while the islands will be teeming with more than 10 different species of dinosaurs.</p><p>According to an <a href="https://orbxstudios.com/jwarchipelago/faqs/">FAQ on Orbx Studios’ website</a>, the <em>Jurassic World: Archipelago</em> expansion is an official collaboration with Universal Products &amp; Experiences and will be available sometime in late August or early September, 2025. It will initially launch for all versions of <em>Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024</em> on Xbox and PC, but is compatible with the entry-level Standard Edition which is also available through Xbox Game Pass. The studio says it’s also “working towards making compatible products for <em>Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020</em> and <em>X-Plane 12</em>.”</p><p>The expansion lets you visit the five new islands — including Isla Nublar, Sorna, Matanceros, Peña, and Tacaño — as they were before the events of 2015’s <em>Jurassic World</em> “when the park is operational but not everything is under control.” You’ll be able to fly over Isla Nublar and see the park alive with activity, while the breeding facilities on Isla Sorna, as seen in <em>The Lost World: Jurassic Park,</em> remain abandoned and overgrown.</p><p><em>Jurassic World: Archipelago</em> includes new flying challenges like transporting VIPs between the islands and nearby Costa Rica and conducting guided tours. You can visit the facilities and theme park structures seen in the various films and land at recognizable airfields and helipads, all while dodging the local wildlife that includes brachiosaurus, stegosaurus, velociraptor, t.rex, and flying pteranodons.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTYw"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Andrew Liszewski</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/720070/orbx-universal-jurassic-world-park-dinosaurs-microsoft-flight-simulator-2-024]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>