<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 15:31:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia’s RTX 5060 Ti arrives on April 16th starting at $379]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/648705/nvidias-rtx-5060-ti-gpu-pricing-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nvidia%E2%80%99s-rtx-5060-ti-arrives-on-april-16th-starting-at-379.1164675/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/648705/nvidias-rtx-5060-ti-gpu-pricing-release-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Nvidia is <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nvidia.com%2Fen-gb%2Fgeforce%2Fnews%2Frtx-5060-desktop-family-laptop-5060-coming-soon%2F" rel="sponsored">announcing</a> its RTX 5060 family of GPUs today, just a day before it releases the RTX 5060 Ti on April 16th. Two variants of the RTX 5060 Ti are launching, the $379 8GB of VRAM model and the $429 16GB version. The $299 RTX 5060 will launch at some point in May with 8GB of VRAM.</p><p>The RTX 5060 Ti will ship with 4,608 CUDA cores, a 2.4GHz base clock, 2.57GHz boost clock, and a 128-bit memory bus with either 8GB or 16GB of GDDR7. Nvidia says the RTX 5060 Ti 16GB is launching on April 16th, but that the 8GB model will follow “shortly afterwards.” The cheaper RTX 5060 features 3,840 CUDA cores and uses a 128-bit memory bus with 8GB of GDDR7 memory.</p><p>Both the RTX 5060 Ti and RTX 5060 will support <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24337402/nvidia-dlss-4-upscaling-announcement-ces-2025">DLSS 4 and Multi Frame Generation</a> (up to 4x), as well as PCI Express Gen 5 and DisplayPort 2.1b. The RTX 5060 Ti will have a total graphics power of 180 watts, while the RTX 5060 will consume up to 145 watts.</p><p>Nvidia is promising high RTX 5060 frame rates in a variety of games, thanks mainly to Multi Frame Generation. The GPU maker has tested games at 1080p with max Frame Gen levels, AMD’s Ryzen 7 9800X3D CPU, and 1080p max settings:</p><div><ul><li><span><em>Half-Life 2 RTX</em> - 130fps</span></li><li><span><em>Hogwarts Legacy</em> - 234fps</span></li><li><span><em>Alan Wake II</em> - 114fps</span></li><li><span><em>Black Myth: Wukong </em>- 130fps</span></li><li><span><em>Cyberpunk 2077 </em>- 148fps</span></li><li><span><em>Stalker 2</em> - 208fps</span></li><li><span><em>Star Wars Outlaws </em>- 105fps</span></li><li><span><em>Marvel Rivals </em>- 330fps</span></li><li><span><em>Avowed</em> - 220fps</span></li></ul></div><p>While Nvidia is obviously pushing 4x Frame Gen with these new RTX 5060 cards, there will also be performance improvements to rasterization. “In a game that doesn’t support Multi Frame Gen, you’ll see about a 20-25 percent performance improvement gen over gen on the RTX 5060,” says Justin Walker, Nvidia’s senior director director of GeForce product management, in a press briefing. “You’ll see about 20 percent on the RTX 5060 Ti.“</p><p>Nvidia isn’t making Founders Edition versions of the RTX 5060 cards, so it won’t be able to directly impact the pricing its board partners set this time around with its own cards. That means it might be very difficult to find an RTX 5060 at $299, especially with the uncertainty around <a href="https://www.theverge.com/604742/trump-tariffs-canada-mexico-china-updates">Trump’s tariff situation</a> that changes almost daily.</p><p>That said, the pricing might not be the only uncertain aspect of these new cards. The choice to offer 8GB of VRAM will be controversial, I’m sure. “We are trying to optimize price and performance,” says Walker. “When you get to a GPU like the RTX 5060, you have to look really hard at trade offs.”</p><p>Nvidia argues that VRAM doesn’t have a big impact on GPU performance, and that it has optimized for pricing with the RTX 5060 series. But we’re still regularly seeing games consume a lot of memory, which really impacts 8GB cards. “The RTX 2060 was $349, and that was years ago,” says Walker. “The RTX 3060 was $329, and I bet even if you looked back and did the inflation math of the RTX 1660 and RTX 1060, I think you’ll find that $299 for a GPU is a pretty good price.”</p><p>Pricing and VRAM debates aside, the RTX 5060 will also be available in laptops in May. With prices starting at $1,099, Acer, Asus, Dell, Gigabyte, HP, Lenovo, MSI, and Razer will all have models with Nvidia’s latest RTX 5060 laptop GPUs.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>