<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 18:55:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam store pages are wider now]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/816599/valve-steam-store-pages-wider</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steam-store-pages-are-wider-now.1347286/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTIz"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Jay Peters</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a senior reporter covering technology, gaming, and more. He joined The Verge in 2019 after nearly two years at Techmeme.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Valve is making Steam store pages wider as part of a new update rolling out today. With the changes, “many pages” will be widened from “940 pixels to now 1200 pixels,” <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/games/593110/announcements/detail/506217467911081529?utm_source=SteamDB">Valve says</a>. The company picked that 1200 pixels number because it found that it “felt like a good balance where we can show more content on screen without overwhelming the page and making it hard to navigate.”</p><p>If your browser or client window is narrower than 1200 pixels, Valve says that “Steam store pages are designed to shrink appropriately to fit well” and that the pages adapt “to fit on tablets, Steam Decks, and mobile devices.” Valve says it’s even tested the changes “on a tiny old iPod that someone had laying around,” where “it mostly works, but things get pretty small.”</p><p>The changes follow Valve’s improvements to the Steam Trailer Player for store pages that it introduced <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.steampowered.com%2Fnews%2Fapp%2F593110%2Fview%2F500579723494031419" rel="sponsored">in July</a>, which include a more adaptable UI and reprocessing videos to work better with the new player.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTIz"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Jay Peters</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/816599/valve-steam-store-pages-wider]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Texas sues Roblox for allegedly failing to protect children on its platform]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/816549/texas-roblox-lawsuit-child-safety</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/texas-sues-roblox-for-allegedly-failing-to-protect-children-on-its-platform.1347250/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Texas AG Ken Paxton is <a href="https://x.com/KenPaxtonTX/status/1986529630124126245">accusing Roblox</a> of “putting pixel pedophiles and profits over the safety of Texas children,” alleging in a lawsuit filed this week that it is “flagrantly ignoring state and federal online safety laws while deceiving parents about the dangers of its platform.”</p><p>The <a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/26220082-texas-roblox-lawsuit/">lawsuit</a> accuses Roblox of deceptive trade practices for misleading parents and users about its safety features, and for creating a common nuisance by harboring a space “that has become a habitual destination for child predators engaging in grooming and child sexual exploitation.”</p><p>The lawsuit’s examples focus on instances of children who have been abused by predators they met via Roblox, and the activities of groups like <a href="https://www.ic3.gov/PSA/2025/PSA250306">764</a> which have used online platforms to identify and blackmail victims into sexually explicit acts or self harm. According to the suit, Roblox’s parental controls push only began after a number of lawsuits, and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/8/24265145/roblox-hindenburg-reseach-dau-child-safety-short-seller-report">a report released last fall by the short seller Hindenburg</a> that said its “in-game research revealed an X-rated pedophile hellscape, exposing children to grooming, pornography, violent content and extremely abusive speech.”</p><p>In August, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/760162/roblox-louisiana-lawsuit-child-predators-safety">Louisiana filed a similar lawsuit</a>, alleging that Roblox “permitted and perpetuated an online environment in which child predators thrive.” A couple of months later, the state of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/793711/another-state-is-suing-roblox">Kentucky also sued Roblox</a>, calling it “a hunting ground for child predators.” Last month, Florida Attorney General James Uthmeier <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/tech-news/florida-attorney-general-issues-subpoenas-roblox-child-safety-rcna238711">subpoenaed Roblox</a> over similar allegations. It’s not just states suing Roblox, either. Numerous <a href="https://www.wfaa.com/article/news/local/texas-lawsuit-roblox-discord/285-ea17aa89-62bb-4bb5-8877-266b82f7efb7">families and Roblox players</a> have also sued the platform for alleged abuse, such as the cases detailed in Texas’s lawsuit.</p><p>Eric Porterfield, Senior Director of Policy Communications at Roblox, responded to the lawsuit in a statement to <em>The Verge</em>, saying, “We are disappointed that, rather than working collaboratively with Roblox on this industry-wide challenge and seeking real solutions, the AG has chosen to file a lawsuit based on misrepresentations and sensationalized claims.” He added, “We have introduced over 145 safety measures on the platform this year alone.”</p><p>Roblox <a href="https://corp.roblox.com/newsroom/2025/09/roblox-rdc-2025">reported in September</a> that it has over 111 million daily active users, many of whom are children. Earlier this year, Roblox announced plans to roll out <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/708670/roblox-trusted-connections-age-estimation-privacy">age verification</a> using IDs and facial scans, along with <a href="https://corp.roblox.com/newsroom/2025/08/open-sourcing-roblox-sentinel-preemptive-risk-detection">an AI system</a> intended to “detect early signals of potential child endangerment.”</p><p>It echoes similar changes on social media platforms like Discord, which also <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/650493/discord-age-verification-face-id-scan-experiment">began rolling out age verification</a> this year and has even been cited in some of the same lawsuits filed against Roblox, including <a href="https://abc7.com/post/online-gaming-parental-controls-lawsuit-claims-roblox-discord-failed-protect-galveston-texas-girl-alleged-predator/16294376/">one case</a> involving a 13-year-old from Texas. Social media platforms have often <a href="https://blog.ericgoldman.org/archives/2025/10/section-230-preempts-predator-access-claims-against-apple-snap-and-verizon-joan-doe-v-snap.htm">successfully used Section 230</a> to shield themselves from liability for individual users’ actions on their platforms, however — a barrier this Roblox suit, like others against the company, will face.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6ODAzMzIw"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Stevie Bonifield</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/816549/texas-roblox-lawsuit-child-safety]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BioWare says it’s ‘focused exclusively’ on the next Mass Effect]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/816555/bioware-mass-effect-5-development-focused-tv-show-amazon-n7-day</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bioware-says-it%E2%80%99s-%E2%80%98focused-exclusively%E2%80%99-on-the-next-mass-effect.1347247/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTIz"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Jay Peters</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a senior reporter covering technology, gaming, and more. He joined The Verge in 2019 after nearly two years at Techmeme.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>It’s been five years since BioWare first announced it was working on <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/7/21554092/bioware-new-mass-effect-game-announced-n7-day">a brand new <em>Mass Effect</em> game</a>. But today, November 7th (N7 Day), BioWare shared a promising sign of life: the BioWare team is “heads-down and focused exclusively” on the game, according to its executive producer.</p><p>“We have a lot of universe to cover, lots of features to build, and lots of romances to figure out.” <a href="https://blog.bioware.com/2025/11/07/n7-day-2025/">Mike Gamble says</a>. “We’re excited by what we’re building, and we promise you: when we’re ready, it’ll be a lot of fun to show.” Gamble also addresses “the rumors lately,” perhaps referencing concerns about the series’s future if <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/787723/ea-private-deal-buyout-future-games-layoffs">the deal to take EA private</a> goes through. “You’ve made it clear you care deeply about what’s next. So let’s start by setting the record straight: the next <em>Mass Effect</em> game is in development, and EA and BioWare remain committed to telling more stories in this universe.</p><p>The blog post has some info about the upcoming <em>Mass Effect</em> TV series BioWare is <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/7/24290596/mass-effect-tv-show-amazon-fallout">working on with Amazon</a>, too. “The writers room is going strong, and we’ve got a lot figured out about how it fits within the <em>Mass Effect</em> canon, and where it sits in respect to the new game,” Gamble says. “The show will explore a brand-new story within the universe’s timeline, and will be set after the original trilogy. It won’t be a retread of Commander Shepard’s story – because after all … that’s YOUR story, isn’t it?”</p><p>As someone who finally finished the original trilogy last year thanks to the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22256806/mass-effect-legendary-edition-pc-ps4-xbox-one-mac-walters-release-date"><em>Legendary Edition</em></a>, I’m looking forward to what’s next for the series. Fingers crossed we don’t have to wait until next year’s N7 Day to hear more about the next game.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTIz"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Jay Peters</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/816555/bioware-mass-effect-5-development-focused-tv-show-amazon-n7-day]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>