<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 11:24:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite is getting Unity games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/report/823233/fortnite-epic-games-unity-creators-developers-tim-sweeney-matt-bromberg</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-is-getting-unity-games.1357636/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Epic Games is teaming up with arguably its biggest game development rival, Unity, to bring games made using Unity’s engine into <em>Fortnite</em>. The change will mean that Unity games could sit alongside Epic’s own suite of experiences as well as those created by third-party developers using the Unreal Editor for <em>Fortnite</em> — and it opens the door for significantly more games to be available to play within <em>Fortnite</em>.</p><p>“Just like the early days of the web, we believe that companies need to work together in order to build the open metaverse in a way that’s interoperable and fair,” Epic Games CEO Tim Sweeney says in a statement. “Working alongside Unity we’re helping developers build fun games, reach bigger audiences, and find success.”</p><p>The change represents an important step in Epic’s long-running vision of turning <em>Fortnite</em> into an open metaverse that’s a big 3D social space with a huge number of experiences to participate in with your friends. Epic has been marching down this path for years with <em>Fortnite</em> itself by putting an increased focus on <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/3/28/23659492/fortnite-creator-economy-2-0-epic-games-catch">creator-made experiences</a> and making browsing through those experiences in the Fortnite lobby feel like <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/10/11/23912919/fortnite-creator-made-maps-youtube-redesign">scrolling YouTube</a>. You can even check out experiences on the web — and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/19/24223669/fortnites-item-shop-is-now-on-the-web-too">buy new <em>Fortnite</em> outfits in your browser, too</a>.</p><p>Right now, <em>Fortnite</em> is a closed ecosystem, meaning that creators can only make games for the platform using Epic’s tools, can’t (yet) easily drop those games into Unreal Engine to bring them to other platforms, or bring experiences built on other engines into <em>Fortnite</em>. But even <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/3/23/23652928/tim-sweeney-interview-epic-games-fortnite-metaverse">in 2023</a>, Tim Sweeney was telling <em>The Verge</em> how much he believed in the future of interoperable game engines being key to his vision.</p><p>Epic has had some success expanding <em>Fortnite</em> from being a battle royale into a broad, <em>Roblox</em>-like ecosystem with games from outside creators. By the end of last year, it <a href="https://www.fortnite.com/news/fortnite-ecosystem-2024-year-in-review-celebrating-creators-and-looking-ahead?lang=en-US">had 70,000 total creators</a> that published nearly 200,000 “islands,” or <em>Fortnite</em>’s term for experiences. But the Unity Editor, which is designed to help developers build their games once and run them across multiple platforms, has more than <a href="https://unity.com/our-company">1.2 <em>million</em> monthly active users</a>. Even a fraction of those developers also bringing their games to <em>Fortnite</em> could add a lot to the platform.</p><p>The plan is to allow Unity games to come to <em>Fortnite</em> next year, Matt Bromberg, President and CEO of Unity, tells <em>The Verge.</em></p><p>The partnership potentially gives developers another potential avenue to find an audience and monetize their games, which could be a lifeline for smaller developers amid continued <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24172733/summer-game-fest-video-game-announcements-layoffs-labor-live-service-fortnite">industry struggles</a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/22/24349728/gdc-state-of-the-industry-survey-2025-results">layoffs</a>. It could also consolidate even more power into <em>Fortnite</em>, which is already a behemoth. But Sweeney actually envisions a world for <em>Fortnite</em> that’s much more decentralized — more like the open web.</p><p>“<em>Fortnite</em>’s still this big thing operated by Epic completely,” Sweeney says. “But there will be a day when you can, from the program that’s currently called <em>Fortnite</em>, go to other sites that are completely controlled by other companies. We have nothing to do with them. We make no revenue from them. We don’t have commercial agreements with them. They’re just like websites on the web.” Today’s news with Unity is the first opportunity for “the rubber to meet the road” of engines that are operating together.</p><p>For now, whether a creator makes a <em>Fortnite</em> experience using <em>Fortnite</em>’s tools or with Unity, Sweeney says there will be a review process to ensure that it’s “ratings-compliant and works adequately.” But in the future, “as this evolves into a completely open system, we’d only have reviews for stuff that we host, and anybody would be able to put anything anywhere, and people would be able to browse to it like you do in a web browser today.”</p><p>Allowing Unity games will “greatly expand the developer base,” Sweeney says. “The challenge of building content in <em>Fortnite</em> today is you start from scratch.” You can’t currently take an Unreal Engine game and deploy it into <em>Fortnite</em> — that’s something that Epic is <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/5/24262376/epic-unreal-engine-6-fortnite-metaverse-plans">aiming for with Unreal Engine 6</a>, which is likely years away. Ironically, Sweeney says, “publishing Unity games into <em>Fortnite</em> will happen before publishing standalone Unreal Engine games into <em>Fortnite</em>.”</p><p>There’s a second component to today’s news, too: Unity will bring support for Unreal Engine to the commerce management platform <a href="https://unity.com/news/unity-launches-native-cross-platform-commerce-management-for-game-developers-worldwide">it announced last month</a>, which lets developers manage their digital storefronts across many platforms from all inside Unity Engine. That was pitched at the time as a way to make it much easier to deal with the complexities of different storefronts and payment processors.</p><p>Bringing support for Unreal Engine to the platform gives developers “more choice around how they build stores and how they manage those stores,” Bromberg says. “Ultimately, I think the thing that Tim and I couldn’t agree any more strongly on is that having more choice and more places where developers can build things and giving them more control over their destinies is the most important thing we can do to help the gaming ecosystem.”</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTIz"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Jay Peters</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/report/823233/fortnite-epic-games-unity-creators-developers-tim-sweeney-matt-bromberg]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>