<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 22:20:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valve will officially let you install SteamOS on other handhelds as soon as this April]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/7/24338405/valve-steamos-beta-other-handhelds-beyond-steam-deck</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valve-will-officially-let-you-install-steamos-on-other-handhelds-as-soon-as-this-april.1076505/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/7/24338405/valve-steamos-beta-other-handhelds-beyond-steam-deck<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>SteamOS was <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24315098/valve-steam-machines-steamos-steam-deck-vr">always supposed to be bigger</a> than Valve’s own Steam Deck, and 2025 is the year it finally expands. Not only will Lenovo ship <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/7/24338028/lenovo-legion-go-s-steam-windows">the first third-party SteamOS handheld</a> this May, Valve has now revealed it will let you install a working copy of SteamOS on <em>other </em>handhelds even sooner than that. </p><p>Pierre-Loup Griffais, one of the lead designers on the Steam Deck and SteamOS, tells me a beta for other handhelds “is slated to ship after March sometime,” and that you might discover the OS <em>just starts working properly</em> after that happens! </p><p>Griffais and his co-designer Lawrence Yang would not confirm which handhelds might just start working, though there are some obvious candidates: <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/13/24219469/valve-steamos-asus-rog-ally-steady-progress-dual-boot">the company confirmed to us in August</a> that it had been adding support for the Asus ROG Ally’s controls. </p><p>Also, quite a few PC gamers have also discovered that <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/30/24329005/bazzite-asus-rog-ally-x-steam-os-editorial">Bazzite, a fork of Valve’s Steam Deck experience that I loved testing on an Ally X</a> and vastly preferred to Windows, also works wonderfully on the Lenovo Legion Go. There still aren’t that many handhelds out there at the end of the day, and I would think Valve would take advantage of work the Linux gaming community has already done on both.</p><p>Speaking of Bazzite, Valve seems to be flattered! “We have nothing against it,” says Yang. “It’s a great community project that delivers a lot of value to people that want a similar experience on devices right now,” says Griffais, adding later “In a lot of ways Bazzite is a good way to kind of get the latest and greatest of what we’ve been working on, and test it.” </p><p>But he says Bazzite isn’t yet in a state where a hardware manufacturer could preload it on a handheld, nor would Valve allow that. While users can freely download and install the SteamOS image onto their own devices, companies aren’t allowed to sell it or modify it, and must partner with Valve first.</p><p>There are some non-selfish reasons for that. Among other things, Griffais explains that the Lenovo Legion Go S will run the same SteamOS image as the Steam Deck itself, taking advantage of the same software updates and the same precached shaders that let games load and run more smoothly, just with added hardware compatibility tweaks. Valve wants to make sure SteamOS is a single platform, not a fragmented one.</p><p>“In general, we just want to make sure we have a good pathway to work together on things like firmware updates and you can get to things like the boot manager and the BIOS and things like that in a semi-standardized fashion, right?” says Griffais, regarding what Valve needs to see in a partnership that would officially ship SteamOS on other devices.</p><p>Valve isn’t currently partnered with any other companies beyond Lenovo to do that collaboration — Yang tells me the company is <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24337913/no-valve-isnt-working-with-gpd-to-bring-steamos-to-its-handheld"><em>not</em> working with GPD on official SteamOS support</a>, despite that manufacturer’s claim. </p><p>Valve’s also not promising that whichever Windows handheld you have will necessarily run SteamOS perfectly — in a <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.steampowered.com%2Fnews%2Fapp%2F593110%2Fview%2F529834914570306831">new blog post</a>, Valve only confirms that a beta will ship before Lenovo’s Legion Go S, that it “should improve the experience on other devices,” and that users “can download and test this themselves.”</p><p>As far as other form factors, like possible SteamOS living room boxes, Valve says you might have a good experience trying that. And partnerships are a possibility there too: “if someone wants to bring that to the market and preload SteamOS on it, we’d be happy to talk to them.”</p><p>Valve wouldn’t tell me anything about the rumors that it’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/2024/11/19/24300757/valve-steam-controller-2-roy-deckard-leak">developing its own Steam Controller 2, VR headset with wands</a>, and possibly its own living room box, but did tell me that we “might expect more Steam Input compatible controllers in the future.”</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>