<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 09:44:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals’ US team is undergoing layoffs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/614819/marvel-rivals-us-layoffs-netease</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals%E2%80%99-us-team-is-undergoing-layoffs.1112793/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/614819/marvel-rivals-us-layoffs-netease<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/ash-parrish">Ash Parrish</a> <span>is a reporter who covers the business, culture, and communities of video games, with a focus on marginalized gamers and the quirky, horny culture of video game communities.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p><em>Marvel Rivals</em>, the <em>Overwatch </em><em>2</em>-lunch-eating multiplayer shooter that boasted <a href="https://x.com/MarvelRivals/status/1869080172814848471">20 million players</a> within days of its December 2024 launch, has laid off an unspecified number of employees in its US operations, according to separate posts by recently laid off employees on LinkedIn.</p><div><p>“Welp, just got laid off from my job working on Marvel Rivals with NetEase,” <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/jack-burrows-b7896399_opentowork-yacantwinthemall-activity-7297445172118724608-mTi7?utm_source=social_share_send&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop_web&amp;rcm=ACoAAA9BgVwBB0XYHn1NW6Tz1QOci2RGVfq4ykg">wrote level designer Jack Burrows</a>.</p></div><p>“My stellar, talented team just helped deliver an incredibly successful new franchise in Marvel Rivals for NetEase Games... and were just laid off!” <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/thadsasser_this-is-such-a-weird-industry-my-stellar-activity-7297672154060361729-xYIX?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;rcm=ACoAAA9BgVwBB0XYHn1NW6Tz1QOci2RGVfq4ykg">wrote Thaddeus Sasser</a>, a game director at NetEase.</p><p><em>The Verge</em> has reached out to NetEase for comment on the scope and reason for the layoffs. </p><p>One way players have reacted to the news by lodging complaints via user reviews on Steam, voicing their anger that NetEase would lay off the team responsible for a game so evidently popular. Out of the roughly 1,000 reviews posted today, more than 300 have been negative.</p><p>Along with <em>Palworld</em> and <em>Helldivers 2</em>, <em>Marvel Rivals </em>has proved one of the standouts in a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/3/24312584/ubisoft-xdefiant-shutting-down-refunds">series </a>of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/4/24235163/concord-cancellation-live-service-games">live-service</a> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/9/24317407/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league-final-season-offline-mode">flops</a> in the face of stiff competition from entrenched live-service games like <em>Call of Duty</em> and <em>Fortnite</em>. It’s in the <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3lihyilygps2s">top 5 games</a> based on weekly active users across Xbox, PlayStation, and Steam and it’s currently sitting at number three on <a href="https://steamdb.info/charts/">Steam’s most-played games chart</a>. And yet, apparently, that wild success wasn’t enough to insulate its US team from layoffs.</p><p>Sasser vocalized the disconnect in his LinkedIn post, writing, “This is such a weird industry…”</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rockstar’s working on bringing Roblox creators to GTA VI]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/614743/gta-vi-user-generated-content-roblox-fortnite</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rockstar%E2%80%99s-working-on-bringing-roblox-creators-to-gta-vi.1112715/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/614743/gta-vi-user-generated-content-roblox-fortnite<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/ash-parrish">Ash Parrish</a> <span>is a reporter who covers the business, culture, and communities of video games, with a focus on marginalized gamers and the quirky, horny culture of video game communities.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>With <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/607885/gta-vi-is-still-coming-this-fall"><em>GTA VI</em> looming over the fall 2025 release schedule</a>, a new report from <a href="https://digiday.com/media/rockstar-games-talks-with-top-metaverse-creators-with-an-eye-on-making-grand-theft-auto-the-next-creator-platform/"><em>Digiday</em></a> claims that Rockstar is going all-in on user-generated content. According to the report, the developer is having discussions with <em>Fortnite, Roblox</em>, and <em>GTA</em> creators about making “custom experiences” inside what’s shaping up to be the biggest gaming release since the last <em>Grand Theft Auto</em> game launched way (<em>way</em>) back in 2013.</p><p>That Rockstar has made user-generated content part of its strategy for <em>GTA VI</em> should come as no surprise. Despite the last <em>GTA</em> launching over ten years ago (same with <em>GTA Online</em>), interest in the game <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/23/20880410/twitch-gta-nopixel-role-play-best-grand-theft-auto-v">has stayed fresh with the help of mods</a> like FiveM that allow users to host and join their own multiplayer servers. </p><p>Rockstar <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/rockstar-responds-to-grand-theft-auto-mod-ban-complaint/">initially banned some of the creators of FiveM</a> back in 2015, citing that their mod was “an unauthorized alternate multiplayer service that contains code designed to facilitate piracy.” However, as the popularity of the kinds of games and role-playing enabled by FiveM and similar mods grew, Rockstar reversed course. In 2023, the company acquired Cfx.re, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/8/11/23828431/rockstar-cfx-re-mod-tools-roleplay-server">the team that developed FiveM</a>.</p><p>Games like <em>Fortnite</em>, <em>Roblox</em>, and <em>Minecraft</em> remain at the top of US sales charts years after their release thanks to the popularity of user-generated content. Arranging deals with creators prior to its launch will help <em>GTA VI</em> hit the ground running in a crowded marketplace.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>