<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - theverge_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/theverge_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for theverge_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 16:38:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You can still score a PlayStation 5 for as low as $374 for Black Friday]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/30/24308967/black-friday-2024-playstation-5-ps5-slim-digital-edition-disc-cyber-monday</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/you-can-still-score-a-playstation-5-for-as-low-as-374-for-black-friday.1048572/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/30/24308967/black-friday-2024-playstation-5-ps5-slim-digital-edition-disc-cyber-monday<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Sony and other game makers are running all kinds of Black Friday sales right now, allowing you to save on games, consoles, and plenty of accessories. However, one of the better offers still available is on the latest<strong> PlayStation 5 Digital Edition</strong>, which is on sale at <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSony-PlayStation-5-PS5-Digital-Console-Slim%2F5113183757">Walmart</a>, <a href="https://howl.link/ow8vdkonq4ogj">Best Buy</a>, and Sony’s <a href="https://direct.playstation.com/en-us/buy-consoles/playstation5-digital-edition-console-model-group-slim">PlayStation Direct storefront</a> for an all-time low of $374 ($75 off). It’s also available at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/PlayStation%C2%AE5-Digital-slim-PlayStation-5/dp/B0DJHG2VVS?tag=theverge02-20">Amazon</a> as part of a <em>Fortnite</em> bundle that includes some in-game cosmetics and other freebies.</p><p>Alternatively, if you prefer your console to come with its disc drive (instead of having to potentially add one later), you can get a <strong>disc-ready PS5</strong> for $424 (regularly $499) at <a href="https://howl.link/a96z6zpacc2ax">Best Buy</a>, <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSony-PlayStation-5-PS5-Disc-Console-Slim%2F5113183756">Walmart</a>, <a href="https://direct.playstation.com/en-us/buy-consoles/playstation5-console-model-group-slim">PlayStation Direct</a>, and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/PlayStation%C2%AE5-Digital-slim-PlayStation-5/dp/B0DJHF6Q9Z?th=1&amp;tag=theverge02-20">Amazon</a> (in that same <em>Fortnite</em> bundle). <a href="https://direct.playstation.com/en-us/">According to Sony’s listing</a>, the ongoing promo should last through the holidays. So, while you may have time to mull it over, there’s no guarantee your preferred retailer (or the one you collect rewards points from) will have it in stock the whole time.</p><div><p>The PlayStation 5 Digital doesn’t come with a disc drive, but you can buy one separately if you later decide you want one. The console otherwise plays all of the same games as the version equipped with a disc drive.</p></div><div><p>Sony’s new standard PlayStation 5 includes a removable disc drive, dual front-facing USB-C ports, 1TB of storage, and a slightly smaller and lighter design.</p></div><p>The PS5 has been with us for more than four years now, so it’s built up an expansive lineup of 4K-capable games and now offers a little something for everyone. It may not seem as special now that the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/reviews/24289319/ps5-pro-review">PS5 Pro</a> is out, but at this discounted price, the PS5 “slim” is almost half the cost of a $699 Pro (and even with the Pro, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/10/24240906/sony-ps5-pro-disc-drive-separate-price">you don’t get a disc drive</a>).</p><p>The regular PS5s may not have the same level of graphical performance as the Pro, but in the end, they all play the same games. And if you’re not the type to notice or care about the tiniest of details when it comes to resolution, frame rate, or extras like raytraced lighting,  the difference between a PS5 and PS5 Pro may not be very stark.</p><div><form><div><h2>Verge Deals</h2><p> / <span>Sign up for Verge Deals to get deals on products we've tested sent to your inbox weekly.</span></p></div></form></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom has dropped to $30 for the first time]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/29/24309019/black-friday-2024-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-totk-nintendo-switch-cyber-monday</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-has-dropped-to-30-for-the-first-time.1048434/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/29/24309019/black-friday-2024-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-totk-nintendo-switch-cyber-monday<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Significant discounts on first-party Nintendo Switch games can be notoriously difficult to come by, particularly on landmark titles like <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/3/2/14787082/the-legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-review"><em><strong>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</strong></em></a>. However, that trend seems to be shifting with Black Friday, as last year’s Game of the Year contender has dropped to just $30 ($40 off) at <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FThe-Legend-of-Zelda-Tears-of-the-Kingdom-Nintendo-Switch%2F3416965843">Walmart</a> for a limited time, beating its previous low by $10.</p><p>Nintendo’s action-adventure RPG presents a familiar premise: you’re ultimately chasing after the malevolent Ganon in hopes of saving Princess Zelda and protecting the kingdom of Hyrule. But wait, didn’t we do that in the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/3/2/14787082/the-legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-review">last game</a> and many before it? How could she <em>possibly</em> fall into that predicament yet again? I’ll leave you to uncover the details, but let’s just say there’s enough timeline shifting to make Doctor Strange blush. </p><div><p><em>Tears of the Kingdom </em>is the latest installment in the <em>Zelda </em>franchise. The storyline and gameplay are similar to <em>Breath of the Wild</em>’s<em>, </em>but enough has changed to make Link’s return to Hyrule plenty special. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23718926/zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-review-nintendo-switch">Read our review</a>.</p></div><p>You’ll have tons to do around the realm in pursuit of her safety, too. There are plenty of puzzling shrines to complete, weapons to collect, and open regions to explore, including floating islands and harrowing subsurface caverns. It’s a familiar trek on the surface, but there are enough changes and secrets to keep it feeling fresh if you’ve played the equally impressive <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/3/2/14787082/the-legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-review"><em>The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild</em></a>.</p><p>What you can’t find in the wild, you’ll probably be able to craft using an imaginative system that lets you leverage anything you can stuff into your inventory. Link also has a few new tricks up his sleeve to aid in combat and traversal, including teleportation and the ability to alchemically phase through walls and objects. If you could have just one game hold you over until Nintendo launches the heavily rumored<a href="https://www.theverge.com/24051677/nintendo-switch-2-pro-rumors-news"> Switch 2</a>, <em>Tears of the Kingdom </em>is it.</p><div><form><div><h2>Verge Deals</h2><p> / <span>Sign up for Verge Deals to get deals on products we've tested sent to your inbox weekly.</span></p></div></form></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Leak: Intel’s Battlemage desktop GPUs are just days away]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/29/24309086/intel-battlemage-gpu-leak-arc-b580-b570</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/leak-intel%E2%80%99s-battlemage-desktop-gpus-are-just-days-away.1048422/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/29/24309086/intel-battlemage-gpu-leak-arc-b580-b570<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Under financial pressures, Intel’s desktop gaming graphics business <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/1/24285513/intel-ceo-lunar-lake-one-off-memory-package-discrete-gpu#:~:text=Unfortunately%20for%20PC%20graphics%20enthusiasts">may be on the chopping block</a> — but it seems that a pair of Battlemages will escape unscathed. <a href="https://videocardz.com/newz/exclusive-intel-arc-battlemage-to-launch-december-12th"><em>Videocardz</em> is reporting</a> that Intel will announce the Arc B580 and B570 graphics cards just days from now on December 3rd, and launch them on December 12th alongside media reviews. </p><p>You shouldn’t expect these card to compete at the high-end. Far from it, based on leaked specs that suggest they have fewer cores, less memory, and less memory bandwidth than some of their Intel predecessors. </p><p>But they could also be a value leader. Retailer leaks <a href="https://x.com/momomo_us/status/1861788237456711881">spotted by Momomo_us</a> suggest Intel’s own “Limited Edition” Arc B580 could cost just $250. </p><p>While no confirmed specs have surfaced just yet, <a href="https://www.hardwareluxx.de/index.php/news/hardware/grafikkarten/64956-intel-arc-battlemage-amazon-f%C3%BChrt-asrock-intel-arc-b580-steel-legend.html">one particular GPU leak on Amazon</a> suggested that the B580 will feature 20 Xe2 cores, a 2.8GHz GPU clock, 12GB of GDDR6 graphics memory at 19Gbps with a 192-bit memory interface, and require as little as two axial fans and one single 8-pin PCIe power connector (though another variant was spotted with three fans and two connectors.) They may also connect to a motherboard with a PCIe 5.0 x8 connector.</p><p>If <em>Videocardz</em> is correct, we won’t have to speculate for long: full confirmed details should arrive this Tuesday. </p><p>It’d be nice to see the lower end of the GPU market get shaken up a bit. What with the pandemic, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/7/1/23191634/nvidia-amd-gpu-shortage-over-3080-3070-3060-radeon-rx-6900-6800">the great GPU shortage</a>, and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/5/24/23734022/nvidia-rtx-4060-ti-amd-rx-7600-gpu-graphics-card-benchmark-test">its aftermath</a>, it’s been a while since big GPU boosts have felt affordable. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>