<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 10:12:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nioh 3 Sells 1M Copies, Is the Fastest-Selling Game in the Series; Franchise Reaches 10M Units Sold]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nioh-3-sells-1m-copies-fastest-selling-game-series/</link>
            <guid>1441435</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>This morning, <strong>KOEI TECMO</strong> and <strong>TEAM NINJA</strong> announced that <strong>Nioh 3</strong> has already become a <strong>million-seller</strong> and is, to date, <strong>the fastest-selling game in the action RPG series</strong>. We previously had a glimpse of the game's early success in its concurrent player peak on Steam, <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/nioh-3-is-here-and-in-just-3-hours-it-became-the-most-played-nioh-game-on-steam/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">which far surpassed its predecessors'</a></strong>.</p>



<p>Another side is the very strong critical reception, which is being celebrated with a dedicated accolades trailer that <strong>prominently features our own review score (9.8/10)</strong>. Earlier this month, Francesco De Meo <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/nioh-3-review-rise-of-the-shogun/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">explained in great detail</a> why he felt <strong>Nioh 3 is the Japanese developer's best work yet</strong>:</p>



<p><em>Nioh 3 is the culmination of Team NINJA’s evolution. By masterfully blending the engaging exploration of an open-field structure with a deep, dual-style combat system that bridges the gap between 'Masocore' and character-action, it has evolved into a genre of its own. While technical issues hold the game back, it is the definitive samurai fantasy and a modern masterpiece of action design.</em></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Nioh 3 - Accolades Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-RMpMyfitco?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>The only real downsides are the performance issues, although that's not exactly surprising given that <strong>KOEI TECMO and TEAM NINJA have historically always struggled in this area</strong>. In Wccftech's technical analysis and graphics tuning guide, Sebastian Castellanos <a href="https://wccftech.com/how-to/nioh-3-pc-graphics-tuning-guide-how-to-get-the-best-experience-on-pc/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">wrote</a>:</p>



<p><em>Frankly, Nioh 3 underwhelms when it comes to its achieved balance between visual fidelity and performance — and that’s disappointing for a AAA PC title released in 2026. Despite generally strong reviews for its combat systems and world design, the PC port still carries forward some of the same technical shortcomings that plagued previous Team Ninja releases: subpar optimization on both the CPU and GPU, and an engine that struggles to present a stable experience unless the game is locked to fixed framerates.</em></p>



<p><em>The Katana Engine’s sensitivity to non-standard framerates results in noticeable judder and uneven camera motion when your framerate isn't holding at a steady framerate figure, and many players are still reporting performance issues even on fairly powerful hardware. These issues are not minor tweaking details — they are foundational to the core gameplay feel, and it’s frankly unacceptable that a AAA 2026 PC release ships in this state, requiring players to lock framerates or rely heavily on upscaling/frame generation just to achieve a semblance of stability.</em></p>



<p><em>In short, while Nioh 3 unquestionably has depth and quality in its combat and systems, those strengths are strongly let down by a technical package that feels unfinished and insufficiently optimized. In the modern PC landscape — where much better-looking titles offer solid uncapped performance, smooth frametimes, and correct behavior with fluctuating framerates — Nioh 3 feels like a step backward. Until game updates from Team Ninja or community mods address these issues in a meaningful way, getting a truly impressive visuals to performance balance out of this game remains an uphill battle.</em></p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/nioh-3-sells-1m-copies-fastest-selling-game-series/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>