<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 11:27:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wuchang: Fallen Feathers Has Been Upgraded to Unreal Engine 5 for Improved Quality and Performance]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/wuchang-fallen-feathers-has-been-upgraded-to-unreal-engine-5-for-improved-quality-and-performance/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wuchang-fallen-feathers-has-been-upgraded-to-unreal-engine-5-for-improved-quality-and-performance.1105611/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/wuchang-fallen-feathers-has-been-upgraded-to-unreal-engine-5-for-improved-quality-and-performance/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Following the new gameplay footage <a href="https://wccftech.com/wuchang-fallen-feathers-looks-promising-in-new-gameplay-video/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">shared last month</a>, Leenzee Games has <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=53KnH8qJDXI" target="_blank" rel="noopener">released</a> a developer diary for its upcoming game Wuchang: Fallen Feathers.</p>
<p>Producer Xia Siyuan introduced a new video that delves into the game's lore. Afterward, he talked about game mechanics and even some technical details. For example, we received confirmation that the game is now running on Unreal Engine 5:</p>
<p><em>Wuchang: Fallen Feathers has been upgraded from Unreal Engine 4 to UE5. This brings significant improvements in visual and technical performance. Realistic lighting, scanned models, and physics-based effects, along with a more robust game framework, create a more immersive game experience. This upgrade also allows us to better showcase the cultural essence we aimed to convey.</em></p>
<p>On the combat system, Siyuan said:</p>
<p><em>Skyborn Might represents the power of the Feathered clan, the ability to control over karma. As the core of the game's combat system, Skyborn Might seamlessly blends combo mechanics with RPG builds. The game features five weapon types, with 25 unique weapons spread across these categories. Each weapon offers distinct combat style and combo techniques. Players can equip both a main weapon and a secondary one. Switching weapons and quickly unleashing weapon skills further extend the combo chains.</em></p>
<p><em>The game features 40 different spells, which can be assigned to four spell slots. Players can integrate spells into their weapon combos or choose to forgo weapon combos entirely and create their own spell-focused combat style. We encourage players to build their own unique playstyles. At the Shrine, players can freely try out different weapon skills, discipline skills, and spell combinations without any cost.</em></p>
<p>Wuchang: Fallen Feathers is undoubtedly one of the most promising action RPG games of 2025. Published by 505 Games, it will be released for PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series S|X. It has also been confirmed that the game will be added to the Game Pass subscription service from its launch day.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delta Force Black Hawk Down Campaign to Launch on February 21]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/delta-force-black-hawk-down-campaign-to-launch-on-february-21/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/delta-force-black-hawk-down-campaign-to-launch-on-february-21.1105602/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/delta-force-black-hawk-down-campaign-to-launch-on-february-21/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>TiMi Studio's Team Jade has announced the release date for Delta Force Black Hawk Down. The first-person shooter game's campaign mode will be available on PC starting on February 21 at 02:00 UTC+0.</p>
<p>The Black Hawk Down mode will be added to Delta Force, which <a href="https://wccftech.com/delta-force-gets-pc-open-beta-test-on-december-5-console-due-next-year/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">launched</a> in early December as a free to play Open Beta. So far, though, the game hasn't exactly thrived. On Steam, the average score for recent user reviews is at a meager 63%, while the average score for overall user reviews is at 68%. We'll know soon if this new mode, which will be playable solo or in co-op, can turn it around for Team Jade.</p>
<p><iframe title="Delta Force | Official Black Hawk Down Teaser - Launch on February 21" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pXnHhjWNxds?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The Delta Force campaign will put players and their squad in the thick of battle, inspired by the iconic Black Hawk Down film and 2003 video game. Powered by Unreal Engine 5, the campaign is designed to test the combat skills and teamwork of the squad. These are the official features shared by the development team:</p>
<ul>
<li><em><strong>A LEGENDARY BATTLE, REIMAGINED</strong> - Powered by Unreal Engine 5, BLACK HAWK DOWN delivers stunning visuals that immerse you in Mogadishu like never before. With an unprecedented level of detail and a diverse range of missions, every corner of the city tells a story, and every encounter feels visceral and real.</em></li>
<li><em><strong>TEST YOUR LIMITS</strong> - It takes courage, determination, and sacrifice to become a legend. BLACK HAWK DOWN is the ultimate test of skill, demanding everything you've got. This isn't a shooting gallery - it's war. Every turn could be your last, and survival is never guaranteed.</em></li>
<li><em><strong>A FAITHFUL REBOOT</strong> - The BLACK HAWK DOWN co-op campaign is a faithful reboot of the classic 2001 film and a heartfelt love letter to fans of the original 2003 Delta Force: Black Hawk Down, breathing new life into those legendary stories and moments.</em></li>
<li><em><strong>PLAY AS A TEAM</strong> - Only the best squads survive. Choose your class, customize your loadout, and, most importantly, move as a unit to overcome the unprecedented challenges ahead.</em></li>
</ul>
<p>Are you eager to check out Black Hawk Down in Delta Force?</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>