<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 08:40:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NCSOFT Says Horizon Steel Frontiers Could Launch as Early as Next Year, and Its Early Reception Has Been Great]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ncsoft-says-horizon-steel-frontiers-could-launch-as-early-as-next-year/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ncsoft-says-horizon-steel-frontiers-could-launch-as-early-as-next-year-and-its-early-reception-has-been-great.1352185/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>This morning, South Korean developer NCSOFT (Lineage, Aion, Throne and Liberty) took the stage at G-Star 2025 to <a href="https://wccftech.com/horizon-steel-frontiers-is-a-full-fledged-mmorpg-for-pc-and-mobile/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announce</a> the long-rumored Horizon Steel Frontiers MMORPG. The game, which is targeting a launch on PC and mobile, is a collaboration between the studio and franchise holder Guerrilla Games.</p>



<p>The announcement provided a few initial and fairly vague details, such as the region (the Deadlands, modeled after Arizona and New Mexico) the game will take place in, the fact that players will cooperate to take down machines but also compete for resources and fight against rival tribes, and the tweaks made to the combat system. The developers claim there will be new mechanics, such as climbing onto a damaged machine part with the Pullcaster to set traps and inflict status effects, picking up weapons dropped during battle, carrying them on your mount, and using them at a later time. Perhaps the biggest difference shown in the debut Horizon Steel Frontiers gameplay, though, is the addition of greatswords. Whereas Aloy only ever used a spear for melee while heavily favoring bows, it looks like this game will allow proper melee combat with parries and counterattacks.</p>



<p>What neither the announcement video nor the official press release mentioned was any launch window. However, NCSOFT executives spoke about it two days ago during the company's <a href="https://irsvc.teletogether.com/ncsoft/ncsoft.php?c=ncsoft&amp;y=3230" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Q3 2025 earnings call</a>. They were confident that it could launch in 2026 or early 2027 and also boasted of having received acclaim from those who had already played it.</p>



<p><em>Internally, the development has progressed pretty significantly, so we think that based on the development progress, it would be available to be launched either next year or early two years from now, but we need to discuss the specifics with the IP holder. What I want to emphasize is that significant progress has been made in development, so with refinement, we will be able to release this title, too. Everyone gave us a round of applause after viewing the demonstration and playing the game firsthand.</em></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="[Horizon Steel Frontiers] Gameplay Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9qwAulK6db4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Of course, with game development becoming increasingly complex, especially for an MMORPG, I would say there's a solid chance we'll see it in 2027. Still, that NCSOFT thinks it could launch as early as next year suggests we could at least be able to try the game in pre-release testing events throughout 2026.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/ncsoft-says-horizon-steel-frontiers-could-launch-as-early-as-next-year/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horizon Steel Frontiers Is a Full-Fledged MMORPG for PC and Mobile]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/horizon-steel-frontiers-is-a-full-fledged-mmorpg-for-pc-and-mobile/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/horizon-steel-frontiers-is-a-full-fledged-mmorpg-for-pc-and-mobile.1352173/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Three years after <a href="https://wccftech.com/horizon-mmo-game-reportedly-in-the-works-supposedly-made-by-sony-and-ncsoft/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the first rumors on the project</a>, NCSOFT has now unveiled Horizon Steel Frontiers at G-Star 2025. This is a full-fledged MMORPG for PC (via the South Korean studio's PURPLE platform) and mobile (iOS and Android) based on Guerrilla Games' popular action/adventure franchise.</p>



<p>The announcement video features comments from Jan-Bart van Beek, now Studio Head at the Dutch developer, and also the person who came up with the original concept of Horizon. Van Beek says this is a version of the world that's meant to be played 'anywhere and at any time' (on mobile devices), and adds that Guerrilla was able to playtest the game and feels amazing about it, as it sports a unique identity that also fits with the universe. The Guerrilla Games Studio Head also seemed to hint that there will be PvP in addition to PvE:</p>



<p><em>You're sharing the frontier with thousands of other players, sometimes working together to take down machines, other times competing with rival tribes or fighting over resources. That mix of cooperation and competition creates moments that you could never script. At the heart of Horizon's story is the search for the balance between humanity, nature, and technology. And sometimes that's harmony, sometimes that's conflict, but it always creates a world filled with mystery and beauty.</em></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="[Horizon Steel Frontiers] Announcement Video" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bN-NNgWIyIQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>In the video, Sung-gu Lee, the Executive Producer of Horizon Steel Frontiers at NCSOFT, talked about tweaking the franchise's signature combat for an MMORPG:</p>



<p><em>Our main focus is designing a new combat experience tailored for an MMORPG. In Horizon Steel Frontiers, we’ve added unique, original gameplay elements to the process of taking down giant machines. For example, after destroying a specific part of a machine, you can quickly approach and climb onto it using a Pullcaster, set traps on the damaged part, and inflict status effects. During battle, you can even pick up weapons dropped by the machine, carry them on your mount, and use them in subsequent fights.</em></p>



<p><em>At the heart of giant machine hunts are two core values: cooperation and strategy. Players must take on their roles, act strategically, and work together seamlessly. These combat mechanics truly shine in large-scale battles, offering the scale and dynamism that only an MMORPG can provide.</em></p>



<p>Horizon Steel Frontiers will take place in a new area of the post-apocalyptic United States, known as the Deadlands, which is inspired by the landscapes of New Mexico and Arizona.</p>



<p>More details will undoubtedly follow. Meanwhile, you can find the official website <a href="https://hsf.plaync.com/en-us/conts/teaser" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">at this URL</a>.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/horizon-steel-frontiers-is-a-full-fledged-mmorpg-for-pc-and-mobile/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>