<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 11:16:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rust Director Just Offered Amazon $25 Million to Get New World and Keep It Alive]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/rust-director-offered-amazon-25-million-to-get-new-world/</link>
            <guid>1408018</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>It didn't take long for <strong>Amazon</strong> to decide when <strong>New World</strong> would be taken offline. As you might remember, the gaming division of the giant corporation <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/new-world-gets-killed-off-amazon-just-as-people-were-returning/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced that no more content would be made for the game</a></strong> just three months ago, while also <a href="https://wccftech.com/amazon-game-studios-lord-of-the-rings-mmo-cancelled-again-amidst-mass-layoffs/">quietly </a><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/amazon-game-studios-lord-of-the-rings-mmo-cancelled-again-amidst-mass-layoffs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">canceling the in-development The Lord of the Rings MMO project</a></strong>.</p>



<p>Yesterday, Amazon <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-world-aeternum-delisted-go-offline-january-2027-amazon-game-studios/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">revealed</a> that New World had been delisted from stores, making it unavailable for new purchases, and clarified the date the servers will go offline forever: <strong>January 31, 2027</strong>.</p>



<p>While that's over a year away, having a definitive shutdown date is a particularly sad occurrence for any MMO. Unlike regular games, MMOs are actual virtual worlds inhabited by thousands of players on each server, creating permanent communities and social structures such as guilds. For some players, losing access is a bit like losing connection to places and people you've come to appreciate. That's why communities often fight to keep them alive one way or another. </p>



<p>That sentiment is indeed very strong for New World, which <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-world-horror-themed-nighthaven-looks-good-players-eager-dive-back/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">was doing better with the latest updates released by the developers</a> and was actually trending upward in player counts - just not as much as Amazon desired. The game's community has discussed ways to keep the game alive; there's precedent for it, chiefly with <strong>City of Heroes</strong>, the superhero-themed MMORPG created by <strong>Cryptic Studios</strong> and later acquired by <strong>NCSoft</strong>. When NCSoft shut down the game in 2012, fans spun up a private server, and the server code leak in <strong>April 2019</strong> led to multiple private servers. One in particular, called <strong>Homecoming</strong>, eventually emerged above all others, and NCSoft granted Homecoming an official license to host the game in 2024.</p>



<p>That was about the best outcome New World fans could hope for. However, in a veritable twist, <strong>Alistair McFarlane</strong>, COO and Company Director at <strong>Facepunch</strong> (the British developer behind <strong>Rust</strong> and <strong>Garry's Mod</strong>), <a href="https://x.com/Alistair_McF/status/2011894052128768316" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">tweeted</a> a <strong>$25 million 'offer'</strong> to purchase the game from Amazon, adding that 'games should never die'. </p>



<p>Needless to say, having an actual professional game studio pick up the game would be far better. Amazon also demonstrated they are not actually averse to the idea; as part of their mass gaming layoffs, <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-acquires-march-of-giants-moba-from-amazon/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">they sold the upcoming MOBA, <strong>March of Giants</strong>, to <strong>Ubisoft</strong></a>. The difference is that in that case, they sold the game alongside the development team based in Montréal, Canada, whereas most of the New World team is likely already gone. </p>



<p>This would make it hard for a game like New World to sustain itself over time. Unlike sandbox games like Rust or Garry's Mod, the MMO is mostly themepark-based, meaning it sustains itself on developer-made content rather than user-generated content. Even if it acquired the license, Facepunch <strong>would still have to build a small team to keep it going and add new content every once in a while</strong>.</p>



<p>We've reached out to Facepunch to ask whether McFarlane's offer was genuine in the first place and will update this story if and when they respond.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/rust-director-offered-amazon-25-million-to-get-new-world/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Nintendo Has Been Leaky. Maybe They Need a Plumber?’: New Potential Nintendo Switch 2 Model Discovered On Official Website]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-has-been-leaky-maybe-they-need-a-plumber-new-potential-nintendo-switch-2-model-discovered-on-official-website/</link>
            <guid>1407979</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Nintendo used to be one of the <strong>most secretive game companies around</strong>, and one of those that took the hardest stance against leakers, giving rise to the long-lasting joke that the <strong>company sends its household ninja warriors </strong>to take care of them. </p>



<p>Over the past few years, however, <strong data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)">a lot of information </strong><span><strong>about the company's systems and games has leaked online</strong>&nbsp;ahead of&nbsp;</span>official announcements, such as the <strong>Nintendo Switch 2</strong>, which had been an <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-design-ports-leak-developers-excited/">open secret</a></strong> long before its<strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-officially-revealed-with-a-new-trailer-dedicated-direct-confirmed-for-april/"> official reveal</a></strong> and release last year.</p>



<p>With so many leaks, one may think the Japanese company addressed the issue and <strong>tightened the lid</strong> on its future releases before their announcements, but this doesn't seem to be the case, as <strong>a possible new Nintendo Switch 2 model</strong> may have leaked online, and via one of the company's official websites, no less.</p>



<p>Bluesky user <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/dootsky.re"><strong>@dootsky.re</strong></a> confirmed to have discovered <strong>something interesting</strong>. <em>"On Nintendo's Account Portal, there's an unused model code under the name "OSM". (The Switch 2's model code is BEE.)"</em></p>



<p>In addition, the portal has images for every Switch model, and <strong>requesting OSM returns the image of a Nintendo Switch 2</strong>, which is confirmed not to be a random placeholder, as trying to get an image for any other combination of strings on the company's web service to generate icons returns an error message.</p>







<p>As the Bluesky user highlighted, <strong>the image for the Nintendo Switch 2 "OSM" model is the same used for the current system</strong>, so it shouldn't be used to speculate about which product OSM will be.</p>



<p>However, it's hard not to think about <strong>a Nintendo Switch 2 Lite</strong>, especially in light of what president Shuntaro Furukawa said earlier this month regarding the company's desire to make the system more accessible to people<em> "who pick up their first console when reaching a certain age." </em></p>



<p>With <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">current RAM shortages and price spikes</strong> <span data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">set </span>to&nbsp;affect many<strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed"> <a data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" href="https://wccftech.com/no-one-can-escape-memory-shortages-says-samsungs-co-ceo/">tech products,</a></strong> however, it remains to be seen <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">how much cheaper a Lite model would be</strong>, given that the current Nintendo Switch 2 model's price could increase if the situation doesn't normalize anytime soon.</p>



<p><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">'Nintendo has been very "leaky" over the last two years. Maybe they need a plumber?'</em> commented gamerweeb1 on the <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/potential-new-switch-2-model-osm-discovered-on-nintendos-internal-website.1407796/post-150113233"><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">ResetERA forums</strong></a>, echoing a common community sentiment with a joke. <span>Hopefully, this leak will amount to something interesting, as most of the company's leaks have in the past few years, or will, at least, make a certain plumber materialize,&nbsp;<a href="https://wccftech.com/review/super-mario-odyssey-unmissable-adventure/" target="_blank"><strong>who has been absent with his 3D adventures for quite a long time.</strong></a></span></p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-has-been-leaky-maybe-they-need-a-plumber-new-potential-nintendo-switch-2-model-discovered-on-official-website/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘We Won’t Implement GenAI Into Our Games Without Prior Notice’, Vows Granblue Developer Cygames]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/granblue-developer-cygames-responds-to-gen-ai-backlash/</link>
            <guid>1407937</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Japanese developer <strong>Cygames</strong>, known mainly for the <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/granblue-fantasy-relink-sold-2-million-units/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Granblue Fantasy</a></strong>, <strong>Shadowverse</strong>, and <strong>Umamusume: Pretty Derby</strong> franchises, has recently faced significant backlash from several of its otherwise staunch fans over the establishment of a subsidiary, <strong>Cygames AI Studio</strong>.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.cygames.co.jp/news/id-24704/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Announced last week</a>, Cygames AI Studio is a new division whose purpose is to pursue AI technology that creators can use safely and securely, drawing on the experience it has cultivated in game development. The company's goal is to build a '<strong>unique creative cycle</strong>' that goes beyond simply improving efficiency to expand creators' creativity. The announcement also mentioned that, with this new AI ​​Studio, Cygames will take on the challenge of creating new user experiences to realize its vision of being a company that '<strong>creates the best content</strong>.' As mentioned above, the news wasn't taken kindly by many of the studio's usual supporters. Now, the developer <a href="https://x.com/Cygames_EN/status/2011423481712517537?" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">has shared a public letter of apology</a> in which it vowed that <strong>no genAI assets have been used in their games</strong>, and that <strong>genAI wouldn't be implemented at all in their games</strong> without prior notice.</p>



<p><em>To all our Cygames fans and supporters, </em></p>



<p><em>Over the past few days, we've received numerous comments expressing anger and disappointment from many of you. This was because we released a simplified announcement in Japanese concerning the founding of Cygames AI Studio, Inc., without addressing any of the current problems and social debates surrounding generative AI. We sincerely apologize for the concern we've caused.</em></p>



<p><em>We would like to take this opportunity to state that art produced from genAI isn't used in our products. Furthermore, we won't implement genAI into our products without prior notice. We hold in the highest regard those who love games, as well as the dignity, passion, and heart of the creators and artists who act as the architects of gaming culture. The art for all current Cygames games and other products is crafted from the technical know-how and manual work of our many staff members.</em></p>



<p><em>Once again, we deeply apologize for causing our beloved fans much grief and anxiety. We at Cygames will continue to honor creators, as well as champion the free expression of people, and, in doing so, will continue to strive to be the best in entertainment. Thank you for your continued support.</em></p>



<p>The Japanese developer is only the latest to become embroiled in controversy over genAI. The most famous case recently was undoubtedly <strong>Larian</strong>'s: when studio founder and CEO <strong>Swen Vincke</strong> mentioned in an interview that they had been experimenting with genAI to quickly develop concept art and write placeholder text <a href="https://wccftech.com/divinity-is-a-turn-based-rpg-will-be-way-better-than-baldurs-gate-3-says-larian/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">while working on the new <strong>Divinity</strong> game</a>, a massive backlash ensued, forcing Vincke and Larian as a whole to first say that <a href="https://wccftech.com/larian-studios-ceo-says-a-lot-has-become-lost-in-translation-over-genai-backlash/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">'a lot had been lost in translation'</a> and then, last week, to <a href="https://wccftech.com/larian-studios-will-refrain-from-using-genai-tools-to-develop-concept-art-will-use-it-elsewhere/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">backtrack on any usage of genAI</a> to make concept art or even placeholder text for the upcoming game.</p>



<p>No doubt, more controversies within the industry are on the way, given the polarizing subject. On which side are you on? Speak your mind in the comments.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/granblue-developer-cygames-responds-to-gen-ai-backlash/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>