<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 15:46:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xenoblade Chronicles X: Definitive Edition New Overview Trailer Provides a Glimpse At New Story Content and More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/xenoblade-chronicles-x-definitive-edition-overview-trailer/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xenoblade-chronicles-x-definitive-edition-new-overview-trailer-provides-a-glimpse-at-new-story-content-and-more.1119459/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/xenoblade-chronicles-x-definitive-edition-overview-trailer/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A new Xenoblade Chronicles X: Definitive Edition trailer was shared online today, providing a new look at the game's mechanics and features.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ioWlTKzw2VM">The new overview trailer</a>, which can be watched below, is an excellent introduction to the game, as it goes over its most important features, like exploration and traversal, the combat system, the armored vehicles Skells, online features, and more. The trailer also has something for those who played the game on Wii U, as it provides a new look at the additional story content of the Definitive Edition, which includes a new location to explore, new characters, and more.</p>
<p><iframe title="Everything you need to know about Xenoblade Chronicles X: Definitive Edition (Nintendo Switch)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ioWlTKzw2VM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Xenoblade Chronicles X: Definitive Edition is setting out to be the best way to enjoy the game developed by Monolith Soft, thanks to its visual improvements and updated interface that make it easier to get into what can be a very overwhelming game, even for veterans of the series. You can learn more about what the game offers in its first ten or so hours by checking out Nathan's <a href="https://wccftech.com/xenoblade-chronicles-x-definitive-edition-hands-on-impressions/">preview</a>.</p>
<p><em>Xenoblade Chronicles X: Definitive Edition doesn’t feel like a particularly radical upgrade through its first 10-or-so hours, but some UI updates and a limited visual makeover ought to make the game more approachable for the large majority of Switch owners who missed out on it the first time around. I still have a lot more to try out, including the game’s teased new content, but so far, it feels like X still marks the spot.</em></p>
<p>Xenoblade Chronicles X: Definitive Edition launches on Nintendo Switch on March 20th worldwide.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valve’s Deckard VR Headset Rumored to Launch in Late 2025 at $1200]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/valves-deckard-vr-headset-rumored-to-launch-in-late-2025-at-1200/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valve%E2%80%99s-deckard-vr-headset-rumored-to-launch-in-late-2025-at-1200.1119369/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/valves-deckard-vr-headset-rumored-to-launch-in-late-2025-at-1200/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>According to a new rumor, Valve's Deckard Virtual Reality headset might be launching before the end of the year at a rather steep price. The info comes from Valve-focused insider and content creator Gabe Follower, who <a href="https://x.com/gabefollower/status/1894636466480771136" target="_blank" rel="noopener">tweeted</a>:</p>
<p><em>Several people have confirmed that Valve is aiming to release new standalone, wireless VR headset (codename Deckard) by the end of 2025. The current price for the full bundle is set to be $1200. Including some "in-house" games (or demos) that are already done. Valve want to give the user the best possible experience without cutting any costs. Even at the current price, it will be sold at a loss. A few months ago, we saw leaked models of controllers (codename Roy) in the SteamVR update. It will be using the same SteamOS from Steam Deck, but adapted for virtual reality. One of the core features is the ability to play flat-screen game that are already playable on Steam Deck, but in VR on a big screen without a PC. The first behind closed doors presentations could start soon.</em></p>
<p>We last reported on the matter in September 2023, when an unannounced Valve-made hardware device was <a href="https://wccftech.com/valve-possibly-prepping-for-a-new-vr-device-receives-certification-in-south-korea/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">certified</a> in South Korea. Previously, in late 2022, Valve had kind of confirmed they were developing a new Virtual Reality headset via Product Designer Greg Coomer, who said at the time:</p>
<p><em>I can definitely say that we are continuing to develop VR headsets recently. Valve has a lot of expertise in VR devices and has faith in the medium and VR games. We hope to remain open on PC platforms rather than having VR games exclusively on a certain platform. While adhering to this belief, we are continuing development.</em></p>
<p>The Valve Index <a href="https://wccftech.com/full-valve-index-vr-kit-priced-e1079-out-on-june-28th/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">launched on the VR market in June 2019</a>, priced at $999 (€1079 in Europe). For a while, it was the most advanced VR headset available, and Valve also bundled it with Half-Life: Alyx. The game won several awards for its quality. Even so, sale volumes remained niche.</p>
<p>Shortly after the release of the Index, Valve founder Gabe Newell <a href="https://wccftech.com/gabe-newell-talks-untethered-valve-index-vr-teases-half-life-3/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">talked</a> about an untethered VR headset, admitting that the company was looking into ways to do that. Based on the leaks and rumors, Deckard should definitely deliver on that front with a fully wireless standalone headset. The rumored $1200 pricing is also pretty much the same as the Index when aligned for inflation. It appears that Valve is once again aiming for the smaller high-end segment rather than going for a broader market, as Meta has attempted to do with the <a href="https://wccftech.com/meta-quest-3-unveiled-days-before-the-apple-ar-headset-out-this-fall-for-499/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Quest 3</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/meta-quest-3s-unveiled-out-on-october-15-for-299/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Quest 3S</a>.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Quantic Dream Reassures Fans After NetEase Upheaval]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/quantic-dream-reassures-fans-after-netease-upheaval/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/quantic-dream-reassures-fans-after-netease-upheaval.1119297/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/quantic-dream-reassures-fans-after-netease-upheaval/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Following <a href="https://wccftech.com/netease-ceo-reportedly-cutting-funding-for-a-dozen-games-wont-support-marketing-for-nagoshis-and-other-japanese-made-games/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the decision of NetEase CEO William Ding</a>&nbsp;to pull out of several investments made across North America, Europe, and Japan, Quantic Dream fans were fearful about the studio's prospects. After all, the Paris-based developer was <a href="https://wccftech.com/quantic-dream-has-been-acquired-by-netease-games-for-100-million-euros/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">acquired</a> for €100 million in February 2023. However, CEO and Head of Publishing Guillaume de Fondaumière reassured them with a lengthy post <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7300062734602100737/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">shared on LinkedIn</a>: the studio is unaffected.</p>
<p><em>We were deeply saddened to learn about the recent layoffs and studio closures affecting some of the NetEase group’s divisions. Our thoughts are with everyone impacted, and we sincerely hope that they quickly find new opportunities.</em></p>
<p><em>David Cage and I would like to express our gratitude to the fans and friends who have reached out to us in recent days regarding QUANTIC DREAM. We want to reassure everyone that our studios in Paris and Montreal remain unaffected. We are continuing to develop our projects at full pace, with several open positions available in both locations (please visit https://lnkd.in/e_AJFbUa for more details).</em></p>
<p><em>Founded 28 years ago, QUANTIC DREAM remains committed to the strategy outlined by David and I in 2019, when NetEase initially acquired a minority stake in our company. Over the past six years, NetEase has been a dedicated partner, providing us with creative freedom and the financial resources necessary for our studio to grow and strive. In 2022, QUANTIC DREAM became a wholly owned subsidiary of NetEase, aligning with our shared vision for the future.</em></p>
<p><em>In 2024, we achieved the highest revenue in our history, driven by the exceptional performance of our back catalogue titles. Notably, Detroit: Become Human reached 11 million units in global sales across PlayStation and PC last year, a remarkable 2 million increase year-on-year, demonstrating the lasting appeal and quality of our titles. The developments of our current projects are progressing as planned, and we are fully committed to delivering and launching these innovative, high-quality titles in the future.</em></p>
<p>De Fondaumière's mention of multiple projects is interesting, as we only publicly know about Star Wars: Eclipse. Originally <a href="https://wccftech.com/star-wars-eclipse-announced-by-quantic-dream-and-lucasfilm-games/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> at The Game Awards 2021, the game is reportedly <a href="https://wccftech.com/star-wars-eclipse-2026-release/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">targeting</a> a 2026 launch, although it could still be delayed further. Last we <a href="https://wccftech.com/star-wars-eclipse-development-is-reportedly-simmering-reveals-quantic-dream/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">heard</a> from Quantic Dream, the development was 'simmering' in September 2023. We also know that it will retain the studio's classic branching narrative while greatly expanding the gameplay with more action elements than in previous titles made by the developer.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>