<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 06:46:51 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Servers Immediately Hit Capacity At Launch, Steam Charts Soar to 747K Players]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-servers-hit-capacity-at-launch-steam-charts-747k-players/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-servers-immediately-hit-capacity-at-launch-steam-charts-soar-to-747k-players.1322224/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Battlefield 6 is finally live and available around the globe, and it's clear that players were looking forward to it. Not just because the beta saw <a href="https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-beta-surpassed-battlefield-2042-all-time-concurrent-player-count-steam/">hundreds of thousands of players on Steam alone</a> (and likely millions when adding consoles to the mix), do nothing but play Battlefield 6 <a href="https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-open-beta-most-players-in-beta-in-series-history/">during the beta period</a>, but because when it launched today, servers immediately hit capacity.</p>



<p>Players were immediately shuffled into a queue system, though thankfully, we've not seen reports of players having to wait a lengthy amount of time to jump in, and the concurrent player count on Steam soared beyond the beta, hitting a <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/2807960/charts/">peak of 747,440 players per SteamDB</a> shortly after launch. At the time of this writing, it remains above 700K and has stayed there since hitting that peak.</p>



<figure><figcaption><em>Battlefield 6 SteamDB charts on launch day, October 10, 2025.</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Even with a queue system kicking in right away, the fact that players aren't waiting extraordinarily long seems to be thanks to the fact that EA and Battlefield Studios were prepared for this. Earlier today the studio warned that a queue system would be implemented to help keep things running smoothly, and so far, it seems to have worked.</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>A short update on login queues as we prepare for the launch of Battlefield 6 later today.</p><p>Battlefield 6 launches today at 15:00UTC and we anticipate many of you to login at the same time during this initial moment.</p><p>To help ensure a smooth and stable login experience for…</p></div>— Battlefield Comms (@BattlefieldComm) <a href="https://twitter.com/BattlefieldComm/status/1976626423369494630?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 10, 2025</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>If you're one of the players jumping into Battlefield 6 on launch day, then you might want to check out our guide on the <a href="https://wccftech.com/how-to/battlefield-6-guide-best-early-weapons-and-loadouts-for-each-class/">best early game loadouts to put your best foot forward in multiplayer matches</a>. For more on Battlefield 6, <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/battlefield-6-battlefield-is-mostly-back/">you can also check out our review where we gave it an 8.5/10</a>, saying, "<em>Battlefield 6 is an incredibly strong return to form for the series, with a multiplayer experience that is finely tuned with huge potential for what it could build into, destruction mechanics that bring a level of immersion back to the series that it was missing, and a more than solid visual and sound design package tying up how endlessly fun it is to play. The single-player campaign fails to impress, but the multiplayer experience more than makes up for it.</em>"</p>





			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-servers-hit-capacity-at-launch-steam-charts-747k-players/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>