<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 18:53:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dying Light: The Beast Is Out Now, Is Steam Deck Verified, and Has a New Shiny Launch Trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/dying-light-the-beast-steam-deck-verified-out-now-techland/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dying-light-the-beast-is-out-now-is-steam-deck-verified-and-has-a-new-shiny-launch-trailer.1301880/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Techland has been working up to the third mainline installment in the series for the last few years since the launch of Dying Light 2: Stay Human, and <a href="https://wccftech.com/dying-light-the-beast-receives-four-week-delay/">after a late delay</a>, followed by the <a href="https://wccftech.com/dying-light-the-beast-release-date-moved-up-one-day-techland/">release date being moved forward</a>, Dying Light: The Beast is officially out on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X/S.</p>



<p>A new launch trailer premiered alongside the game going live on all platforms, showing even more gameplay off and giving players a recap on how they'll find returning protagonist Kyle Crane at the beginning of The Beast's story.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Dying Light: The Beast — Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qsqBCs7o5go?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Techland has also confirmed that the game is Steam Deck verified, so players can take their parkouring adventure on the go with them if they want. Rendering and audio director at Techland, Tomasz Szałkowski, said that he was "<em>personally driven</em>" to ensure that the game would run on Steam Deck, overseeing the creation of a special performance mode "<em>that contains a mix of tweaked settings and special optimizations together with HDR and VRR running smoothly on an OLED display.</em>"</p>



<p>"<em>Dying Light is back, and I couldn't be more proud of my team and the game we created</em>," said Paweł Marchewka, Techland's chief executive officer in a press release. "<em>Their passion, dedication, and hard work have resulted in something truly great. This project taught us more than any before about the importance of staying true to the core elements of our IP. For players, it's an exciting return to the roots of the series, and for us, we're back on the right track!</em>"</p>



<p>Franchise director Tymon Smektała added, "<em>Dying Light: The Beast is our love letter to the series and to the incredible Dying Light community. Our players have stood with us through highs and lows, and our greatest ambition with this project was to deliver the game that our community truly deserves. To all the fans of Kyle Crane and Dying Light, the moment is here. It's time to unleash The Beast!</em>"</p>



<p>I <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/dying-light-the-beast/">reviewed</a> Dying Light: The Beast for Wccftech, and while its tried-and-true approach to combat and parkour mechanics delivers an undeniably fun time, the overall package of the game was lacking in anything more substantial.</p>



<p>You can check out my full review for more details, and what led me to feeling that, "<em>Overall, those two pillars only keep the game interesting for as long as you want to keep your brain turned off. A dash of well-executed survival elements around those pillars doesn't make up for the rest of the ways the game is lacking, making Dying Light: The Beast a missable title as we move into the final months of 2025 with plenty of major releases on the horizon.</em>"</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/dying-light-the-beast-steam-deck-verified-out-now-techland/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>