<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 18:38:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First in a Trilogy of Trailers Released for KARMA: The Dark World, Paying Homage to David Lynch]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/first-in-a-trilogy-of-trailers-released-for-karma-the-dark-world-paying-homage-to-david-lynch/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/first-in-a-trilogy-of-trailers-released-for-karma-the-dark-world-paying-homage-to-david-lynch.1093947/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/first-in-a-trilogy-of-trailers-released-for-karma-the-dark-world-paying-homage-to-david-lynch/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/martha-is-dead-playstation-cut-content-face-peeling-masturbation/">Wired Productions</a> and Pollar Studio have released the first of three trailers for Karma: The Dark World in the lead-up to the release of the title. Karma: The Dark World is an upcoming first-person psychological horror that's set to channel iconic movie and game directors such as Lynch, Kojima, and Nolan. The first trailer is called 'ROAM.' At the moment, the release date for Karma: The Dark World still hasn't been announced, but it's said that it will soon be announced, most likely coinciding with the trailers that will be released. You can watch the brand-new trailer for the game below.</p>
<p><iframe title="KARMA: The Dark World | ROAM Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gQA9fdoVetQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>As said above, this is the first of three trailers to be released for Karma: The Dark World, with the developers planning to release them to release key aspects of the game's story, as well as showing off the immersive world and intense gameplay mechanics that you'll have to contend with when playing the game. This first trailer is used to set the stage for the game, so players know what they are getting into when jumping into this first-person psychological horror.</p>
<p>"We are deeply saddened by the passing of director David Lynch. His art has had a profound influence on our game development, inspiring us to pay tribute to and learn from his work," said Ke Yang, Art Director of Pollard Studio. Even in the above trailer released, a quote by the iconic director is used to help set the scene.</p>
<p>For those who are hearing about this game for the first time, Karma: The Dark World is a psychological horror title where players will be playing as a Roam Agent and investigating the deepest and darkest secrets of their suspects' minds. The game takes place in an alternate timeline after the war in Germany. In the alternate timeline, Germany has instead fallen into a dystopian state that is ruled over by the Leviathan Corporation. The corporation uses mass surveillance and mind-bending technology to keep an eye on the citizens of the country, providing no privacy at all. Playing as Daniel McGovern, you investigate crime scenes and interview suspects to then report your findings back to Leviathan. However, it's not quite as it seems, and the world begins to crumble around him, where he doubts everything and anyone, including himself.</p>
<p>Karma: The Dark World has been developed in Unreal Engine 5 and will be <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1376200/KARMA_The_Dark_World/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">released soon on PC</a>, PlayStation 5, and Xbox.</p>
<p>Will you be playing Karma: The Dark World when it releases?</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gears of War E-Day Is Being Co-Developed by People Can Fly]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/gears-of-war-e-day-is-being-co-developed-by-people-can-fly/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gears-of-war-e-day-is-being-co-developed-by-people-can-fly.1093905/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/gears-of-war-e-day-is-being-co-developed-by-people-can-fly/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>fYesterday, Polish developer People Can Fly <a href="https://peoplecanfly.com/partnership-announcement/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> that it is co-developing the upcoming prequel Gears of War: E-Day with The Coalition. People Can Fly has a long history with the franchise, having ported the first installment to PC and having led the development of Gears of War: Judgment, so it's a return home in a way for them.</p>
<p>PCF CEO Sebastian Wojciechowski stated:</p>
<p><em>Returning to collaborate on the next chapter of this legendary saga is both a privilege and an exciting opportunity to build upon the intense, visceral action and rich storytelling that fans have come to love. We are deeply grateful for our partners’ trust and support on this journey.</em></p>
<p>Guillaume Barry, Development Director at PCF, said:</p>
<p><em>Our team at People Can Fly, made up of dedicated Gears of War fans, is pouring everything we have into creating an experience that will exceed expectations. While we can’t share more just yet, we’re eager for the day when we can show all the exciting things we’ve been working on.</em></p>
<p>Mike Crump, Studio Head at The Coalition, added:</p>
<p><em>Gears of War: E-Day is not just our next major game; it’s a return to what makes Gears of War games special and authentic. We’re pleased to be partnering with the talented folks at People Can Fly who have been a part of our franchise’s legacy for so long.</em></p>
<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/gears-of-war-e-day-prequel-announced-by-the-coalition/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Announced</a> at the Xbox Games Showcase 2024, Gears of War: E-Day will take fans back fourteen years before the events of the first entry, to Emergence Day, when the Locust Horde first emerged from the underground of the planet Sera to wreak havoc among humans. This will provide the chance to explore the beginning of the narrative as well as the birth of the close friendship between Marcus Fenix and Dom Santiago.</p>
<p>No&nbsp;<span>official release window has been provided yet, although rumors&nbsp;<a href="https://wccftech.com/fable-q4-2025-gears-of-war-e-day-before-that-rumor/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">point</a> to a launch sometime this year—and a PlayStation 5 port <a href="https://wccftech.com/gears-of-war-e-day-playstation-release/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">may also be on the cards</a></span>.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>