<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 01:43:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Astro Bot Levels And Limited DualSense Controller Announced, Coming This July]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/new-astro-bot-levels-and-limited-dualsense-controller-announced-coming-this-july/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-astro-bot-levels-and-limited-dualsense-controller-announced-coming-this-july.1207818/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/new-astro-bot-levels-and-limited-dualsense-controller-announced-coming-this-july/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>While <a href="https://wccftech.com/ghost-of-yotei-gameplay-deep-dive-announced-for-july-2025/">Ghost of Yotei</a> might've been a game players expected to see in during today's State of Play, <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/astro-bot-celebrated-platformer/">Astro Bot</a> was definitely not what people would've expected.</p>
<p>Team Asobi studio head Nicolas Doucet briefly appeared during the presentation to announce that five new levels will be added to <a href="https://wccftech.com/all-winners-at-the-game-awards-2024-astro-bot-game-of-the-year/">The Game Awards 2024 GOTY winner</a> on July 10, 2025, and that a new version of the limited-edition Astro Bot DualSense controller will be launching sometime later this year.</p>
<p>This latest batch of levels brings the total for the game over 90, and like most of the levels Team Asobi has released for Astro Bot post-launch, they're meant to provide a little extra challenge for the platformer fans who want it.</p>
<p>All together, they are the Vicious Void levels, and Team Asobi revealed the names for four of the five, and a sneak peek that the Ghost of Yotei protagonist, Atsu, has been added to the game as a new bot to collect.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>Regarding the new version of the controller, it pretty much looks exactly the same as the old one, except the eyes are made to look like the Astro-persona inside your controller is smiling. The rest of the color layout, and everything about it, seems to be exactly the same.</p>
<p>Now that Astro Bot has more than 90 levels, and that we're starting to come up on the one-year anniversary from the game's launch, it's possible that this is one of, if not the last batch of DLC levels Team Asobi releases, before moving on to whatever its next project will be.</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/06/04/astro-bot-five-new-vicious-void-galaxy-levels-special-bots-launch-this-july/">PlayStation Blog</a> post for the update, Doucet wrote "<em>It has been a real delight to continue offering you, our valued fans, an extended Astro Bot experience at no additional cost</em>," which doesn't exactly have the ring of Team Asobi wanting to slow down soon. We'll see what the anniversary brings, and if we get more clarification on what Team Asobi's future looks like, then.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Announces Project Defiant, A Wireless Fight Stick For PS5 And PC]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/playstation-announces-project-defiant-a-wireless-fight-stick-for-ps5-and-pc/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-announces-project-defiant-a-wireless-fight-stick-for-ps5-and-pc.1207794/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/playstation-announces-project-defiant-a-wireless-fight-stick-for-ps5-and-pc/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>PlayStation has announced its latest peripheral, a wireless fight stick that's currently codenamed Project Defiant.</p>
<p>Fittingly, it was revealed during today's<a href="https://wccftech.com/40-minute-playstation-state-of-play-announced-for-tomorrow/"> State of Play</a> presentation, right after retro-remastering experts Digital Eclipse announced their latest game, the <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/06/04/mortal-kombat-legacy-collection-launches-on-ps5-ps4-this-year/">Mortal Kombat: Legacy Collection</a>, which will bring nine classic Mortal Kombat titles to PS5, PS4, Xbox Series X/S, Xbox One, Nintendo Switch, Nintendo Switch 2, and PC sometime in 2025.</p>
<p>According to a<a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/06/04/introducing-project-defiant-the-first-wireless-fight-stick-designed-by-sony-interactive-entertainment-for-ps5-and-pc/"> PlayStation Blog post</a>, Project Defiant uses PlayStation's proprietary PlayStation Link technology, which "<em>provides ultra-low latency,</em>" though it's not a wireless-only fight stick, as it does work with a wired connection as well.</p>
<p>The short trailer for the fight stick that we saw during the presentation just gave us some glamour shots of the new game pad, which bears the signature white and black PS5 pattern. Notably, the&nbsp; fight stick will come with a sling carry case, according to the Blog post, presumably to make it easier to transport between fighting game tournaments.</p>
<p><iframe title="Project Defiant Wireless Fight Stick - Teaser Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oCeba1xfKxg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Project Defiant also touts "<em>a high-quality digital stick that's custom designed by Sony</em>," and "<em>toolless interchangeable restrictor gates (square, circle, and octagon) for the stick, buttons with mechanical switches, and a touch pad like the one found on the DualSense controller.</em>"</p>
<p>We won't hear more about Project Defiant, like the price or what it'll officially be called, until 2026, when it's expected to launch. Considering the large fighting game community that exists on PlayStation, it's a wonder why the company hasn't made its own fight stick before. But at least it's on its way.</p>
<p>Speaking of fighting games, Mortal Kombat: Legacy Collection wasn't the only fighting game revealed during the State of Play, as we also got the reveal of <a href="https://wccftech.com/marvel-tokon-fighting-soul-is-a-new-4-vs-4-fighting-game-by-arc-system-works-launches-in-2026-on-playstation-5-and-pc/">Marvel Tokon: Fighting Soul,</a> a new 4v4 fighting game from Arc System Works, set to launch in 2026.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghost Of Yotei Gameplay Deep Dive State of Play Announced For July 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ghost-of-yotei-gameplay-deep-dive-announced-for-july-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ghost-of-yotei-gameplay-deep-dive-state-of-play-announced-for-july-2025.1207719/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/ghost-of-yotei-gameplay-deep-dive-announced-for-july-2025/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Ghost of Yotei did appear during Sony's State of Play presentation today, <a href="https://wccftech.com/40-minute-playstation-state-of-play-announced-for-tomorrow/">as I predicted it would</a>. Although, as I predicted, it was just a small tease letting us know that a dedicated Ghost of Yotei event is coming soon.</p>
<p>All that we got regarding Sucker Punch's next game is that a <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/06/04/state-of-play-ghost-of-yotei-gameplay-deep-dive-coming-july-2025/">gameplay deep-dive will be showcased</a> sometime in July 2025. No official release date was given, and the teaser trailer was just a short clip of the game's protagonist, Atsu, talking to the wolf we've seen her with in previous trailers.</p>
<p><iframe title="Ghost of Yotei - State of Play Announcement Trailer | PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qRiTEkU3Utg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>It could be the setup for the presentation, and that the buildings Atsu is looking at in the middle of the night is where the gameplay showcase will begin, starting off with some stealth gameplay before getting into the rest of what it'll feature, but that's just speculation.</p>
<p>At least we have an idea of when we'll hear more about the game ahead of its launch in October. Hopefully, we'll have the exact date for the special Ghost of Yotei State of Play sometime soon, as it feels at least a little odd that Sony didn't just share it today along with the news that the event is coming.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>