<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 23:31:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wolfenstein TV Show Coming From Amazon MGM Studios, with Fallout Producer Patrick Somerville as Showrunner]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/wolfenstein-tv-show-amazon-fallout-producer/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wolfenstein-tv-show-coming-from-amazon-mgm-studios-with-fallout-producer-patrick-somerville-as-showrunner.1253622/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A new report from <a href="https://variety.com/2025/tv/news/wolfenstein-tv-series-amazon-kilter-patrick-somerville-1236469609/">Variety</a> reveals that a television series adaptation of Wolfenstein is in the works at Amazon MGM Studios, with Fallout producer Patrick Somerville signed on as the show's creator, writer, executive producer, and showrunner.</p>



<p>While Variety notes that there aren't any details being given out yet regarding what the show's story will be, the tagline for the show is "<em>The story of killing Nazis is evergreen</em>."</p>



<p>Jerk Gustafsson, who is currently an executive producer at <a href="https://wccftech.com/machinegames-might-have-canceled-an-unannounced-project/">MachineGames</a> and has worked as either a game designer, writer, producer, or managing director on all of MachineGames' Wolfenstein titles, is also attached to the show as an executive producer. </p>



<p>It'll be interesting to see what shape this show takes. Variety's report adds that Somerville has been a fan of the Wolfenstein series since he was a kid, but with the series spanning 14 games, that doesn't necessarily mean he adores or even prefers MachineGames' take on the series.</p>



<p>That said, Somerville coming from Amazon's successful adaptation of Fallout does inspire a great deal of confidence. And hopefully for game fans, the potential success of the show is part of a plan to go along with MachineGames returning to the series.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/wolfenstein-tv-show-amazon-fallout-producer/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>