<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 13:20:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘No, The Half-Year Montage Is Not Cut Content’: Cyberpunk 2077 Act 1 Was Designed To Prevent A Meandering, Unfocused Experience]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/no-the-half-year-montage-is-not-cut-content-cyberpunk-2077-act-1-was-designed-to-prevent-a-meandering-unfocused-experience/</link>
            <guid>1398142</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Although <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Cyberpunk 2077</em></strong> was released in a rather poor state in <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">2020</strong> which required <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-2-0-update-release-date/">multiple updates to fix</a></strong>, the story was always considered to be among the game's strongest points. <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Act 1</strong>, however, has long <span data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-processed">remained one of the most controversial parts of the game's engaging story, especially the&nbsp;<strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">half-year montage</strong>&nbsp;that propels&nbsp;<strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">V</strong>&nbsp;to the top of the&nbsp;<strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Night City</strong>'s&nbsp;mercenary world, setting the stage for the heist that would put</span> the proper story in motion.</p>



<p>For a long time, it has been speculated that the <strong>half-year montage replaced cut content</strong>, but that is not the case, as <strong>Act 1</strong> was reportedly designed the way it was from the beginning to avoid a <strong>meandering, unfocused experience</strong> that would have made most players bounce off the game.</p>



<p>Speaking on <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed"><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/srznsk.bsky.social" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bluesky</a></strong>, <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Cyberpunk 2077's</em></strong> sequel creative director <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Igor Sarzynski</strong> commented on <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Act 1</strong>, detailing why extending it wouldn't have made for a better experience, making an interesting comparison with the first movie in the original <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Star Wars</em></strong> trilogy: "<em data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)">No, it wouldn't. It's like saying we should spend more time on <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Tatooine</strong> with farmer <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Luke</strong> before he got involved with all this <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Jedi stuff</strong>,"</em> Sarzynski said.</p>



<p>Besides, extending the story of <strong>Act 1</strong> wouldn't have necessarily extended playtime for most players, as with <strong>open-world games</strong>, players are free to choose their own pace. More interestingly, however, the <strong><em>Cyberpunk 2077</em></strong> creative director highlighted how the motivation in this portion of the game wouldn't have made for an engaging experience.</p>



<p><strong><em>"The motivation / goal in this section of the game is pretty vague - 'get to the top' - which, prolonged and without stakes or pressure would result in a meandering, unfocused experience,"</em></strong> Sarzynski explained.</p>



<p>In another message, the sequel creative director provided further clarification on this motivation being too vague:<em> <strong>"Do jobs, make money, make reputation" - ok but what for? what are you trying to achieve? there would have to be a more specific goal for this section. 'Do stuff' without a clear hurdle to clear would make a lot of players bounce off the game."</strong></em></p>



<p>This isn't just a vague prediction, according to <strong>Sarzynski</strong>, as building reputation <strong><em>"is not a specific, measurable goal. and it's not about my opinion, we have telemetry, UX lab, survey data."</em></strong> Feeling that a good balance was also struck in regards to the time to bond with <strong>Jackie</strong>, Sarzynski ultimately confirmed that the <strong><em>"half-year montage is not cut content. We always planned it like this</em>."</strong></p>



<p>Given <span data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">that&nbsp;<strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Act 1</strong>&nbsp;remains one of the most hotly debated&nbsp;<em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">topics in Cyberpunk 2077</strong></em>, the community's opinion on the ma</span>tter appears to be generally at odds with the way this story segment has been designed. Some like user <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/mcleansix.bsky.social/post/3mbpbvdf27k2p" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Matthew C. McLean</a></strong> feel that the in-game <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">reputation rating</strong> would have made the "reach the top" goal more tangible. </p>



<p>While setting a goal like reaching a certain level is not the kind of storytelling <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">CD Projekt Red</strong> wants to do, <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Sarzynski</strong> admits that something of the sort would have been doable, but <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><em>"it would require a significant rewrite and introducing a storyline that contextualizes and structures this getting to the top."</em></strong> </p>



<p>Likewise, others would have loved to experience <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">V</strong> reaching the top, or spending more time with <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Jackie</strong>, although in some ways, not having had that much time with this likeable character made the events of the <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">heist</strong> even more impactful.</p>



<p>Considering how it's possible to spend so much time in <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">Night City</strong> completing meaningful content that further fleshes out the franchise's universe, I understand why the developer made some sacrifices to keep the narrative pace tighter. However, it's undeniable that, for a first playthrough, the <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">half-year montage can feel disappointing</strong>. </p>



<p>Nevertheless, it will be interesting to see if the community's opinion on this matter will influence the development of the <strong>second entry in the series</strong>, which promises to be <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/the-cyberpunk-2077-sequel-includes-a-second-city-that-is-like-chicago-gone-wrong/">an even bigger game.</a></strong></p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/no-the-half-year-montage-is-not-cut-content-cyberpunk-2077-act-1-was-designed-to-prevent-a-meandering-unfocused-experience/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Quest VII Reimagined Demo Launches Tomorrow; Save Will Carry to the Full Game]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/dragon-quest-vii-reimagined-demo-launches-tomorrow-save-will-carry-to-full-game/</link>
            <guid>1398094</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Today, Japanese publisher <strong>Square Enix</strong> has revealed that a demo of <strong>Dragon Quest VII Reimagined</strong> will be available tomorrow (<strong>January 7, 2026</strong>) on all platforms. Data from the demo's save file can be transferred to the full game, allowing players to continue where they left off. Moreover, everyone who plays the demo will receive the 'Day Off Dress' costume for Maribel to use in the final game.</p>



<p>We first heard about a Dragon Quest VII remake in July 2025, when a rumor <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/dragon-quest-vii-remake-in-the-works/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">suggested</a> a potential 2026 or early 2027 launch</strong>. <span>The official confirmation came just a couple of months later, in September 2025, when, during a Nintendo Direct</span>, Square Enix&nbsp;<a href="https://wccftech.com/dragon-quest-vii-reimagined-annuounced-for-an-early-2026-release-on-pc-and-consoles/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced</a>&nbsp;the planned release date of&nbsp;<strong>February 5, 2026</strong>,&nbsp;for PC, PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series S and X, and Nintendo Switch 2.</p>



<p>With this remake, the publisher has gone in an entirely different direction than with the recent <strong>HD-2D</strong> style featured in the <strong>Dragon Quest I–III remakes</strong>. Square Enix collaborated with developer <strong>HEXADRIVE</strong> (<strong>Monkey King: Hero Is Back</strong>, <strong>Voidcrisis</strong>) to craft a <strong>hand-painted diorama aesthetic</strong> that treats the game world as a miniature landscape populated by three-dimensional, doll-like characters. The character models themselves derive from actual physical dolls created during development, a deliberate choice to evoke <strong>Akira Toriyama</strong>'s original character designs.</p>



<p>In a slightly controversial move, Square Enix <strong>deliberately cut three entire islands</strong> and converted four others to optional sidequests, directly addressing <strong>the original's bloated 100+ hour structure</strong>. However, new content compensates: expanded character backstories, a new Kiefer scenario, and hints at an alternative ending absent from prior versions. The game now also supports non-linear progression, allowing players to tackle episodic arcs in varying order once the tablet fragments have been collected.</p>



<p>The signature vocation system also received a comprehensive redesign in Dragon Quest VII Reimagined. The 50+ vocation roster is now streamlined to 20 per character, with "Moonlighting" enabling dual-vocation equipping and simultaneous progression. Most critically, the Career Sphere menu eliminates the dreaded mandatory backtracking to Alltrades Abbey. Monster vocations are now Monster Hearts (accessories), while a new Monster Master vocation consolidates scattered abilities. Lastly, the producer <a href="https://wccftech.com/dragon-quest-vii-reimagined-will-feature-a-brand-new-ending-producer-confirms/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">confirmed</a> that <strong>there is a new ending in the remake</strong>.</p>



<p>Starting tomorrow with the demo, everyone will be able to experience some of these changes firsthand and judge for themselves. By the way, Square Enix has also just released the opening movie of Dragon Quest VII Reimagined. Check it out in the embedded video below.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Opening Movie | DRAGON QUEST VII Reimagined" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GL2-tty-p4M?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/dragon-quest-vii-reimagined-demo-launches-tomorrow-save-will-carry-to-full-game/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Total War: PHARAOH Is Getting an In-Game AI Advisor Powered by NVIDIA ACE]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/total-war-pharaoh-is-getting-in-game-advisor-powered-by-nvidia-ace/</link>
            <guid>1397992</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p><strong>Creative Assembly's</strong> <strong>Total War: PHARAOH</strong>, the latest game <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/total-war-pharaoh-sands-of-time/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">released over two years ago</a> in the iconic real-time strategy series, will soon feature <strong>an in-game AI advisor powered by <a href="https://wccftech.com/nvidia-ace-kairos-npc-demo-shown-in-exclusive-ces-24-video/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">NVIDIA ACE</a> technology</strong>.</p>



<p>The news was <a href="https://wccftech.com/watch-nvidia-ces-2026-ceo-jensen-huang-live-here/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">unveiled by NVIDIA at <strong>CES 2026</strong></a> today. This updated version of the in-game advisor reimagines the traditional strategy game guide by using on-device AI to provide real-time, context-aware assistance.</p>



<p>Total War: PHARAOH players <strong>can engage with the advisor via natural language prompts</strong> (voice or text), rather than searching through menus or FAQs. The advisor has been trained on the specific mechanics of Total War: PHARAOH and has game-state awareness (as well as using a historically appropriate tone and lore-driven mindset). For example, <strong>it can analyze why a settlement revolted</strong> or offer strategic advice based on the player's current campaign situation. The AI processes player prompts, the current game state, and data retrieved from the game's complex database, which contains up-to-date information on units, the economy, resource management, faction traits, buildings, and status effects.</p>



<p>Behind the scenes, the Total War: PHARAOH AI advisor <strong>is powered by a small language model that runs locally on the user's GPU</strong>. The studio used NVIDIA ACE developer tools to build the pipeline connecting Total War's extensive game data to the model.</p>



<p>This new feature is part of a program to <strong>investigate how Creative Assembly can make Total War more approachable, dynamic, and ultimately more accessible</strong> to players of all skill levels, without compromising any of the depth that has defined the franchise over the past 25 years. The CES 2026 announcement also included confirmation that an upcoming playtest program for this AI advisor is scheduled to launch for select community members in 2026. </p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="NVIDIA ACE | Master Total War: PHARAOH with an In-Game AI Advisor" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6es-Zvh5bu4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>During the CES 2026 NVIDIA ACE update, we also received an update on the <strong>PUBG Ally</strong> in-game companion that was <a href="https://wccftech.com/nvidia-ace-to-power-dynamic-ai-characters-companions-and-bosses-in-pubg-naraka-bladepoint-inzoi-and-mir5/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">originally announced at last year's Consumer Electronics Show</a>. PUBG Ally will initially be tested in the first half of 2026 via a limited-time event in <strong>PUBG: BATTLEGROUNDS Arcade</strong>, and will be available for players using English, Chinese, and Korean. These <strong>CPC</strong> (<strong>Co-Playable Characters</strong>) are powered by small language and speech models via <strong>efficient on-device inference</strong>. An automatic speech recognition model understands the player's voice, while a small language model (SLM) combines these instructions with PUBG Ally's perception of the game state for strategic planning and real-time reactions. A text-to-speech model then generates dynamic voice lines to communicate with the player.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>At CES 2026, it was also confirmed that PUBG Ally will include a <strong>long-term memory system</strong> that lets Co-Playable Characters recall previous performances and gameplay interactions, allowing the AI to draw on these memories while interacting with the player. This definitely opens up to more immersive interactions, although it will be interesting to see how the gaming community reacts to it, given the growing anti-AI sentiment.</p>



<p>In other Total War news, Creative Assembly is working on two big games: <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/total-war-medieval-iii-is-in-early-development-warcore-engine-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Total War Medieval III</a></strong> and <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/total-war-warhammer-40000-announced-the-game-awards/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Total War: Warhammer 40,000</a></strong>.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/total-war-pharaoh-is-getting-in-game-advisor-powered-by-nvidia-ace/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>