<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 02:52:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon’s God of War TV Show Reportedly Begins Filming in March 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/amazon-god-of-war-tv-show-begins-filming-march-2026/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon%E2%80%99s-god-of-war-tv-show-reportedly-begins-filming-in-march-2026.1290855/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The God of War TV show, which will air on Amazon Prime Video, could begin filming its debut season in March 2026, according to a rumor <a href="https://www.nexuspointnews.com/post/exclusive-god-of-war-series-set-to-begin-filming-in-march-2026" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">posted on Nexus Point News</a>. The website's sources also allege that the show will be filmed in Vancouver, a renowned filming hub thanks to its significant cost savings due to the lower Canadian dollar and generous government tax credits. The Canadian city also boasts a highly skilled and experienced local crew, state-of-the-art facilities, and incredibly diverse scenery.</p>



<p>The God of War TV show was <a href="https://wccftech.com/god-of-war-tv-series-officially-coming-from-amazon-prime-video/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced</a> on December 15, 2022, but had to be <a href="https://wccftech.com/god-of-war-tv-series-starts-from-scratch-with-battlestar-galactica-for-all-mankind-producer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">rebooted</a> about a year ago after changing the showrunner and producers. Ronald D. Moore, known for Star Trek: Next Generation, Star Trek: Deep Space Nine, Star Trek: Voyager, Battlestar Galactica, Outlander, and For All Mankind, is the new showrunner, writer, and executive producer. There are other writers, though:</p>



<ul>
<li>Matthew Graham (Life on Mars, Ashes to Ashes, Electric Dreams, and Spanish Princess)</li>



<li>Stephanie Shannon (For All Mankind and Outlander)</li>



<li>Naren Shankar (The Expanse and For All Mankind)</li>



<li>Joe Menosky (Star Trek: Next Generation, Voyager, Discovery, The Orville, and For All Mankind)</li>



<li>Marc D. Bernardin (Castle Rock, Treadstone, Carnival Row, and Star Trek: Picard)</li>



<li>Tania Lotia (The Witcher and Carnival Row)</li>
</ul>



<p>If the beginning of filming is indeed this close, the main cast is probably already chosen, and an announcement may be made before the end of the year. Furthermore, fans can probably anticipate the series to air on Prime Video at some point in 2027.</p>



<p>Overall, Amazon is betting heavily on gaming IPs with Prime Video adaptations. Fallout's debut season registered incredible success and they're looking to repeat it with the <a href="https://wccftech.com/fallout-season-2-lands-december-17-prime-video/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">upcoming second season</a> and an already announced third season, while <a href="https://wccftech.com/like-a-dragon-yakuza-is-a-live-action-tv-adaptation-of-the-game-series-due-this-october-on-amazon-prime-video/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Like a Dragon: Yakuza</a> wasn't quite as acclaimed. There's a lot more on the way, though, including the Tomb Raider TV show adaptation, which we just learned <a href="https://wccftech.com/tomb-raider-tv-crystal-dynamics-amazon-mgm-sophie-turner-lara-croft-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">will feature Sophia Turner (Sansa Stark in Game of Thrones) as Lara Croft</a>, the <a href="https://wccftech.com/amazon-mass-effect-tv-show-same-production-team-behind-fallout-tv-show/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mass Effect TV series</a> that will be produced by the same team behind Fallout, a <a href="https://wccftech.com/wolfenstein-tv-show-amazon-fallout-producer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Wolfenstein TV show</a>, a <a href="https://wccftech.com/life-is-strange-tv-series-amazon-charlie-covell-kaos-writer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Life is Strange adaptation</a> confirmed just two days ago, and the long-awaited <a href="https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40k-tv-series-from-amazon-will-star-henry-cavill/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Warhammer 40,000 cinematic universe featuring Henry Cavill</a> (although the status of this one is unclear). </p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/amazon-god-of-war-tv-show-begins-filming-march-2026/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>