<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 19:24:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands 4 Confirms Fairly Tame PC Requirements]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/borderlands-4-confirms-fairly-tame-pc-requirements/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-4-confirms-fairly-tame-pc-requirements.1219860/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/borderlands-4-confirms-fairly-tame-pc-requirements/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Earlier today, Gearbox Software <a href="https://wccftech.com/borderlands-4-wont-cost-80/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">opened</a> up the official pre-orders for Borderlands 4. Fans of the looter shooter franchise certainly held their breath for a while when Gearbox president Randy Pitchford wouldn't confirm the pricing, and now they can rest a bit easier knowing that the game won't be priced at $80 as some had feared.</p>
<p>Alongside the opening of pre-orders, though, the Texas-based development studio also revealed the minimum and recommended PC requirements for Borderlands 4. They can be read on the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1285190/Borderlands_4/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/borderlands-4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a> pages, although we've posted them below too for your convenience.</p>
<p><em><strong>Minimum:</strong></em><br>
<em>Requires a 64-bit processor and operating system</em><br>
<em>OS: Windows 10 / Windows 11</em><br>
<em>Processor: Intel Core i7-9700 / AMD Ryzen 7 2700X</em><br>
<em>Memory: 16 GB RAM</em><br>
<em>Graphics: NVIDIA GeForce RTX 2070 / AMD Radeon RX 5700 XT</em><br>
<em>Storage: 100 GB available space</em><br>
<em>Additional Notes: Requires a 64-bit processor and operating system. Requires 8 CPU Cores for processor. Requires 8 GB VRAM for graphics. SSD storage required</em></p>
<p><em><strong>Recommended</strong>:</em><br>
<em>Requires a 64-bit processor and operating system</em><br>
<em>OS: Windows 10 / Windows 11</em><br>
<em>Processor: Intel Core i7-12700 / AMD Ryzen 7 5800X</em><br>
<em>Memory: 32 GB RAM</em><br>
<em>Graphics: NVIDIA GeForce RTX 3080 / AMD Radeon RX 6800 XT</em><br>
<em>Storage: 100 GB available space</em><br>
<em>Additional Notes: Requires a 64-bit processor and operating system. Requires 8+ CPU Cores for processor. Requires 12+ GB VRAM for graphics. SSD storage required</em></p>
<p>Considering that Borderlands 4 is powered by Unreal Engine 5, these system requirements are fairly tame compared to others we've seen. The game is also said to offer the largest and most seamless map in the franchise, with anything you see in the distance reachable by the players.</p>
<p>Traversal has been improved, too, with moves such as double jumping, gliding, dodging, and grappling available. As with the previous entries, drop-in, drop-out cooperative gameplay is said to be the centerpiece of the game, and cross-play is also supported (although you'll need to sign up for a SHiFT Account to join fellow teammates from other platforms).</p>
<p>Borderlands 4 is set to debut on September 12 for PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series S|X, and Nintendo Switch 2.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SHADOW Launches Next-Generation Cloud Gaming Tier ‘Neo’]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/shadow-launches-next-generation-cloud-gaming-tier-neo/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shadow-launches-next-generation-cloud-gaming-tier-%E2%80%98neo%E2%80%99.1219821/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/shadow-launches-next-generation-cloud-gaming-tier-neo/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, French cloud platform <a href="https://wccftech.com/shadow-impressions-cloud-gaming/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SHADOW</a> announced '<a href="https://shadow.tech/shadowpc/offers/#pricing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Neo</a>', a new tier of its cloud gaming offering. Neo replaces the previous 'Boost' tier with much-improved specifications, delivering greatly accelerated performance in gaming (up to 150%) and software (up to 200%). All current subscribers at the Boost tier have been upgraded to Neo, which is still priced at $37.99 monthly, taxes excluded. These are the updated specs:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>CPU:</strong> AMD EPYC – 8 vCores @ 3.25-3.8GHz</li>
<li><strong>GPU:</strong> Equivalent to NVIDIA RTX 4060 16GB (Server-grade NVIDIA RTX 2000 ADA 16GB)</li>
<li><strong>RAM:</strong> 16GB DDR5</li>
<li><strong>Network:</strong> 1Gb/s fiber connection</li>
<li><strong>OS:</strong> Windows 10/11</li>
</ul>
<p>Olivier Abecassis, CEO at Shadow, said in a statement:</p>
<p><em>Neo is our newest and most versatile cloud PC yet. Whether you’re gaming in 2K with RTX and DLSS, editing complex 3D models, or working on the go, Shadow Neo gives you the power of a high-end PC — instantly and from anywhere.</em></p>
<p>The new configuration supports DirectX 12, Vulkan 1.3, RTX, DLSS, FSR, and Frame Generation. This, however, raises the question of whether the Power tier makes any sense anymore. Currently, Power provides access to a similar CPU and an older GPU, the RTX 3070 Ti. When factoring in the fact that the RTX 4060 has access to DLSS Frame Generation while the RTX 3070 Ti does not, paying $50 for the Power tier does not make much sense, as the performance is <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qdmAG4PL7Nk" target="_blank" rel="noopener">nearly the same</a> in some games. SHADOW will have to upgrade this tier too shortly to make it viable again.</p>
<p>Overall, you might be baffled to hear about such high prices compared to, for example, NVIDIA's GeForce NOW platform, which lets you rent an RTX 4080-class GPU for $20 monthly. The big difference is that SHADOW gives you access to a whole PC, so you can use it however you see fit. That means installing any kind of software, or, staying within the gaming subject, being able to install mods for your PC games, which isn't really possible on GeForce NOW (or similar competitors like Boosteroid).</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft Says It Is Still “Deep” In Prince Of Persia: Sands Of Time Remake Development]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-says-it-is-still-deep-in-prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake-development/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-says-it-is-still-%E2%80%9Cdeep%E2%80%9D-in-prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake-development.1219818/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-says-it-is-still-deep-in-prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake-development/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Ubisoft has finally provided an update on how things are going with the highly anticipated Prince of Persia: Sands of Time Remake, and the update is that they're still working on it.</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://x.com/princeofpersia/status/1934642136500060166">post on the studio's official Prince of Persia X account</a>, Ubisoft simply says, "<em>Yep, we're still deep in the game - exploring, building, and ensuring the sands move with purpose. This game is being created by a team that truly cares, and they're pouring their hearts (and a lot of coffee) into every step. Thank you for sticking with us</em>."</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://x.com/princeofpersia/status/1934642139247321113">follow-up post</a>, Ubisoft reminds players that there's another Prince of Persia game they could go play right now, <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/the-rogue-prince-of-persia-early-access-review-the-year-of-the-prince/">The Rogue Prince of Persia</a>.</p>
<p>"<em>While development continues behind the scenes, there's another adventure waiting for you right now: The Rogue Prince of Persia</em>."</p>
<p>The post also includes a new piece of art from the game, displaying the exterior of one of the buildings those who played the original game will remember.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>Last month, the company's annual earnings report confirmed that the remake will be out by<a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake-2026-no-word-on-splinter-cell-remake/"> March 2026</a>, which is only a small update from the game's previous release window of '<a href="https://wccftech.com/prince-of-persia-the-sands-of-time-remake-releases-in-2026/">sometime in 2026</a>'.</p>
<p>Ubisoft has <a href="https://wccftech.com/prince-of-persia-the-sands-of-time-remake-will-expand-farahs-character-long-development-time-is-due-to-high-remake-bar/">previously spoken</a> about having a high bar for this remake, which is evident from the fact that the company <a href="https://wccftech.com/prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake-fully-rebooted/">entirely rebooted the game's development once before</a>, after its initial reveal <a href="https://wccftech.com/prince-of-persia-the-sands-of-time-remake-ubisoft-montreal/">failed to impress</a>.</p>
<p>It may be upsetting for fans of the series who are looking forward to this remake that there's still basically no update on how things are going, but it's also not surprising given <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-reveals-release-date-for-anno-117-pax-romana-a-1-0-release-window-for-the-rogue-prince-of-persia-and-showcases-a-new-game-morbid-metal-at-sgf-2025/">Ubisoft's muted appearance during this year's Summer Game Fest festivities</a>. And with the lack of a <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-will-not-host-its-annual-ubisoft-forward-event-this-year/">Ubisoft Forward</a> event for 2025, it's not worth holding your breath on any major updates from Ubisoft this year.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sloclap Reveals Rematch Won’t Support Cross-Play At Launch, Just Before It Released In Early Access]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/sloclap-rematch-wont-support-cross-play-at-launch/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sloclap-reveals-rematch-won%E2%80%99t-support-cross-play-at-launch-just-before-it-released-in-early-access.1219770/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/sloclap-rematch-wont-support-cross-play-at-launch/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Rematch, the upcoming soccer game from Sifu developer Sloclap, is due to arrive for everyone this <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/sifu-developer-sloclap-has-announced-a-release-date-for-its-new-soccer-game-rematch/">Thursday, June 19, 2025</a>.&nbsp;</strong>It should be an exciting launch for the studio, as Rematch had an extremely popular beta test with more than 1.9 million players jumping in on PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC.</p>
<p>But that excitement has been significantly quelled, with today's reveal by Sloclap that the game will not support cross-play between players on other platforms.</p>
<p>"<em>Crossplay between Steam, PlayStation &amp; Xbox won't be available at launch,</em>" <a href="https://x.com/PlayRematch/status/1934529603244028143">Sloclap announced in a post on the game's official X account</a>. "<em>But it's one of our top priorities for upcoming updates! We'll share an ETA as soon as possible, stay tuned!</em>"</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://x.com/PlayRematch/status/1934628094624567591">separate post</a>, Sloclap said it "<em>aimed for launch but couldn't quite get it ready in time. We're actively working on it.</em>"</p>
<p>Rematch is already available for those who paid for early access, and it was only about an hour before that early access launch that Sloclap delivered the disappointing news about cross-play functionality. It's clear the team was trying to have it ready in time, but delivering the news so close to the game's early access release, the one reserved for those who paid extra for the privilege of playing three days early, is <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Rematch/comments/1lcua7w/the_game_still_feels_like_a_beta/">upsetting players online</a>.</p>
<p>The mood around Rematch isn't helped by the fact that players are reporting major server issues impacting their experience.</p>
<p><iframe title="REMATCH | Golden Rules Trailer | Release Date Announcement" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EFMw23F-KbA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hopefully, by the time the game is available for everyone on Thursday, Sloclap has resolved the biggest of its server issues, and players are able to have a smoother time than they are now. And hopefully it doesn't all break again once cross-play support is added.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>