<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 17:58:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[“You Gonna Cancel It Like You Canceled Sands of Time?”: Ubisoft’s Reply to New Assassin’s Creed IV: Black Flag Remake Leak Draws Ire]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/you-gonna-cancel-it-like-you-canceled-sands-of-time-ubisofts-reply-to-new-assassins-creed-iv-black-flag-remake-leak-draws-ire/</link>
            <guid>1418788</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>On top of <strong>Ubisoft</strong> being under fire from all sides after its <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-major-reset-cancels-prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake/">recent "<em><strong>major reset</strong></em>" announcement</a>, with <a href="https://wccftech.com/enough-is-enough-ubisoft-worker-unions-call-for-strike-in-response-to-layoffs-and-mandatory-rto/">its <strong>workers planning to strike</strong></a>, its <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-lost-nearly-95-of-value-in-eight-years-34-share-price-drop-after-major-reset/">share price dropping to historic lows</a>, and upsetting its fans by cancelling projects like the <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/breathtaking-leaked-pre-alpha-images-of-prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake-are-salt-in-the-wound-for-fans-in-mourning/">Prince of Persia: Sands of Time Remake</a></strong>, the studio's social media team has seemingly gone out of its way to cause more confusion and unrest in players with a bit of an odd response to a new leak regarding the heavily-rumored <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-iv-black-flag-remake-targeting-march-2026-launch/">Assassin's Creed IV: Black Flag Remake</a></strong>.</p>



<p>There have been several leaks regarding the Black Flag remake, the most recent of which (prior to today's leak) revealed the remake's supposed title: <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-iv-black-flag-remake-assassins-creed-black-flag-resynced-pegi-rating-ubisoft/">Assassin's Creed Black Flag Resynced</a><em>.</em></strong> That was a result of a PEGI rating, which, compared to the new leak, is arguably a bigger deal than what we have now.</p>



<p>Today's leak came in the form of a new statue figurine for <strong>Edward Kenway</strong>, the protagonist of Assassin's Creed IV. The statue was shared online by <a href="https://x.com/TheRealZephryss/status/2016172983551984100">a user on X (formerly Twitter)</a> after being spotted on resale platform <strong>Vinted</strong>, where a seller identified it as a new figure that would be out later this year.</p>



<p>Ultimately, this leak doesn't do much beyond <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-assassins-creed-iv-black-flag-remake-major-changes-rumor/">adding to the pile of leaks</a> we've already seen, which have really only proven <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-edward-kenway-actor-threatened-with-lawsuit-by-ubisoft/">that we can expect the remake to arrive eventually</a>. The current buzz is that the statue is that it's actually what'll be included in the Collector's Edition of the remake. However, for some reason, the leaked statue has prompted a direct response from the <a href="https://x.com/assassinscreed/status/2016531108486095252">official Assassin's Creed account on X (formerly Twitter)</a>.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Ubisoft's social media team employed the classic Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas "<em>Ah s***, here we go again</em>" meme as its way of responding to the leak. Now, this can of course be taken positively, as if it's Ubisoft providing a soft confirmation that the remake is happening and that we're about to "<em>go again</em>" with Edward Kenway's journey.</p>



<p>But instead of Assassin's Creed fans replying with excitement to a soft unofficial confirmation, the reply has brought more ire towards Ubisoft, with multiple replies from users immediately taking the negative approach, with one saying, "<em>What? You gonna cancel it like you canceled Sands of Time?</em>"</p>



<p>As to the actual status of the remake, since the project has never been directly confirmed, we can't actually say where it stands. Following the announcement of Ubisoft's restructuring, it was reported that the Black Flag remake was one of the seven projects to get delayed, but that it was not one of the unannounced projects to get cancelled. The only cancelled project we knew about was the Sands of Time Remake, while the others were unannounced. None of the games that got delayed have been officially identified by Ubisoft.</p>



<p>If Ubisoft was even on the verge of thinking about cancelling the Black Flag Remake, then it's likely this reply never gets posted. This is much more likely a soft tease, potentially indicating that we'll get a reveal for the remake sometime soon, even if it has been delayed.</p>



<p>Still, it feels like if there was ever a time to pull back on memes and soft teases, this would be it for Ubisoft,<a href="https://wccftech.com/french-union-claims-ubisoft-ceo-has-no-knowledge-or-understanding-of-his-company-after-major-reset/"> as it is currently under heavy amounts of scrutiny over its restructuring</a>.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/you-gonna-cancel-it-like-you-canceled-sands-of-time-ubisofts-reply-to-new-assassins-creed-iv-black-flag-remake-leak-draws-ire/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Breaking Into Stores, Faking IDs and Flying Drones: How Far is Too Far For An Early Grand Theft Auto 6 Look?]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/breaking-into-stores-faking-ids-and-flying-drones-how-far-is-too-far-for-an-early-grand-theft-auto-6-look/</link>
            <guid>1418653</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Although the <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">multiple delays</strong> may have dampened the enthusiasm of some fans, the <em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Grand Theft Auto 6</em> fever is growing each day as we get closer to the <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-6-delayed-to-november-2026/">November 19 launch</a></strong>, as is the thirst for more information on the game. </p>



<p>While more leaks in the coming months are not entirely out of the question, Take-Two is reportedly going to limit them as much as possible by not<strong> <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-6-digital-only-launch/">releasing physical copies of the game at launch</a></strong>. A sensible choice, considering what some crazed fans have attempted to do in the past.</p>



<p>Speaking on X, Reece "Kiwi Talkz" Reilly, who consistently talks with former Rockstar Games employees, <a href="https://x.com/kiwitalkz/status/2016319221333164304?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E2016319221333164304%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=notebookcheck.com"><strong>commented on the possibility of the sixth entry in the series not launching in retail stores</strong></a>. <em>"GTA 6 is going to be the biggest launch in entertainment history and by a wide margin, nothing will ever come close to it," Kiwi Talkz said. "GTA is a way bigger beast now than it was when GTA 5 launched, and I'd bet all my money that this game would leak early if there are physical discs."</em></p>



<p>Surprisingly enough, the danger of <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">copies getting into the hands of players a few days earlier</strong> could not be the real reason why Grand Theft Auto 6 may not hit retail stores at launch. <span data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">"<em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Unfortunately, there are a number of crazy Rockstar fans that would 100% break into retail stores and manufacturing facilities to steal discs, and people on the inside would leak it a</em></span><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">s well,"&nbsp;</em>Kiwi Talkz said. </p>



<p>This prediction is wholly justified.<em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">"I have heard stories from Rockstar devs over the years of nutty fans trying to get into their buildings to get any info they can from faking IDs to flying drones above windows to try to get images/video,"</em> Kiwi Talkz added. Talk about emulating your favorite video game characters!</p>



<p>As <em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">"people are breaking into card stores to steal Pokémon Cards because of the hype and demand"</em>, as X user <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://x.com/Phischer/status/2016334510795981108"><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Phischer Stanley highlighted,</strong></a> it really wouldn't be surprising to see <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">crazed fans pull an illegal stunt</strong> to get that coveted early look at <em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Grand Theft Auto 6</em>. And it wouldn't even be unprecedented either: back in 2023, some <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><a data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" href="https://wccftech.com/starfield-leaker-review/">very early copies of Starfield illicitly got into the hands of people</a></strong> who did not hesitate to share more on the game before its launch.</p>



<p>Whether it’s flying drones or faking IDs, the <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">extreme lengths</strong> some fans are willing to go for a glimpse of <em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">Grand Theft Auto 6</em> proves that this isn't just a game launch. If Take-Two does indeed go with a digital-first strategy, it could mark a historic turning point for the industry, indicating that the risk of leaks may outweigh the rewards of a retail presence.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/breaking-into-stores-faking-ids-and-flying-drones-how-far-is-too-far-for-an-early-grand-theft-auto-6-look/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ARC Raiders and The Finals Hit by “Extensive, Coordinated DDoS Attacks,” Embark Studios Confirms]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/arc-raiders-and-the-finals-hit-by-extensive-coordinated-ddos-attacks-embark-studios-confirms/</link>
            <guid>1418650</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>If you've been having trouble trying to play one of <strong>Embark Studios</strong> popular multiplayer titles, <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/roundup/arc-raiders-everything-we-know-about-the-latest-hot-extraction-shooter/">ARC Raiders</a></strong> and <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/embark-studios-the-finals-season-9-dragon-rising/">The Finals</a></strong>, then you're not alone, as the studio has confirmed via the official ARC Raiders Discord server (spotted by <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/arc-raiders-and-the-finals-hit-by-coordinated-ddos-attacks">Eurogamer</a>) that both games are suffering from "<em>extensive, coordinated DDoS attacks</em>."</p>



<p>The game's community manager, <strong>Ossen</strong>, shared the following message earlier on Wednesday, with players in the server to confirm they are aware of the attack and that the studio is currently working to fight it.</p>



<p>"<em>Hey Raiders, both ARC Raiders and THE FINALS have been under extensive, coordinated DDoS attacks</em>. <em>The strike team has been working hard on mitigations and solutions to fix the problem, and we are making good progress - but at this point in time the attacks are still ongoing</em>." </p>



<p>The good news is that the latest update from Ossen, which was shared within the last hour states "<em>We are noticing that servers are recovering. Thanks for your patience and please let us know if you notice any more issues</em>." It has not been made clear, however, whether Embark Studios has resolved the issue entirely, so you could still experience issues when trying to log in for either game.</p>



<p>That said, the ARC Raiders Discord server is the only place Embark has addressed the issue, and the lack of a post on any of its other social media channels does seem to indicate that the issue is either close to being resolved, or has been resolved, since the team at Embark doesn't seem to deem it necessary to make players who may not be in the ARC Raiders Discord server aware of the situation.</p>



<p>If you want more signs that things are improving, you can also look to <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1808500/charts/">the SteamDB concurrent player numbers for ARC Raiders</a>, which did drop to the lowest point the game has seen since it launched, but has since begun to rise back to its usual activity. That said, ARC Raiders' lowest point since launch was still above <strong>100K</strong> concurrent players, proving that not even a DDoS attack can bring the popular extraction shooter below six figures of concurrent players.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/arc-raiders-and-the-finals-hit-by-extensive-coordinated-ddos-attacks-embark-studios-confirms/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>