<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 16:42:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Dev Put A Lot Of Effort Into Making The Game Hit Performance Targets On Wide Range of Hardware, Even Minimum Specs]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-effort-minimum-specs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-dev-put-a-lot-of-effort-into-making-the-game-hit-performance-targets-on-wide-range-of-hardware-even-minimum-specs.1284096/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A good portion of the Battlefield 6 open beta PC players were on or below minimum specs, but the game's development team made sure all players could enjoy the open beta properly, regardless of their system configuration.</p>



<p>Speaking in a new interview with <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/battlefield-6-dev-says-a-significant-number-of-users-played-the-game-below-the-minimum-recommended-specs-as-ea-points-to-the-importance-of-weaker-hardware">Eurogamer</a>, technical director Christian Buhl confirmed that of the millions of players who joined the Battlefield 6 open beta, a substantial number of them were on minimum specs or below. The team, however, wasn't caught unprepared, as they went to great lengths to ensure the open beta and the game would be playable on a wide range of system configurations, making sure maps were performant enough to hit certain performance targets regardless of the hardware. "<em>Min spec is certainly one of our most important spec, it's super important from both a commercial and business perspective - we want as many people as possible playing the game,"</em> Buhl added.</p>



<p>With the rising costs of living and PC hardware, Battlefield 6 running well on low-end hardware is welcome, although it remains to be seen if the remainder of the game will run as nicely as the open beta did. Some players will get the chance to test this out themselves before the game launches in a little over a month, as another round of testing via <a href="https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-battlefield-labs-playtesting-resumes/">Battlefield Labs</a> is planned to test some of the changes coming to the game based on beta feedback, new maps like Operation Firestorm, and server browsing.</p>



<p>Battlefield 6 launches on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X, and Xbox Series S on October 10 worldwide.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-effort-minimum-specs/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valve Has Started Requesting Age Verification for UK Steam Users to Access Mature Content]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/valve-steam-age-verification-required-uk-users-uk-online-safety-act/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valve-has-started-requesting-age-verification-for-uk-steam-users-to-access-mature-content.1284060/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>As a response to the enforcement of the UK Online Safety Act (spotted by <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/steam-now-requires-age-verification-in-the-uk-for-mature-game-pages/">VGC</a>), Valve has begun requesting and requiring that UK players verify their age if they want to access any content pages marked as 'mature' on the platform.</p>



<p>Unlike other age verification processes we've started to see that <a href="https://wccftech.com/youtube-tests-ai-powered-age-verification-in-the-u-s-to-safeguard-teens/">rely on AI tools</a>, Valve is taking a simpler approach, and enforcing age verification through users inputting their credit card on Steam. A <a href="https://help.steampowered.com/fr/faqs/view/292B-3DA3-CFC8-97F6">support page outlining how it'll work</a> explains that this route was chosen due to UK regulations around needing to be 18 years of age to have a credit card in your name, and because "<em>this process preserves the maximum degree of user privacy</em>."</p>



<p>Users online began to notice this was in effect as of last Friday, according to VGC, though if you're over 18 with your own credit card registered to your Steam account, then you wouldn't have known the verification had begun since you would already be past its requirements.</p>



<p>"<em>In the UK, Ofcom is the independent regulator for online safety. Ofcom's guidance on the OSA states that one highly effective age assurance measure is credit card checks. This is because, in the UK, an individual must be at least 18 years of age to obtain a credit card, therefore credit card issuers are obliged to verify the age of an applicant before providing them with a credit card.</em>..<em>The data processed in the verification process is identical to that of the millions of other Steam users who make purchases or store their payment details for convenience. The verification process therefore provides no information about a user's content preferences to payment providers or other third parties.</em>"</p>



<p>Valve is one of several companies that have begun instituting age verification. Some, like <a href="https://wccftech.com/nexus-mods-age-verification-changes-uk-eu-users/">Nexus Mods</a>, are still trying to work out how age verification will be implemented, but have confirmed that it is coming. Others, like Rockstar's <a href="https://wccftech.com/gta-online-age-verification/">GTA Online</a> have yet to confirm that it is being implemented, but some version of verification being enforced seems highly likely. So far, these verification implementations have mostly impacted users in the UK and the EU.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/valve-steam-age-verification-required-uk-users-uk-online-safety-act/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>