<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:57:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nioh 3 Developer Made Sure There Won’t Be Sudden Difficulty Spikes in the Game]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nioh-3-dev-made-sure-there-wont-be-sudden-difficulty-spikes/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nioh-3-developer-made-sure-there-won%E2%80%99t-be-sudden-difficulty-spikes-in-the-game.1363099/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Nioh 3 will be the first game in Team NINJA's fantasy action RPG series to be published by the studio's own parent company, Koei Tecmo. The first two games were published by Sony Interactive Entertainment, which meant they launched first on PlayStation consoles and only later on PC, whereas the new one will be available on PS5 and PC at the same time.</p>



<p>That's far from the only change in this third entry. Another big one is that it will offer an 'open field' environment instead of the relatively linear maps seen in the previous two installments. This, as explained by producer Fumihiko Yasuda <a href="https://multiplayer.it/articoli/nioh-3-i-producer-del-team-ninja-ci-hanno-svelato-tutti-i-retroscena-del-progetto.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in an interview with Multiplayer.it</a>, will make the game more accessible than the first two Nioh games, and the team also avoided sudden difficulty spikes that could make the game unpalatable to newcomers. However, the overall level of challenge remains as high as customary for an action game created by Team NINJA, a studio known mainly for the Ninja Gaiden series (which <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/ninja-gaiden-4-bathed-in-blood/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">just received an excellent new release</a>).</p>



<p><em>There are players out there who probably invested thousands of hours in the Nioh series, but there are many more who may be interested in Nioh 3 as newcomers, and I'd like everyone to be able to enjoy the game. For newcomers, we have added a very thorough, albeit not excessive, tutorial. But the most important thing was to ensure that the game wouldn't have sudden difficulty spikes. Everything must happen gradually. The exploration has much more freedom, but there are also very tough foes to defeat on the open field. What we focused on was offering players many more ways to defeat the bosses, be it equipment or the exploration itself. But the challenge level typical of our games was not reduced.</em></p>



<p><em>I always thought that the focal point, which is really important for this game, is how you face defeat. Perhaps in a demo like the one we showed at Tokyo Game Show, you are defeated, and that can be frustrating. But what really matters is what the player thinks after being defeated. What do I have to get? How do I have to prepare to win? We chose to offer many options so that players could find their own way to victory, to defeat those powerful bosses. Ultimately, being able to succeed, the exhilarating sensation that comes with that, discovering that you could indeed beat that boss, is very important, and it was essential that we maintained that in Nioh 3, too.</em></p>



<p>Nioh 3 will be released on February 6, 2026 for PC and PlayStation 5. You can read <a href="https://wccftech.com/nioh-3-is-the-culmination-of-every-team-ninja-action-rpg-hands-on-preview/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our recent hands-on preview here</a>.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/nioh-3-dev-made-sure-there-wont-be-sudden-difficulty-spikes/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Half-Life 3 Is Reportedly Getting Announced Soon, But How Will It Play?]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/half-life-3-is-reportedly-getting-announced-soon-but-how-will-it-play/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/half-life-3-is-reportedly-getting-announced-soon-but-how-will-it-play.1362967/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>For a very long time, the possibility of the long-anticipated Half-Life 3 was nothing more than an illusion, but in the past few months, evidence piled up regarding a new project codenamed HLX, which could actually be the game that most fans of the series lost hope in.</p>



<p>Although Half-Life 3 has yet to be officially announced, we already have some information on how the game might play. For some time, dataminers have taken a close look at every update made to the Source 2 engine, which powers Valve's currently supported games, such as Counter-Strike 2, and have discovered <a href="https://wccftech.com/half-life-3-final-development/">a wealth of information related to the gameplay mechanics that will power the project codenamed HLX.</a></p>



<p>In case you haven't followed all the leaks, some dedicated users have <span><a href="https://miro.com/app/board/uXjVJnkh8Q4=/" target="_blank">created a board on Miro</a>&nbsp;that compiles</span> all the known information regarding the yet-to-be-announced Half-Life 3, providing an excellent overview of the game's core mechanics and engine features.</p>



<h2 id="h-core-gameplay-and-player-systems">Core Gameplay and Player Systems</h2>



<p>At its core, Half-Life 3 will provide an immersive experience, featuring core gameplay mechanics centered on unique environmental interactions through fire and heat conductivity mechanics, as well as a granular weapons system with a physics engine that determines how projectiles interact with the environment. Vehicles will also be return from Half-Life 2, with simulation features that focus on realistic low-level wheel and suspension physics and mechanics that will handle passengers, FOV changes depending on speed and more.</p>



<figure><table><tbody><tr><th>Feature</th><th>Key Elements</th></tr><tr><td><strong>Fire and Heat Conductivity</strong></td><td>Highly detailed simulation for tracking heat transfer, focusing on how different materials and the player react to fire and heat sources.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Weapons</strong></td><td>Granular system covering multiple fire modes, attachments, and the specific rules defining how projectiles interact with deformable physics.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Vehicles</strong></td><td>Realistic handling and movement based on simulation of Wheel Dynamics, including tire friction, suspension, and responsive damage tracking.</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="h-physics-fluids-and-other-environmental-interactions">Physics, Fluids and Other Environmental Interactions</h2>



<p>The Gravity Gun will play a significant role in Half-Life 3's environmental interactions, powered by a physics system that handles complex object manipulation with high precision. Another core element of the game's environmental interactions will be represented by the simulation of multiple liquid types, as well as their interactions with the environment and the player. A complex physics system will also handle character ragdoll behavior and the destruction of environmental objects. Additionally, advanced world manipulation via precise physics adjustments and the ability to alter the gravity of specific locations will provide an even more immersive experience, offering numerous gameplay possibilities.</p>



<figure><table><tbody><tr><th>Features</th><th>Key Elements</th></tr><tr><td><strong>Gravity Gun</strong></td><td>Dedicated, complex system for lifting, manipulating, and launching objects with high precision. Essential for core physics-based puzzles and combat.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Ragdoll &amp; Destruction</strong></td><td>Advanced, physics-driven death animations and object shattering. Focuses on granular, realistic destruction of large props and entities.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Water / Liquids</strong></td><td>Simulation of diverse fluid types (acid, oil, water) and their unique physical interactions, visual effects, and environmental consequences.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Deformable Physics</strong></td><td>Implementation of objects capable of bending, denting, or deforming under stress and force, adding realism.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Track/Train Changes</strong></td><td>Specific engine modifications to handle the physics, tracking, and switching of large moving platforms, trains, and interactive machinery.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Gravity Shifting</strong></td><td>Core system for modifying local or global gravity vectors, used for complex puzzle design and unique gameplay scenarios.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>BasePhys Adjustments</strong></td><td>Low-level customization layer for the base physics engine parameters, allowing precise tuning of collision, friction, and mass for every object type.</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="h-core-engine-features">Core Engine Features</h2>



<p>The Half-Life 3 gameplay mechanics will be further compounded with some of the core engine features. Chief among them will be an enhanced audio experience with positional sound systems that provide accurate 3D audio implementation, augmenting stealth gameplay mechanics. This will enable NPCs to detect player noise and react accordingly.</p>



<p>The supposed complexity of the game's world will be compounded by the SpatialOctree data partitioning structure, which will organize every visual element to deliver highly optimized interactions between a multitude of in-game elements. A G2 Generation system will also be introduced, enabling the rapid creation of levels and areas. Further enhancing the world's immersion will be a save system that manages data persistence across maps and more.</p>



<figure><table><tbody><tr><th>Features</th><th>Key Elements</th></tr><tr><td><strong>Positional Sound</strong></td><td>High-end 3D audio engine ensuring accurate spatialization, including environmental effects like echo, reverberation, and sound occlusion.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>SpatialOctree</strong></td><td>A high-performance spatial partitioning data structure used to organize all world entities, geometry, and light sources for efficient lookup and query operations.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>G2 Generation</strong></td><td>Dedicated tools for Automated Content Generation, suggesting methods for procedurally or systematically creating assets and environments.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Map Shared Environment</strong></td><td>System for managing environment data that must remain consistent and synchronized across different map sections.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Game System / Save System</strong></td><td>Framework essential for saving and restoring the entire state of the game world, including the status of all interactive physics objects.</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="h-visual-features-and-rendering">Visual Features and Rendering</h2>



<p>Although the Half-Life 3 gameplay features promise to be the main focus of the experience, the next entry in the series is also set to feature some great visuals featuring a realistic global illumination and shadow mapping systems alongside necessary optimization tweaks that will ensure that models and effects not currently on screen are not drawn, and an LOD and AI system that will manage the level of detail of distant objects depending on the distance from the player.</p>



<figure><table><tbody><tr><th>Features</th><th>Key Design Elements</th></tr><tr><td><strong>PostFX Effects</strong></td><td>Cinematic visual enhancements, including advanced implementations of Lens Dirt, detailed blurs, and tunable chromatic aberration.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Lighting / Shaders</strong></td><td>Physically-based rendering (PBR) foundation with specialized components like Skylight for global illumination and custom shaders for material fidelity.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Observer Fields</strong></td><td>Critical performance optimization using sophisticated Occlusion Culling logic to ensure only visible elements are processed by the GPU.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>AI LOD</strong></td><td>Level-of-Detail system that scales both the geometric complexity of models and AI based on viewer distance.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Detail Props</strong></td><td>Efficient system designed for the mass rendering of numerous small, non-essential environment objects (debris, scattered items) with minimal performance impact.</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>As all of this information has been datamined, there's the chance some of these features may not make it into the final version of Half-Life 3. Still, they paint a very exciting picture for a game whose release may be a hallmark for reasons other than its now legendary status. Hopefully, <a href="https://wccftech.com/half-life-3-hlx-optimization-trailer-prepared/">it really won't take much longer </a>to learn everything about the game directly from Valve itself.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/half-life-3-is-reportedly-getting-announced-soon-but-how-will-it-play/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rockstar Reportedly Used The Discussion of Slack Policy Changes in a Discord Server to Fire 34 Union Members]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/rockstar-reportedly-used-internal-slack-changes-shared-in-discord-server-to-fire-34-union-members/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rockstar-reportedly-used-the-discussion-of-slack-policy-changes-in-a-discord-server-to-fire-34-union-members.1362964/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>A new report from <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8TvWNFBBwuY">People Make Games</a>, the investigative journalists and documentarians who have recently been doing boots-on-the-ground coverage of Rockstar's firing of 34 union members and accusations of union busting, seems to have discovered the messages behind Rockstar's claim that the fired employees were discussing confidential information in a public forum.</p>



<p>To quickly catch you up if you've not been following this story, on November 1, Rockstar <a href="https://wccftech.com/gta-developer-accused-union-busting-after-firing-dozens-of-employees/">was accused of union-busting when it fired 34 employees between Rockstar North and its Rockstar Toronto offices</a>. Five days later, Rockstar followed up by denying it was union-busting, <a href="https://wccftech.com/rockstar-says-fired-gta-developers-had-been-leaking-information/">claiming that the employees were fired for "<em>gross misconduct</em>," </a>and cited that misconduct to be "<em>distributing and discussing confidential information in a public forum</em>."</p>



<p>As the IWGB held its ground, continuing to claim that Rockstar was union-busting, an anonymous <a href="https://wccftech.com/anonymous-rockstar-employee-says-there-were-no-leaks-layoffs-union-busting/">employee took to GTAForums to fire back at their company's claims</a>. They alleged that this was nothing more than union-busting and said that Rockstar was trying to claim that a Discord server that only included Rockstar employees and IWGB members was a 'public forum' and pin the discussion of company policy changes as confidential information that was publicly shared.</p>



<p>The IWGB followed up <a href="https://wccftech.com/rockstar-hit-by-legal-claim-issued-by-iwgb-refusing-to-meet-fired-workers/">with two legal claims against Rockstar</a>, over <a href="https://wccftech.com/200-rockstar-north-employees-sign-letter-calling-out-management-vicious-union-busting/">200 Rockstar employees signed a letter to management in support of the fired employees</a>, and protests have taken place outside of the Rockstar offices in Edinburgh, London, and Paris, <a href="https://wccftech.com/fired-rockstar-workers-want-to-be-reinstated-get-back-to-work-on-gta-vi/">calling for the reinstatement of the fired employees</a>.</p>



<p>Now, People Make Games' latest report seems to not only corroborate what the anonymous employee shared on GTAForums, but also provides a more specific account of the messages that are likely the ones Take-Two and Rockstar are using as the reason for the firings.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="The Messages Rockstar Saw Before Firing 34 Union Members" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8TvWNFBBwuY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>According to information shared with People Make Games by a Rockstar employee who is not a union member, the messages that the company is likely calling "<em>gross misconduct</em>" and the "<em></em><em>distributing and discussing confidential information in a public forum</em>" are employees sharing changes to the company's internal Slack policies in the aforementioned union-focused, employee-only Discord server.</p>



<p>The Slack policy changes reportedly came in October, which included the removal of miscellaneous channels, meaning that employees now had no place within the company's internal communications to discuss any non-work-related topics. Discussing what was dubbed "<em>The Slack Purge</em>" in a Discord server that had been around since 2022, with the intention of it being a place for union members to discuss working conditions, is the exact kind of thing that, in the eyes of the IWGB, is protected under UK law.</p>



<p>These weren't employees sharing the latest information about Grand Theft Auto VI in a public Discord server that anyone can join. It was employees talking about their working conditions in a private Discord server that was set up for employees to talk about their working conditions, and is only accessible to IWGB members and Rockstar employees who had verified their identity.</p>



<p>Now, because Discord is not the company's chosen internal communication platform, and because the policies were discussed and shared in the server, it could potentially hold up in court that the employees were sharing company information in a 'public forum.' That'll be for a judge to decide, depending on how far this case goes. Still, it's clear that this wasn't a case of the company cracking down on leaks as we move closer to GTA VI's launch.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/rockstar-reportedly-used-internal-slack-changes-shared-in-discord-server-to-fire-34-union-members/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>