<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 22:22:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40,000: Darktide’s Free Update Releases December 3]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40000-darktides-free-update-releases-december-3/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40-000-darktide%E2%80%99s-free-update-releases-december-3.1039884/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40000-darktides-free-update-releases-december-3/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>If you're still enjoying Warhammer 40,000: Darktide and all it has to offer, you are in for more content coming on December 3, 2024. Fatshark has announced that the Grim Protocols update will be released on all platforms as of December 3. This update introduces a lot of new content as well as quality-of-life improvements to celebrate <a href="https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40k-darktide-patch-13-preview-and-qa-class-system-overhaul-xbox-specs-and-pc-performance-boost/">the second anniversary</a> of Warhammer 40,000: Darktide. To celebrate the announcement made by Fatshark today, a narrative trailer was released to accompany the news.</p>
<p><iframe title="Warhammer 40,000: Darktide - Grim Protocols | Narrative Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oC1HRacColU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>First and foremost, the Grim Protocols free update will be adding a new game mode to the game named Havoc. Havoc is specifically an end-game experience where it tests the limits of the player and their experience in the game thus far. There will be plenty of challenges to complete, which can net the player cosmetic rewards.</p>
<p>Additionally, players will get to dive into a new mission in Warhammer 40,000: Darktide. The mission is titled Dark Communion and sees players return to the Carnival, where you have to face off against hordes of cultists who are trying to complete their ritual. You'll have to be prepared to fight them off and make sure to do everything in your power so that they don't achieve their dark communion.</p>
<p>Playable content isn't the only thing that is being added in the Grim Protocols update for Warhammer 40,000: Darktide. There are now three new weapon families that you can experiment with. If you've wanted to feel even more robust than you already are, you can now use Two-Handed Force and Power Swords, as well as the Ogryn Heavy Stubber. It will provide a great experience to the chaos and bloodshed ahead of you and allow you to feel stronger than ever in melee combat.</p>
<p>To celebrate the second anniversary of Warhammer 40,000: Darktide, there will be a special Anniversary event taking place within the game which will allow players to get a unique weapon trinket.</p>
<p>While these are the main attractions of the free update to Warhammer 40,000: Darktide, there are other quality-of-life improvements that have been added to the Grim Protocols update, including expanding the Penance progression track and improving the Party Finder feature.</p>
<p>This update will be available for PC players via Steam and Windows Store, Xbox Series X|S and the game is <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/EP4122-PPSA21255_00-0888672453602469" target="_blank" rel="noopener">available for preorder on PlayStation 5</a>, where the game is set to release on December 3, 2024, alongside the new update.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>