<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 09:34:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steel Seed Gets Slight Delay; Developer Shares PC Specs]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/steel-seed-gets-slight-delay-developer-shares-pc-specs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steel-seed-gets-slight-delay-developer-shares-pc-specs.1151790/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/steel-seed-gets-slight-delay-developer-shares-pc-specs/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Publisher ESDigital Games and developer Storm in a Teacup have announced a slight delay to the release date of the upcoming stealth action/adventure game Steel Seed. Previously scheduled to launch on April 10, the game will now debut on April 22.</p>
<p>Ilia Svanidze, Head of Marketing of ESDigital Games, said in a statement:</p>
<p><em>Since the game’s announcement, your excitement has been truly inspiring, and we know how much you've been looking forward to a deep dive into a dark sci-fi future on all platforms. That’s why we want to be completely open with you: We encountered some technical hurdles related to platform adaptation when running our platform certification tests. Rather than rushing the console release and risking a potentially substandard console user experience that requires swift patching, we have made the difficult but necessary decision to delay the launch. Our goal is to ensure that all players, regardless of platform, enjoy a polished and seamless experience. We are committed to delivering the best possible experience for our players. This additional time will allow us to optimize and polish all versions for launch so they meet the standard we know you deserve.</em></p>
<p>PC store pages like <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/458430/Steel_Seed/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/steel-seed-cdc5d9" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a> also now include the system requirements for Steel Seed, which aren't too demanding.</p>
<div><p><strong>Minimum:</strong></p><ul>
<li>
<ul>
<li><strong>OS:</strong>&nbsp;Windows10</li>
<li><strong>Processor:</strong>&nbsp;Intel i7-3770k 3.50GHz or AMD equivalent</li>
<li><strong>Memory:</strong>&nbsp;16 GB RAM</li>
<li><strong>Graphics:</strong>&nbsp;NvidiaGTX 1070 / Intel ARC 580 / AMD equivalent</li>
<li><strong>DirectX:</strong>&nbsp;Version 12</li>
<li><strong>Storage:</strong>&nbsp;50 GB available space</li>
<li><strong>VR Support:</strong>&nbsp;No</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div><p><strong>Recommended:</strong></p><ul>
<li>
<ul>
<li><strong>OS:</strong>&nbsp;Windows10</li>
<li><strong>Processor:</strong>&nbsp;Intel Core i7 6700K, 4.00 Ghz or AMD equivalent</li>
<li><strong>Memory:</strong>&nbsp;16 GB RAM</li>
<li><strong>Graphics:</strong>&nbsp;Nvidia RTX 2070 / Intel ARC 770 / AMD RX 5700xt</li>
<li><strong>DirectX:</strong>&nbsp;Version 12</li>
<li><strong>Storage:</strong>&nbsp;50 GB available space</li>
<li><strong>VR Support:</strong>&nbsp;No</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>You can download a demo to check out how the game runs for yourself. If you don't have the time but still wish to learn more, though, head to <a href="https://wccftech.com/steel-seed-hands-on-preview-a-gem-in-the-making/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">our recent hands-on article</a>, which included some encouraging first impressions from Francesco De Meo:</p>
<p><em>With an interesting setting that sets up some compelling mysteries right off the bat, great responsiveness, solid gameplay mechanics, and some impressive visuals powered by Unreal Engine 5, Steel Seed has the chance of becoming one of the surprises of this packed 2025.</em></p>
</div>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>