<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 18:15:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Team Asobi Adds Another Batch Of Astro Bot Levels, And Two Iconic Characters Finally Join The Roster Of Cameo Bots]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/team-asobi-astro-bot-dlc-levels-iconic-characters-cameo-bot/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/team-asobi-adds-another-batch-of-astro-bot-levels-and-two-iconic-characters-finally-join-the-roster-of-cameo-bots.1240701/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Announced <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-astro-bot-levels-and-limited-dualsense-controller-announced-coming-this-july/">last month</a>, the latest batch of DLC levels for Astro Bot have officially been added to the game today, and as an additional surprise, two iconic characters that are recognized by video game fans around the world have finally joined the roster of the cameo bots that players can collect in each level. </p>



<p>Today's update adds another five levels to Astro Bot, putting the total number of levels in Astro Bot over 90, but what's perhaps more significant to diehard PlayStation fans are two of the characters that have finally made their way into the game as cameo bots. </p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Final Fantasy's Cloud and Sephiroth are now part of the roster of cameo bots that players can collect in the five new levels available today. </p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Other notable cameo bot inclusions are Atsu, the protagonist for Sucker Punch's upcoming follow-up to their 2019 samurai epic, Ghost of Yotei, which is also due to have its <a href="https://wccftech.com/ghost-of-yotei-july-state-of-play-gameplay-deep-dive/">own State of Play presentation</a> later today at the time of this writing.</p>



<p>Unfortunately for collectors, there's no update regarding the other announcement from last month's Astro Bot news, which was the reveal of a new limited-edition Astro Bot-themed DualSense controller. For now, it's still due out "<em>later this year</em>," with no official release date revealed. </p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/team-asobi-astro-bot-dlc-levels-iconic-characters-cameo-bot/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HOTEL BARCELONA, The New Game from SWERY and SUDA51, Is Out in September]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/hotel-barcelona-out-in-september/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hotel-barcelona-the-new-game-from-swery-and-suda51-is-out-in-september.1240659/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, White Owls announced the release window of <a href="https://wccftech.com/hotel-barcelona-suda-51-swery-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">HOTEL BARCELONA</a>. The new game from revered creators Hidetaka 'Swery' Suehiro (Deadly Premonition, <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/the-good-life-team-dog-or-team-cat/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Good Life</a>) and Goichi 'Suda51' Suda (Killer7, No More Heroes, <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/shadows-of-the-damned-hella-remastered-doomed-to-an-eternity-of-heavy-metal-jokes/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Shadows of the Damned</a>, Lollipop Chainsaw, Let It Die) will be available in September for PC (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2286600/HOTEL_BARCELONA/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steam</a>), PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series S|X. </p>



<p> The game is a 2.5D sidescroller/slasher featuring roguelite and action game elements. It is set in a mysterious hotel, located in a remote location on the Pennsylvania-West Virginia border. Its luxurious appearance hides a terrifying truth—it’s a trap for America’s most dangerous serial killers. Players step into the role of Justine, a rookie federal marshal with a deadly secret—her mind is connected to Dr. Carnival, a deranged murderer with a violent past. Together, Justine and Dr. Carnival must eliminate the Seven Slash Killers and try to survive long enough to escape.</p>



<p>Hotel Barcelona has seven unique explorable areas, each inspired by a different subgenre of horror, such as haunted mansions or twisted laboratories. Each zone features an unforgettable boss battle.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="HOTEL BARCELONA - Dr Carnival Steam Next Fest Trailer 2025 | A new game from SWERY &amp; Suda51" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Rfgsl6E0XsM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Each time Justine dies, a memory of her past self is born. These echoes, known as Slasher Phantoms, mimic the previous run's movements and can harm enemies. Clever players may use them as shields, allies, or distractions. Thus, with each failure, their strength increases.</p>



<p>The game even supports an online multiplayer mode that can be unlocked. Up to three players can team up in co-op mode to work together to complete missions and survive the hotel's murderous inhabitants. For those seeking a more competitive thrill, PvP mode allows a fourth player to invade your world, where you can hunt or be hunted in a brutal game of cat and mouse.</p>



<p>HOTEL BARCELONA is playable at BitSummit XIII: Summer of Yōkai, Japan's largest indie game festival. From July 18 to 20 at the Miyako Messe in Kyoto, attendees can experience the game's opening section, including its brutal first boss, Jacob, a baseball-obsessed serial killer rumored to strike every few years at the nearby baseball field of the hotel.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/hotel-barcelona-out-in-september/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SAG-AFTRA Members Have Approved The New IMA Contract, Officially Ending Video Game Voice Actor Strike]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/sag-aftra-members-approved-new-ima-contract-ending-video-game-voice-actor-strike/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sag-aftra-members-have-approved-the-new-ima-contract-officially-ending-video-game-voice-actor-strike.1240590/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>SAG-AFTRA members under the Interactive Media Agreement (IMA), the contract under which video game companies hire voice actors for their games have overwhelmingly voted to approve the new version of the contract that had been negotiated for the last three years, officially bringing an end to the strike that began in <a href="https://wccftech.com/sag-aftra-videogame-strike-now-in-effect-due-to-ai-concerns-potentially-leading-to-game-delays/">July 2024</a>.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.sagaftra.org/sag-aftra-members-approve-2025-video-game-agreement">SAG-AFTRA announced</a> that the deal, which was <a href="https://wccftech.com/sag-aftra-reaches-tentative-deal-with-video-game-companies-voice-actors-strike-might-be-coming-to-an-end/">tentatively reached last month</a> and marked a suspension of the strike, was approved after 95.04% of members voted 'Yes' to ratifying the deal, with only 4.96% of members voting 'No.'</p>



<p>The core issue that kept negotiations going for so long, and that kicked off the strike, revolved around generative AI tools and actors wanting to ensure they would be protected against video game companies abusing the technology to use actors' voices and likenesses without properly compensating the actors and without the actors' consent. This new deal includes a pay raise for actors, but more significantly, it includes the protections that SAG-AFTRA members and contract negotiators were hoping to achieve.</p>



<p>"<em>The new contract also accomplishes performer safety guardrails and gains around A.I., including consent and disclosure requirements for A.I. digital replica use and the ability for performers to suspend consent for generation of new material during a strike</em>," SAG-AFTRA's statement on the deals ratification reads. </p>



<p>SAG-AFTRA president Fran Drescher said on the deal's approval, "<em>I commend the strong leadership of Interactive Media Agreement negotiating chair Sarah Elmaleh, who remained steadfast through three years of hard bargaining while facing many challenging headwinds during a challenging negotiating cycle. This deal achieves important progress around A.I. protections, and progress is the name of the game! My sincere respect goes out to the entire video game performer community and their allies for their solidarity during the strike which provided the necessary leverage to secure this deal's many essential gains</em>."</p>



<p>Chief negotiator and SAG-AFTRA national executive director, Duncan Crabtree-Ireland added, "<em>All of us at SAG-AFTRA would like to extend our deepest appreciation to the video game performers and allies who endured a great deal of sacrifice through the 11-month strike. I'd also like to express my sincerest gratitude to the Interactive Media Agreement Negotiating Committee, and its chair, Sarah Elmaleh, who have worked tirelessly for nearly three years in order to achieve these necessary gains and protections alongside our negotiating staff and lead negotiator Ray Rodriguez.</em>"</p>



<p>For the part of the video game companies like Take-Two, Activision, PlayStation, EA, and more on the other side of the aisle, spokesperson Audrey Cooling said, "<em>We are pleased that SAG-AFTRA members have ratified a new Interactive Media Agreement, which delivers historic wage increases, industry-leading A.I. protections, and enhanced health and safety measures for performers. We look forward to building on our industry's decades-long partnership with the union and continuing to create groundbreaking entertainment experiences for billions of players worldwide.</em>"</p>



<p>Now that the agreement has been ratified, actors under the IMA won't have to worry about another potential strike or negotiating period for at least a few years.  The conclusion of the strike also means that we won't have to see any games delayed due to companies not being able to hire actors to cast in their games.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/sag-aftra-members-approved-new-ima-contract-ending-video-game-voice-actor-strike/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>