<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 20:44:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dark Messiah of Might and Magic RTX Remix Mod Gets New Trailer; Online Co-Op Mod Now Available]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/dark-messiah-of-might-and-magic-rtx-remix-mod-gets-new-trailer-online-co-op-mod-now-available/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dark-messiah-of-might-and-magic-rtx-remix-mod-gets-new-trailer-online-co-op-mod-now-available.1109013/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/dark-messiah-of-might-and-magic-rtx-remix-mod-gets-new-trailer-online-co-op-mod-now-available/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The cult classic Dark Messiah of Might and Magic is receiving a lot of attention in the modding community <a href="https://wccftech.com/dark-messiah-of-might-and-magic-modders-show-rtx-remix-upgrade-co-op-also-planned/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">thanks to wiltOS Technologies</a>, which is hard at work on three mods (plus a bonus one) to rejuvenate the 2006 game originally developed by Arkane and published by Ubisoft.</p>
<p>Firstly, there's the <a href="https://www.moddb.com/mods/dark-messiah-restoration-mod" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Restoration mod</a>, which brings back some cut content with the help of Ubisoft. The modders were provided with access to assets from Elements, the Xbox 360 version of the game. Thanks to this, the bonus missions and alternate levels that were featured in that version of the game can now be played on PC. Players can also experience The Caves, a cut level, and use cut weapons such as the Sword of Misery or the Necromancer's Staff.</p>
<p>WiltOS Technologies even introduced quality-of-life features such as the Bonus Maps system, which allows level loading without console commands, and a redesigned new game menu with chapter and class selection taken from the Elements. With the Bonus Maps menu, the madders also added a Challenge mode that uses the map add system.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>Then there's the online co-op mod, which has just launched as a public test build downloadable <a href="https://github.com/KingDavidW/DarkMessiah-Coop-Mod-Files" target="_blank" rel="noopener">via GitHub</a>. This is still an early build, though, as evidenced by the fact that three major features are missing: the new player models, the refined revive mechanics, and the cutscenes.</p>
<p>Lastly, there's the Dark Messiah of Might and Magic graphics overhaul mod powered by NVIDIA RTX Remix. This mod just got a new trailer, which you can find embedded below.</p>
<p><iframe title="RTX Remix Project | Dark Messiah of Might and Magic | The City of Stonehelm" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kN347m66sgc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The team of asset makers for the RTX Remix mod has expanded from two to three, but these high-quality assets take a long time to complete. Because of that, wiltOS Technologies plans to first release a version with the original textures and the RTX Remix enhanced lighting and then slowly introduce the improved textures as they are ready.</p>
<p>The bonus mod mentioned earlier in the article is a proof-of-concept for random map generation based on certain rules. Called 'The Trials of Kha-Baleth', it's meant to be an unofficial continuation to the story that uses DungeonGen technology derived from Alien Swarm's TileGen technology. In addition, players have the option to simply start a randomized level or create their own campaign. You can follow the progress of this work <a href="https://www.moddb.com/mods/the-trials-of-kha-baleth" target="_blank" rel="noopener">on the dedicated page</a>.</p>
<p>Are you excited that Dark Messiah of Might and Magic is getting all this attention after nearly twenty years from its release?</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lost in Random: The Eternal Die Launching in Summer 2025, Demo Available on Steam]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/lost-in-random-the-eternal-die-launching-in-summer-2025-demo-available-on-steam/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lost-in-random-the-eternal-die-launching-in-summer-2025-demo-available-on-steam.1108941/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/lost-in-random-the-eternal-die-launching-in-summer-2025-demo-available-on-steam/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, Thunderful announced that Lost in Random: The Eternal Die will be launching in the Summer of 2025 on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, Nintendo Switch, and PC. This game is set within the same universe as Lost in Random, a Gothic fairy-tale-inspired action-adventure that was released in 2021 as an<a href="https://wccftech.com/ea-announces-originals-it-takes-two-lost-in-random-rocket-arena/"> EA Original</a>. If you want to see what you can expect from Lost in Random: The Eternal Die, there is an official gameplay trailer below to introduce you to the world and combat.</p>
<p>This game is the leading project for Stormteller Games, the recently rebranded studio that was previously known as Thunderful Gothenburg.</p>
<p><iframe title="Lost in Random: The Eternal Die | Official Gameplay Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BsxC6L4k-kE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>For those on PC, the first public demo is available now on Steam, with the demo also being available on Xbox as of tomorrow, February 14. There is no word as to whether there will be a demo for this game on PlayStation 5 or Nintendo Switch as of yet.</p>
<p>In Lost in Random: The Eternal Die, Aleksandra, who was once known as The Queen, has been captured alongside her companion Fortune and jailed inside the Black Die by Mare the Knight, who is plotting their final chapter. As a result of this, you have to fight your way through a randomly generated gauntlet, where there will be pawns to take on and giant board games. As you explore, you will be given the opportunity to claim treasure, which will improve your improve your chances of dealing with Aleksandra's tormentor, much like typical roguelikes.</p>
<p>The roguelike element comes in with the randomly generated gauntlet, as well as the ability to combine over 100 relics that have powerful card-based abilities that can then unleash devastating synergies. You get to pick between four unique weapons as you explore four randomly generated worlds, with each of them being home to unique secrets and challenges to undertake. There are over 30 different enemy types that you will encounter on your journeys, with some really challenging bosses that will pull you out of your comfort zone.</p>
<p>Lost in Random: The Eternal Die is set to stand out from the crowd with a fully voiced story that takes place in a Tim Burton-inspired world, which is brought to life with gorgeous Gothic landscapes and a fitting soundtrack that encompasses the energy of Tim Burton's work.</p>
<p>Lost in Random: The Eternal Die will be available on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, Nintendo Switch, and PC via Steam in Summer 2025. As a reminder, there is also <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2564520/Lost_in_Random_The_Eternal_Die/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a demo</a> available on PC right now, with the demo set to release on Xbox tomorrow.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Open Beta Test Continues Today with Extended Hours]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta-test-continues-today-with-extended-hours/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta-test-continues-today-with-extended-hours.1108881/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta-test-continues-today-with-extended-hours/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Due to the PlayStation Network outage, Capcom has made the decision to extend the Open Beta Test by a full 24 hours across all platforms. The PlayStation Network outage occurred during the first weekend of the Monster Hunter Wilds Open Beta Test. Specifically, it happened on February 8, and as a result, millions of gamers were left without a way to play their games. This caused players to be locked out of all online services, even their single-player games, if they happened to own them digitally. While players who had them on the disc would be able to play, it would only be the case if the data of the game was already on the PlayStation and did not need to be installed.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, Sony didn't really give much of a <a href="https://x.com/AskPlayStation/status/1888454556125708758" target="_blank" rel="noopener">full reason</a> as to why the network was down for so long, but blamed the outage on an "operational issue." Luckily, it sounds as if it was just an internal error rather than the network being hacked from the outside and causing major data breaches across the board.</p>
<p>As a result of the network outage, the Monster Hunter Wilds Open Beta Test 2 will resume today at 7 PM PST / 10 PM ET / 3 AM GMT and will continue until February 17 at 6:59 PM PST / 9:59 PM ET / 2:59 AM GMT.</p>
<p>As the Open Beta Test takes place, players will be able to unlock the participation bonus that will become available in the full version of the game, which is set to release on February 28 on PlayStation 5, PC, and Xbox Series X|S.</p>
<p>If you're not sure whether this game will run on your PC, Capcom has released a Benchmark for you to utilize, as well as the <a href="https://wccftech.com/monster-hunter-wilds-gets-free-benchmark-and-updated-pc-requirements/">full specification requirements</a>.</p>
<p>Like the original beta, Open Beta Test 2 will include a character creator, where the data can then be transferred into the full game. It will also include a story mission and free-roaming hunts with cross-platform multiplayer. Compared to the first Beta Test, this one comes with additional content, such as fighting the Gypceros and the flagship monster of the game, Arkveld.</p>
<p>Alongside those new features, the Training Area and online features such as Private Lobbies and Online Single Player mode are also included in this upcoming Beta Test.</p>
<p>Although it's been <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/tWqiYSA-t8E" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced by the Monster Hunter developers</a>, the performance and balance adjustments will not be available in this beta build; instead, the developers are instead focused on implementing these changes in the full release of the game.</p>
<p>Will you be participating in the Monster Hunter Wilds Open Beta Test 2? Let us know in the comments.</p>
<p>Monster Hunter Wilds will be released on February 28 on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, and PC.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>