<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 10:07:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[God of War Ragnarök PC Gets Newest “Patch 6” Update, Focusing On Performance Improvements For Older AMD CPUs]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/god-of-war-ragnarok-pc-gets-newest-patch-6-update-focusing-on-performance-improvements-for-older-amd-cpus/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/god-of-war-ragnar%C3%B6k-pc-gets-newest-%E2%80%9Cpatch-6%E2%80%9D-update-focusing-on-performance-improvements-for-older-amd-cpus.1020774/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/god-of-war-ragnarok-pc-gets-newest-patch-6-update-focusing-on-performance-improvements-for-older-amd-cpus/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>God of War Ragnarök PC has received a new patch update, explicitly focusing on performance improvements for AMD's "older" CPUs, notably Zen1 and Zen2.</p>
<p>God of War Ragnarök was indeed a significant port by Jetpack Interactive when it comes to debuting with optimized performance and a bug-free experience, and with the <a href="https://wccftech.com/god-of-war-ragnarok-pc-patch-4-frame-generation-improvements/">constant patch updates released by the developers</a> post-launch, it certainly has made the title a refined piece, especially when compared against other PC ports. Now, the latest Patch 6 (via <a href="https://steamdb.info/patchnotes/16143442/">SteamDB</a>) has brought in further refinements, explicitly focusing on consumers with older AMD CPUs, and has provided performance improvements in areas where the game was "CPU limited."</p>
<h4 id="updates"><em><strong>Updates</strong></em></h4>
<ul>
<li><em>Fixed a crash in UI when opening certain Journal pages</em></li>
<li><em>Fixed a crash that could happen when controllers get disabled or enabled in rapid succession</em></li>
<li><em>Fixed a crash that would occur in various locations in Vanaheim</em></li>
<li><em>Improved performance of AMD Zen1 and Zen2 processors in areas where the game was CPU limited</em></li>
<li><em>Increased tessellation in Realm Between Realms back to PS5 quality</em></li>
<li><em>Note that the performance issue related to tessellation is resolved in NVIDIA drivers 565.90 or higher</em></li>
<li><em>Fixed an issue where lock on would rapidly bounce between targets when using mouse. It will now be more "sticky" requiring more effort to change targets</em></li>
<li><em>Fixed an issue where attack indicators would not look correct when using frame generation</em></li>
<li><em>Fixed an issue where cinematic dialogue audio would be lower volume than intended</em></li>
</ul>
<p>Apart from the performance improvements, the new Update 6 also brings fixes to crashes in locations such as Vanaheim and enhancements to the UI of certain Journal Pages. There have also been optimizations with Frame Generation, so the update is constructive for improving user experience. We haven't seen the improvements the new update has brought in with older AMD CPUs, but we shouldn't expect out-of-the-roof bumps in performance.</p>
<p>Steam will automatically download the update when you get the title running next time, and if you haven't experienced the game yet, you can learn more about the latest entry in the series by checking out our<a href="https://wccftech.com/review/god-of-war-ragnarok-becoming-a-good-father/">&nbsp;review.</a></p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>