<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 14:06:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2077 Overdrive Mode Continues to Be the Most Impressive Path Tracing Showcase to Date, New Comparison Video Highlights]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-path-tracing-continues-impressive-showcase/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cyberpunk-2077-overdrive-mode-continues-to-be-the-most-impressive-path-tracing-showcase-to-date-new-comparison-video-highlights.1039314/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-path-tracing-continues-impressive-showcase/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Cyberpunk 2077 Overdrive Mode, which introduced path tracing to the game, continues to be the most impressive showcase of the technology to date despite being among the very first games to implement it, as highlighted by a new comparison video shared online.</p>
<p>The comparison video put together by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@MxBenchmarkPC">MxBenchmarkPC</a> shows Cyberpunk 2077, Alan Wake 2, Black Myth: Wukong, Resident Evil 4, Resident Evil 2, and Desordre running without ray tracing, with ray tracing and with path tracing, highlighting the differences between the different rendering techniques. While the differences path tracing brings to Alan Wake 2 and Black Myth: Wukong, for example, are minimal in most scenarios, they are really transformative in Cyberpunk 2077, elevating the game's visuals to heights that no open-world game has managed to match to date.</p>
<p><iframe title="Ray Tracing vs Path Tracing in 6 Games - The Ultimate Graphics/Performance Comparison | RTX 4080" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lixD81ToGcg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>While developer CD Projekt Red stopped supporting Cyberpunk 2077, the development team having moved on to working on the second entry in the series, the game is still getting image quality improvements thanks to mods and new NVIDIA DLSS versions. The upscaler's latest version, version 3.8.10, brings significant <a href="https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-nvidia-dlss-3-8-10-performance-improvements/">anti-aliasing, VRAM, and performance improvements.</a></p>
<p>Cyberpunk 2077 is now available on PC, PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Xbox Series X, Xbox Series S and Xbox One. You can learn more about the 2.0 update and the Phantom Liberty expansion released last year on PC and current generation consoles in Alessio's <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/cyberpunk-2077-phantom-liberty-shiny-firmware-update/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">review.</a></p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PS5 Pro Silent Hill 2, Star Wars Jedi Survivor Issues Are Being Looked Into]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ps5-pro-silent-hill-2-star-wars-jedi-survivor-issues/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ps5-pro-silent-hill-2-star-wars-jedi-survivor-issues-are-being-looked-into.1039278/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/ps5-pro-silent-hill-2-star-wars-jedi-survivor-issues/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The widely reported PS5 Pro issues seen in the Silent Hill 2 remake and Star Wars Jedi Survivor are being looked into, Bloober Team and EA confirmed a few hours ago.</p>
<p>As for the remake of the second entry in the series, developer <a href="https://x.com/BlooberTeam" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bloober Team</a> confirmed they are currently working on the issues replying to a user's question without specifying if every image quality issue is being addressed or when. Likewise, Star Wars Jedi Survivor issues have been <a href="https://x.com/EAStarWars" target="_blank" rel="noopener">confirmed</a> to be under active investigation, but no further detail was provided.</p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">We’re working on it!</p>
<p>— Bloober Team (@BlooberTeam) <a href="https://twitter.com/BlooberTeam/status/1858610797871513693?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 18, 2024</a></p></blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">We’re aware of issues with Star Wars Jedi: Survivor on PlayStation 5 Pro and are actively investigating.</p>
<p>— EA Star Wars (@EAStarWars) <a href="https://twitter.com/EAStarWars/status/1858635462577172846?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 18, 2024</a></p></blockquote>

<p>Despite the developers not providing additional details, it's good to know that the PS5 Pro issues in both games are being looked into. Silent Hill 2 and Star Wars Jedi Survivor, however, aren't the only games that suffer from image quality issues on new consoles, but it is not yet known if anything can be done for other games that could only implement <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-pro-bad-pssr-older-version/">older versions&nbsp;of the PSSR upscaler</a> due to having been developed using an SDK older than version 10, the only one that supports the latest versions of the AI-powered upscaler.</p>
<p>Thankfully, not all PS5 Pro-enhanced games suffer from image quality issues. In games like <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-pro-god-of-war-ragnarok-pssr-framerate-down/">God of War Ragnarok</a> and<a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-pro-final-fantasy-vii-rebirth/"> Final Fantasy VII Rebirth</a>, the developers have done an excellent job taking advantage of the console's features to offer significantly improved experiences. You can learn more about the new features the console offers by checking out our <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/playstation-5-pro-hardware-the-next-gen-graphics-upgrade/">review.</a></p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>