<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 10:26:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Death Stranding 2: On the Beach – How to Turn Weapons Lethal]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/how-to/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-how-to-turn-weapons-lethal/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-%E2%80%93-how-to-turn-weapons-lethal.1227747/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Much like in the first entry in the series, there's a very good reason why killing people in Death Stranding 2: On the Beach is not a very smart idea. Following the cataclysmic event known as the Death Stranding, the spirits of the dead have started roaming the world of the living, manifesting themselves as Beached Things, or BTs for short. Every time one of these beings manages to consume a human, a massive explosion that annihilates everything in its vicinity, called a voidout, occurs.</p>
<p>As such, the game makes it abundantly clear right from the onset how going for non-lethal options when dealing with human enemies like MULEs is the way to go to be able to defend oneself without having to deal with the terrible consequences of a voidout. However, if you really want to, there's a way to unlock some lethal weapon options as soon as Sam's new adventure begins in Mexico.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/DEATH-STRANDING-2_-ON-THE-BEACH_20250625114400-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p><strong>Every weapon in Death Stranding 2: On the Beach with an MP designation can be turned into a lethal weapon from the weapon wheel menu</strong>. Hold the right direction button to bring up the menu, select an MP weapon on the main weapons tab, and<strong> press and hold the right and left triggers as well as the O button</strong>. As soon as you do, you will see a little animation play out in the circle surrounding the weapon, and once the animation has played out, the weapon will have turned lethal and can be used to kill human enemies. This little trick is revealed in-game for the first time after delivering to the pizza chief a few hours in, but you don't have to wait to complete this delivery, as the option of turning most weapons lethal is active right from the start of the game. Do note, however, that not every weapon can be used to kill enemies, as weapons that are specified to use rubber bullets or tranquillizer rounds cannot be rendered lethal, no matter what.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/how-to/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-how-to-turn-weapons-lethal/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 Display Is 50% Slower Than the Original Switch]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-display-is-50-slower-than-the-original-switch/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-display-is-50-slower-than-the-original-switch.1227711/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 display has been bashed a few times already since the console's release earlier this month, but the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AB67B8LCorI" target="_blank" rel="noopener">latest analysis from Monitor Unboxed</a> is perhaps even more damning. We already knew of the nearly <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-below-average-hdr/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">non-existent HDR capabilities</a> and of the <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-display-problematic-worse-predecessor/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Variable Refresh Rate issues</a>, but Monitor Unboxed, which regularly reviews PC displays, has now measured the screen's response time, and the results are really disappointing.</p>
<p>While the channel couldn't perform testing with their usual tools for monitors, they manually conducted a series of 20 gray-to-gray transitions to measure the response time of the Nintendo Switch 2 display set to 60Hz (as there are no current games that support the maximum 120Hz). The test's average was 33 milliseconds, which makes the screen far slower than typical PC monitors that range between 6 and 20 milliseconds. What's even more surprising, though, is that the display is around 50% slower even than the original Nintendo Switch, which measured 21 milliseconds.</p>
<p>Monitor Unboxed postulates that one of the reasons behind this underwhelming measurement could be the lack of Overdrive technology, which is pretty much mandatory on most displays nowadays but would require higher voltage, which, in turn, would affect the device's overall battery life, a critical feature of a handheld console. This is especially important for the Nintendo Switch 2 since it already comes with a larger display (7.9 inches versus 6.2), a higher resolution (1080p versus 720p), and higher brightness (430 nits versus 310 nits) compared to the original Nintendo Switch, all of which impact the battery life.</p>
<p>Because the display's response time is approximately twice the 16.7 ms frame interval at 60 Hz, it cannot fully update before the next refresh. This results in persistent blur trails and poor motion clarity, as seen in the <a href="https://www.testufo.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Blur Busters UFO test</a> performed in the video. Furthermore, Monitor Unboxed reckons that the 120 Hz capability will not significantly improve motion since the panel cannot keep up with the faster refresh cycles anyway.</p>
<p>The only real solution to this issue will be an OLED Nintendo Switch 2 display, which will inevitably offer far superior response times (and, therefore, motion clarity), not to mention greatly superior contrast, which will also improve the console's mediocre HDR representation. Meanwhile, pretty much the only upside to the current LCD screen (other than the aforementioned improvements) compared to the original Switch is its far better wide color gamut support, which covers 98% of the DCI-P3 color space, up from the 79% of the previous console.</p>
<p>Despite all these shortcomings, the console is <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-nintendo-switch-2-is-selling-twice-as-fast-as-the-og-switch/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">selling like hotcakes</a>, proving that most of Nintendo's user base doesn't really care about such topics.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-display-is-50-slower-than-the-original-switch/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hytale Is Officially Dead and Its Studio Disbanded]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/hytale-is-officially-dead-and-its-studio-disbanded/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hytale-is-officially-dead-and-its-studio-disbanded.1227675/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>It's game over for Hytale, the long-awaited Minecraft-style sandbox game, and its studio, Hypixel. The news was <a href="https://hytale.com/news/2025/6/a-difficult-update-about-hytale" target="_blank" rel="noopener">posted</a> this week on the game's official website, where Director Aaron Donaghey wrote:</p>
<p><em>Game development is brutally hard - especially when you’re trying to build something original that speaks to a creative, passionate community. Over time, as our vision evolved and the genre matured around us, the bar kept rising. Our technical ambitions grew more complex, and even after a major reboot of the game engine, the team found that Hytale still wasn’t as far along as it needed to be. It became clear we’d need a lot more time to get it to a place where it could support the ambitious vision for the game.</em></p>
<p><em>We looked at reducing scope, adjusting timelines, and finding new angles to keep moving forward. But each of those options would have meant compromising on what made Hytale special in the first place. It wouldn’t have been the game we set out to make. And it wouldn’t have been the game you deserve.</em></p>
<p>The game was going to be set in a procedurally generated fantasy world featuring RPG-style combat and dungeons. Of course, as you'd expect in a Minecraft-inspired game, there would also be block-based construction and mods. Hytale would have been published by Riot Games, which <a href="https://wccftech.com/riot-games-just-acquired-hytale-developer-hypixel-studios/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">acquired</a> Hypixel Studios in April 2020. In the cancellation letter, Hypixel thanked Riot for their support of the personnel following this transition:</p>
<p><em>We’re also deeply grateful to Riot - not just for the years of support and the opportunities they gave us, but for the care they’re showing our team during this transition. They supported us in going out into the world to see if there were investors or acquirers who could continue to help carry Hytale forward. And now, as we begin winding things down, they’re ensuring our team is supported with generous severance and resources to help them find what’s next. It’s not just thoughtful - it’s human. And it shows a genuine effort to take care of the people behind the work.</em></p>
<p>The original Hypixel server in Minecraft is not affected and will remain operational.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/hytale-is-officially-dead-and-its-studio-disbanded/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>