<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 13:29:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation 6 Likely to Feature 24 GB RAM for Advanced Ray Tracing and Machine Learning Without Raising Costs]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/playstation-6-likely-24gb-ram/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-6-likely-to-feature-24-gb-ram-for-advanced-ray-tracing-and-machine-learning-without-raising-costs.1245924/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The PlayStation 6 is expected to feature more RAM than the 16 GB RAM of the PlayStation 5 and the PlayStation 5 Pro, but the tech experts at Digital Foundry don't think the next-generation system will have much more RAM than the current systems for several reasons.</p>



<p>Replying to a supporter's question during their weekly podcast, the known tech-experts commented on how much RAM the next-generation systems should be expected to have, starting with the PlayStation 6. Given what already can be achieved with 16 GB and how we are already hitting limits in regards to textures and art assets, 24 GB of RAM sounds reasonable, as the extra RAM over the current systems will be needed for machine learning and the more advanced ray tracing that's already been teased as part of the future of PlayStation. Additionally, the cost of DRAM is high and hasn't seen any significant drop in the past few years, so this will undoubtedly be a limiting factor. Also, if the rumored PlayStation handheld is real, it will likely come with 16 GB of RAM, making 24 GB RAM a more sensible choice for the home system if developers are supposed to target both systems with their games.</p>



<p>With the next Xbox, however, predictions are a little harder to make, as Microsoft may decide to go in a different direction and not compete directly with the PlayStation 6 with their next-gen system, but with pre-built PCs. As such, a premium system could easily have a bigger APU and more RAM than Sony's system. According to Digital Foundry, studies were done at Microsoft some time ago looking into the possibility of launching a "PC-in-a-box" rather than a lead console, highlighting how costs escalated dramatically, making such a system not an enticing option in the console space. In the pre-built PCs space, however, there's a price gap between the cheapest systems and consoles that such a system could fill, so the possibility is definitely there to launch a "PC-in-a-box" with better specs than Sony's next-gen system.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Will Next-Gen Consoles Go Heavy on Memory? 24GB? 32GB?" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LArhALvoFFA?start=32&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Though Sony is expected to launch a PlayStation 6 in the next few years, it will be much more interesting to see if the rumored PlayStation handheld is launching alongside the traditional home console. This system is said to be able to run<a href="https://wccftech.com/portable-playstation-6-ps5-games-patch/"> PlayStation 5 games natively</a> and will be more powerful than the<a href="https://wccftech.com/portable-playstation-6-more-powerful-xbox-series-s/"> Xbox Series S.</a></p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/playstation-6-likely-24gb-ram/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Father of The Elder Scrolls Series, Julian LeFay, Is Leaving The Industry Due to Terminal Illness]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-father-of-the-elder-scrolls-series-julian-lefay-is-leaving-the-industry-due-to-terminal-illness/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-father-of-the-elder-scrolls-series-julian-lefay-is-leaving-the-industry-due-to-terminal-illness.1245897/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Julian LeFay, the father of The Elder Scrolls series, is leaving the video games industry following a terminal cancer diagnosis.</p>



<p><span>In a new message shared on YouTube, Victor Villarreal</span>, Creative Producer of The Wayward Realms, and<span> Ted Peterson,</span> co-founder of OnceLost Games confirmed that the father of one of the most popular RPG series still running today is leaving the gaming industry due to a terminal cancer diagnosis. The heartfelt message goes over how the two met, their work on The Elder Scrolls series, and how development of their new game continued even as Julian LeFay was battling cancer courageously, documenting his vision and concepts well to ensure the team was left with the resources needed to complete the game even beyond its Early Access build. We extend our best wishes to Julian LeFay and his loved ones, and our deepest respect to his legacy, which will not be forgotten by anyone who experienced the games he has worked on.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="A Message From Ted &amp; Victor" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vwMyPR8Li6k?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Julian LeFay joined Bethesda shortly after the company's creation in 1987, holding the role of Chief Engineer for many years before quitting the company for good in 1998. Among the games he has worked on, as already mentioned, are the first entries in The Elder Scrolls series, Arena and Daggerfall, as well as Battlespire. He also worked on the third entry in the series, Morrowind, as a contractor before leaving Bethesda. In 2019, he co-founded OnceLost Games with Ted Peterson, whose first game, The Wayward Realms, is a spiritual successor to Daggerfall.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/the-father-of-the-elder-scrolls-series-julian-lefay-is-leaving-the-industry-due-to-terminal-illness/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>