<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 18:32:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40K Space Marine 2 Has Sold 7 Million Units]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40k-space-marine-2-has-sold-7-million-units/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40k-space-marine-2-has-sold-7-million-units.1216968/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40k-space-marine-2-has-sold-7-million-units/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, publisher Focus Entertainment proudly <a href="https://x.com/Focus_entmt/status/1933192827170627788" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> that Warhammer 40K Space Marine 2 has surpassed the enviable milestone of seven million units sold to date.</p>
<p>Saber Interactive's third-person shooter game launched on September 9, 2024, and immediately became a hit. The following day, Focus Home <a href="https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40k-space-marine-2-already-sold-two-million-units/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">revealed</a> that two million copies had already been sold. Those <a href="https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40k-space-marine-2-has-sold-5-million-units-will-get-dlss-fsr-frame-generation-with-next-patch/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">became</a> five million units near the end of November.</p>
<p>A sequel was already inevitable at that point, though we weren't expecting an announcement anytime soon. Instead, Warhammer 40K Space Marine 3 was <a href="https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40k-space-marine-3-is-officially-in-development-will-offer-even-more-spectacular-large-scale-battles/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">confirmed</a> to be in development as early as this March, promising even larger battles.</p>
<p>That doesn't mean support for Warhammer 40K Space Marine 2 is ending anytime soon. In fact, at the recent 2025 Skulls event, we <a href="https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40k-games-roundup-from-2025-skulls-dawn-of-war-definitive-edition-updates-for-darktide-and-space-marine-2-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">learned</a> that Siege Mode is being added to the game in a couple of weeks.</p>
<p><iframe title="Space Marine 2 - Siege Mode Teaser Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NDScTIUHlnc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Here's a detailed overview of Siege Mode provided by Saber Interactive:</p>
<p><em>The battle unfolds within a fortified Imperial stronghold on Kadaku, relentlessly attacked by endless waves of Tyranid and Thousand Sons enemies. The fortress has three rotating sectors: Defensive Positions, the Arsenal, and the Control Room. In each sector, you will face five waves of enemies before your squad advances to the next sector, ultimately cycling back to reinforce earlier positions.</em></p>
<p><em>Face increasingly challenging enemy waves, with direct assaults from Tyranids and cunning sabotage by Chaos forces. Brief (1 minute) intermissions between waves offer strategic opportunities, clearly indicated through UI notifications. Dynamic tasks such as capturing strategic points or retrieving Data-slates from fallen allies deepen tactical gameplay and supply critical resources essential for continued survival.</em></p>
<p><em>Earn Siege Mode resources through successful combat and Side Objective completion. You can spend these resources at the fortress Shop. You can:</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Buy ammunition, medicae stimms, equipment, armour boosts, guardian relic (these items have the same exact behaviour as in Operations Mode).</li>
<li><em>Summon specialized Space Marines providing targeted support and bonuses. Each player can have only one summoned Space Marine.</em></li>
<li><em>Deploy Cadian Troopers to provide additional firepower.</em></li>
<li><em>Collectively pool your resources to unleash the devastating power of a Dreadnought.</em></li>
</ul>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MindsEye Developer Build A Rocket Boy “Heartbroken” Over The Game’s Launch, Details Patches Coming Throughout June]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/mindseye-developer-build-a-rocket-boy-heartbroken-over-the-games-launch-details-patches-coming-throughout-june/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mindseye-developer-build-a-rocket-boy-%E2%80%9Cheartbroken%E2%80%9D-over-the-game%E2%80%99s-launch-details-patches-coming-throughout-june.1216926/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/mindseye-developer-build-a-rocket-boy-heartbroken-over-the-games-launch-details-patches-coming-throughout-june/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The launch for Build A Rocket Boy's debut game, MindsEye, hasn't exactly gone the way the studio would have hoped. The simple fact that PlayStation, a company that very rarely gives players refunds for purchases on the PS Store, <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-is-giving-players-refunds-for-mindseye/">is giving players refunds for their purchases of MindsEye</a>&nbsp;says a lot about how things are going on its own.</p>
<p>Shortly after players started to publicly announce they had gotten refunds from PlayStation, and as more videos of bugs and long statements from players appear on the game's <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MindsEye/">Reddit,</a> developer Build A Rocket Boy released a <a href="https://x.com/MindsEyeGame/status/1933167455238594939">statement to the game's official X account</a>, saying that the team is "<em>heartbroken that not every player was able to experience the game as we intended</em>."</p>
<p>The studio also pinned the issues the game is having on a memory leak, claiming that "<em>roughly 1 in 10 of our players</em>" were impacted by this issue, and that a hotfix has been made to fix the problem. That fix, along with a few more that Build A Rocket Boy detailed in its statement, will be pushed to players starting tomorrow, with more fixes to come throughout the weekend, continuing on through next week, and basically through the rest of the month.</p>
<p>"<em>We are fully committed to ensuring all our players have a great experience, and we will continue to provide frequent and transparent updates</em>," the studio continued in its statement. "<em>We will do our best to respond to all your comments and feedback. Thank you for playing MindsEye. Thank you for your understanding and continued support - it truly means the world to us. We're grateful and blessed to have you on the journey with us</em>."</p>
<p>For this weekend, Build A Rocket Boy says the first hotfix for MindsEye will include:</p>
<ul>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="eqsha" data-offset-key="e948l-0-0">
<p><span data-offset-key="e948l-0-0"><span data-text="true">Initial CPU and GPU performance improvements, along with memory optimizations</span></span></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="eqsha" data-offset-key="a1dqb-0-0">
<p><span data-offset-key="a1dqb-0-0"><span data-text="true">Reduced difficulty for the CPR mini-game</span></span></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="eqsha" data-offset-key="b11f9-0-0">
<p><span data-offset-key="b11f9-0-0"><span data-text="true">A new setting to disable or adjust Depth of Field</span></span></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="eqsha" data-offset-key="84llj-0-0">
<p><span data-offset-key="84llj-0-0"><span data-text="true">Fix for missing controls in the MineHunter and Run Dungeon mini-games</span></span></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="eqsha" data-offset-key="6o5po-0-0">
<p><span data-offset-key="6o5po-0-0"><span data-text="true">Pop-up warnings for PCs with Hardware Accelerated GPU Scheduling disabled and for PCs with CPUs prone to crashes</span></span></p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Over the course of next week, the game's second hotfix will include:</p>
<ul>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="eqsha" data-offset-key="85nr9-0-0">
<p><span data-offset-key="85nr9-0-0"><span data-text="true">Continuous incremental performance and stability improvements</span></span></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="eqsha" data-offset-key="3m8l9-0-0">
<p><span data-offset-key="3m8l9-0-0"><span data-text="true">Fix for the buggy wheels not visually spinning while driving</span></span></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="eqsha" data-offset-key="7308h-0-0">
<p><span data-offset-key="7308h-0-0"><span data-text="true">Fix for areas in Car Manufacturing where players could fall through the world</span></span></p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>And by the end of the month, the third major patch for the game will include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ongoing performance and stability improvements</li>
<li>Rebalance "Hard" difficulty setting</li>
<li>Animation fixes</li>
<li>AI improvements</li>
</ul>
<p>At the time of this writing, more players have publicly posted that they got a <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MindsEye/comments/1l8qqh1/nope/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">refund</a> for their <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MindsEye/comments/1l87qjk/hows_your_launch_day_experience_going/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">purchase</a> of MindsEye, while others are posting videos of their gameplay and the bugs they're experiencing with the simple message <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MindsEye/comments/1l91k8a/dont_buy_this_game/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">"<em>Don't buy this game</em>."</a></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>