<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 19:23:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Skate Developer Full Circle Announces Layoffs Less Than Six Months After Skate’s Early Access Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/skate-developer-full-circle-announces-layoffs-less-than-six-months-after-skate-early-access-release/</link>
            <guid>1446337</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Last year, <strong>EA</strong> brought back one of its most beloved franchises from the seventh generation of consoles with the return of <strong>Skate</strong>. It was absolutely not the <strong>Skate 4</strong> that fans of the series had hoped they might get one day. It was EA's attempt at turning the franchise into a live service game that could churn out cash for the publisher, and despite it being the <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/top-3-best-selling-aaa-pc-console-games-all-ea-games-battlefield-6-ea-fc-25-ea-fc-26/">most-downloaded free-to-play PC and console game</a></strong> in 2025 according to a new Sensor Tower report, less than six months from its launch, developer <strong>Full Circle</strong> has been impacted by <strong>layoffs</strong>.</p>



<p>A statement from the studio on its <a href="https://www.ea.com/ea-studios/full-circle/news/an-update-from-fullcircle">official website</a> announced the cuts, though in the standard style of these kinds of announcements, it does not specify how many developers were impacted or provide any real clarity behind the decision to make these cuts. </p>



<p>"<em>Since launching Early Access in September, tens of millions of you have stepped into San Vansterdam</em>," the statement begins. "<em>Your passion, creativity, and feedback have reinforced our belief in what skate. can become. As skate. continues to evolve, we’re transforming as a studio. We’re reshaping Full Circle to better support skate.’s long-term future and focus the team on the things that matter most to you - and making those things great</em>."</p>



<p>"<em><strong>These shifts mean making changes to our team structure, and some roles will be impacted.</strong> The teammates affected are talented colleagues and friends who helped build the foundation of skate. Their creativity and dedication are deeply ingrained in what players experience today. This decision is not a reflection of their impact and we’re committed to supporting them through this transition.</em>"</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>EA was the <a href="https://wccftech.com/microsoft-spent-most-on-ads-2025-ea-biggest-publisher-game-downloads-pc-console-ps5-xbox-steam/">biggest publisher by game downloads in the PC and console space last year</a>. It had all three of the top-selling AAA PC and console games in its portfolio, with <a href="https://wccftech.com/tag/battlefield-6/"><strong>Battlefield 6</strong> </a>ahead of everything else in a year when shooters and action games were the most popular genres. </p>



<p>While it's always a bit mind-boggling to see major publishers lay off developers while they're having a strong commercial year, one likely factor in this instance of it is the <a href="https://wccftech.com/ea-shareholders-officially-approved-55bn-sale-to-saudi-arabia-pif-silver-lake/">not-yet-official <strong>buyout of EA</strong> by the <strong>Saudi Arabia PIF</strong> and <strong>Silver Lake</strong></a>. The <strong>$20B</strong> of debt EA will take on as part of the deal, should it go through, has been identified by several analysts as <a href="https://wccftech.com/20-billion-debt-ticking-time-bomb-ea-studios-says-analyst/">a "<em>ticking time bomb</em>" for layoffs</a>, and this could just be the first of many to come from EA this year in preparation and anticipation of the deal going through.</p>



<p>Which is not yet a guarantee, as it still has to get approval from several global regulatory bodies, including the US's <strong>FTC</strong>. Members of Congress in the States have <a href="https://wccftech.com/46-congress-members-express-serious-concerns-over-ea-saudi-arabia-buyout-ftc/">already petitioned the FTC to take extra care when scrutinizing this deal,</a> and it'll be interesting to see whether the FTC tries to fight it like it did <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/the-us-federal-trade-commission-v-microsoft-over-the-activision-blizzard-deal-has-come-to-an-end-the-ftc-officially-drops-the-case/">Microsoft's acquisition of Activision Blizzard.</a></strong></p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/skate-developer-full-circle-announces-layoffs-less-than-six-months-after-skate-early-access-release/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[“Reactive Medieval Fantasy World” Valorborn From Laps Games Arrives in Early Access in April 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/valorborn-release-date-early-access-medieval-fantasy-rpg-laps-games/</link>
            <guid>1446334</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p><strong>Valorborn</strong>, the upcoming open-world sandbox RPG that developer <strong>Laps Games</strong> describes as a "<em>dangerous, reactive medieval fantasy world full of freedom, tension, and possibility</em>," officially has an early access release date. It'll arrive on PC first through Steam, and it'll be out in early access on <strong>April 15, 2026.</strong> </p>



<p>Sim and city-building fans may already recognize Laps Games as the developer behind <strong><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1981570/Land_of_the_Vikings/">Land of the Vikings</a></strong>, the 2023 strategy city-building sim that lets you create intricate Viking colonies and challenges you to lead your people through difficult winters, military expeditions, all while managing resources so your colony can thrive instead of just getting by.</p>



<p>Valorborn zooms its focus in on your individual character rather than an entire colony, with emergent storytelling that evolves depending on where you choose to explore. It's a world that'll continue to grow and evolve with or without you, with villagers in their routines, different factions constantly vying for power on their own clock, and a shifting world that may seem safe when you leave it only for its most dangerous elements to be right on your doorstep when you return.</p>



<p>When it arrives in early access, you'll be able to start your journey in <strong>Thareon</strong>, the first major kingdom you'll be able to explore. Thareon is one of several kingdoms that were part of the <strong>Allarion Empire</strong>, with your journey kicking off just after the fall of the Allarion Empire. More kingdoms within the fallen empire will be made available as the game continues to grow and develop, and each will bring its own unique quirks and customs, like how the worst crime you can commit in Thareon is practicing magic. A significant contradiction to the fact that magic was once a significant part of Allarion, and remains a significant force in the world.</p>



<p>Because Valorborn is a game that moves on even when you're not playing, with you driving your own path, one of its more significant elements is <strong>permadeath</strong>. Laps Games calls it a <strong>core feature</strong> in the game's design, forcing you to think very carefully about how you move through the world, whether you've chosen to be a sword-for-hire, a thief, a hunter, a lone traveler or a member of a larger party.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Valorborn Developer Q&amp;A - Demo / Release Date / Limb DMG / Lore" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hOWko9xT-ys?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>"<em>Valorborn</em>&nbsp;is an ambitious project for us, and it was made possible by the support we received for&nbsp;<em>Land of the Vikings</em>," said Laps Games founder <strong>Onurhan Akçay,</strong> in a press release. "<em>That support gave us the foundation to build something bigger and more systemic. With&nbsp;Valorborn</em>, <em>we wanted to create a world where players can truly choose their own path and write their own stories. A lot of our inspiration comes from games like&nbsp;<a href="https://wccftech.com/mount-and-blade-ii-bannerlord-war-sails-qa-interview-with-taleworlds-entertainment/">Mount &amp; Blade</a>,&nbsp;Wartales, and&nbsp;Kenshi, and from worlds like&nbsp;Game of Thrones&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://wccftech.com/amazon-game-studios-lord-of-the-rings-mmo-cancelled-again-amidst-mass-layoffs/">The Lord</a> <a href="https://wccftech.com/amazon-game-studios-lord-of-the-rings-mmo-cancelled-again-amidst-mass-layoffs/">of the Rings</a>. Those inspirations helped shape the kind of experience we wanted to make, a dangerous, reactive medieval fantasy world full of freedom, tension, and possibility.</em>"</p>





			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/valorborn-release-date-early-access-medieval-fantasy-rpg-laps-games/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ninja Gaiden 4: The Two Masters DLC Arrives Next Week With New Chapters, Weapons, Enemies, and More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ninja-gaiden-4-two-masters-dlc-release-date/</link>
            <guid>1446280</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>One of the best <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftech-awards-25-winners-clair-obscur-gta-6/"><strong>action games</strong> of 2025</a> and the return of one of the best action series in video games last year, <strong>Ninja Gaiden 4</strong>, will get its first major <strong>DLC</strong> release <strong>next week</strong>, with the arrival of its previously announced <strong>The Two Masters</strong> DLC on <strong>March 4, 2026</strong>.</p>



<p>The confirmation of its release date comes after we previously learned that the DLC would arrive <a href="https://wccftech.com/ninja-gaiden-4-get-two-masters-dlc-early-2026/">sometime in early 2026.</a> Announced in an <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2026/02/25/ninja-gaiden-4-the-two-masters-dlc-release-date/">Xbox Wire blog post</a>, we also got a new look at gameplay from the DLC, which adds two new weapons (one for Ryu and one for Yakumo), three new chapters, and plenty of new enemies to slice through.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="NINJA GAIDEN 4 - 'The Two Masters' Release Date Reveal" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-k91_EndqCc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>"<em>This story-driven expansion continues Yakumo and Ryu’s battle against fiends that once again threaten to take over the world</em>," the blog post reads. "<em>&nbsp;After completing the main story, players will unlock new story chapters that push both characters into battles against even deadlier enemies, challenging bosses, and new trials that will test the skills of even the most seasoned master ninja.</em>"</p>



<p>Ryu is getting a new <strong>Jakotsumon</strong> serpent gauntlets as his new weapon, while Yakumo will be able to wield a new <strong>Solitaire</strong> scythe. You'll be able to test these weapons and put your ninja skills to the limit in the additional story content added in the DLC, and in the main campaign by around the halfway point. While you'll need to beat the main story to access the DLC chapters, you won't have to beat the story to get your hands on the new DLC weapons.</p>



<p> You'll also be able to test the new weapons out in a brand new "<em>endurance-style mode</em>" called <strong>Abyssal Road</strong>, where success is measured by your ability to survive waves of combat encounters that get more and more difficult.</p>



<p>Part of the increased difficulty comes from new <strong>Special Blood Essence</strong> and <strong>Frenzied</strong> enemy mechanics that shake things up compared to what you got used to over the course of the rest of the game. There are also new bosses and enemies to face, though it seems like we'll have to encounter them in the DLC to learn about them, as Team NINJA doesn't go into any detail about the creatures that will try to get in Ryu and Yakumo's way.</p>



<p>Lastly, along with the new content, Team NINJA is also including a slew of quality-of-life updates and bug fixes that we'll hopefully learn more about next week when the update arrives. If you already own Ninja Gaiden 4 and want to grab the DLC, it'll run you an extra <strong>$14.99</strong> on its own, while the upgrade to the Digital Deluxe version of the game, which includes the DLC and a few in-game cosmetics, costs <strong>$20.</strong></p>



<p>That said, it is currently on sale on both <strong>PlayStation</strong> and <strong>Xbox</strong>, with the deluxe edition of the game on sale for <strong>35% off</strong> on both platforms, and if you already have the game, the deluxe edition upgrade is <strong>25% off</strong> on both platforms. The only platform where it's not on sale, at least at the time of this writing, is Steam.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/ninja-gaiden-4-two-masters-dlc-release-date/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft Splinter Cell, Far Cry Veteran and Assassin’s Creed Hexe Creative Director, Clint Hocking, has Left the Company]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-splinter-cell-far-cry-veteran-assassins-creed-hexe-creative-director-has-left-ubisoft/</link>
            <guid>1446184</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p><strong>Ubisoft</strong> has seemingly lost another one of its veteran developers as part of its ongoing organizational restructuring following the company's announcement of a <strong><em><a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-major-reset-cancels-prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake/">"major reset</a></em></strong>" last month. After learning <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-taps-senior-assassins-creed-black-flag-devs-to-lead-assassins-creed-future/">who would be taking charge</a> of the <strong>Assassin's Creed</strong> franchise going forward in its new structure yesterday, today we've learned that <strong>Clint Hocking</strong>, a Ubisoft veteran who was the creative director on <strong>Splinter Cell: Chaos Theory</strong>, <strong>Far Cry 2, Watch Dogs: Legion</strong>, and most recently the creative director on the upcoming <strong>Assassin's Creed: Hexe</strong> project, has left the company.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/assassins-creed-hexe-director-clint-hocking-has-left-ubisoft-as-part-of-franchise-upheaval/">VGC</a> initially reported Hocking's departure, and when we reached out to Ubisoft to confirm the report, we received the following statement in response:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>"<em>Clint Hocking, Creative Director on <strong>Assassin’s Creed Codename Hexe</strong>, will be <strong>departing Ubisoft</strong>. We sincerely thank him for his vision, creative contributions, and dedication over the years, and we wish him the very best in his next chapter.</em> <em>Development on Assassin’s Creed Codename Hexe continues with a seasoned team. The game will deliver something distinctive within the Assassin’s Creed franchise. <strong>Jean Guesdon</strong>, Head of Content for the Assassin's Creed brand, is now acting as the Creative Director on the project.</em> <em>We look forward to sharing more information in the future.</em>"</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Since the Hexe project was <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-project-red-japan-project-hexe-witchcraft-infinity-hub-detail/">announced in 2022</a> alongside other future AC titles, we've only <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-hexe-magic-powers-possession-fear-system/">heard rumours about the upcoming title</a>, and most recently heard that it had been <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-infinity-live-servies-assassins-creed-red-hexe-in-2026/">pushed to sometime in 2026</a>. Since the company's major restructuring announced last month, and now Hocking's departure, it seems likely that Hexe is one of the titles that was delayed in the portfolio shifting Ubisoft did, which included cancelling the <a href="https://wccftech.com/breathtaking-leaked-pre-alpha-images-of-prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake-are-salt-in-the-wound-for-fans-in-mourning/"><strong>Prince of Persia: Sands of Time Remake</strong>.</a></p>



<p>Hocking was with Ubisoft across two significant periods in his career. The first was a nine-year stay at the company during which he led development on Far Cry 2 and Chaos Theory as creative director. He left in 2010 to join <strong>LucasArts</strong> for two years, then <strong>Valve</strong> for one year, and <strong>Amazon Game Studios</strong> for one year. He then rejoined Ubisoft in 2015, where he led the <a href="https://wccftech.com/splinter-cell-remake-team-ubisoft-toronto-layoffs/"><strong>Ubisoft Toronto</strong> </a>team on Watch Dogs: Legion before joining the Montreal team to work on Hexe.</p>



<p>Hocking may not have been with the Assassin's Creed franchise throughout his whole Ubisoft career, like another recently departed Ubisoft veteran, <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/former-assassins-creed-boss-marc-alexis-cote-sues-ubisoft-1-3-million/">Marc-Alexis Côté,</a></strong> but as the creative director behind two of the company's most iconic titles, his departure signals how the company's 'reset' continues to include a changing of the old guard, of sorts, at least when it comes to those in major creative roles.</p>



<p>Marc-Alexis Côté, <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-tells-the-division-players-dont-worry-series-producer-julian-gerighty-leaves-for-battlefield/">Julian Gerighty</a></strong>, and now Clint Hocking are all senior creative leads, all of whom have led successful projects for Ubisoft, all of whom the company has now lost in this reorganization. While we know that Gerighty left to go work on the <strong>Battlefield</strong> franchise, it's unclear who will scoop up Hocking and Côté.</p>



<p>Ultimately, in a company as big as Ubisoft, a project's success or failure cannot be laid at the feet of an individual person. That said, it does not bode well to continue seeing people who have stuck with Ubisoft for years look elsewhere in the industry.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-splinter-cell-far-cry-veteran-assassins-creed-hexe-creative-director-has-left-ubisoft/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>