<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 19:37:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 8nm SoC Is More Likely Due to Ampere Architecture; Good Performance and Battery Life Are a Challenge, but the Chip Was Likely Design]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-8nm-soc-ampere-efficiency-goals/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-8nm-soc-is-more-likely-due-to-ampere-architecture-good-performance-and-battery-life-are-a-challenge-but-the-chip-was-likely-design.1075053/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-8nm-soc-ampere-efficiency-goals/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 T239 could be an 8nm chip, and while this could make good performance and battery life a challenge, there's a good chance this process node won't significantly impact the system.</p>
<p>The tech experts at <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@DigitalFoundry" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Digital Foundry</a> took a good look at the leaked system's motherboard, focusing on the T239 SoC, as most of the other components found on it aren't particularly interesting. While it is currently difficult to pinpoint the exact size of the chip due to the angled picture, Digital Foundry's experts think that the Samsung 8nm process node was more likely used for the chip over other rumored process nodes for a few reasons.</p>
<p>For starters, the chip is somewhat of an offshoot of the T234 chip, which uses the Samsung 8nm process node. Additionally, NVIDIA Ampere architecture was designed for this process node, and porting it to a different process node like 4nm would be a waste of time, as it would have made more sense simply to go with the Lovelace architecture, which was built with 4nm in mind. <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-leaked-soc-5nm/">A Samsung 5nm process node</a> could still be possible, but it would still require porting Ampere over to a different process node. Also, the Samsung 8nm process node is quite cheap, as it has never been extremely popular, and Samsung likely doesn't have that many customers for it right now, so its low cost would definitely fit Nintendo's approach.</p>
<p>Even if the Nintendo Switch 2 is powered by a Samsung 8nm chip, the process node may end up not being as big an issue as many are speculating. While 8nm is not particularly power-efficient, and achieving good performance and battery life on it may be a challenge, all the current power measurements are likely way off the mark, as they are based on the T234 chip, which is much bigger than the T239 and requires a certain amount of power even with reduced clock speeds. Additionally, the T239 chip may have begun development as some sort of offshoot of the much bigger and more power-hungry T234 chip, but the two chips have been designed by different teams, have different CPUs, and the Nintendo Switch 2 chip has some additional features, such as a file decompression block required for fast loading and asset management, so it's not a cut-down version of the chip used in the automotive segment. Having likely been designed from scratch on the 8nm process node with certain power-efficiency goals in mind, which are suggested by the small battery cavity seen in the leaked motherboard, there's a very good chance that the chip's process node is not going to impact the system in any significant way.</p>
<p><iframe title="DF Direct Weekly #195: Switch 2 Motherboard Leak, HQ GTA6 Trailer, Nintendo Upscaling Patent!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/H6okXGEMWJQ?start=102&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 motherboard leak was only the first one to surface online in the first few days of 2025. <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-high-quality-pictures-joy-con/">Yesterday</a>, pictures showcasing the new Joy-Con controller emerged online, and some of the additions from the original controller suggest that the controller could be used as a <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-rumor-mill-joycons-as-pc-mice-no-mans-sky-on-the-way/">PC mouse</a>. Will this be the new gimmick of the system? Hopefully, it won't take much longer to get the answer to this question and every other that fans have been asking themselves for a few months.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Hyperkin Controller Revealed, PS5 Style for Xbox Named The Competitor]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/new-hyperkin-controller-revealed-ps5-style-for-xbox-named-the-competitor/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-hyperkin-controller-revealed-ps5-style-for-xbox-named-the-competitor.1075050/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/new-hyperkin-controller-revealed-ps5-style-for-xbox-named-the-competitor/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Over the years, there have been a variety of PS5-style Xbox controllers, none of them causing quite as much of a stir as the Hyperkin controller. During the<a href="https://wccftech.com/watch-nvidia-ces-2025-ceo-jensen-huang-keynote-live-here/"> CES 2025</a>, Hyperkin announced a brand-new Xbox controller, which is called "The Competitor" and seems very similar to that of the PlayStation 5 DualSense. Much like the DualSense, the thumbstick on the left has now been moved down to be parallel to the right thumbstick, and the D-pad is moved above to replicate the design of the DualSense. While it has an Xbox-style design in terms of pattern, the colors are that of the DualSense, in a classic white and black design.</p>
<p>Hyperkin is well known for making controllers and other accessories that have a retro vibe, with many of the controllers they created being similar to the original Xbox controllers. <a href="https://hyperkin.com/full-product-list.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Their website</a> is a safe haven for those who want a hit of nostalgia, as they have items that pertain to every type of popular console on the market. This ranges from the PlayStation One to the PS Vita and even a Nintendo DS, for example.</p>
<p>Compared to other controllers on the market, the brand-new Hyperkin controller is a wired controller that can be used on Xbox One, Xbox Series X|S, and PC. While PC gamers commonly use Xbox controllers over DualSense controllers, this new Hyperkin controller contains something that is incredibly beneficial to the longevity of a controller. That is the Hall Effect sticks. For those just hearing about these for the first time, Hall Effect Sticks use non-contact magnetic sensors to detect movement, which should prove to be beneficial in making sure that the thumbstick lasts longer than that of a typical Xbox controller.</p>
<p>At the moment, there aren't many details about this new Hyperkin Controller other than the name of it and a trailer that was released on the IGN YouTube channel. Here, you can see the aesthetic they went for with the controller and the sleekness of the design. By the looks of the trailer, it seems you can either get the controller in black and white, or just fully black, depending on your preference in aesthetic.</p>
<p><iframe title="Hyperkin's Redesigned Competitor Xbox Controller Teaser (DualSense-Style Gamepad for Xbox)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/k6rko8BbWgw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The video is only short and doesn't provide any details about the Competitor, but it's very obvious that they have taken heavy inspiration from the DualSense, even in the styling of the D-Pad and the buttons.</p>
<p>Those who have seen the controller now wish it had the option to be wireless, but that is proprietary tech belonging to Microsoft, and thus, it's not possible for Hyperkin to do so without getting permission from the company. While some are delighted with this new option, there is also an outcry from those who dislike using symmetrical thumbsticks, with some even saying that it will cause issues in the hands later on down the line.</p>
<p>At the moment, there is no sign of how much this Hyperkin controller will cost, but we will keep you updated when the information arrives.</p>
<p>Will you be getting The Competitor controller by Hyperkin?</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>