<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 19:28:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apex Legends: From The Rift Update Available Today, Adding New Cosmetics, Launch Royale & More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/apex-legends-from-the-rift-update-available-today-adding-new-cosmetics-launch-royale-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/apex-legends-from-the-rift-update-available-today-adding-new-cosmetics-launch-royale-more.1028205/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/apex-legends-from-the-rift-update-available-today-adding-new-cosmetics-launch-royale-more/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The newest <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/apex-legends/news/from-the-rift-season-updates" target="_blank" rel="noopener">major update</a> for Apex Legends is out, and is titled From The Rift. In this update, fans will be able to relive the original Apex Games in Launch Royale, where you'll be able to play Lifeline, who is revived with new abilities. Launch Royale takes players back to the original Kings Canyon, where you'll get to experience the game as it initially started, playing with only the original Legends, Weapons, and Loot. With this, it means there are no EVO Armor or Ability Upgrades, and you have to rely on fast reactions and skill to be able to survive in this game mode.</p>
<p><iframe title="Apex Legends: From the Rift Gameplay Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ve-pSwKn79I?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>When it comes to Lifeline, she is back and better than ever. With this, Lifeline is revived as a "Frontline menace." This sees Lifeline get a new kit, where she can teleport DOC to allies who need healing, as well as the ability to deploy a forcefield that makes healing more effective for the whole squad. With a healer this strong, there will be a lot more chaos than there was previously.</p>
<p>In addition to the Launch Royale being added back to Apex Legends, players will be able to get Rift Relics. This will be noticeable due to the appearance of cosmic portals, which are the signal for a Rift Relic. This comes with some of the most iconic, overpowered weapons in the series, along with Boost Kits, which can make or break the build for the players who manage to get their hands on the Rift Relic. To get the Rift Relic, you just have to destroy it to get the reward. However, if it moves outside of the Ring, you may not be able to get the reward as it becomes unstable.</p>
<p>Finally, a brand-new Universal Melee cosmetic is being added to the game called Raptor's Claw. This is a universal Melee cosmetic that you'll be able to get through the Void Mercenary Store from November 5 through to January 7. Additionally, once you've unlocked this cosmetic, you'll be able to get the Crystal Chamber Death Box, which has five other variants to match the Death Boxes. The Raptor's Claw cosmetic will then be moved to the Mythic Shop after January 7.</p>
<p>This is a <a href="https://wccftech.com/apex-legends-removes-steam-deck-support-due-to-cheating/">massive update</a> for Apex Legends and adds a ton of new content, including new support class perks and better skill displays. This is intended to help balance out the matches better and will update live as each player loads into the game, showing you the ranking of the other players you're up against.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gamesir T7 Xbox Wired Controller Review: Gets The Job Done]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/review/gamesir-t7-xbox-wired-controller-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gamesir-t7-xbox-wired-controller-review-gets-the-job-done.1028175/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/review/gamesir-t7-xbox-wired-controller-review/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
				<main>

					

					<!--<div class="ads-container banner-ad floated p-0">
						<div data-pg-ad-spot='div-gpt-ad-wccftechcom38564' style="min-height: 280px;"></div>
					</div>-->
					
										<div><header>Product Info</header><div>
						<h5>Gamesir T7 Xbox Wired Controller</h5></div></div>
					<p>There are a lot of titles where the gaming experience is unparalleled with a gaming controller. Surely, there are instances where a mouse excels but the multi-tasking of a controller is what makes it stand out. Thankfully, there are plenty of controllers available to choose from and this goes for most price ranges.</p>
<p>The majority of gamers usually settle for a cheap one, which is why companies like Gamesir have introduced their brand new budget T7 Xbox wired controller. The <a href="https://www.gamesir.hk/products/gamesir-t7">Gamesir T7</a> brings an Xbox layout and a wired connection that works with several devices out of the box but is it good enough for us to recommend it?</p>
<p>We will see how it performs in various areas and review it in detail in this article. That will be followed by our verdict on the T7 Xbox wired controller which will sum up all the pros and cons of it, providing a clear picture of whether it will be suitable for your needs or not.</p>
<h2>Packaging and Contents</h2>
<figure>
<div>

<div>
		
		
		<p><span>2 of 9</span>
	</p></div></div>
</figure>


<p>Gamesir T7 came in a well-packaged box with a few accessories. Upon opening the box you will find the following:</p>
<ol>
<li>Gamesir T7 Xbox wired controller</li>
<li>A USB A to C cable</li>
<li>A user manual</li>
<li>Xbox game pass</li>
</ol>
<p>It's good to see a free Xbox game pass, specifically the Ultimate one, which will get the users started for some good titles for free for a while. It's going to give you free games for the first month, assuming you are a new user.</p>
<h2>Specifications</h2>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><b>Model</b></td>
<td>T7 Xbox Wired</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Connection</strong></td>
<td>Wired</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>JoySticks</strong></td>
<td>Hall Effect</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Triggers</strong></td>
<td>Hall Effect</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Mappable Buttons</strong></td>
<td>0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Gyro</strong></td>
<td>No</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>RGB Lighting</strong></td>
<td>No</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Compatible Platforms</strong></td>
<td>PC, Xbox consoles, Steam Deck</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2>Gamesir T7 Summary</h2>
<figure>
<div>

<div>
		
		
		<p><span>2 of 9</span>
	</p></div></div>
</figure>


<p>Gamesir T7 is a budget Xbox controller, which is compatible with multiple Xbox consoles out of the box. Moreover, it can be used with PC and Steam Deck, making it a suitable option for those who own these platforms. Since the controller is wired, connecting it to mobile phones won't be possible as it misses the Bluetooth connection.</p>
<p>The T7 controller is aimed at offering all the necessary controls for playing modern games and whether it is FPS, action-adventure, RPG, or competitive titles, the T7 has all the basic controls for Xbox and PC games.</p>
<p>I liked how it looked from the outside. The white chassis with some grey and orange buttons and accents add to its aesthetics. The controller is also available in various other colors, including Sapphire Blue and Ruby Red, but the Creamsicle White is minimalistic and feels lovely sitting on the desk.</p>
<h2>Connectivity and Compatibility</h2>
<figure>
<div>

<div>
		
		
		<p><span>2 of 9</span>
	</p></div></div>
</figure>


<p>Gamesir T7 can only be connected to the devices via the USB A to C cable connection. The USB C port is available on top of the controller and the cable is quite long for letting you play from a distance. While it isn't braided, it is still a high-quality and thick orange-colored cable, which you can comfortably store anywhere using the available cable tie strap.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Gamesir-T7-21.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>There is a 3.5mm jack at the bottom of the controller, which can be used to connect a gaming headset. It's pretty convenient and a must-feature for controllers if you own a wired headset. Unfortunately, the more expensive <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/gamesir-tarantula-pro-controller-review-solid-but-can-be-overwhelming/">Gamsir Tarantula Pro misses on this feature, which we have reviewed previously</a>.</p>
<h2>Controls</h2>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Gamesir-T7-7.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>The control layout is roughly the same as you find on regular Xbox controllers. There are four face buttons, a D-Pad, two joysticks, an Xbox home button, and a few miscellaneous buttons for various functions. Let's dive into each in the following sections.</p>
<h3>Face Buttons and D-Pad</h3>
<figure>
<div>

<div>
		
		
		<p><span>2 of 9</span>
	</p></div></div>
</figure>


<p>The face buttons are mushy and so is the D-Pad. Both use membrane switches but I found a bit different feel when pressing the two. Face buttons are pretty much how you will find on most budget controllers but the D-Pad is a bit clicky-type. The size of the D-Pad may not be large, but it's adequate.</p>
<p>The XY buttons are colored in grey while the AB buttons are orange. This contrast helps users adjust to the Xbox controller layout quickly while offering an attractive look.</p>
<h3>Joysticks And Triggers</h3>
<figure>
<div>

<div>
		
		
		<p><span>2 of 9</span>
	</p></div></div>
</figure>


<p>Both joysticks and triggers use the Hall Effect mechanism for detecting the movement. Hall Effect is pretty popular in most budget controllers nowadays since there is zero drifting. With Hall Effect technology, the input is registered even in the smallest movements of buttons and joysticks as the mechanism involves magnets to measure voltage to know the distance and direction.</p>
<p>As per Gamesir, the T7 triggers are accurate up to 0.1mm. These are usually good for racing games but for genres like FPS, it would have been great if the triggers could be adjusted to hair-trigger mode. The official website does say that the triggers support both analog and hair-trigger modes, but I didn't find any button or latch to switch to the hair-trigger mode. The latter makes shooting pretty instant similar to a gaming mouse.</p>
<p>As for the joysticks, these are pretty reliable with a lifespan of up to 5 million cycles.</p>
<h2>User Experience</h2>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Gamesir-T7-13.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>The Gamesir T7 is a light-weight controller and it's mostly because it doesn't use any batteries. This helps in long gaming sessions and since you don't have to worry about battery life, it's decent for PC and Xbox gaming. Still, it doesn't take away the fact that there are instances where you would have to manage that long cable and would rather want to play wirelessly.</p>
<p>There are a lot of controllers out there that bring Bluetooth connectivity for the same price as the T7. This has reduced the compatibility of T7 to just devices that bring a USB A port connection.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, the controls are responsive and satisfactory. I particularly liked the D-Pad and the bumpers. They always gave a clicky feel, which was satisfying and didn't feel flimsy or low quality. Joysticks are also decent but I wouldn't say that these are the best ones. I have used some budget controllers before like EasySMX X05, which had smoother joysticks for better aiming.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Gamesir-T7-14.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Coming to the grip, even though the T7 has a textured grip as you can see in the image, these are very minimal. The textured grip extends all the way to the top at the back but I didn't find them significant to make a solid grip.</p>
<h2>Verdict</h2>
<p>Gamesir T7 Xbox wired controller is an all-right gaming controller for PC and Xbox users. The controls are satisfactory, the build quality is good, and the experience overall is positive. I liked the appearance and how good it looks despite featuring no RGB lighting. It would have been great if it had more buttons and some remappability but at this price, it isn't a big complaint.</p>
<p>The long and good quality cable is an additional pro for the T7, which will let you play from the couch unless you are planning to sit several meters away from your device. The Gamesir T7 isn't the best at this price but it gets the job done by offering up-to-the-mark and competitive features. However, I would prefer to go with a controller that offers both wired and wireless connectivity if my budget is $35.</p>

					
					

<p>Gamesir T7 is a satisfactory gaming controller for your daily gaming needs that works with various devices out of the box. While it doesn't have premium features, it gets the job done with its modern and responsive controls.</p>

<div>
		<div>
		<h6>
			<span>Pros</span>
		</h6>
		<ul>
			<li>Good build quality
</li><li>Minimalistic design
</li><li>Pleasant buttons
</li><li>Hall effect joysticks and triggers
</li><li>Responsive
</li><li>Long and high quality cable
</li><li>3.5mm audio jack
</li><li>Compatible with PC, Xbox consoles and Deck
</li><li>Microphone mute button</li>		</ul>
	</div>
			<div>
		<h6>
			<span>Cons</span>
		</h6>
		<ul>
			<li>Not the smoothest joysticks
</li><li>Fewer customizations
</li><li>Only wired connection
</li><li>Grips are slightly textured
</li><li>No back paddles or buttons
</li><li>No software support</li>		</ul>
	</div>
	</div>

					
				</main>
			</article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PS5 Pro Runs Naraka: Bladepoint Twice as Fast, Says Developer; PSSR Has Similar Quality to DLSS]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ps5-pro-runs-naraka-bladepoint-twice-as-fast-says-developer/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ps5-pro-runs-naraka-bladepoint-twice-as-fast-says-developer-pssr-has-similar-quality-to-dlss.1028172/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/ps5-pro-runs-naraka-bladepoint-twice-as-fast-says-developer/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>This is the week of the PS5 Pro, and you can expect lots more coverage on Sony's mid-generation console refresh. Earlier today, we published our <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-pro-unboxing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">unboxing</a> of the hardware; now, here's another episode of our chats with game developers who have chosen to support the new console at launch.</p>
<p>This time around, we interviewed&nbsp;Yongcheng Liu, Console Version Producer of <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/naraka-bladepoint-review-musou-royale/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Naraka: Bladepoint</a> at NetEase ThunderFire Universe X Studio. The free-to-play battle royale game continues to be extremely popular and just received a new gameplay mode and new hero (Cyra, a high priestess from the Temple of Light and Shadow, a support-oriented character who excels at healing teammates, controlling enemies, and dealing damage).</p>
<p>In our PS5 Pro chat, Liu said the new console runs the game twice as fast as the base PlayStation 5. The producer also reckons PlayStation Spectral Super Resolution offers similar visual quality to the current AI upscaling benchmark, NVIDIA DLSS, save for minor differences in small details. Keep scrolling below for the full Q&amp;A.</p>
<p><iframe title="New Mode, New Cosmetics | Halloween is there!  NARAKA: BLADEPOINT" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GGHrJNXB7Hc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><strong>What do you think of the PS5 Pro's hardware? Which single feature were you most impressed with?</strong></p>
<p>The GPU upgrade is highly significant, offering approximately double the performance improvement for Naraka: Bladepoint. The most impressive features are PSSR and VRS. In particular, VRS, when applied to specific rendering processes in Naraka: Bladepoint, can drastically reduce rendering time. This is extremely important for a competitive game like Naraka.</p>
<p><strong>Compared to the jump between PS4 Pro and PS4, would you say the PS5 Pro-PS5 difference is similar, reduced, or increased?</strong></p>
<p>The PS5 version of Naraka: Bladepoint is our first console game, so unfortunately, we did not have the experience of transitioning from PS4 to PS4 Pro. I believe that with the next generation of console upgrades, we will have much more experience and informed insights to answer this question.</p>
<p>Due to Naraka: Bladepoint's large PC user base and our diligent efforts, we release game updates frequently, with significant content updates every 2–3 weeks. Consequently, you will consistently notice new graphical technologies and features being added to the game. For the console version, our usual approach is to optimize the performance of these updates as much as possible rather than retain everything. Therefore, Sony's recent hardware upgrade will allow us to timely integrate many of the accumulated graphical effects into the console version.</p>
<p><strong>How much of an improvement is there between the PS5 and PS5 Pro versions of the game? Also, how does the PS5 Pro version stack with the maxed-out PC game?</strong></p>
<p>Naraka: Bladepoint can achieve 4K 60FPS on the PS5 Pro without using upscaling technologies, which is not possible on the PS5. In balanced mode, the PS5 Pro with PSSR enabled offers better visual quality compared to the PS5 using other upscaling methods while still maintaining a stable<br>
frame rate.<br>
As a live-service battle royale game, Naraka: Bladepoint places significant stress on the CPU, often resulting in CPU bottlenecks in many circumstances. Therefore, there is some FPS difference between the PS5 Pro and high-end PCs. However, we have implemented different graphical modes to provide our fans with more freedom of choice.</p>
<p><strong>Can you share the complete details of the various PS5 Pro modes available to Naraka: Bladepoint players?</strong></p>
<p>● <strong>Quality Mode:</strong> Provides native 4K ultra-clear visuals, ideal for users seeking better visual experiences.<br>
● <strong>Balanced Mode:</strong> Enhances fluidity while maintaining 4K resolution, balancing both visual quality and smoothness.<br>
● <strong>Frame Rate Mode:</strong> Offers native 1080P visuals for users who need the highest frame rates, ensuring smoother gameplay.</p>
<p><strong>Are you using PSSR? If so, how does it compare to the premiere AI-based upscaling solution, NVIDIA DLSS?</strong></p>
<p>Yes, Naraka: Bladepoint does use PSSR. We believe that the various upscaling technologies have<br>
had the most significant impact on game development in recent years, and we actively embrace this trend while also exploring the application of new graphics technologies.<br>
When comparing PSSR to DLSS, the overall visual performance is similar, with minor differences in some small details. For a competitive game like Naraka: Bladepoint, we strive to ensure that players do not notice these differences during regular gameplay unless the platform's performance cannot support it.</p>
<p><strong>The big controversy about Sony's new console is related to its pricing. Based on the hardware, do you believe it to be fair or excessive?</strong></p>
<p>From a developer's perspective, better GPUs and CPUs provide more development headroom, helping us apply new graphics technologies to our games. The high pricing could be due to various reasons, such as changes in chip prices, increased manufacturing costs, and so on. I hope these<br>
factors do not hinder players from experiencing the games they love. Therefore, we will continue to<br>
support both the PS5 and PS5 Pro versions, ensuring that every PS player who enjoys Naraka:<br>
Bladepoint can have a great experience with the game.</p>
<p><strong>Thank you for your time.</strong></p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starfield Beta Update 1.14.74 Reintroduces Uncapped Frame Rate on Xbox Series X, Improves Performance]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/starfield-beta-update-1-14-74-reintroduces-uncapped-frame-rate-on-xbox-series-x-improves-performance/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/starfield-beta-update-1-14-74-reintroduces-uncapped-frame-rate-on-xbox-series-x-improves-performance.1028130/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/starfield-beta-update-1-14-74-reintroduces-uncapped-frame-rate-on-xbox-series-x-improves-performance/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Bethesda Game Studios has just <a href="https://x.com/BethesdaStudios/status/1853843353495884212" target="_blank" rel="noopener">released</a> a new Starfield beta update, version 1.14.74. Like all beta updates, it can be checked out on PC via the Steam branch; to access it, right-click&nbsp;on Starfield in your Steam library, select Properties, then Betas, and finally [beta] in the drop-down menu.</p>
<p>Highlights for this patch include reintroducing the uncapped frame rate option on Xbox Series X, various performance improvements, and multiple bug fixes.</p>

<ul data-offset-key="djpg2-0-0">
<li data-block="true" data-editor="ae9sn" data-offset-key="djpg2-0-0">
<p><em>General performance and stability improvements.</em></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="ae9sn" data-offset-key="57lku-0-0">
<p><em>The uncapped frame rate option is available again for Xbox Series X users.</em></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="ae9sn" data-offset-key="3kv9b-0-0">
<p><em>The Message of the Day now displays more consistently on the Xbox.</em></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="ae9sn" data-offset-key="10vh6-0-0">
<p><em>Addressed an issue where some console commands did not disable certain achievements.</em></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="ae9sn" data-offset-key="2b3fc-0-0">
<p><em>Shattered Space will now show ownership correctly for Steam users.</em></p>
</li>
</ul>

<ul data-offset-key="eb82e-0-0">
<li data-block="true" data-editor="ae9sn" data-offset-key="eb82e-0-0">
<p><em>The Annihilator Particle Beam damage-over-time effect no longer triggers companion reactions.</em></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="ae9sn" data-offset-key="9fojl-0-0">
<p><em>Resolved a Leadership skill issue that could cause companions to not speak up.</em></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="ae9sn" data-offset-key="885dd-0-0">
<p><em>Improved function of the stealth bar while around crowd NPCs.</em></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="ae9sn" data-offset-key="cju6f-0-0">
<p><em>Addressed an issue where destroyed ships could load in without collision.</em></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="ae9sn" data-offset-key="ednib-0-0">
<p><em>Addressed an issue where loading a save that relied on missing content could place the Starfield player in an undesirable location.</em></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="ae9sn" data-offset-key="9spup-0-0">
<p><em>Tracker's Alliance - Roach will now accurately track the number of completed bounties.</em></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="ae9sn" data-offset-key="co203-0-0">
<p><em>Tracker's Alliance - Bounty targets will now appear in Akila, Gagarin, and Cydonia.</em></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="ae9sn" data-offset-key="8cmon-0-0">
<p><em>Tracker's Alliance - Fixed an issue where the player could receive additional credits by extorting the target and then killing them.</em></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="ae9sn" data-offset-key="8r94o-0-0">
<p><em>Tracker's Alliance - Bounty targets should now have a larger variety of appearances.</em></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="ae9sn" data-offset-key="1pci7-0-0">
<p><em>Tracker's Alliance - Bounty targets will now be removed after being dealt with and leaving the area.</em></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="ae9sn" data-offset-key="9cen4-0-0">
<p><em>Tracker's Alliance - Extorting or bribing a bounty target is no longer a guaranteed success.</em></p>
</li>
</ul>

<ul data-offset-key="6ttkp-0-0">
<li data-block="true" data-editor="ae9sn" data-offset-key="6ttkp-0-0">
<p><em>The Starjacker - The correct quest objective will display when the player boards the Junker Watchdog.</em></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="ae9sn" data-offset-key="4nova-0-0">
<p><em>Legacy of the Fang - Addressed an issue that could cause the key to no longer open the door if the player had left the area.</em></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="ae9sn" data-offset-key="5r5d6-0-0">
<p><em>The Duel - If the Starfield player attacks Danika and gets arrested, they are now able to speak to her afterwards to complete the quest.</em></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="ae9sn" data-offset-key="52e5u-0-0">
<p><em>The Scaled Citadel - Anasko’s ID Key is now flagged as a quest item.</em></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="ae9sn" data-offset-key="1lbpo-0-0">
<p><em>What Remains - Addressed an issue where having certain creations installed could make the hatch on The Oracle non-interactable.</em></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="ae9sn" data-offset-key="2hoo0-0-0">
<p><em>What Remains - The Engineering Bay Access Card is now flagged as a quest item.</em></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="ae9sn" data-offset-key="djj7l-0-0">
<p><em>A House Divided - The doors in the Radiology center will stay unlocked during this quest if the player exits the area and returns.</em></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="ae9sn" data-offset-key="a7dq8-0-0">
<p><em>A House Divided - The player can now obtain the keycard from Madri after the quest is completed.</em></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="ae9sn" data-offset-key="a4ih1-0-0">
<p><em>Zealous Overreach - Fixed an issue that could occur if the Va’ruun Zealots at the exterior of Shadow Station Epsilon were killed before receiving the quest.</em></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="ae9sn" data-offset-key="f9n1p-0-0">
<p><em>Zealous Overreach - Addressed an issue that could prevent the player from speaking to Razma or Viktor if the quest “Conflict in Conviction” is started at the same time.</em></p>
</li>
<li data-block="true" data-editor="ae9sn" data-offset-key="ejrgk-0-0">
<p><em>Zealous Overreach - Vortex Phantoms will no longer spawn close enough to interrupt the negotiation scene.</em></p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Starfield recently <a href="https://wccftech.com/starfield-turns-one-today-and-bethesda-has-shared-some-new-shattered-space-details/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">celebrated</a> its first anniversary and shortly afterward launched the first expansion, Shattered Space. However, it wasn't <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/starfield-shattered-space-may-the-great-serpent-save-us/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">received</a> very well.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>