<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 15:22:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 New Patent Suggests Voice Chat OS Integration, Proximity Chat Support in First-Party Titles]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-voice-chat-os-proximity-chat/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-new-patent-suggests-voice-chat-os-integration-proximity-chat-support-in-first-party-titles.1129896/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-voice-chat-os-proximity-chat/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A recent patent filed by Nintendo strongly suggests that voice chat will be integrated into the Nintendo Switch 2 operating system, addressing one of the original Switch's biggest oversights.</p>
<p>The patent, which was <a href="https://image-ppubs.uspto.gov/dirsearch-public/print/pdfRedirectDownload/20250058223?requestToken=eyJzdWIiOiI0YjEwOGFlNS0yYjc4LTRlMzQtOTRiYi1kNjZkZDNlMDZiNmEiLCJ2ZXIiOiJlZjViYmE5NC1hMDAxLTQyNzUtOTM1ZC03NTMyY2MyNjE5ZjAiLCJleHAiOjB9" target="_blank" rel="noopener">published</a> late last month by Nintendo in the United States, outlines a system for implementing proximity chat in games, suggesting not only OS voice chat integration for the Nintendo Switch 2, but also that first-party titles will likely support proximity chat, which could considerably improve multiplayer games like the next entry in the Mario Kart series or a potential new entry in the Splatoon series.</p>
<p>Voice chat support directly on the Nintendo Switch 2 has yet to be confirmed, but it's been speculated over the months that the mysterious new C button on the new <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-joy-con-pictures/">Joy-Con controller</a> could have something to do with it. Thankfully, we won't have to wait much longer to learn what the new button does and how the new system will improve the user experience over its predecessor, as the dedicated Nintendo Direct focused on the console, which will likely be out <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-june-release-announced-direct/">before the end of summer</a>, will air in less than a month.</p>
<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 launches on a yet-to-be-confirmed 2025 release date worldwide. We will keep you updated on the highly anticipated system as soon as possible, so stay tuned for all the latest news.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steel Seed Hands-On Preview – A Gem in the Making?]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/steel-seed-hands-on-preview-a-gem-in-the-making/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steel-seed-hands-on-preview-%E2%80%93-a-gem-in-the-making.1129869/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/steel-seed-hands-on-preview-a-gem-in-the-making/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Developing an original experience is becoming increasingly difficult in the video game industry, due both to the market's failure to always reward truly innovative games and the objective difficulty of creating something that hasn't already been done and making it fun. Still, plenty of titles inspired by gaming greats have managed to carve out a space in the industry thanks to the quality of the experience they offer.</p>
<p>This definitely feels like it will be the case with Steel Seed, a stealth action-adventure game in development by Storm in a Teacup, a small Italian development studio that has released some pretty unique indie games like N.E.R.O. - Nothing Ever Remains Obscure, Enki, and <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/close-to-the-sun-review/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Close to the Sun</a>, which attempted to do something different from the norm to varying degrees of success. With their latest game, on the other hand, the Italian studio seems to be playing it a little safely, as Steel Seed is a game that draws inspiration from other linear action-adventure titles like the Uncharted and the Star Wars Jedi series, featuring some light platforming and parkour and a combat system that's vaguely reminiscent of a Soulslike game. This, however, could be the best for the game.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/20250306164231_1-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>While the experience felt almost immediately familiar in the short 20-minute-long demo I had the chance to try, the combination of elements from different games and their quality is sure to set the game apart from its illustrious inspirations. Set in a dark sci-fi world where humanity is on the brink of destruction, Zoe wakes herself up from what felt like a very long slumber to discover herself changed with a robotic body that grants her abilities far superior to those of a regular human. Lost in a world she doesn't recognize, Zoe sets out together with the mysterious drone KOBY to find her father and obtain the answers she seeks, only that this new world she woke up in won't make it very easy for her, as it is filled with machines out to take her down.</p>
<p>Steel Seed is clearly going for a cinematic approach, which feels well-realized already a few minutes into the adventure with some impressive set pieces like a giant robot going after Zoe and her companion drone, but developer Storm in a Teacup is clearly doing things right regarding gameplay as well. While the game employs a Soulslike combat system without a stamina system with light and heavy attacks and dodging, which can become a perfect dodge when timed correctly, as the sole defensive option, at least in the beginning, it implements these features well, thanks to how enemies react to hits, and how responsive Zoe feels to control. The challenge level also seems to be on point, as the enemies in the first area hit hard and don't just stand still taking hits. Over the course of the adventure, it will be possible to expand Zoe's skills to perform more complex maneuvers that will make combat feel more varied than in the first few minutes of the adventure.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/20250306164614_1-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Another big part of the Steel Seed experience will be the stealth mechanics, which also felt well put together in the short demo I played. Moving from one cover to another, Zoe will have to be extra careful avoiding and taking enemies down with instant takedowns, as their AI is mostly on point, making them react properly to Zoe's presence and alerting others in case she is found out. Overall, the stealth mechanics at the beginning of the game are somewhat straightforward, but they are well put together, and they are sure to evolve over the course of the game with more complex level design and an increased involvement of KOBY, who will be able to scan the environment unseen to help Zoe plan a course of action. Best of all, stealth sequences don't seem forced, although going straight for the enemy will put Zoe at a clear disadvantage due to the enemies' higher numbers.</p>
<p><iframe title="Steel Seed | Release Date Announcement Trailer | Coming April 10 | Demo Available Now" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fCuNl3h0IJ8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>With an interesting setting that sets up some compelling mysteries right off the bat, great responsiveness, solid gameplay mechanics, and some impressive visuals powered by Unreal Engine 5, Steel Seed has the chance of becoming one of the surprises of this packed 2025. I did not know anything about the game, but the short demo I tried was enough to make me very interested in a game I feel will surprise many when it launches later this year on PC, PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>