<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 21:16:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Casts Ragnarok’s Thor, Ryan Hurst, as Kratos in Upcoming God of War TV Show]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/god-of-war-tv-show-amazon-prime-ryan-hurst-kratos-cast/</link>
            <guid>1406323</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Amazon's upcoming <strong>God of War TV show</strong> has a <a href="https://wccftech.com/first-god-of-war-tv-series-details/">showrunner in <strong>Ronald D. Moore</strong></a>, a director for its first few episodes in Shogun director <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/god-of-war-tv-series-two-seasons-shogun-director-to-direct-opening-episodes-amazon/">Frederick E.O. Toye</a>,</strong> and today, Amazon and <strong>PlayStation Productions</strong> announced the first confirmed member of the show's cast. <strong>Ryan Hurst</strong>, who players will recognize as the voice of <strong>Thor</strong> from <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/god-of-war-ragnarok-becoming-a-good-father/">God of War Ragnarok</a></strong>, will step into the role of <strong>Kratos</strong> for the upcoming show.</p>



<p>The news was announced with a<a href="https://x.com/PrimeVideo/status/2011529372608364835"> post on X (formerly Twitter) from the official Prime Video account</a>. The post simply reads, "<em>Meet Ryan Hurst, your Kratos in the God of War series coming to Prime Video</em>."</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Though it's not <strong>Christopher Judge</strong> in the role, the voice actor who is now famous for his portrayal of Kratos and his ability to say <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H30ydojdbuc">one three-letter word with more authority than anyone has ever put behind it</a>, Ryan Hurst is still an incredible choice. The side-by-side photo shows that he at least has the beard down (save for some colouring that'll likely come once filming starts), and we know from his performance as Thor that he'll be able to step into the role of Kratos without skipping a beat.</p>



<p>Now that we have our Kratos, with the show reportedly <a href="https://wccftech.com/amazon-god-of-war-tv-show-begins-filming-march-2026/">set to begin filming in <strong>March 2026</strong></a>, hopefully, we'll soon learn who else will be filling out the rest of the cast. As cast members and characters start to be named, we'll also learn more about the approach that Amazon is taking to this show. We know that it will be jumping into the Norse setting of the recent games, but whether it will follow the same story from the previous two games or create its own is unclear.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/god-of-war-tv-show-amazon-prime-ryan-hurst-kratos-cast/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[“It’s Outrageous”: CWA Canada Files Complaint at Ubisoft Over Halifax Closure After Ubisoft Got Nearly $1 Billion in Tax Subsidies]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/cwa-canada-files-complaint-ubisoft-halifax-closure-ubisoft-1-billion-tax-subsidies/</link>
            <guid>1406224</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>In December 2025, <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-halifax-vote-in-favour-of-wall-to-wall-union-under-cwa-canada/"><strong>Ubisoft Halifax</strong> announced it had voted for wall-to-wall union representation</a> under the <a href="https://wccftech.com/cwa-canada-toronto-game-developers-protest-at-rockstar-toronto-in-solidarity-with-fired-workers/"><strong>CWA Canada</strong>,</a> with <strong>61</strong> of the studio's <strong>71</strong> employees joining <strong>Local 30111 </strong>alongside <strong><a href="https://cwacanada.ca/2024/07/01/game-workers-file-to-unionize-with-cwa-canada/">Bethesda Game Studios Montreal</a></strong>. Not even three weeks later, <strong>Ubisoft</strong> announced it was <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-shuts-down-ubisoft-halifax-claims-decision-had-nothing-to-do-with-studio-unionizing/"><strong>shutting down the studio and laying off all 71 workers</strong></a>, denying that the shutdown had anything to do with the majority of its staff unionizing.</p>



<p>In response, the CWA Canada said it would "<em></em><em>pursue every legal recourse to ensure that the rights of these workers are respected and not infringed in any way</em>." That process has seemingly begun, as the media union has <a href="https://cwacanada.ca/2026/01/13/union-files-labour-board-complaint-over-ubisoft-halifax-shutdown/">filed an official complaint with the <strong>Nova Scotia Labour Board</strong></a> over the closure, and today, the union expressed further outrage after learning that Ubisoft was given <strong>nearly $1 billion CAD in tax credit subsidies</strong> in the last five years alone while operating in Nova Scotia.</p>



<p>Provincial and state governments will often offer companies tax breaks as incentives to establish a base of operations in their state or province, and in the case of Ubisoft, the <strong>Assassin's Creed</strong> company has quite the history of taking advantage of these breaks to establish what have become some of its most important offices. </p>



<p><strong>Ubisoft Montreal</strong>, for example, was first set up due to Quebec having attractive tax incentives. If not for those incentives driving Ubisoft to open a studio in Montreal, the city may not have grown into the incredible hub of game development it is today, with scores of talented developers calling Montreal their home.</p>



<p>While Halifax hasn't grown as a game development hub in the same way that Montreal did, as CWA Canada president Carmel Smyth pointed out when the union filed its complaint, "<em>Ubisoft took $12 million in taxpayer money from the government of Nova Scotia to nurture a generation of talent, and to build a tech industry. Now it’s walking away without so much as an apology</em>."</p>



<p>Once the union dug through French Senate documents to see just how much of a tax break the company was receiving, it not only found that Ubisoft had received more tax breaks from Canada than any other country, but also that in the last five years, it had received hundreds of millions in tax credits.</p>



<p>"<em>According to the documents, Ubisoft got 605.6 million Euros (about C$980 million at today’s exchange rates) in tax credits from Canadian governments from 2020 through 2024</em>," CWA Canada writes in a press release.</p>



<p>"<em>It’s outrageous that a company can take hundreds of millions in tax breaks – public money – and then shut down an operation and lay off workers</em>," added Smyth. "<em>And it’s shocking that governments allow it to happen</em>. <em>We need immediate changes to hold companies to account. The rules must make it clear that if you close or significantly downsize a business, you must pay back any government subsidies.</em>"</p>



<p>CWA Canada is also holding to its accusation that Ubisoft shut down the Halifax studio "<em>to keep out the union</em>." While Ubisoft denies that the shutdown had anything to do with the studio unionizing, CWA Canada notes that if the shutdown had been planned as Ubisoft claims, it wouldn't have caught the staff entirely by surprise as it did, and that Ubisoft has yet to provide evidence proving the shutdown was a decision made through "<em>financial necessity</em>."</p>



<p>Since the shutdown was announced, legal and public pressure from the CWA Canada has already pushed Ubisoft to <a href="https://cwacanada.ca/2026/01/12/ubisoft-agrees-to-reconsider-compensation-for-laid-off-halifax-workers-amid-union-public-pressure/">consider raising the severance offered to the 71 workers laid off from the Halifax studio</a>. While that may be all the union is able to get out of this, the pressure applied here, specifically regarding how Canada and its provincial governments approach tax incentives, could create significant change down the line.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/cwa-canada-files-complaint-ubisoft-halifax-closure-ubisoft-1-billion-tax-subsidies/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>