<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 13:57:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Witcher IV Ciri Model Hasn’t Been Changed in Recent Behind-the-Scenes Video, Game Director Confirms]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-iv-ciri-model-not-changed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-witcher-iv-ciri-model-hasn%E2%80%99t-been-changed-in-recent-behind-the-scenes-video-game-director-confirms.1121718/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-iv-ciri-model-not-changed/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Despite what may have looked like, Ciri's model in The Witcher IV hasn't been changed in the recently released behind-the-scenes video, the game's director confirmed.</p>
<p>A few hours ago, Game Director Sebastian Kalemba provided a clarification on <a href="https://x.com/Skalemba" target="_blank" rel="noopener">X</a>, saying that the behind-the-scenes video released earlier this week, which provided a look at how the game's reveal trailer was created, features the same in-game mode of Ciri seen in the reveal trailer shown during this year's The Game Awards show. What makes the model feel different is the fact that, in the behind-the-scenes video, the model is shown without facial animation, lighting or virtual camera lenses.</p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The behind-the-scenes video features the same in-game model of Ciri as seen in the original trailer. We have not modified it. What you’re seeing is raw footage—without facial animation, lighting, or virtual camera lenses. While it’s still in-engine, it represents a… <a href="https://t.co/krs0czANqK">https://t.co/krs0czANqK</a></p>
<p>— Sebastian Kalemba (@Skalemba) <a href="https://twitter.com/Skalemba/status/1895148428176375925?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 27, 2025</a></p></blockquote>

<p>In case you missed the aforementioned new The Witcher IV behind-the-scenes video, you can check it out below.</p>
<p><iframe title="The Witcher 4 – Cinematic Reveal Trailer – Behind the scenes" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pGJ-B7v5tYI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Previously known as <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-polaris-development-cdpr-acquired/">Polaris</a>, The Witcher IV was officially unveiled late last year with a <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-iv-gets-first-trailer-showing-off-cirilla/">cinematic trailer</a> that confirmed, as many speculated, that Ciri will be the main character in the new entry in the series. Featuring the<a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-iv-will-be-around-the-same-size-of-wild-hunt-devs-aim-for-quality-over-quantity/"> same size as The Witcher 3</a> in a bid to go for quality over quantity, The Witcher IV will put<a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-iv-devs-comment-on-ciri-as-the-new-protagonist-explain-that-player-agency-will-be-at-the-center/"> player agency at the center of the experience</a>, providing players with plenty of meaningful choices to make, including opting to play <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-iv-dev-confirms-gwent-talks-about-ciris-new-powers/">Gwent</a> once more instead of focusing on solving whichever crisis will challenge Ciri during the course of the new adventure.</p>
<p>The Witcher IV launches on a yet-to-be-confirmed release date on PC and consoles.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds – How to Upgrade Armor]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/how-to/monster-hunter-wilds-how-to-upgrade-armor/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-%E2%80%93-how-to-upgrade-armor.1121706/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/how-to/monster-hunter-wilds-how-to-upgrade-armor/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Crafting new armor is something you will be doing a lot in Monster Hunter Wilds, as it is a central part of its engaging gameplay loop. As you defeat more monsters and obtain new parts from them, you will be able to craft even more new armor pieces, which, with their stats and skills, will help you better define your character build. The game constantly offering you new armor to craft doesn't mean that you should always discard your old gear, as Monster Hunter Wilds, like previous entries in the series, gives you the option of upgrading every piece of gear to enhance its basic Defense stat.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/20250228113010_1-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>To upgrade any armor piece in Monster Hunter Wilds, you will first need to make some progress in the game's main story campaign and complete<strong> Chapter 2-2</strong>. Once this is done, all you need to do to upgrade your armor is speak with Gemma at the <strong>Smithy</strong> and select the <strong>Upgrade From Box</strong> option, which will allow you to use Armor Spheres to increase any armor piece Defense value up until it reaches a certain level that varies per gear. The higher the rarity value of the gear you are upgrading, the more points will be needed to upgrade, so it is always a good idea to only focus on armor that you know you will use often, as, while the game is pretty generous when it comes to rewarding you with Armor Spheres, there will come a time with high rarity gear when upgrading any armor piece will become very expensive.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hogwarts Legacy Latest PC Patch Introduces Intel XeSS 2, Extended NVIDIA Frame Generation Features Support and More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/hogwarts-legacy-intel-xess-2-support/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hogwarts-legacy-latest-pc-patch-introduces-intel-xess-2-extended-nvidia-frame-generation-features-support-and-more.1121703/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/hogwarts-legacy-intel-xess-2-support/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A new Hogwarts Legacy patch is now live on PC, introducing new features to the game, including support for <a href="https://wccftech.com/intel-xess2-frame-generation-low-latency-mode-smoother-gaming-first-titles/">Intel XeSS 2.</a></p>
<p>The February 27th patch primarily focuses on improving mod support with plenty of fixes, which include input prompt, text, and interface fixes. The patch also introduces some gameplay fixes for fast travel, Third Time's a Charm not being unlocked, silent restart falling with mods, and basic attacks leaving blank impacts on hit surfaces, among other fixes. The biggest new feature added to the game by the latest patch, however, is the introduction of Intel XeSS 2 support, specifically the frame generation features of Intel's tech that can only be used on Intel GPUs, both Alchemist and Battlemage. Extended NVIDIA Frame Generation features are also mentioned in the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/990080/view/506195909797741136?l=english" target="_blank" rel="noopener">patch notes</a>, although it is not yet clear what these are since the game already supports Multi Frame Generation on the NVIDIA RTX 5000 series.</p>
<p>Hogwarts Legacy has been a smashing success since its release in 2023, so much so that the game is reportedly getting an <a href="https://wccftech.com/hogwarts-legacy-directors-cut/">expanded Definitive Edition</a> that will also receive DLC content. Avalanche Software is reportedly also working on <a href="https://wccftech.com/hogwarts-legacy-2-reportedly-wont-be-live-service-hogwarts-definitive-edition-will-include-dlc/">a second entry in the series</a> that will not be a live service game, which is definitely good news, considering how Warner Bros' recent<a href="https://wccftech.com/multiversus-to-end-with-season-5-game-to-go-offline/"> live service offerings</a> have <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league/">turned out.</a></p>
<p>Hogwarts Legacy is now available on PC, PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Xbox Series X, Xbox Series S, Xbox One, and Nintendo Switch. You can learn more about the game by checking out Chris' <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/hogwarts-legacy-review/">review.</a></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds – Best Gear to Get Started for Beginners]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/how-to/monster-hunter-wilds-best-gear-to-get-started-for-beginners/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-%E2%80%93-best-gear-to-get-started-for-beginners.1121673/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/how-to/monster-hunter-wilds-best-gear-to-get-started-for-beginners/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Monster Hunter series is known for giving players tons of viable options to build their hunter, and Monster Hunter Wilds is no different, as even at the beginning of the adventure in the Forbidden Lands, you have a decent choice of gear coming with skills that are more or less useful, depending on the situation. For a newcomer to the series, however, even the few choices available at the start of the game can feel overwhelming. This, combined with the lack of knowledge regarding the <a href="https://wccftech.com/how-to/monster-hunter-wilds-best-beginner-weapons-to-learn/">14 weapon types</a> and the general flow of the game, can make the first few hours of the game a little frustrating.</p>
<p>While Monster Hunter Wilds does an excellent job at introducing its core mechanics to the player, you are going to make a lot of mistakes as you hunt your very first monsters. As such, the first thing to look for in gear at the very beginning of the campaign is what it can offer in terms of survivability. In this regard, there's no better early choice than the<strong> Hope Mail</strong> and <strong>Hope Vambraces</strong>, which are both available from the start of the game and come with the <strong>Divine Blessing</strong> skill, which reduces received damage and activates fairly frequently. This will help you survive while you are learning how the game works.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/20250227115609_1-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Every other piece of gear available during the early game in Monster Hunter Wilds is generally fine for protection, but not as much for skills, so pick any option that looks good for you until you can craft either the <strong>Bone Helm</strong>, which requires 1 Mystery Bone, or the <strong>Alloy Helm</strong>, which requires 1 Machalite Ore and 1 Iron Ore which can be found rather easily on the Windswept Plain. The Marathon Runner skill of the first, which reduces Stamina depletion for actions that constantly deplete it, like running, and Quick Sheathe of the second, which makes you sheathe your weapon faster and lets you use items more quickly with the exception of the Sword and Shield that doesn't need to be sheathed to use them, are decent skills that can enhance your survivability.</p>
<p>For a good Coil and Greaves, you will need to proceed a bit further into the game until you can craft better gear.&nbsp;<span>The&nbsp;<strong>Balahara Coil and Greaves</strong> come with the Evade Extender skill that increases the distance of your dodge maneuver, which is a big help not only for defensive purposes but also for repositioning yourself when needed.</span> To craft them, you will first have to hunt a Balahara as part of the main campaign and then collect 1 Balahara Certificate, 2 Balahara Scales, 1 Balahara Shell, and 1 Balahara Pearl. for the Coil 2 Balahara Shells and 1 Balahara Skulls for the Greaves.</p>
<p>As Monster Hunter Wilds rewards experimenting with gear, these recommendations may not be the best for everyone and are based on my experience as a former newcomer who got pulled into the series with Monster Hunter Rise, before going back to playing older entries in the series, so you may find some other early game gear combination that could work better. In addition, these recommendations don't take the used weapon type into account. For any weapon that can guard and has an offset attack, like the Great Sword, for example, the <strong>Doshaguma Armor set</strong> is a good choice due to Doshaguma's Might, a set bonus that increases attack when Power Clashing against a monster or successfully deflecting an attack with an Offset attack. The Long Sword, on the other hand, benefits greatly from the <strong>Alloy Helm and Greaves</strong>, which come with Quick Sheate that speeds up all weapon sheating, including Special Sheathe, which you will want to learn to use properly if you want to master this weapon type. You will need 1 Machalite Ore and 1 Iron Ore to craft either of them and with some upgrades, they can potentially carry you throughout all of Low Rank.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds – Best Beginner Weapons to Learn]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/how-to/monster-hunter-wilds-best-beginner-weapons-to-learn/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-%E2%80%93-best-beginner-weapons-to-learn.1121652/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/how-to/monster-hunter-wilds-best-beginner-weapons-to-learn/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>With 14 different weapon types and so many mechanics to learn, trying to get into the Monster Hunter series can feel daunting, and even with its streamlining of many of the experience's core mechanics, Monster Hunter Wilds can be difficult to get into for newcomers, since the game still plays like very little else on the market. Every journey, however, begins with a single step, and the very first step in any Monster Hunter game, including Wilds, is finding the best weapon not only to learn the game's intricacies but also to have fun relatively quickly. And just like monsters, not all weapon types are made the same, and some are better suited for beginners than others.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/20250215123352_1-1-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>The best beginner weapons in Monster Hunter Wilds share some common traits. For starters, they have relatively simple game plans that don't require managing resources or multiple gauges to hit hard, have versatile movesets that include both solid offensive and defensive options and have very simple combos that don't require pressing multiple buttons.</p>
<p>The first weapon that falls perfectly into this category is the <strong>Sword and Shield</strong>. This weapon has some very simple combos that are still satisfying to pull off, no gauges to manage or multiple stances, a very functional guard, and the ability to use items without sheating the weapon, which is quite helpful when you are trying to learn the game.</p>
<p>The other three great beginner weapons in Monster Hunter Wilds are slightly more complex than the Sword and Shield, but not by much, and still work great to learn the game. The <strong>Dual Blades</strong> are a little lacking in defensive options, as they cannot guard whatsoever and only have a perfect dodging mechanic that requires being in two of the three possible stances, but when it comes to offense, they are very straightforward with great mobility and some easy combos. The one thing that makes them slightly more complicated to use besides the lack of defensive options is resource management, as entering the powerful Demon Mode drains stamina. Keeping an eye on the Demon Gauge to enter Archdemon Mode once full adds a little more complexity, but the weapon's flow is generally pretty easy to understand, making it a solid choice for beginners.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/20250226120617_1-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>The <strong>Lance</strong> is also a great beginner weapon in Monster Hunter Wilds thanks to its extremely good Guard, which can be kept up while attacking with its simple combos. Guarding also allows to counterattack when timed right, and with the addition of a few techniques that essentially allow Lance users to intercept monsters' attacks, the weapon is also great to learn some advanced techniques down the line that can be brought over to other weapons.</p>
<p>In past entries in the series, the <strong>Great Sword</strong> wasn't entirely a great beginner weapon. While its moveset was very simple, it required excellent positioning and good knowledge of monsters' tendencies and movesets to land those powerful True Charged Slashes. The buffing of the first two Charged Slashes in the weapon's basic combo, and the addition of Focus Mode, have made using the weapon much, much easier than in previous games, and the improvements made to guarding have made it more than viable to use, in addition to another advanced defensive tool, Offset Rising Slash, which allows you to intercept attacks with good timing. If you're looking for a weapon that hits very hard while being simple to use, the Great Sword is the weapon you want.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/20250226115127_1-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>While these weapons are, in my opinion, the best for beginners in Monster Hunter Wilds, there are a few additional choices that may be better suited for your playstyle. The <strong>Hammer</strong>, for example, is a good choice with a simple gameplan and combos, but it feels a little weak in the game at the beginning without a proper build, so it may prolong fights a little too much. The <strong>Long Sword </strong>comes with relatively simple gameplay as well, but<strong>,</strong> on the other hand, you will need to learn how to use its counterattacks properly, like Foresight Slash and Iai Spirit Strike from Special Sheathe, to use the weapon to its full potential, which can feel a little overwhelming if you're just starting out your Monster Hunter journey. The ranged weapons - <strong>Bow, Light Bowgun, and Heavy Bowgun</strong> - are decent choices for beginners as well, but they require resource management to deal serious damage, and I think they don't really teach you the game properly, as a ranged playstyle doesn't carry much over to a short range playstyle.</p>
<p>At the end of the day, however, you could potentially feel more at ease with even the more complex weapons in the game, like the Charge Blade and the Switch Axe, so you should definitely try them all to see which one feels the best for you. Monster Hunter Wilds is not a competitive game, so having fun remains the most important thing. Back when I started my Monster Hunter journey with <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/monster-hunter-rise-pc-dont-fear-the-rampage/">Rise</a> after many failed attempts over the years, I learned the game with the Long Sword before moving on to some more complex weapons like the Insect Glaive and the Charge Blade, so don't stop at your first pick once you have learned the basics of the series' formula: you may find some more fun ways to play the game and enjoy it for longer!</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>