<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 20:04:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yooka-Replaylee Only Runs at 30FPS on Nintendo Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/yooka-replaylee-only-runs-30fps-nintendo-switch-2/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/yooka-replaylee-only-runs-at-30fps-on-nintendo-switch-2.1309143/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>UK indie developer Playtonic Games is about to launch Yooka-Replaylee, a remaster of 2017's platform game Yooka-Laylee, and they have now shared the first gameplay footage and info on the Nintendo Switch 2 version.</p>



<p>The footage was provided to IGN and you can find it embedded below. As for the Switch 2 port, Playtonic Games <a href="https://x.com/PlaytonicGames/status/1971201407001809335" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">shared on X today</a> that this version will only run at 30 frames per second, on both handheld and TV mode.</p>



<p><em>To provide players the best possible looking and seamless version of the game, Yooka-Replaylee will be running at a consistent 30fps on Nintendo Switch 2 both in handheld and docked mode. Due to limited time with the development kits, we're investigating the possibility of implementing a performance mode to follow some time post launch.</em></p>



<p><em>We've also received a lot of questions regarding a playable demo on Nintendo Switch 2. Unfortunately, this is not something we're able to accommodate pre-launch but are planning to release post-launch.</em></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Yooka-Replaylee: 24 Minutes of Nintendo Switch 2 Footage" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QUOTM-dJp8I?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Yooka-Replaylee features many changes compared to the original (which <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/yookalaylee-1998/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">we reviewed on this page</a>):</p>



<ul>
<li>A new storybook-style presentation with new sequences introduced throughout the game.</li>



<li>New areas and challenges have been added, and old challenges have been improved or replaced. </li>



<li>Collectibles have been rearranged across all levels, and the number of discoverable Pagies has doubled.</li>



<li>The moveset has been tweaked and upgraded to include new moves and combos, and the camera has been refined.</li>



<li>New hidden arcade games are scattered throughout the adventure.</li>



<li>A new collectible currency called Q.U.I.D.S.</li>



<li>An adventurer's notebook to help players hunt down everything hidden in the game</li>



<li>New tonics offer multiple game-changing enhancements to customize and perk up your playstyle.</li>
</ul>



<p>Yooka-Replaylee launches on October 9 for PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series S|X, and Nintendo Switch for $29.99.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/yooka-replaylee-only-runs-30fps-nintendo-switch-2/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands 4 Update Adds FOV Slider on Consoles, Stability Improvements, And More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/borderlands-4-update-adds-fov-slider-consoles-stability-improvements-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-4-update-adds-fov-slider-on-consoles-stability-improvements-and-more.1309101/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A new update for Borderlands 4 was <a href="https://borderlands.2k.com/borderlands-4/update-notes/">pushed to all platforms today</a>, adding an FOV slider for console players, stability and performance improvements for all platforms, UI, audio, visual, gear refinements, and more.</p>



<p>As the latest entry in Gearbox's shooter series, even with <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/borderlands-4/">critical acclaim from multiple outlets</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/borderlands-4-sold-2-million-units-earned-150-million/">major commercial success right at launch</a>, the story of Borderlands 4 isn't about everyone grabbing their own copies and having a blast. </p>



<p>It's about the game's <a href="https://wccftech.com/borderlands-4-developer-says-fixing-pc-performance-is-top-priority/">poor technical performance at launch</a>, Gearbox boss <a href="https://wccftech.com/gearbox-boss-tells-4k-stubborn-players-switch-1440p-use-dlss/">Randy Pitchford's bizarre approach of antagonizing players upset at the state of the game</a>, and, as of two days ago, how the <a href="https://wccftech.com/borderlands-4-nintendo-switch-2-delayed-pre-orders-cancelled/">Nintendo Switch 2 version of the game has been indefinitely delayed</a> while Gearbox works on the versions already in players' hands.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Today's update, and every update that'll come after it, is slowly trying to chip away at that narrative and turn it around from 'Borderlands 4 is broken but fun' to 'Borderlands 4 is fun.'</p>



<p>Starting with stability updates and performance improvements, which are key elements of today's update, and will likely remain key elements of every update going forward. Character animations have been updated, issues of frame rate hitching and crashes have been addressed, and several issues where players didn't get the rewards they were owed from completing an objective have been fixed. </p>



<p>For console players, an FOV slider has finally been added, and for all players, there's a series of balance changes for each of the Vault Hunters and several gameplay elements.</p>



<p>It's all a start, of course, but the work on Borderlands 4 is far from done. Hopefully, it doesn't take Gearbox too much longer to fix the myriad of issues the game launched with. Though with how many problems the game had, it feels like we're in this for the long haul.</p>









			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/borderlands-4-update-adds-fov-slider-consoles-stability-improvements-more/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>