<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 05:44:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NACON Announces Nintendo Switch 2 Accessories, Expecting Switch 2 Release Between April and September]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nacon-announces-nintendo-switch-2-accessories-expecting-switch-2-release-between-april-and-september/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nacon-announces-nintendo-switch-2-accessories-expecting-switch-2-release-between-april-and-september.1087269/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nacon-announces-nintendo-switch-2-accessories-expecting-switch-2-release-between-april-and-september/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>In a new report, NACON has announced their accessories that have been created with the Nintendo Switch 2 in mind. Just last week, people finally got their first look at the <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-joy-con-hall-effect-diablo-iv/">long-awaited Nintendo Switch 2</a>. While it didn't reveal many details, it has been confirmed that people will get more information about the upcoming console in April thanks to a special Nintendo Direct dedicated to the console. NACON is a French publisher and accessory creator and has confirmed that it already has a bunch of peripherals for gamers to purchase when the Nintendo Switch 2 officially releases.</p>
<p>While we don't know the official release date yet of the console, NACON is expecting a significant rise in sales in the first half of the fiscal year of 2025/26, as that is when they are expecting the official release of the Nintendo Switch successor. In the report, they have also confirmed that they have a number of games ready to be published for the Nintendo Switch 2. This information comes from a snippet of the <a href="https://x.com/MauroNL3/status/1881421491285393857/photo/1" target="_blank" rel="noopener">report posted on X by MauroNL</a>, which you can read for yourself on their social media.</p>
<p>Additionally, you can see the line-up of accessories for the Nintendo Switch 2 on the official NACON website, where you can see everything from foldable driving wheels to carrying cases and tempered glass protectors. So far, there are 16 items listed on the website, all for very reasonable prices. While they can't be purchased yet, they will be open to purchase as soon as the Switch 2 releases.</p>
<p>It's likely that once the console releases, NACON will continue to make even more products for the console, including themed accessories such as Mario and Zelda-themed items.</p>
<p>In the snippet of the report posted by MauroNL, NACON says that their business levels will be boosted thanks to the games and accessories that were created in 2024/25 but weren't released in that period and will instead be released in 2025/26. There will also be a NACON Connect Event taking place on March 6, where they will be showcasing some of the games that they have planned for this year. According to the post, they have 10 new games ready to be published, which will all be released at different points throughout the year. The most significant games out of the bunch will be revealed during their special event on March 6.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stronghold Crusader: Definitive Edition Comes to Steam on July 15]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/stronghold-crusader-definitive-edition-comes-to-steam-on-july-15/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/stronghold-crusader-definitive-edition-comes-to-steam-on-july-15.1087179/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/stronghold-crusader-definitive-edition-comes-to-steam-on-july-15/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/firefly-studios-announce-romans-age-of-caesar/">Firefly Studios</a> has announced today that Stronghold Crusader: Definitive Edition will be coming to PC <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3024040/Stronghold_Crusader_Definitive_Edition/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">via Steam</a> on July 15, 2025. If you're not sure whether this will be a faithful remaster of the original 2002 title, there is a demo that is already available on Steam.</p>
<p>For those who want to know more, there is an overview of the game that explains that this new version of the game is an expanded remaster of the original 2002 title from Firefly Studios. The game has received top-tier treatment from the original game's veteran developers to help create a remastered version of the artwork, animations, and music. That's not all, as the game will also feature fresh gameplay, the return of iconic voice actors, and larger maps to explore and build upon. To keep the gameplay fresh, the pre-existing units have been refreshed and reworked, as well as the addition of new playable units, characters, and new campaigns.</p>
<p>This title takes place in the Middle East, as you have to command Crusader Warriors that have to traverse difficult terrain, as well as playing as Saladin to lead a mighty army to repel invaders. It's set in the medieval age, where you will get to experience brutal wars in epic fortresses, unforgettable battlefronts,, and major parts of history. This includes Richard the Lionheart, King of England, and Sultan Saladin bin Ayyub, for example.</p>
<p>Some of the key features include four new AI opponents, a new cooperative skirmish trail, new custom options, and two historical campaigns to get stuck into.</p>
<p>If you want to see what you can get into when the game releases, make sure to check out the Stronghold Crusader: Definitive Edition announcement trailer above. It showcases some of the gritty action you can get involved in, as well as the boosted art design to give a 23-year-old game a new coat of paint.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/developer/fireflystudios" target="_blank" rel="noopener">original titles</a> are still available on Steam, with Stronghold Crusader HD currently on a 70% discount for the next seven days. This also includes the DLC for Stronghold Crusader 2, with all of them being discounted for a combined 80%.</p>
<p>Will you be picking up Stronghold Crusader: Definitive Edition when it releases on July 15, 2025? Let us know in the comments.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>