<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 13:40:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA-Like Open World Game Shows Off Photorealistic Visuals in Debut Images]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/gta-like-open-world-game-shows-off-photorealistic-visuals-in-debut-images/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gta-like-open-world-game-shows-off-photorealistic-visuals-in-debut-images.1019223/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/gta-like-open-world-game-shows-off-photorealistic-visuals-in-debut-images/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Liquid Swords, a Swedish studio established by former <a href="https://wccftech.com/avalanche-studio-founder-opens-up-on-2015s-mad-max-development-blames-warner-bros-for-canceled-dlc-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Avalanche Studios founder Christofer Sundberg</a>, has <a href="https://x.com/LiquidSwords/status/1849727432904872311" target="_blank" rel="noopener">shared</a> the first in-game screenshots of its GTA-like open-world game, and they look stunning. When asked whether these were actual images, the official X account confirmed they were real.</p>
<p>The game is being developed with Unreal Engine 5, whereas Avalanche has historically used its own Apex engine for Just Cause, Mad Max, and Rage 2. Tech Director Fredrik Lönn explained the engine choice with the following statement:</p>
<p><em>Custom engines were historically the way forward, and that's what my former team at Avalanche did over 18 years ago when development started on Just Cause 1. The landscape has changed since then, and now it's quite the opposite. </em><em>We decided to go with Unreal Engine 5. Unreal has been proven for high-quality AAA games, both by Epic themselves in the case of Fortnite and by other game studios worldwide shipping amazing games on Unreal. With Epic making improvements toward open-world development, we get full access to the source code, and the integrations with other software and pipelines are excellent.</em></p>
<figure>
<div>

<div>
		
		
		<p><span>2 of 9</span>
	</p></div></div>
</figure>


<p>Liquid Swords was founded in December 2020. Sundberg recalled why he created this new studio:</p>
<p><em>In December 2020, I set out on a journey to make a difference in the world of game development– which has been my professional and entertainment world since the early 90s. I want to make a difference to how games are made, how the teams work, and how the creative process evolves. Liquid Swords is the realization of an ambition to refocus the game-development process.</em></p>
<p>Around two years later, the studio announced it had received an investment from NetEase Games. Sundberg said at the time:</p>
<p><em>NetEase Games has been exceptionally supportive from the very get-go, believing in our high ambitions and quality-focused approach to game development. We are very pleased to have them as our partners on this adventure and with their support, we can begin to realize the vision for our studio.</em></p>
<p>While those screenshots are indeed very reminiscent of a photorealistic version of Rockstar's GTA series, Liquid Swords is making a single player open world, narrative driven action RPG. We still don't know anything else, but hopefully that will change soon following these first screenshots.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Will Be A Very Accessible Game For Newcomers; Traversal Improvements Detailed]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/monster-hunter-wilds-accessible/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-will-be-a-very-accessible-game-for-newcomers-traversal-improvements-detailed.1019220/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/monster-hunter-wilds-accessible/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Monster Hunter Wilds will be a very accessible game for newcomers, thanks to the implementation of some new features.</p>
<p>Speaking with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@GamerBraves">GamerBraves</a>, producer Ryozo Tsujimoto commented on some of the new game mechanics, including those that are meant to ease newcomers into the experience, such as tutorials. These tutorials, which teach the basics of the experience, come with some options that allow players to tweak them to show as little or as much as they want. These tweaking options are certainly quite welcome, as they will not only help newcomers but will also allow more experienced players to hide them so that they can play without any hindrance right from the start. Tsujimoto-san also mentioned that players can get some help from Alma the handler to pick the weapon best suited for their play styles by replying to some questions. This feature was also available in the <a href="https://wccftech.com/monster-hunter-wilds-gamescom-preview/">Gamescom demo</a> I had the chance to try out earlier this year, so it is likely it will be in next week's <a href="https://wccftech.com/monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta/">open beta</a>, which seems to be based on the public demos, and in the final game as well.</p>
<p>Not every new feature in Monster Hunter Wilds was implemented just to help newcomers, however. The introduction of weapon switching, for example, is meant to provide players with more options and not break the gameplay action loop too much. As for why players can only bring two weapons, Tsujimoto-san confirmed it was to make things realistic, as being able to switch between all 14 types wouldn't have been so. Palicoes now being able to talk was also a change that was made to help the flow of action, as auditory cues are just better than visual ones in this regard. If players want, however, they can revert the Palicoes' voices to the meows of the previous entries in the series. Speaking of characters talking, Tsujimoto-san also confirmed that the hunter talking was a change made to help immersion, but players shouldn't expect them to speak a lot, as the team wanted to keep the tone of the series intact in Monster Hunter Wilds.</p>
<p>Thanks to feedback from Monster Hunter World, traversal has been improved considerably in the new entry in the series. The introduction of bigger, seamless maps proved to be somewhat of an issue for some players in the 2018 game, and with the bigger maps of Monster Hunter Wilds, Scoutflies wouldn't have been enough. With the technological advancements made in the past few years, the development team not only was able to implement the Seikret, but also to improve their AI so much that they can bring the player to the target monster by pressing a single button.</p>
<p><iframe title="Ryozo Tsujimoto Making Monster Hunter Wilds EASIER for Newcomers | GCA 2024 Interview" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Lezi2Pwx5zw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Monster Hunter Wilds launches on February 28th on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X, and Xbox Series S worldwide. Thanks to the aforementioned open beta, players on all formats will be able to try out the game next week.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metaphor: ReFantazio PC Users Can Now Get a Stunning Texture Improvement Mod]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/metaphor-refantazio-pc-users-can-now-get-a-stunning-texture-improvement-mod/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metaphor-refantazio-pc-users-can-now-get-a-stunning-texture-improvement-mod.1019169/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/metaphor-refantazio-pc-users-can-now-get-a-stunning-texture-improvement-mod/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Metaphor: ReFantazio, the new JRPG made by the Persona team, <a href="https://wccftech.com/metaphor-refantazio-becomes-million-seller-on-launch-day/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">is already a million seller</a> and has received widespread critical acclaim, too. On Wccftech, Kai Tatsumoto <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/metaphor-refantazio-persona-non-grata/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">rated</a> it 9 out of 10:</p>
<p><em>No matter how much I engaged with the core fundamentals of Metaphor: ReFantazio, I couldn’t escape the feeling that this was largely Persona 6 by another name rather than some new IP that could stand on its own merits. That isn’t to say that Hashino’s team hasn’t created another stylish JRPG with broad appeal, but the premise that Metaphor: ReFantazio is a brand-new fantasy is dead. If the Persona series left you wanting more, Metaphor: ReFantazio certainly is a tale worth experiencing for yourself. Those who harbor an innate distaste for the social systems and time limits of modern Persona titles will find no solace here, but those who are willing to embrace what very well could be the sixth Persona title in all but name alone will experience one of the most stylish Japanese roleplaying games of 2024.</em></p>
<p>However, Atlus games have never exactly stood out for their visuals, and this one is no exception. If you're playing it on a 4K display, chances are you will have noticed some really low resolution textures. Luckily, a PC modder has already uploaded a texture improvement mod <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/metaphorrefantazio/mods/25?tab=description" target="_blank" rel="noopener">on Nexus</a>. As you can see in these comparisons, the difference is absolutely massive. According to the modder, some of the original textures were only 128x128 or 256x256.</p>

<figure></figure>


<figure></figure>


<figure></figure>


<figure></figure>

<p>The mod overhauls Metaphor: ReFantazio textures across all zones, NPCs, monsters, and DLC outfits. However, it is also quite big at 4.4 GB. Not all textures are 4K resolution; as the modder explained, it would have been too costly from a performance point of view. Still, they're all HD textures and higher, which is a big improvement in visual clarity over the original game.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 NVIDIA DLSS, AMD FSR, Intel XeSS Support is Reportedly Broken, Resulting in Minimal Performance Improvements]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-dlss-fsr-broken/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-nvidia-dlss-amd-fsr-intel-xess-support-is-reportedly-broken-resulting-in-minimal-performance-improvements.1019142/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-dlss-fsr-broken/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 features a broken implementation of all three major upscalers, resulting in minimal performance improvements despite rendering at lower resolutions.</p>
<p>As reported on the game's subreddit by <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Important_Shake_1491/">Important_Shake_1491</a>, every upscaler apparently has a performance overhead of around 40% when enabled, meaning that whenever NVIDIA DLSS, AMD FSR, or Intel XeSS are enabled, the base framerate drops around 40% before getting increased by upscaling. This issue, according to the user, was also present in later seasons of Modern Warfare III and hasn't been fixed. The user also provided some benchmark results from tests conducted on two different system configurations (12900h + 3070ti mobile, 9900k + 3080 desktop) to offer proof, showing a way too big performance drop with DLAA and FSR 3 Native enabled. Other users are reporting similar performance issues, so it definitely seems like there's something wrong that needs to be patched.</p>
<blockquote><p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/blackops6/comments/1gbnd6q/dlss_fsr_xess_completely_broken_and_actually/">DLSS, FSR, XESS completely broken and actually reduces performance on PC BO6.</a><br> by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Important_Shake_1491/">u/Important_Shake_1491</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/blackops6/">blackops6</a></p></blockquote>

<p>Being a competitive-focused game, Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 isn't particularly demanding in terms of <a href="https://wccftech.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-pre-load-details-revealed-102-gb-ssd-needed/">system requirements</a> compared to other games released this year. However, achieving the best possible performance is extremely important, so hopefully, the developers will fix this issue as quickly as possible to allow PC users to boost performance properly with upscalers without being forced to use frame generation.</p>
<p>Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 is now available on PC, PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Xbox Series X, Xbox Series S and Xbox One.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>