<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 19:20:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PvPvE Mech Shooter SAND Enters Early Access via Steam on April 3]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/pvpve-mech-shooter-sand-enters-early-access-via-steam-on-april-3/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pvpve-mech-shooter-sand-enters-early-access-via-steam-on-april-3.1124055/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/pvpve-mech-shooter-sand-enters-early-access-via-steam-on-april-3/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>This news was announced at the IGN Fan Fest, where publisher tinyBuild games and developer Hologryph said that the highly anticipated PvPvE extraction shooter SAND, would be getting an Early Access release date of April 3, 2025.</p>
<p>Players were first introduced to SAND and the difficulty of the intense game with a demo that was showcased during <a href="https://wccftech.com/sands-steam-next-fest-demo-available-now/">Steam Next Fest</a> last year and was so popular that it ranked among the top ten most played demos. Additionally, last month saw an open playtest for SAND, with over 200,000 testers participating.</p>
<p>If you haven't seen what SAND is all about, make sure to check out this trailer below, which showcases the Tramplers you'll get to pilot, as well as some of the high-octane combat you'll get to take part in.</p>
<p><iframe title="SAND | Release Date Reveal | Action-packed Multiplayer Mech Action" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6rvIyS0eIlY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>In SAND, you are thrown into an alternate history of 1910 with an industrial spin. In this game, you'll get to experience first-person PvPvE combat, where you can choose to play on your own or with a group of friends, where you can then take on other players in the dunes of Sophie, an area that was once filled with resources but now lays barren and desolate.</p>
<p>Not only will you get to pilot the Tramplers, which are your gigantic walking bases. Here, you will be able to store any resources that you plunder, as well as hide here to get protection from the intense elements, as well as get to utilize it in battle. You can choose the size, the layout, the placement of its engine and compartments, as well as what weapons you equip on your Trampler.</p>
<p>According to the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1431300/Sand/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam page</a> for SAND, the developers are estimating that the title will be in Early Access for around a year based on the roadmap and developmental goals. This game has been in the works since 2023, where the game has built up a dedicated community that has participated in multiple playtests and demos to provide valuable feedback to the team.</p>
<p>When asked how the full version will differ from the Early Access version, the developers have stated the following:</p>
<p>"<em>SAND is expected to evolve and grow significantly over the course of Early Access, with new weapons, Trampler compartments, islands/POIs, PvE mechanics, crafting mechanics, cosmetic options, world hazards, visual improvements, optimization and more already either under discussion or in active development."I</em></p>
<p>Will you be playing SAND when it releases in Early Access? Let us know in the comments below.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Visions of Mana Director Kenji Ozawa Unveils New Studio Sasanqua]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/visions-of-mana-director-kenji-ozawa-unveils-new-studio-sasanqua/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/visions-of-mana-director-kenji-ozawa-unveils-new-studio-sasanqua.1123860/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/visions-of-mana-director-kenji-ozawa-unveils-new-studio-sasanqua/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Kenji Ozawa, the Director of Visions of Mana, has announced that he has founded his own games studio, named Studio Sasanqua. This was originally spotted on <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/former-dev-from-netease-games-ouka-studio-establishes-his-own-company-that-wont-push-the-responsibility-of-management-onto-developers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Automaton Media.&nbsp;</a>Studio Sasanqua was formally founded in January but was only revealed officially on March 3. The unveiling came with a small teaser trailer, which is entirely in Japanese. It doesn't show much and is a very arty video overall.</p>
<p><iframe title="STUDIO SASANQUA: new game development studio announcement" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-bepiAuDR-g?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Kenji Ozawa left his previous employer, Ouka Studios, in December after the studio was closed down on the same day as Visions of Mana's incredibly successful release. This caused a huge uproar in the industry, but it doesn't come as much of a surprise considering the incredibly volatile climate in the games industry. On top of that, once people realized that <a href="https://wccftech.com/visions-of-mana-studio-to-close-down-as-netease-and-tencent-pare-down-their-japanese-investments/">NetEase was responsible</a>, it was less of a surprise, as the giant continues to make layoffs and studio closures even in 2025. Most recently, Netease has had layoffs in its subsidiary Skybox Labs, as well as laying off some of the staff that worked on Marvel Rivals, despite being an incredibly successful game across the board.</p>
<p>All of this played a part in Kenji Ozawa's departure, saying that he moved to Studio Sasanqua after seeing that managers were not taking responsibility for failed projects. He also said, "Management needs to protect creators," which is something that isn't seen very often in today's climate. Plenty of developers in big and small companies have said that there is a severe lack of job security, with <a href="https://wccftech.com/members-of-spiders-go-on-strike-due-to-issues-within-the-company/">Spiders going on strike</a> last year as a result of this. In an interview with Automaton Media, he explains that due to management not taking responsibility for the failures of a project, it's putting "too much responsibility on the shoulders of individual developers," who don't typically have a say in the decision-making at the company.</p>
<p>With his new studio, he plans to find a way to "integrate management and development," two parts of a company that are typically separate and function on their own. He also says that he is fully prepared to assume responsibility should one of the studio's projects fail because of poor management decisions. Ozawa says that the studio will start off by developing small-scale games that are developed in Unreal Engine, with the goal being to move over to making bigger titles on both PC and console.</p>
<p>For now, there is no news about what is coming from his studio other than knowing that the titles will be made in Unreal Engine.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>