<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 17:17:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation 6 SoC is Design Complete and In Pre-Si Validation Phase; GPU is an Early Fork of Gfx13 – Rumor]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/playstation-6-soc-design-complete/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-6-soc-is-design-complete-and-in-pre-si-validation-phase-gpu-is-an-early-fork-of-gfx13-%E2%80%93-rumor.1086096/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/playstation-6-soc-design-complete/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Work on the PlayStation 6 seems to be in a much more advanced stage than most people thought, according to rumors circulating online.</p>
<p>Speaking on the NeoGAF Forums, well-known AMD leaker Kepler L2 commented on the next-generation system from Sony, revealing that its SoC is <a href="https://www.neogaf.com/threads/playstation-6-to-utilize-amds-3d-stacked-chips-amd-udna-flagship-gpu-revived-for-2026-zen-6-halo-with-3d-stacking-technology-and-zen-6-all-on-tsmc.1679744/page-2#post-270022279" target="_blank" rel="noopener">design complete</a> and is currently in pre-silicon validation already, with A0 tapeout scheduled for late this year. While this may mean little to most, this new information suggests that the console may not be too far from release, as Sony's usual cadence between A0 tapeout and the release of a system is <a href="https://www.neogaf.com/threads/playstation-6-to-utilize-amds-3d-stacked-chips-amd-udna-flagship-gpu-revived-for-2026-zen-6-halo-with-3d-stacking-technology-and-zen-6-all-on-tsmc.1679744/page-2#post-270023151" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2 years</a>, meaning that, if this will be the same for the PlayStation 6, we could see the launch of the system in 2027.</p>
<p>The AMD leaker also provided some additional information on the PlayStation 6 GPU, <a href="https://www.neogaf.com/threads/playstation-6-to-utilize-amds-3d-stacked-chips-amd-udna-flagship-gpu-revived-for-2026-zen-6-halo-with-3d-stacking-technology-and-zen-6-all-on-tsmc.1679744/page-2#post-270022949" target="_blank" rel="noopener">revealing</a> it is a fork of AMD gfx13, which was formerly known as RDNA 5 and is now known as UDNA. The leaker couldn't say how big it will be, but the fact that it will belong to the gfx13 will eventually provide some information on some of its features once AMD fully unveils the architecture.</p>
<p>Very little is known about the PlayStation 6 as of now besides the fact that it will once again be powered by AMD. This was revealed <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-6-powered-amd/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">last year</a> in a report which confirmed that Intel lost the bid to produce the console to AMD due to a dispute over how much profit Intel would make from each chip sold to Sony which prevented the company from settling on a price.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>