<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 09:35:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 Already Sold More Than 10 Million Units, Outpacing Its Predecessor]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-sold-more-10-million-units-outpacing-predecessor/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-already-sold-more-than-10-million-units-outpacing-its-predecessor.1342933/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>This morning, Nintendo <a href="https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/pdf/2025/251104e.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reported</a> its quarterly and half-year results for 2025, covering the period from April to September, and revealed that the Nintendo Switch 2 is already outselling its predecessor.</p>



<p>As of September 30, the new hybrid handheld console has sold 10.36 million units, significantly outpacing the original Switch (which took about ten months to sell a similar amount of units). When it comes to Nintendo Switch 2 software sales, they have reached 20.62 million units, meaning that there's an average of nearly two Switch 2 games per unit.</p>



<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/mario-kart-world/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mario Kart World</a>, the big launch exclusive, predictably secured the lion's share of the software sales, selling 9.57 million units. <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/donkey-kong-bananza/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Donkey Kong Bananza</a> also sold pretty well, achieving 3.49 million units from July to September.</p>



<p>In light of these promising results, Nintendo has revised its previous conservative forecast of 15 million units sold by the end of the fiscal year (March 2026). It now forecasts 19 million Nintendo Switch 2 units sold in the console's first year on the market. If achieved, it will be all the more remarkable because it happened under the shadow of the US tariffs. For example, DFC Intelligence <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-estimated-to-sell-15m-units-in-2025-in-resounding-success-but-tariffs-shadow-remains/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">previously revised its original 17 million units forecast down to 15 million</a> specifically due to that ongoing issue.</p>



<p>During the reported timeframe, the original Nintendo Switch sold 1.89 million hardware units and 61.56 million software units. The full-year forecast for the older console was slightly reduced from 4.5 million units to 4 million, although software units are now estimated to reach 125 million copies, up from the 105 million copies of the previous forecast. Overall, the Nintendo Switch has sold 154 million units since its launch in March 2017. At this rate, it seems unlikely it will ever reach the 160.6 million units sold by Sony's PlayStation 2, the best-selling console of all time, but it probably doesn't matter that much to Nintendo.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-sold-more-10-million-units-outpacing-predecessor/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>