<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 19:38:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FBC: Firebreak Is Out on June 17, Reveals Remedy]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/fbc-firebreak-is-out-on-june-17-reveals-remedy/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fbc-firebreak-is-out-on-june-17-reveals-remedy.1173081/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/fbc-firebreak-is-out-on-june-17-reveals-remedy/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>During a special livestream that <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0s2x2a35wP8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">just aired</a>, Finnish developer Remedy Entertainment announced the final release date for its first multiplayer game, FBC: Firebreak. The cooperative first-person shooter game for up to three players will be launched for PC (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2272540/FBC_Firebreak/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/fbc-firebreak-fc3830" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a>), PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series S|X on June 17, priced at $39.99 / €39.99 / £32.99.</p>
<p>As previously <a href="https://wccftech.com/fbc-firebreak-multiplayer-game-set-in-the-control-world-revealed-with-new-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a>, it will also be available on day one via Microsoft's PC Game Pass/Game Pass Ultimate and Sony's PlayStation Plus Extra and Premium tiers in a bid to maximize the player base from the get-go.</p>
<p>Remedy is also releasing a Deluxe Edition, priced at&nbsp;$49.99 / €49.99 / £39.99. This edition includes exclusive cosmetic items and voice packs that allow players to customize their audiovisual identity.</p>
<p>FBC: Firebreak Deluxe Edition includes:</p>
<ul>
<li>“The Firestarter” Premium Voice Pack</li>
<li>“The Pencil Pusher” Premium Voice Pack</li>
<li>Firestarter Armor Set, Apex Revision (Helmet, Body Armor, Gloves)</li>
<li>Scorched Remnant Double-Barrel Shotgun Skin</li>
<li>Golden Firebreak Spray</li>
<li>Classified Requisition: “Firestarter”: A collection of 36 unlockable cosmetic items, including weapon skins, sprays, and armor sets</li>
</ul>
<p>Owners of the base game can upgrade to the Deluxe Edition at any time for $10.00 / €10.00 / £7.00.</p>
<p><iframe title="FBC: Firebreak Developer Update April 2025" width="500" height="375" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0s2x2a35wP8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>During today's live stream, Remedy also briefed fans on the post-launch support. Two new Jobs (missions) will be released later in 2025, while even more updates will be made available throughout 2026. As the studio previously <a href="https://wccftech.com/fbc-firebreak-info-all-post-launch-content-will-be-free/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">confirmed</a>, all post-launch content will be free, and monetization will be limited to cosmetic-only items.</p>
<p>FBC: Firebreak is powered by Remedy's proprietary Northlight engine, previously seen in Control and Alan Wake 2. However, being a multiplayer game first and foremost, the studio has <a href="https://wccftech.com/fbc-firebreak-will-have-lower-pc-requirements-than-remedys-single-player-games/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">taken care to optimize it</a> to be more accessible to a wider range of PC configurations. Even so, high-end features like path tracing (already implemented in Alan Wake 2) and NVIDIA DLSS 4 Multi Frame Generation will be supported on PC.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Analysts Expect Nintendo Will Have 6-8 Million Switch 2 Consoles Ready For Players To Buy At Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/analysts-expect-nintendo-will-have-6-8-million-switch-2-consoles-ready-for-players-to-buy-at-launch/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/analysts-expect-nintendo-will-have-6-8-million-switch-2-consoles-ready-for-players-to-buy-at-launch.1172955/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/analysts-expect-nintendo-will-have-6-8-million-switch-2-consoles-ready-for-players-to-buy-at-launch/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>According to a <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-04-23/nintendo-says-demand-for-switch-2-console-in-japan-overwhelming?srnd=undefined">Bloomberg</a> report, analysts are expecting Nintendo to have &nbsp;6-8 million <a href="https://wccftech.com/roundup/nintendo-switch-2-everything-we-know-about-nintendos-new-console/">Nintendo Switch 2</a> units on hand for its June 5 launch. This would make it one of the biggest console launches in the video game industry's history.</p>
<p>Coming into 2025, everyone expected the launch of the Nintendo Switch 2 to be one of the most significant events of the year. Demand for the Switch 2 has even exceeded Nintendo's expectations. In Japan alone, Nintendo received 2.2 million applications from consumers looking to grab a Switch 2 console.</p>
<p>Nintendo President Shuntaro Furukawa had to take to <a href="https://x.com/Nintendo/status/1914982671522083155">X</a> to formally apologize to players that "<em>a significant number of applicants won't be selected</em>" because the demand exceeded expectations. Bloomberg's report also notes that Nintendo is doing what it can to increase console production to meet the demand as best it can by June 5.</p>
<p>Pre-orders for the Nintendo Switch 2 only went live in the United States and Canada today, after having been <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-pre-orders-have-been-delayed-in-canada-thanks-to-us-tariffs/">delayed</a> due to tariffs announced by the U.S. Consumers looking to lock in their pre-orders<a href="https://x.com/spencerhakimian/status/1915257488703705328?s=46"> reported</a> that websites for retailers like Best Buy and Walmart crashed due to the overwhelming flood of traffic. The outages weren't too bad overall, as many people were still gleefully announcing they had grabbed a pre-order.</p>
<p>While the price of the Switch 2 and its games remains controversial for players, those who could grab a pre-order or buy it on day one are likely getting a better deal than those who choose to wait. Tariffs still loom over the console's pricing like a dark cloud, and we've already seen them impact the Switch 2, as Nintendo <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-pre-orders-us-hardware-pricing-stays-the-same-accessories-bump/">increased the price</a> of several Switch 2 accessories as a response to tariffs.</p>
<p>The price of the console has stayed the same for now, but Nintendo stipulated that it could still increase in the future, "<em>depending on market conditions</em>."</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>