<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 17:13:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Capcom Announces More Expansion Plans With A New Development Hub To Be Built In Osaka And Adding 100 New Employees A Year]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/capcom-announces-more-expansion-plans-with-a-new-development-hub-to-be-built-in-osaka-and-adding-100-new-employees-a-year/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/capcom-announces-more-expansion-plans-with-a-new-development-hub-to-be-built-in-osaka-and-adding-100-new-employees-a-year.1197624/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/capcom-announces-more-expansion-plans-with-a-new-development-hub-to-be-built-in-osaka-and-adding-100-new-employees-a-year/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Capcom has been on a pretty incredible hot streak since 2017, with Monster Hunter, Resident Evil, and Street Fighter all playing huge roles in the company's growth and success since.</p>
<p>The company has grown significantly since its biggest series all started to take off in record-breaking ways, and in its latest <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ni0ZYaiinJ8">presentation</a> to investors regarding its recent financial results for its previous fiscal year, Capcom laid out even more plans to expand.</p>
<p>A key point in its expansion is the announcement of a new development hub that will be built near the company's headquarters in Osaka, Japan. Reported by <a href="https://gamebiz.jp/news/406072">GameBiz</a> (and spotted by <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/capcom-to-continue-upsizing-workforce-by-100-employees-each-year/">Automaton</a>), the building is scheduled to be finished in 2027 and will be a new office meant to help Capcom accelerate its development capabilities. It's described as a new environment where "<em>creators can unleash their talents fully</em>."</p>
<p>The studio also reiterated its plans to continue hiring 100 new employees every year. In an age when so many others are looking towards generative AI and other technology to boost their potential, Capcom recognizes human talent as the "<em>essential driver of growth</em>."</p>
<p>Monster Hunter Wilds is the best-selling game of 2025 so far, and after 2023's excellent remake of Resident Evil 4, fans of the long-running horror series are on the edge of their seats waiting to see what the studio has in store for<a href="https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-9-open-world-multiplayer-game/"> Resident Evil 9</a>.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals Debuts Ultron Gameplay Ahead Of Season 2.5 Launch Next Week]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/marvel-rivals-debuts-ultron-gameplay-ahead-of-season-2-5-launch-next-week/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-debuts-ultron-gameplay-ahead-of-season-2-5-launch-next-week.1197603/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/marvel-rivals-debuts-ultron-gameplay-ahead-of-season-2-5-launch-next-week/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/marvel-rivals-surpassed-40-million-players-tomorrows-patch-adds-nvidia-dlss-4-and-amd-anti-lag-2/">Marvel Rivals</a> developer NetEase has revealed gameplay for the next character joining the roster, Ultron, and showcased more of what's to come in Season 2.5 ahead of its launch next week on&nbsp;<strong>May 30, 2025.&nbsp;</strong>The studio also released the latest <a href="https://www.marvelrivals.com/gameupdate/20250520/41548_1235575.html">patch notes</a> for the game's most recent update, which includes all the balance changes and fixes made.</p>
<p>The Hellfire Gala Moments event has been extended for another week in the back-half of this season, and on top of adding Ultron to the game, NetEase is also adding a new map and making some significant changes to Team-Up abilities, like the addition of the Jeff-Nado ability.</p>
<p><iframe title="Marvel Rivals: Season 2.5 Kick Off! | Dev Vision Vol. 06" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kXtEMrHcLDA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Season 2.5 will also include a new limited-time mode to be added on June 6 called Ultron's Battle Matrix Protocol. The mode lets six players choose their own hero lineups and upgrade their abilities before going head-to-head against other players. According to a press release for the new update, the mode is "<em>an experiment for how the development team can attempt to fulfill players' fantasies of Marvel Super Heroes and Super Villains</em>."</p>
<p><iframe title="Ultron: A New Age Begins | Character Reveal | Marvel Rivals" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YUSbKQO674w?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Season 2 is the last season that'll have the three-month-long structure, NetEase revealed<a href="https://wccftech.com/marvel-rivals-reveals-new-details-for-season-2-hellfire-gala-introduces-emma-frost/"> last month</a> ahead of the launch for Season 2. Beginning with Season 3, a full season in Marvel Rivals will last for only two months, with a new character and features added each month. Season 2 also introduced weekly missions to give players even more to do on top of the preexisting daily challenges.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Wars Battlefront II Developers Would Like To “Get The Gang Back Together” For Battlefront III]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/star-wars-battlefront-ii-developers-would-like-to-get-the-gang-back-together-for-battlefront-iii/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/star-wars-battlefront-ii-developers-would-like-to-%E2%80%9Cget-the-gang-back-together%E2%80%9D-for-battlefront-iii.1197534/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/star-wars-battlefront-ii-developers-would-like-to-get-the-gang-back-together-for-battlefront-iii/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>EA's reboot of the Star Wars Battlefront series was a roller coaster of a journey, to say the least. The 2015 game was liked but blasted for a lack of content, an offline mode, and no campaign.</p>
<p>Then the 2017 sequel was, by all accounts, a noted improvement gameplay-wise, but the microtransactions that EA stuffed into it practically killed the game, driving players away at launch. EA supported the game for another three years and was able to turn the ship around with the removal of its awful microtransactions, and <a href="https://wccftech.com/star-wars-battlefront-2-visuals-improvements/">consistent updates</a> to improve the game, culminating in a <a href="https://wccftech.com/star-wars-battlefront-2-celebration-edition-leaks/">Celebration Edition</a> of the game that gave players access to every piece of content that was previously paywalled.</p>
<p>But neither the reboot nor the original series ever made it to a third entry. Star Wars Battlefront III has been <a href="https://wccftech.com/star-wars-battlefront-iii-pitched/">pitched</a> and even worked on, in the case of the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/former-star-wars-battlefront-3-free-radical">original PS2-era series,</a> but never made it to fruition.</p>
<p>Hope rises for Battlefront III once again after a recent surge in popularity in Battlefront II, and (spotted by <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/star-wars-battlefront-2-devs-want-to-get-the-band-back-together-to-make-battlefront-3/">VGC</a>), developers who worked on Battlefront II want to "<em>get the gang back together</em>" to make Battlefront III.</p>
<p>Responding to a comment on<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/StarWarsBattlefront/comments/1ksngo8/comment/mtsa5xq/?context=3"> Reddit</a> about a previous comment he had made that Battelfront II developers want to see the series get a third entry, Mats Helge Holm, who worked as a producer on Battelfront II, said, "<em>Me,</em> <em>having heard around my group of ex-colleagues, we want to get the gang back together.</em>"</p>
<p>Holm isn't the only one who has worked on Star Wars making the call for Battlefront III. Andor actor Muhannad Ben Amor also called for Battlefront III on<a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-andor-actor-joins-calls-for-battlefront-3-as-battlefront-2-popularity-spikes"> Instagram</a>, admitting he's a massive Battlefront fan, having logged 469 hours in Battlefront II.</p>
<p>Even with this new surge in popularity, players shouldn't be expecting EA to green-light a new Battlefront game anytime soon. In the thread where Holm comments that he and other former members of the Battlefront II team would like to work together again on Battlefront III, he says, "<em>I don't expect Battlefront 3 to be announced at the end of this rally. But overall, yeah, I think there are people who are talking about it</em>."</p>
<p>If you enjoyed Battlefront II, it's worth hopping back in to enjoy the rush of players filling up matches. But keep your expectations in check regarding the chances of a third game ever happening.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gears of War: Reloaded Beta Could Be Announced Soon, Judging From Some Recent Findings]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/gears-of-war-reloaded-beta/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gears-of-war-reloaded-beta-could-be-announced-soon-judging-from-some-recent-findings.1197489/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/gears-of-war-reloaded-beta/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A Gears of War: Reloaded beta could be announced soon, judging from what has been recently discovered.</p>
<p>As reported on the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1ktfpwe/gears_of_war_reloaded_beta_to_be_announced/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gaming Leaks and Rumors subreddit</a>, the unannounced beta was added to the Steam backend yesterday, as seen on <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/3749450/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SteamDB</a>, so it's likely that it will be officially confirmed soon. Unfortunately, there is no information on when the beta could take place or what it will offer.</p>
<p>Gears of War: Reloaded will mark the PlayStation debut of one of the series that has long been synonymous with the Xbox brand. Announced<a href="https://wccftech.com/gears-of-war-reloaded-launches-on-pc-playstation-5-xbox-series-xs-this-summer-with-full-cross-progression-and-cross-platform-multiplayer/"> earlier this month</a>, the game is a remaster of the first entry in the series developed by The Coalition in partnership with Sumo Interactive and Disbelief, featuring all the content released for the original, as well as that included in the Ultimate Edition, such as the single-player campaign, all post-launch DLC, and every multiplayer map and play mode. The remaster will also enhance the experience with 4K resolution support on all platforms, 60 FPS gameplay in the campaign and 120 FPS in multiplayer, HDR and VRR support, visual improvements, and cross-platform progression and multiplayer.</p>
<p>Gears of War: Reloaded launches on August 25th on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X, and Xbox Series S. Those who purchased the Ultimate Edition before the remaster's announcement on May 5th will get the remaster via a free upgrade.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>