<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 16:56:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grand Theft Auto 4 With RTX Remix Path Tracing Is The Remaster That Will Never Get Released]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-4-path-tracing-remaster/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grand-theft-auto-4-with-rtx-remix-path-tracing-is-the-remaster-that-will-never-get-released.1340503/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Grand Theft Auto 4 with RTX Remix Path Tracing looks like the remaster we'll likely never get, introducing significant visual improvements that enhance the game's visuals considerably.</p>



<p>How much <a href="https://wccftech.com/take-look-path-traced-gta-4-rtx-remix-test-build/">the mod developed by Xoxor4D</a> enhances the visuals of the fourth entry in the series by Rockstar Games is shown in a new comparison video put together by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@MxBenchmarkPC">MxBenchmarkPC.</a> The video showcases the vanilla version of the game running side by side with the path-traced version at 4K and 1440p resolutions, utilizing NVIDIA DLSS and Frame Generation.</p>



<p>As expected, the mod is highly demanding, and even high-end modern hardware has trouble running it at 60 FPS without Frame Generation, but the results seem well worth the performance hit,  although some of the visual elements of the game, besides lighting and shadows, need an evident update, such as character models and low-quality textures.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="GTA 4 Path Tracing with RTX Remix On vs Off - Graphics/Performance Comparison | RTX 5080" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/snAUbjVE2wI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>The Grand Theft Auto 4 RTX Remix mod is not yet available publicly. However, those interested in trying it out before its launch can do so by <a href="https://www.patreon.com/xoxor4d">supporting Xoxor4D on Patreon.</a></p>



<p>Replaying through Grand Theft Auto 4 with RTX Remix path tracing and other mods is definitely a good way to make the wait for Grand Theft Auto 6 more bearable. The sixth entry in the series was initially scheduled to launch on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S this year, but <a data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(16, 80, 126, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(16, 80, 126, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-launches-may-26/">Rockstar Games ultimately delayed the game to May 2026. </a></p>



<p>While no precise reason was provided for the game's delay, Rockstar Games stated in the message shared to announce the delay that the additional development time was required to meet and exceed players' expectations for a game whose launch is predicted to be <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-is-expected-to-be-the-biggest-entertainment-launch-of-all-time-but-a-performance-below-expectations-could-impact-the-entire-industry/">the biggest entertainment launch to date.</a></p>

			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-4-path-tracing-remaster/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former Fall Guys Developers Form Panic Stations, Will Focus On Co-Op Multiplayer Games]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/former-fall-guys-developers-form-panic-stations-focus-on-co-op-multiplayer-games/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/former-fall-guys-developers-form-panic-stations-will-focus-on-co-op-multiplayer-games.1340452/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Panic Stations is a new game developer formed by former Mediatonic developers who worked on the popular competitive multiplayer title, Fall Guys. The studio announced itself with a <a href="https://x.com/PanicStationsHQ/status/1983881949266530781">post on its official X (formerly Twitter) account</a> in a video filled with cartoon pigeons. Joe Walsh, a game designer at Panic Stations, provides the voice over for the first pigeon you see, beginning the video by saying, "<em>Games should be funnier and they should be stupider. Here at Panic Stations, we're going to fix that</em>."</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>The team is currently working on its debut game, which it says is "<em>not about pigeons</em>" <a href="https://www.panicstations.com/">according to its website</a>. In an interview with GamesIndustry.Biz, co-founder Paul Croft said, "<em>I'm a huge fan of the online co-op space and it's been amazing to see it evolve over the last few years. It is really exciting to team-up with some old friends - we're aiming to build games that bring immediate joy to players and bring people closer together</em>."</p>



<p>Croft is not wrong to point out that cooperative games are having a bit of a moment, especially when you consider how successful games like Peak, R.E.P.O., and Lethal Company have been recently. A cooperative game with a solid gameplay loop that also encourages comedic gameplay scenarios is a real recipe for success.</p>



<p>Whatever Panic Stations makes for their debut game, it'll certainly be interesting to see, especially when considering the pedigree they have coming from Fall Guys, a game that absolutely no one saw coming <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/fall-guys-falling-in-and-out-of-love/">when it first arrived in 2020</a>.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/former-fall-guys-developers-form-panic-stations-focus-on-co-op-multiplayer-games/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Back in the Top Spot in EU Sales Charts While Pokémon Legends Z-A Drops to Third]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-back-in-top-spot-eu-sales-charts-pokemon-legends-z-a-drops-to-third/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-back-in-the-top-spot-in-eu-sales-charts-while-pok%C3%A9mon-legends-z-a-drops-to-third.1340416/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>A new report from <a href="https://www.thegamebusiness.com/p/battlefield-6-reclaims-no1-as-ea">The Game Business</a>, backed by <a href="https://www.gamesalesdata.com/login">GSD data</a> shows that for last week's EU video game sales (October 19-26), Battlefield 6 has taken back the top spot after Pokémon Legends Z-A <a href="https://wccftech.com/pokemon-legends-za-sells-5-8-million-units-debut-week/">had it for its launch week.</a> Legends Z-A drops to third, with EA Sports FC 26 keeping its top-three spot on both the units sold and revenue earned sales charts.</p>



<p>After Pokémon Legends Z-A took the top spot for its launch week, with Battlefield 6 in second and EA Sports FC 26 in third, <a href="https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-eu-launch-sales-beat-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-eu-launch-sales/">Battlefield 6 is back on top</a> with EA Sports FC 26 in second, and Pokémon in third, with regard to units sold. However, this is the point where it should be noted that Nintendo does not share digital sales data, and that the numbers GSD uses are only based on physical sales.</p>



<p>Every other entry on the top ten list for revenue and units sold that's not a Nintendo game is based on both digital and physical sales, so while it's possible that Pokémon Legends Z-A could remain in third place if we had a complete picture, it's also a safe bet that Legends Z-A has in fact remained at the top spot in the charts when including digital sales.</p>



<p>But we don't have the digital sales data, so as it stands, the top three are the same for the revenue earned charts. Beyond the top three, both charts start to show discrepancies, some more significant than others.</p>



<p>Like how on the units sold charts, Ninja Gaiden 4, one of the many major releases in October, is nowhere to be found. The same goes for The Outer Worlds 2; however, both games earned a spot in the top ten for revenue earned, with Ninja Gaiden 4 making the list in the number six spot and The Outer Worlds 2 squeezing in at the number nine spot.</p>



<p>There are also three games on the units sold charts that don't make the revenue charts, and only one of them is a new release. That marker goes to Plants vs. Zombies: Replanted, which makes the units sold top-ten at number six and then just below Grand Theft Auto V, in the number eight spot is Titanfall 2, which jumps up 3,688% compared to where it was on the charts a week prior.</p>



<p>Mass Effect: Legendary Edition is another that made huge leaps to make it into the top ten at the number ten spot on the units sold charts. Both leaps are impressive on the face of it, though slightly less impressive when checking their price history via SteamDB, which shows that both <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1237970/">Titanfall 2</a> and <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1328670/">Mass Effect: Legendary Edition</a> are coming off a major sale where they were both 90% off, making the cost for one of the best shooters of all time and one of the best RPG trilogies of all time the price of a coffee to pick up, if you didn't already own them.</p>





			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-back-in-top-spot-eu-sales-charts-pokemon-legends-z-a-drops-to-third/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>