<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 16:39:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oblivion Remastered Registered Over 9 Million Players, Says Bethesda]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/oblivion-remastered-registered-9-million-players/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/oblivion-remastered-registered-over-9-million-players-says-bethesda.1253487/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Bethesda Game Studios has <a href="https://x.com/BethesdaStudios/status/1948756850171662413" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced</a> that The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered has registered over 9 million players since its launch on April 22. The developer shared the news with a brief message and a picture of the iconic 'adoring fan', a Wood Elf commoner who becomes the player character's "groupie" once they have become the new Grand Champion in the Arena. The adoring fan's hair has been styled into a nine for the occasion.</p>



<p><em>To everyone who emerged as a hero of Kvatch, mastered Arch-Mage, rose to Grand Champion, banished the Blackwood Company, gallivanted as the Gray Fox, and listened to the Night.</em></p>



<p><em>Thank you for sharing in our worlds. ❤️</em></p>



<p>Oblivion Remastered immediately garnered the attention of Elder Scrolls fans, <a href="https://wccftech.com/oblivion-remastered-breaks-4-million-players-in-4-days/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">breaking the four million player milestone in just two days of its release</a>. Of course, the fact that it is available on Game Pass across Xbox Series S|X and PC undoubtedly helped a great deal.</p>



<p>Even so, game industry analytics firm Newzoo <a href="https://wccftech.com/oblivion-remastered-delivered-outstanding-revenue-performance-is-a-benchmark-for-successful-remasters-says-newzoo/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a> the game delivered 'outstanding revenue performance' and became a benchmark for future remasters. Circana had previously <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-dominates-us-game-sales-in-april-2025-with-oblivion-remastered-and-active-player-numbers-with-call-of-duty/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">certified</a> that Oblivion Remastered was the best-selling game of April 2025 in the United States across Xbox, PlayStation, and PC.</p>



<p>Unfortunately, all this success was not enough to prevent Virtuos, the developer behind the remaster, from <a href="https://wccftech.com/oblivion-remastered-developer-virtuos-confirms-mass-layoffs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">cutting nearly 280 employees</a> across its European and Asian offices. It is unclear how these layoffs will impact the game's future support. The game has notoriously inherited the original title's performance issues while roaming the open world, specifically the near-constant hitching. While Update 1.2 <a href="https://wccftech.com/oblivion-remastered-patch-1-2-30-fps-rtx-5080-native-4k/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">brought some improvements</a>, there's still a lot of room for further fixes in this regard. A much improved performance would certainly make exploration even better in a game that is all about that type of gameplay experience, like most titles in the Elder Scrolls franchise. </p>





			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/oblivion-remastered-registered-9-million-players/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[KRAFTON Acquires Last Epoch Makers Eleventh Hour Games]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/krafton-acquires-last-epoch-eleventh-hour-games/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/krafton-acquires-last-epoch-makers-eleventh-hour-games.1253445/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>KRAFTON, the publisher that has more recently been in the news due to a <a href="https://wccftech.com/krafton-confirms-subnautica-2-leaked-documents-are-real/">messy back-and-forth</a> with the co-founders of Unknown Worlds, who allege that <a href="https://wccftech.com/krafton-allegedly-sabotaged-subnautica-2-to-delay-avoid-paying-250-million-bonus/">KRAFTON delayed Subnautica 2 to avoid paying a $250 million bonus</a> to the Unknown Worlds team, is back in the news for a different reason today, a studio acquisition. Eleventh Hour Games, the team behind Last Epoch, has just been acquired by KRAFTON.</p>



<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/last-epoch-qa-on-runemaster-class-1-0-launch-and-advantages-over-diablo-iv/">Eleventh Hour Games</a> (EHG) was founded back in 2017, with chief executive officer Judd Cobler going to Reddit to find people with game development experience to make what would become Last Epoch. A 2018 Kickstarter raised enough funds to get the studio going, and on April 30, 2019, it launched into Early Access on Steam. It didn't hit its <a href="https://wccftech.com/last-epoch-shows-off-unique-trade-system-ahead-of-1-0-launch/">1.0 launch</a> until just last year, February 21, 2024, and according to a <a href="https://press.krafton.com/KRAFTON-Acquires-Eleventh-Hour-Games-Creators-of-Last-Epoch">press release</a> for its acquisition by KRAFTON, Last Epoch has sold 3 million copies since last February.</p>



<p>"<em>Through this acquisition, KRAFTON aims to secure a competitive franchise IP in the Action RPG genre and further strengthen its position in the global market," </em>writes KRAFTON. "<em>The deal provides EHG with the resources and infrastructure to better serve its community, ensuring that Last Epoch</em> <em>continues to evolve and meet the expectations of its growing player base. The acquisition will also enable EHG to scale development across console platforms and expand seasonal content pipelines, setting the stage for long-term franchise development. KRAFTON will support EHG’s live service roadmap, team expansion, and international publishing, while allowing the studio to retain full leadership and creative autonomy</em>."</p>



<p>KRAFTON's head of corporate development, Maria Park, added that the publisher is "<em>thrilled to welcome Eleventh Hour Games into the KRAFTON family,"</em> and that EHG's "<em>rise from a grassroots studio to a globally renowned ARPG developer is nothing short of remarkable."</em> Park also claims that this acquisition "<em>reaffirms our unwavering passion for great games and the teams that build them. We will always stand behind developers who put players first,"</em> which is difficult to see as anything but a snide shot towards the Subnautica 2 co-founders. </p>



<p>On the other side of the aisle, for Eleventh Hour Games, Cobler adds that this acquisition is "<em>a dream come true</em>" for the studio, and that KRAFTON's "<em>deep-rooted passion for ARPGs aligns perfectly with our mission."</em> </p>



<p>"<em>With KRAFTON's support, EHG is poised to elevate the </em><em>Last Epoch</em> franchise to even greater heights. As a studio built from players of the genre, we couldn’t be more excited for its future."</p>



<p>Due to the ongoing legal battle between KRAFTON and Unknown Worlds, it's difficult to take any of these statements at face value when we see how that relationship has eroded in the last four years. Unknown Worlds co-founder Charlie Cleveland also said that Unknown Worlds and KRAFTON were "<em>aligned</em>" in their goals when <a href="https://wccftech.com/subnautica-studio-unknown-worlds-entertainment-acquired-by-krafton-inc/">KRAFTON's acquisition of Unknown Worlds was announced</a>. But, according to Cleveland and the rest of the co-founders, KRAFTON's attitude towards the studio turned on a dime within the last year. </p>



<p>Hopefully, today's statements remain true for Eleventh Hour Games and KRAFTON in the future.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/krafton-acquires-last-epoch-eleventh-hour-games/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Nightreign Duos Update Coming Next Week]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-nightreign-duos-mode-coming-next-week/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-nightreign-duos-update-coming-next-week.1253385/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/elden-ring-nightreign-conquering-the-night/">Elden Ring Nightreign</a> will add its highly-requested two-player mode next week on July 30, 2025, with Patch 1.02, and while the introduction of duo expeditions remains the highlight for the update, FromSoftware is also adding a few key quality-of-life and UI improvements in the patch, like better filtering options for relics.</p>



<p>FromSoftware's co-operative multiplayer roguelike action game has gone better than anyone might've expected when the game was first announced at <a href="https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-nightreign-announced-by-fromsoftware-for-pc-and-consoles/">The Game Awards 2024</a>. In its launch month, it was <a href="https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-nightreign-topped-us-sales-charts-may-2025/">topping sales charts in the US</a> and breaking into the <a href="https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-nightreign-was-one-of-may-2025s-top-5-games-by-revenue-according-to-newzoo-while-oblivion-remastered-remains-firm-in-the-top-20-for-revenue-and-mau/">top five on more global charts</a>.  It stayed in the <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-fastest-selling-gaming-hardware-us-history/">top-10 for US game sales for June</a>, and remained <a href="https://wccftech.com/dune-awakening-rematch-newzoo-june-2025/">one of the top-15 best-selling games globally</a>. </p>



<p>The introduction of a duos mode, which is <a href="https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-nightreign-may-get-proper-duo-support-post-launch/">something players have requested</a> since FromSoftware tested the game's servers in an open beta (and <a href="https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-nightreign-mods-framerate-two-player-mode-easier-solo/">already implemented themselves through mods</a>) is sure to give the community a boost, and might even convince some players who have been on the fence to finally pick it up, knowing that they can hop in with the one other friend they have, and no longer be handicapped by being unable to find a third friend to play with. </p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="ELDEN RING NIGHTREIGN | Two Player Mode Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eWqBTAYa8h4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>It'll be interesting to see where Nightreign stands when we get a look at sales and engagement charts for July halfway through next month. Even though this update is coming right at the end of the month, it has approximately two days to make a significant impact.</p>



<p>FromSoftware also recently celebrated Elden Ring Nightreign <a href="https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-celebrates-10-million-shadow-of-the-erdtree-5-million-nightreign/">surpassing 5 million units sold since it launched in May</a>, a huge milestone for the company's first major foray into multiplayer and the first time it has adapted one of its major narrative and action-driven Souls games into an online multiplayer experience. </p>



<p>It'll be interesting to see how FromSoftware's second foray into turning elements players recognize from its single-player games into a multiplayer experience goes when <a href="https://wccftech.com/fromsoftwares-the-duskbloods-announced-exclusively-for-nintendo-switch-2/">The Duskbloods</a> arrives as a Nintendo Switch 2 exclusive. </p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-nightreign-duos-mode-coming-next-week/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CD Projekt Red’s Project Hadar Will Be An Action RPG With Melee Combat, According to New Job Ad]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/cd-projekt-reds-project-hadar-will-be-an-action-rpg-with-melee-combat-according-to-new-job-ad/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cd-projekt-red%E2%80%99s-project-hadar-will-be-an-action-rpg-with-melee-combat-according-to-new-job-ad.1253340/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>New details on CD Projekt Red's mysterious Project Hadar emerged online today thanks to a new job ad discovered online.</p>



<p>As spotted by<a href="https://tech4gamers.com/cdpr-project-hadar-action-rpg-melee-combat/"> Tech4Gamers</a>, CD Projekt Red is looking to hire a Senior Gameplay Designer specifically for the development of Project Hadar, a new IP from the studio, with at least 5 years of experience in the RPG/action titles with melee-oriented combat, suggesting the game will have a major focus on close range combat. The rest of the required qualifications don't reveal anything new about this game, such as experience in working with Unreal Engine 4 and Unreal Engine 5, as the studio announced a while back that Epic's engine would power its future projects.</p>



<p>Project Hadar is only one of the <a href="https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-sequel-3-witcher-projects-new-ip-in-development-cd-projekt-red/">many projects</a> in development at CD Projekt Red, which include a sequel to Cyberpunk 2077, currently known as Project Orion, and the next entry in The Witcher series, The Witcher 4. Revealed last year during The Game Awards show, the next entry in the series, which will star Ciri in place of Geralt of Rivia, is being made with a console-first approach and will take<a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-4-dev-wants-to-take-full-advantage-of-the-generational-shift-since-the-witcher-3-tech-demos-village-npc-density-was-based-on-novigrad/"> full advantage of the generational shift </a>since The Witcher 3. How this will be achieved remains to be seen, but if the tech demo shown <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-iv-new-trailer-ps5-60-fps-ray-tracing/">last month</a> is of any indication, it definitely looks like CD Projekt Red will have no trouble surpassing anything it has released so far.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/cd-projekt-reds-project-hadar-will-be-an-action-rpg-with-melee-combat-according-to-new-job-ad/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>