<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 20:40:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft And Xbox Invites Developers To Roundtable On AI Tools For Game Development While Laying Off Thousands]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/microsoft-xbox-ai-tools-game-development-laying-off-thousands/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-and-xbox-invites-developers-to-roundtable-on-ai-tools-for-game-development-while-laying-off-thousands.1235505/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/microsoft-mass-gaming-layoffs-have-begun/">Microsoft laid off 9,000 employees</a> across the entire company yesterday, with an unknown number of those cuts impacting the Xbox and gaming division. Part of these cuts are<a href="https://www.seattletimes.com/business/microsoft/microsoft-to-lay-off-as-many-as-9000-employees-in-latest-round/"> reportedly directly related to Microsoft's push into AI</a>, and some of those impacted by the cuts are speaking out about how <a href="https://wccftech.com/microsoft-trying-replace-jobs-ai-agents/">Microsoft is doing its "<em>damndest</em>"</a> to replace people with AI as fast as it can. </p>



<p>You might think, then, that at least for a day, possibly even a few days, Microsoft would post-pone any more pushing of its AI technology into the faces of developers, publicly or privately. Not the case, it would seem, as <a href="https://kotaku.com/microsoft-gen-ai-idxbox-layoffs-npc-chatgpt-1851785609">Kotaku</a> spotted that Necrosoft Games director, Brandon Sheffield, shared the beginnings of an email he received from Microsoft and ID@Xbox, inviting him to a roundtable at Gamescom 2025 where Microsoft will be talking up using "<em>AI in our tools and processes to make the game development and publishing experience more efficient</em>."</p>







<p>Below Sheffield's post, other developers shared their response to getting the same invitation, with Toronto-based developer <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/benjaminrivers.bsky.social/post/3lt36vjygks2t">Benjamin Rivers saying</a> "<em>just get wrecked, mates</em>." Sheffield agreed, "<em>they really should</em>."</p>



<p>While reports of the total layoffs at Microsoft have the number at 9,000, the exact amount of people impacted in the gaming division remains unclear at this time of writing. Meanwhile, these layoffs have left the talented workers and developers out of a job due to poor decisions made by a c-suite of executives who, for some reason still have their jobs, despite the fact that thousands of layoffs is a clear sign they messed up along the way, and <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/sources-banjo-kazooie-sea-of-thieves-director-leaves-rare-after-35-years-following-everwild-cancellation/">pushed out veteran developers</a> who contain a wealth of knowledge that the AI tools Microsoft is pushing cannot hope to replace.</p>



<p>This is just a shot in the dark, but it seems like decisions that don't lead to wasting and mismanaging talent that has been in this industry for years would be the more efficient route towards successful game development, instead of AI tools that have, so far, proven capable costing a lot of money.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/microsoft-xbox-ai-tools-game-development-laying-off-thousands/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anthem Is Going Offline In 2026, EA Finally Sunsetting The Failed Live Service Shooter]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/anthem-going-offline-2026-ea/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/anthem-is-going-offline-in-2026-ea-finally-sunsetting-the-failed-live-service-shooter.1235454/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Anthem is going offline forever next year, EA and BioWare have announced, as the failed third-person shooter will have its servers shut down on <strong>January 12, 2026</strong>, nearly seven years since it launched in 2019.</p>



<p>You'd be forgiven if you thought Anthem's servers had already been shut down. The response online shows several people expressing surprise that the game is still playable. Even Wccftech's Alessio Palumbo thought the game was six-feet-under by now. </p>



<p>That's not the case though, and in fact, we now know that the chances to play Anthem, should you wish to revisit <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-report-details-dragon-age-the-veilguards-troubled-development-and-how-eas-attempt-to-turn-bioware-into-a-live-service-studio-plagued-the-game-all-the-way-to-launch/">EA's failed attempt at forcing BioWare</a> to make a game that <a href="https://wccftech.com/anthem-was-a-key-lesson-for-dragon-age-the-veilguard-says-bioware/">the studio even admitted was not its forte</a>, are numbered. </p>



<p>At one point, it looked like Anthem's failure to launch could be salvaged. Its<a href="https://wccftech.com/review/anthem-flying-high-it-doesnt-last/"> release was a mixed bag</a>, to say the least, with some aspects of the game being truly memorable, with most who were around to try it remembering how good the flying mechanics felt. The rest of the game, however, <a href="https://wccftech.com/ea-anthem-below-expectations-will-support/">did not reach those same heights</a>, and the extent to which BioWare was out of its element was almost palpable. Still, work was put in to try and <a href="https://wccftech.com/anthem-2-0-shooting-looting-redesign-more-satisfying/">find a path forward for Anthem</a>, as EA couldn't seem to let it go as easily as it did <a href="https://wccftech.com/dragon-age-the-veilguard-isnt-getting-any-dlcs-as-bioware-is-wholly-focused-on-mass-effect-next/">Dragon Age: The Veilguard,</a> for example.</p>



<p>Development on Anthem 2.0 <a href="https://wccftech.com/anthem-next-cancelled/">officially stopped in 2021</a>, and since then, the game has sat on EA's servers, collecting dust, it would seem, until someone found it and was no doubt surprised to find it was still active. </p>



<p>"<em>We have an important update to share regarding Anthem</em>," EA began in a <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/anthem/news/anthem-game-update">blog post on the game's official website</a>. "<em>After careful consideration, we will be sunsetting Anthem on January 12, 2026. This means that the game will still be playable online for the next 180+ days. As of today, you can no longer purchase in-game premium currency, but you can still use your remaining balance until the servers go offline. We deeply appreciate your dedication, passion and support over the years and we'd like to thank you for that.</em>"</p>



<p>At the time of this writing, Anthem is playable for another 193 days, to be exact. </p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/anthem-going-offline-2026-ea/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Techland Cancels Two Games, Including Their New Fantasy Action RPG, But Is Rumored to Be Working on a New Call of Juarez]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/techland-cancels-two-games-fantasy-action-rpg/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/techland-cancels-two-games-including-their-new-fantasy-action-rpg-but-is-rumored-to-be-working-on-a-new-call-of-juarez.1235421/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>It isn't just Microsoft that is <a href="https://wccftech.com/microsoft-mass-gaming-layoffs-have-begun/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">canceling games left and right</a>—according to a <a href="https://www.pb.pl/techland-z-potezna-strata-za-2024-r-1244492">report</a> originating from Polish website Pulz Binesu and later <a href="https://www.gamekult.com/actualite/en-souffrance-techland-annule-deux-jeux-dont-son-action-rpg-de-fantasy-en-monde-ouvert-3050864575.html">reported</a> by Game Kult, Dying Light developer Techland has also recently canceled two of its projects.</p>



<p>Here's what they said in a statement provided to Wccftech:</p>



<p><em>Game development is never a straight line, and sometimes fresh approaches are necessary to make great games. What's important here is that none of the reported changes have resulted in staff reductions. Developers were moved to other projects and are working on a number of games in our pipeline. Our primary focus right now is to release Dying Light: The Beast for PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X|S. After the launch of Dying Light: The Beast, we will share more about future titles in due time.</em></p>



<p>Supposedly, one of the canceled games is their upcoming fantasy action RPG based on a new intellectual property. This project has been in the works for at least nine years, as <a href="https://wccftech.com/dying-light-dev-working-fantasy-title-openworld-rpg-elements-huge-aaa-game/">certified</a> by our coverage from May 2016. The game evidently was put to the back burner as Techland focused on Dying Light 2: Stay Human, but the Polish studio quickly started discussing it after that game launched. We <a href="https://wccftech.com/dying-light-techland-fantasy-rpg-first-image-cdpr-veterans/">got</a> the first look at an artwork in May 2022; this title was in development at the Warsaw office, which had been bolstered by former CD Projekt RED developers, and was highly ambitious, according to Techland:</p>



<blockquote>
<p><em>Our ambition is to introduce a brand new IP that is vastly different from what we have been doing for the past several years. We want to create a fully next-gen experience. A new fantasy epic set in a sprawling open world, fueled by the skills and experience we have gained as a team over the years, infused with new ideas, passion, and creativity. </em></p>



<p>Another artwork was <a href="https://wccftech.com/dying-light-techland-fantasy-game-new-concept-art-climbing-huge-world/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">shared</a> in May 2023. That was the last we heard about the project. Nothing much is known about the other game. However, the report says that another project has taken their place. </p>



<p>According to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dying-light-developer-techland-has-canceled-2-upcoming-games/">Insider </a><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dying-light-developer-techland-has-canceled-2-upcoming-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gaming</a>, it should be a new Call of Juarez title. As a reminder, the studio regained the rights to the IP from Ubisoft in 2018.</p>



<p>Techland is, of course, also polishing up Dying Light: The Beast, which will be released on August 22 for PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series S|X, while PlayStation 4 and Xbox One will get it later in 2025. Check out our hands-on preview and developer Q&amp;A <a href="https://wccftech.com/dying-light-the-beast-impressions-and-qa-from-sgf-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">at this URL</a>.</p>
</blockquote>





			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/techland-cancels-two-games-fantasy-action-rpg/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Arc Line Update Smoke & Mirrors Adds Dwarves, New Playable Classes, Story Content And More On July 17]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/new-arc-line-smoke-and-mirrors-update-july-17/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-arc-line-update-smoke-mirrors-adds-dwarves-new-playable-classes-story-content-and-more-on-july-17.1235388/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/new-arc-line-hands-on-preview-a-crpg-full-of-potential/">New Arc Line</a>, a new cRPG from Fulqrum Publishing and developer Dreamate that launched in <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2458310/New_Arc_Line/">early access last November</a>, is getting its first major update later this month on July 17, 2025, with its Smoke &amp; Mirrors update. </p>



<p>Smoke &amp; Mirros will add a new playable race to the game as Dwarves get introduced, along with two new playable classes that'll be exclusively available to Dwarves before being made available to players playing as Humans or Elves. The update will also add a new questline for players to dig into called 'Step Behind the Curtain,' that'll also introduce a new location for players to explore called the Sacred Tree.</p>


<figure>
<div>

<figure>
<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>
</figure>
<div>
			    		
			    		
				    	<p><span>2 of 9</span>
			    	</p></div>
</div>
</figure>



<p>The two new classes being added are the Hellfire Mage and the Steam Mechanic. The Hellfire Mage is pretty self-explanatory. It's the class to play if you want to inflict immense amounts of damage with fire attacks that can really burn anyone who tries to get in your way.</p>



<p>The Steam Mechanic relies on their equipment and ability for invention with steam-powered exoskeletons that help them deal with their foes. As stated previously, both the Hellfire Mage and Steam Mechanic classes will be exclusive to Dwarves before they're available for Human and Elf players sometime in the future. According to a press release from Fulqrum and Dreamate, they'll be available for other races "<em>through subsequent updates</em>."</p>



<p>When New Arc Line launched in early access last year, <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-arc-line-hands-on-preview-a-crpg-full-of-potential/">Wccftech checked out the release</a>, which showed potential, but as is the case with any game in early access, New Arc Line had plenty of room to grow. "<em>You can see the amount of love and effort that has gone into the game's worldbuilding to provide the balance between dystopia and utopia. I'm eager to see how New Arc Line develops throughout its early access journey.</em>"</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/new-arc-line-smoke-and-mirrors-update-july-17/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>