<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 04:24:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NVIDIA Releases New Driver, Confirms DLSS 4 Multi Frame Generation for The Last of Us Part II and Darktide]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nvidia-releases-new-driver-confirms-dlss-4-multi-frame-generation-for-the-last-of-us-part-ii-and-darktide/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nvidia-releases-new-driver-confirms-dlss-4-multi-frame-generation-for-the-last-of-us-part-ii-and-darktide.1138356/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nvidia-releases-new-driver-confirms-dlss-4-multi-frame-generation-for-the-last-of-us-part-ii-and-darktide/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>NVIDIA has released a new GeForce Game Ready driver (version 572.83), which is optimized for a series of games that have just launched or are about to launch. The first is, of course, the Half-Life 2 RTX demo, which features the full extent of the NVIDIA RTX suite as analyzed <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-half-life-2-rtx-demo-is-an-excellent-showcase-of-rtx-remixs-possibilities/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>. But it's also optimized for the <a href="https://wccftech.com/control-arch-2025-update-ultra-ray-tracing-dlss-3-7/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">recent Control update</a> that enhanced Remedy's game with a new Ultra Ray Tracing preset featuring an increased number of rays per pixel, updated DLSS (to version 3.7, which can be overridden to DLSS 4's new transformer model through the NVIDIA app), texture quality improvements, faster texture streaming, support for a wider range of ultra-wide monitor aspect ratios up to 48:9, the addition of a Field of View slider, and High Dynamic Range (HDR) support.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, the new driver is optimized for Assassin's Creed Shadows (which, as <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-shadows-pc-report-a-ray-traced-leap-forward-for-ubisoft-anvil/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">mentioned in our article</a>, supports DLSS 4 Multi Frame Generation via NVIDIA app override) and Warhammer 40,000: Darktide. While not a new game, the cooperative first-person action title by Fatshark will be updated to natively support NVIDIA DLSS 4 Multi Frame Generation with an update scheduled to go live next week.</p>
<p>The driver should&nbsp;<span>also be installed for gamers looking to play inZOI. The life simulation title will debut in early access on Friday, March 28, featuring DLSS Super Resolution and NVIDIA ACE technology powering their '<a href="https://wccftech.com/nvidia-ace-to-power-dynamic-ai-characters-companions-and-bosses-in-pubg-naraka-bladepoint-inzoi-and-mir5/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Smart Zoi</a>' NPCs. The technology is based on a .5B billion parameter Mistral NeMo Minitron small language model, providing high-quality</span>&nbsp;outputs at low latency in a very compact footprint. The feature is only available on GeForce RTX GPUs.</p>
<p>Lastly, NVIDIA has also shared that The Last of Us Part II Remastered, <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-last-of-us-part-ii-remastered-pc-is-out-on-april-3-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">due to launch on PC on April 3</a>, will support NVIDIA DLSS 4 Multi Frame Generation within the game. Of course, DLSS Super Resolution, Frame Generation, and Reflex are also individually supported.</p>
<p>The Game Ready driver's release notes also reveal the following bug fixes:</p>
<ul>
<li>[GeForce RTX 5080/5090] Graphics cards may not run at full speeds on system reboot when overclocked [5088034]</li>
<li>[GeForce RTX 50 series] GeForce RTX 50 series GPUs crashes with black screen [5120886]</li>
<li>Some NVIDIA Control Panel / NVIDIA App settings changes immediately get reset or give error [5160516]</li>
<li>PC may bugcheck IRQL NOT LESS OR EQUAL 0xa during gameplay with HDR enabled [5091576]</li>
<li>[VRED 2026] Optix compile error with R570 branch drivers [5122360]</li>
<li>[Derivative TouchDesigner ] Application stability issues [4606316]</li>
</ul>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur’s Gate Fans Will Know More About the Franchise’s Future in ‘Short Order’, Says Hasbro]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/baldurs-gate-fans-will-know-more-about-the-franchises-future-in-short-order-says-hasbro/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldur%E2%80%99s-gate-fans-will-know-more-about-the-franchise%E2%80%99s-future-in-%E2%80%98short-order%E2%80%99-says-hasbro.1138305/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/baldurs-gate-fans-will-know-more-about-the-franchises-future-in-short-order-says-hasbro/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Following the <a href="https://wccftech.com/baldurs-gate-3-saw-more-players-this-year-than-its-release-in-2023/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">incredible (and continued) success of Baldur's Gate 3</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/baldurs-gate-4-playable-state/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Larian's surprising decision not to pursue a sequel</a>, fans have been left wondering what will happen to the franchise next. According to Hasbro Senior Vice President of Digital Games Dan Ayoub, though, it may not be long before some sort of news is shared. <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/well-hear-more-about-baldurs-gates-future-in-pretty-short-order-hasbro-svp-of-games-says" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Speaking to IGN</a> at GDC 2025, Ayoub said:</p>
<p><em>A lot of people are very interested in Baldur's Gate. We're kind of working out our plans for the future and what we're going to be doing with that. And actually, in pretty short order, we're going to have some stuff to talk about around that.</em></p>
<p><em>It's somewhat of an unenviable position. I mean, we're not in a hurry. Right? That's the thing, we're going to take a very measured approach... We've got a lot of plans, a lot of different ways to go about it. We're starting to think about, okay, yeah, we're ready to start dipping toes a little bit and talking about a few things. And I think, in really short order, like I said, again, not to over-tease that point, we're going to have some other things to talk about around that.</em></p>
<p>That doesn't necessarily mean this announcement would be related to a new mainline installment in the franchise. From Ayoub's statement, it sounds like that is further away from even being agreed upon. However, there could be other ways to keep the interest in Baldur's Gate high.</p>
<p>Eventually, though, what fans really want is a continuation of Baldur's Gate 3, especially with the incredibly interesting characters introduced in that game. In that regard, Hasbro's Dan Ayoub doesn't back down from the noticeable challenge of rising to that level of anticipation:</p>
<p><em>I'm never one to shy down from a challenge. I think anything that forces us to raise our creative bar - and developers love to have a high bar to go after, and I think we've actually seen the team push some really interesting ideas that they're like, 'Okay, we need to raise our bar. We need to go bigger on this.' And things like that. So, I think that's our hope, right? We would keep raising the bar and everyone just tries to go a little higher.</em></p>
<p>What would you like to see next in the revered fantasy RPG series?</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>