<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 15:44:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blizzard Will Detail Diablo IV’s Season 8: Belial’s Return On April 24]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/blizzard-will-detail-diablo-ivs-season-8-belials-return-on-april-24/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/blizzard-will-detail-diablo-iv%E2%80%99s-season-8-belial%E2%80%99s-return-on-april-24.1167975/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/blizzard-will-detail-diablo-ivs-season-8-belials-return-on-april-24/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Blizzard has <a href="https://x.com/Diablo/status/1912967763338891428">announced</a> that it will host a Diablo IV developer live stream on <strong>Thursday</strong>, <strong>April 24, 2025, at 11 a.m. PT / 2 p.m. ET / 7 p.m. BT,&nbsp;</strong>where it will announce details about the upcoming Season 8: Belial's Return, which is due to launch on <strong>April 29, 2025,&nbsp;</strong>five days after the livestream.</p>
<p>The live stream event will also be followed by a Q&amp;A period during which players can ask questions directly to the development team. Should you miss it in the moment and don't want to rewatch the entire stream, Blizzard will also publish an article recapping everything the live stream discusses.</p>
<p>"<em>Tune in to learn more about the new questline coming with the season, new seasonal powers, and more</em>," Blizzard wrote in a <a href="https://news.blizzard.com/en-gb/article/24195998/join-our-next-developer-update-livestream">blog post</a>. More in-depth details about everything coming in Season 8, like the patch notes, will likely come closer to its April 29 launch.</p>
<p>This live stream will instead be our first real look at the new season, and hopefully, some details on the quality of life changes, the new collaboration with an outside series, and Blizzard's plans for Diablo IV's second anniversary, all announced in the <a href="https://wccftech.com/diablo-ivs-2025-roadmap-unveiled-new-expansion-in-2026/">2025 roadmap</a>.</p>
<p>Also revealed in that roadmap was the news that Diablo IV will not have a full expansion in 2025 but instead will receive a series of seasonal updates throughout the year. A new expansion on the scale of <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/diablo-iv-vessel-of-hatred-systems-galore/">Vessel of Hatred</a> will be out sometime in 2026.</p>
<p>That's not to say the seasonal updates won't have anything exciting for players. Season 8 in particular will let players take advantage of boss powers for the first time, which players have <a href="https://wccftech.com/diablo-iv-lets-you-claim-boss-powers-for-yourself-next-season-ptr-opens-today/">already been testing</a> in the PTR for over a month now.</p>
<p>When the stream goes live next Thursday, you can tune into it on Blizzard's official Diablo <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/diablo">Twitch</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@Diablo/featured">YouTube</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/Diablo">X</a>, and <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@diablo">TikTok</a> social channels.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 Pre-Orders Will Begin In The US Next Week, Console Price Stays The Same While Accessories Get A Bump]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-pre-orders-us-hardware-pricing-stays-the-same-accessories-bump/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-pre-orders-will-begin-in-the-us-next-week-console-price-stays-the-same-while-accessories-get-a-bump.1167873/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-pre-orders-us-hardware-pricing-stays-the-same-accessories-bump/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Nintendo has announced that the <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-might-not-support-vrr-when-docked-after-all/">Nintendo Switch 2</a> will be available for pre-order in the United States on <strong>April 24, 2025</strong>. The console's price, including the bundle with Mario Kart World, Mario Kart World separately, and Donkey Kong Bananza, will stay the same.</p>
<p>Accessories for the Nintendo Switch 2, however, have increased in price. Nintendo announced the new pre-order date and the price adjustments in a <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/whatsnew/nintendo-maintains-nintendo-switch-2-pricing-retail-pre-orders-to-begin-april-24-in-u-s/?srsltid=AfmBOoqyV2Xd4TTCZZtccGTsaDJIsgDY1VOZA6jdYT32aCRnPLqexD_s">blog post</a> on its website, citing "<em>changes in market conditions</em>" as the reason for the pricing increase.</p>
<p>Nintendo continued, "<em>Other adjustments to the price of any Nintendo product are also possible in the future, depending on market conditions.</em>"</p>
<p>"<em>We apologize for the retail pre-order delay, and hope this reduces some of the uncertainty our customers may be experiencing. We thank our customers for their patience, and we share their excitement to experience Nintendo Switch 2 starting June 5, 2025.</em>"</p>
<p>While everything else has stayed the same, Nintendo-made accessories for the Switch 2 that were announced on April 2 with the Nintendo Switch 2 Direct have all gone up in price. These are all the accessories Nintendo confirmed are getting a price increase, with the new prices (in US dollars) in bold.</p>
<ul>
<li>Nintendo Switch 2 Pro Controller - was $79.99, <strong>now</strong> <strong>$84.99</strong></li>
<li>Nintendo Switch 2 Camera - was $49.99, <strong>now $54.99</strong></li>
<li>Joy-Con 2 Controller pair - was $89.99, <strong>now</strong> <strong>$94.99</strong></li>
<li>Joy-Con 2 Charging Grip - was $34.99,&nbsp;<strong>now</strong> <strong>$39.99</strong></li>
<li>Joy-Con 2 Strap - was $12.99, <strong>now $13.99</strong></li>
<li>Joy-Con 2 Wheel pair - was $19.99, <strong>now $24.99</strong></li>
<li>Nintendo Switch 2 Dock Set - was $109.99, <strong>now $119.99</strong></li>
<li>Nintendo Switch 2 Carrying Case and Screen Protector - was $34.99, <strong>now $39.99</strong></li>
<li>Nintendo Switch 2 All-In-One Carrying Case - was $79.99, <strong>now $84.99</strong></li>
<li>Nintendo Switch 2 AC Adapter - was $29.99, <strong>now $34.99</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>None of these price increases is a major jump, with the biggest being a $10 increase on the Nintendo Switch 2 Dock Set, but they still add a bit of sting to an already expensive console. Not to mention the fact that the threat of the console's price going up still looms with the tariffs not yet settled.</p>
<p>After pre-orders were <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-pre-order-not-april-9th-tariffs/">delayed in the US</a> just two days after the Nintendo Switch 2 Direct due to the tariffs announced the same day, there was a lot of confusion and concern that <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-price-increase-us/">the console's price would increase</a>. Many even wondered if the console would come to North America on its June 5 release date.</p>
<p>Pre-orders were also <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-pre-orders-have-been-delayed-in-canada-thanks-to-us-tariffs/">delayed in Canada</a> following the announcement that they would be delayed in the US. Pre-orders will also begin in Canada on April 24, 2025. Which is also just a day off from when reliable inside <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-pre-orders-canada-april-23/">billbil-kun predicted</a> they would return.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>