<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 15:23:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ZeniMax Workers Call Out Microsoft For Its “Inhumane” and “Disgusting” Mass Layoff Execution]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/zenimax-workers-call-out-microsoft-mass-layoffs-inhumane-disgusting/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zenimax-workers-call-out-microsoft-for-its-%E2%80%9Cinhumane%E2%80%9D-and-%E2%80%9Cdisgusting%E2%80%9D-mass-layoff-execution.1251144/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>If you follow the video game industry at all, then unless you've been living under a rock for the month of July, you've heard about <a href="https://wccftech.com/microsoft-mass-gaming-layoffs-have-begun/">Microsoft enacting its latest mass layoff</a>, which cut 9,000+ people across the company, a large chunk of those cuts hitting its Xbox and gaming division. It was an awful way to start the month, as we learned, and are still learning, how those cuts impacted studios like <a href="https://wccftech.com/perfect-dark-cancelled-the-initiative-shut-down-microsoft-layoffs/">The Initiative</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/zenimax-online-new-mmorpg-canceled/">ZeniMax Online</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/rare-everwild-cancelled-microsoft-gaming-layoffs/">Rare</a>, and <a href="https://wccftech.com/candy-crush-microsoft-laid-off-developers-being-replaced-by-ai-tools-they-built/">King</a>, to name a few.</p>



<p>In an interview with <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/zenimax-staff-lambast-inhumane-xbox-layoffs-it-s-difficult-to-work-when-you-re-looking-at-a-graveyard-">Game Developer</a>, several ZeniMax Media developers, some of whom are still with the studio and others who were impacted in the layoffs, called out Microsoft and Xbox executive leadership for how poorly the mass layoff was handled, the chaos it caused, and the execution of the whole situation, which some called "<em>inhumane</em>" and "<em>disgusting</em>."</p>



<p>One former employee described to Game Developer how they were booted out of their work email, Slack, everything, without any proper notice that they'd been laid off, and were left for hours without any communication from Microsoft. Member of the <a href="https://wccftech.com/zenimax-workers-united-qa-union-haved-reached-a-tentative-deal-with-microsoft-the-first-deal-reached/">ZWU-CWA</a> union, Page Branson, said the lack of any process to the layoffs left people "<em>distraught and confused and not knowing if they would have a job by the end of the day, or even if the layoffs were done by the end of the day</em>." </p>



<p>When Branson and others started to get a better picture of who was impacted and who wasn't, Branson said that some of those who were cut were "<em>absolutely crucial</em>" and "<em>integral</em>" members of staff, specifically for The Elder Scrolls Online. Autumn Mitchell, a senior QA developer and also a member of the ZWU-CWA union, added, "<em>It's not okay. It wasn't normal. I don't care how many times they do it to try and make it seem normal—it's not. The way they do it is inhumane. I don't care how much they say that it's dignified or they want to do it in a respectful way—it's not."</em></p>



<p>"<em>Some people were here for 15 years and cut out. Making it so that people have to rush to type a goodbye message into Slack to their colleagues that they've been working with on various projects, that have been making your corporation money for 15 years, is disgusting. It's disgusting. If I could get any message to any executive right now it would be review this process because it's not normal and it's not okay."</em></p>



<p>Branson also spoke about what is perhaps the most significant long-term impact of mass layoffs like this: the sudden disappearance of institutional knowledge that developers who had been working at the studio for years had. "<em>A lot of practical knowledge just disappeared overnight</em>. <em>Everyone left now has to pick up the pieces as best they can. The [dwindling] morale and general confusion of it all has extended into our general workflow. We used to have very, very reliable people working on things and they're no longer there. They were integral. I feel like they were numbers on a sheet that got cut, but the real application of what they were doing was integral to making everything run correctly.</em>"</p>



<p>Mitchell added that they estimated a third of ZeniMax Media's institutional knowledge is now gone thanks to the layoffs, and that they "<em>don't really know</em>" how those left standing are supposed to continue making games at the same quality they did before. They also added that they don't see how moving forward in some cases is even possible without critical members of the team who were impacted in the layoffs getting brought back.</p>



<p>Every story from the Microsoft layoffs is upsetting, and these details only compound the sadness for the developers and the frustration towards Microsoft and Xbox leadership for their carelessness in how things were handled. The short-term financial benefit that comes with having fewer people on the payroll only digs a deeper debt when it comes to the lack of experiential knowledge left behind, and the inability to properly train and mentor a new class of workers to take the place of the developers who players praise for creating the games we love in the first place. </p>



<p>These kinds of cuts, and the careless ways in which they're handled, are what make it difficult to see any real future for Xbox and Microsoft in the video game industry beyond that of a third-party publishing house. And even then, it's worth asking why anyone in the video game industry should place their trust in Microsoft, if the company is going to cut whatever it wants to cut, <a href="https://wccftech.com/microsoft-layoffs-funding-increased-spending-ai-infrastructure/">just to chase the latest trends in tech</a>.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/zenimax-workers-call-out-microsoft-mass-layoffs-inhumane-disgusting/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Outer Worlds 2 Price Has Been Reduced to $69.99]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-outer-worlds-2-price-has-been-reduced-to-69-99/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-outer-worlds-2-price-has-been-reduced-to-69-99.1251084/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Outer Worlds 2, the second entry in the series developed by Obsidian Entertainment launching this year on PC and consoles, won't be Microsoft's first $80 game, as the game's price has been reduced ahead of its release in a few months.</p>



<p>In a new message shared today, developer Obisidian Entertainment confirmed that the game's price has been revised to $69.99 instead of $79.99. Considering the series is a relatively recent one without a massive following, pricing The Outer Worlds 2 at $80 was a really weird decision that might have impacted the game's sales significantly.</p>







<p>The last we saw of The Outer Worlds 2 was last month during this year's Xbox Game Showcase with a trailer providing an overview of the story which also confirmed the game's release date, and a more in-depth Direct presentation that provided some additional information on the game's mechanics. Judging from the footage seen so far, the new entry in the series is setting out to expand its predecessor's mechanics considerably, which should result in a game more enjoyable than its predecessor, which left something to be desired in the moment-to-moment gameplay, as highlighted by Alessio in his <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/the-outer-worlds-obsidian-never-changes/">review.</a></p>



<p>"<em>The Outer Worlds is pretty much exactly what you'd expect from Obsidian. The first-person action RPG features a great setting, fantastic writing and remarkable, complex characters to meet. The moment-to-moment gameplay isn't as exciting, though, failing to measure up with the best in the genre. Still, there's plenty to like here as long as you know what you're getting into, not to mention the potential for a sequel to be much better, particularly if the developers had a higher budget to work with.</em>"</p>



<p>The Outer Worlds 2 launches on October 29 for PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X, and Xbox Series S.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/the-outer-worlds-2-price-has-been-reduced-to-69-99/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 Beat the PS4 to Become the Fastest-Selling Gaming Hardware In US History]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-fastest-selling-gaming-hardware-us-history/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-beat-the-ps4-to-become-the-fastest-selling-gaming-hardware-in-us-history.1251036/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 is now the fastest-selling piece of video game hardware in the US in the video game industry's history. With 1.6 million units sold in the US according to Circana executive director and analyst Mat Piscatella, it decisively crushed the previous record holder, the PlayStation 4, which sold 1.1 million units in its debut.</p>







<p>Since the Nintendo Switch 2 launched last month, we've seen multiple reports about how it is selling like hotcakes around the world, including in the United States. Just four days from launch, the Switch 2 had reached <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-debuts-with-3-5-million-units-sold-in-4-days/">3.5 million units sold around the world</a>. It was selling <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-nintendo-switch-2-is-selling-twice-as-fast-as-the-og-switch/">twice as fast as the original Nintendo Switch</a> in when it launched in 2017, and it was already <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-set-another-record-by-selling-1-1-million-units-in-its-launch-week-in-the-us/">breaking records for US sales in its first week</a>. </p>



<p>With Piscatella's report for June 2025, he confirms the Switch 2 is solidly in first place, and also shows how impactful the console's launch was on the video game industry for the month, with hardware spending going up <strong>249%</strong> compared to June 2024. It should also not come as a surprise that the Nintendo Switch 2 was the best-selling bit of video game hardware in the US for the month in terms of units and in dollars, beating the PlayStation 5 for the month. That said, the PS5 is still the best-selling piece of hardware for 2025 in both categories, though it'll be interesting to see if that changes before the year is out.</p>



<p>Another significant part of the Switch 2's blockbuster launch is that 82% of people who bought a Nintendo Switch 2 in the US in June also bought <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/mario-kart-world/">Mario Kart World</a>, either through the Switch 2 bundle or as a physical game separate from the console. The second-best-selling game for Nintendo platforms last month was Cyberpunk 2077, followed by Rune Factory: Guardians of Azuma in third, then The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom and The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild rounding out the top five in fourth and fifth place, respectively. </p>







<p>Leaving Switch 2 territory for a bit, other notable aspects of the June 2025 sales charts for the US video game industry are <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/elden-ring-nightreign-conquering-the-night/">Elden Ring: Nightreign</a> continuing to sell strongly, making its way into the top-10 best-selling games in the US for 2025 so far at the number eight spot, and being the top-selling premium game in the US for June 2025. </p>



<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-review-in-progress-one-more-for-the-road/">Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</a> found itself behind Nightreign in the number two spot on the sales charts for June 2025, and has yet to crack the top-20 best-selling games of the year so far in the US. Zooming in to platform-specific sales charts however shows Death Stranding 2 on the top of the charts for PlayStation 5 game sales in the US.</p>



<p>Lastly, Stellar Blade is the other notable entry on the sales charts, jumping up to second place on the PC sales charts and from 185th place to fifth place on the overall sales charts for June 2025, thanks to its launch on PC. Like everything else though, it still found itself looking up at Nightreign in first place.</p>



<p>All that said, the Nintendo Switch 2 dominating the charts is probably the most unsurprising event in 2025. What's exciting about watching the console now is seeing just how far it goes. We're not yet certain as to how many units were sold globally in June, though reports from earlier in the month put it at surpassing <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-likely-sold-more-than-5-million-units-in-june/">5 million</a>. Marketing analysis firm <a href="https://wccftech.com/switch-2-2025-sales-forecast-bumped-from-15-to-16-million-units-by-dfc-intelligence/">DFC Intelligence has the Switch 2 selling 16 million units</a> before the end of the year.</p>



<p>At this rate, it feels like the Switch 2 will almost certainly reach those heights.</p>





			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-fastest-selling-gaming-hardware-us-history/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>