<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 11:06:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starfield Gets New Update and New Paid Creation Mod from Renowned Modding Team]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/starfield-gets-new-update-and-new-paid-creation-mod-from-renowned-modding-team/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/starfield-gets-new-update-and-new-paid-creation-mod-from-renowned-modding-team.1197201/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/starfield-gets-new-update-and-new-paid-creation-mod-from-renowned-modding-team/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Following the <a href="https://wccftech.com/starfield-beta-update-1-15-214-adds-very-low-display-settings-for-low-end-devices-and-improves-creation-kit/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">testing phase on the Steam Beta ring</a>, Bethesda Game Studios has now released the Starfield May update to everyone. This is a relatively minor patch, although it does introduce Very Low graphic settings for expanded compatibility with lower end PC systems. It also expands the size limit of the official Creation mods to 2GB, while adding support for new icons.</p>
<p>Alongside the patch, a renowned modding team has also launched an interesting paid Creation mod called Watchtower. The mod was made by Kinggath Creations, which originally became famous with the acclaimed <a href="https://wccftech.com/starfields-outposts-meaningless/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sim Settlements</a> series of mods for Fallout 4. Since joining the Bethesda Verified Creator Program, the team has released two fairly large mods for The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim (<a href="https://kinggathcreations.com/bards-college-expansion/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bards College Expansion</a> and <a href="https://kinggathcreations.com/east-empire-expansion/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">East Empire Expansion</a>) and two minor mods for Starfield (<a href="https://kinggathcreations.com/mcclarence-outfitters/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">McClarence Outfitters</a> and <a href="https://kinggathcreations.com/at-hells-gate/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">At Hell's Gate</a>).</p>
<p>Watchtower is much deeper, though. In this mod, which Kinggath says is seamlessly integrated with the base game and the <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/starfield-shattered-space-may-the-great-serpent-save-us/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Shattered Space expansion</a>, players will experience a new storyline where they're chased by the titular new faction. They won't be alone, though, as they'll meet a fellow adventurer who has the same problem and will offer to help.</p>
<p>Throughout Watchtower, players will build a fleet and have them fight alongside you in space. The mod also adds powerful new ship attachments known as Skydrops, which allow your fleet to provide support drops or rain down attacks from orbit to assist you on your adventures on the ground. Dismantling Watchtower’s network will require destroying their listening posts and spy satellite arrays.</p>
<p>There's even a new player home, a formerly derelict star station that can be transformed into a hub for players, their crew, and other allied NPCs. Of course, there's also new equipment that can be looted from Watchtower troops, such as the new Cyberamps, which can augment the players' and crew's piloting skills. Watchtower is priced at $10; as a reminder, if you purchased the Premium Edition, you also received 1000 Creation Credits, which incidentally are the exact sum required to unlock the Creation mod.</p>
<p><iframe title="Watchtower: Orbital.Strike\Fleet.Command - Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_AUNVb3Jvyo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>In other news, a new rumor <a href="https://wccftech.com/starfield-announced-playstation-5/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">suggests</a> that Starfield will be announced and released for PlayStation 5 this year. It is unclear whether this will coincide with the debut of another major expansion. About a year ago, Bethesda's Todd Howard <a href="https://wccftech.com/starfield-crossed-14-million-players-will-get-annual-story-expansions-shattered-space-set-on-single-planet-is-far-harbor-sized/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> the plan was to release annual expansions for the sci-fi RPG, but that was before Shattered Space received a lukewarm welcome.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40K Games Roundup from 2025 Skulls: Dawn of War Definitive Edition, Updates for Darktide and Space Marine 2, and More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40k-games-roundup-from-2025-skulls-dawn-of-war-definitive-edition-updates-for-darktide-and-space-marine-2-and-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40k-games-roundup-from-2025-skulls-dawn-of-war-definitive-edition-updates-for-darktide-and-space-marine-2-and-more.1197192/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40k-games-roundup-from-2025-skulls-dawn-of-war-definitive-edition-updates-for-darktide-and-space-marine-2-and-more/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>During the Warhammer Skulls 2025 livestream, there were a lot of announcements for Warhammer 40K games. We already covered the new <a href="https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40k-dark-heresy-is-owlcats-next-inquisition-themed-crpg/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dark Heresy cRPG</a> from Owlcat Games and the remastered <a href="https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40k-space-marine-master-crafted-edition-announced-launches-on-xbox-and-pc-this-june/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Space Marine: Master Crafted Edition</a>, but there's lots more.</p>
<p>For example, fans of the real-time strategy genre will be delighted to learn that Relic Entertainment will release Dawn of War: Definitive Edition later this year on PC via Steam and GOG.</p>
<p>This version includes all the Dawn of War and Standalone Expansion content (4 Classic Dawn of War Campaigns, 9 Armies, and over 200 Maps). The Warhammer 40K RTS classic will feature 4K support, upscaled textures (4x the originals), and image-based lighting for a higher level of fidelity. World lighting, unit reflections, and shadows have all been improved, and new unit gloss and emissive lighting have been added. Relic also promised an improved gameplay camera and optimized HUD and screen layout for widescreen viewing. Lastly, the game has also been upgraded to a 64-bit platform to support the ongoing efforts of the modding community and will be compatible with existing community mods.</p>
<p><iframe title="Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War - Definitive Edition Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9CLDiE8OQ1M?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Fatshark has also announced updates for Warhammer 40K Darktide. The first paid DLC, the Arbites Class, will launch on June 23 for $11.99; on the same day, the developer will release a free update to improve onboarding and the narrative experience while also reworking the difficulty progression system and making all missions available at every difficulty level.</p>
<p><iframe title="Warhammer 40,000: Darktide - Arbites Class Reveal | Cinematic Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rZ176VVTJZo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The highly successful Warhammer 40K: Space Marine 2 also continues to be expanded by Saber Interactive. The endless co-op PvE Siege Mode will be released on June 26. Players will be able to obtain points with each defeated wave of enemies. They can then spend these points on ammunition, equipment charges, medical stims, and more, or use them to summon Astartes reinforcements such as AI Space Marines or the mighty Dreadnought.</p>
<p><iframe title="Space Marine 2 - Siege Mode Teaser Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NDScTIUHlnc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Lastly, the turn-based tactical game Warhammer 40K Mechanicus II, due later this year on PC and consoles, was also shown with the debut gameplay trailer. The footage offers a first glimpse of a new planetary conflict between the Adeptus Mechanicus and the ancient Necron dynasty, in gripping tactical skirmishes across visually diverse and richly detailed battlefields, each teeming with opportunities for strategic domination.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Warhammer 40,000: Mechanicus II | Allegiances Unknown | Gameplay Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_7ig-tH4yyM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Are you satisfied with the announcements from the livestream? Let us know in the comments.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The US Federal Trade Commission v. Microsoft Over The Activision Blizzard Deal Has Come To An End, The FTC Officially Drops The Case]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-us-federal-trade-commission-v-microsoft-over-the-activision-blizzard-deal-has-come-to-an-end-the-ftc-officially-drops-the-case/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-us-federal-trade-commission-v-microsoft-over-the-activision-blizzard-deal-has-come-to-an-end-the-ftc-officially-drops-the-case.1197132/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/the-us-federal-trade-commission-v-microsoft-over-the-activision-blizzard-deal-has-come-to-an-end-the-ftc-officially-drops-the-case/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>As spotted by <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/673123/ftc-drops-case-microsoft-activision-blizzard-acquisition">The Verge</a>, the US Federal Trade Commission (FTC) has officially dropped its case against Microsoft over its Activision Blizzard King acquisition. The organization <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/system/files/ftc_gov/pdf/d9412_2025.05.22_commission_order_dismissing_complaint_.pdf">filed a motion to dismiss the case</a> today, May 22, 2025, finally closing the door on the FTC's attempts to block the largest acquisition in video game industry history.</p>
<p>Microsoft first announced its acquisition of Activision Blizzard King at <a href="https://wccftech.com/activision-blizzard-has-been-acquired-by-microsoft-for-70-billion/">the beginning of 2022</a>, and by the end of 2022, the <a href="https://wccftech.com/activision-blizzard-microsoft-acquisition-ftc-antitrust-lawsuit/">FTC had filed a lawsuit against Microsoft</a>, and so began the long contest that has continued to stretch on, even <a href="https://wccftech.com/activision-deal-free-to-proceed-ftc-pause-rejected-ninth-circuit/">after the FTC lost</a> in its one major change to really stop the deal from happening. At the beginning of this month, it <a href="https://wccftech.com/microsoft-has-won-the-ftc-appeal-that-still-challenged-its-acquisition-of-activision-blizzard/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">lost a final attempt</a> at stopping the deal and has chosen to put its fight to rest.</p>
<p>"<em>On May 7, 2025, the Ninth Circuit affirmed the decision of the United States District Court for the Northern District of California, FTC v. Microsoft Corp...denying the Commission's application for a preliminary injunction to block the acquisition of Activision Blizzard, Inc. by Microsoft Corp,</em>" the filing reads.</p>
<p>"<em>The Commission has determined that the public interest is best served by dismissing the administrative litigation in this case. Accordingly, it is hereby ordered that the Complaint in this matter be, and it hereby is, dismissed by the Commission</em>."</p>
<p>Vice chair and president of Microsoft <a href="https://x.com/BradSmi/status/1925660906702156072">Brad Smith celebrated the dismissa</a>l, saying "<em>Today's decision is a victory for players across the country and for common sense in Washington, D.C. We are grateful to the FTC for today's announcement.</em>"</p>
<p>After losing its initial attempt to stop the deal, Microsoft closed its acquisition of Activision Blizzard King in <a href="https://wccftech.com/microsoft-closes-68-7-billion-activision-blizzard-deal-after-nearly-21-month-long-odyssey/">October 2023</a>, but that didn't stop the FTC from trying to <a href="https://wccftech.com/ftc-files-appeal-against-judges-decision-hoping-to-delay-microsofts-closure-of-activision-blizzard-deal/">break it up</a> after the fact. The organization also spoke out against decisions Microsoft has made since the deal closed, like raising the price of <a href="https://wccftech.com/ftc-files-complaint-against-microsoft-following-game-pass-price-hike/">Game Pass</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/activision-blizzard-layoffs-ftc-complaint/">laying off thousands of employees.</a></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Rumored A24 Elden Ring Movie With Alex Garland Writing And Directing Is Real [Updated]]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-rumored-a24-elden-ring-movie-with-alex-garland-writing-and-directing-is-reportedly-real/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-rumored-a24-elden-ring-movie-with-alex-garland-writing-and-directing-is-real-updated.1197087/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/the-rumored-a24-elden-ring-movie-with-alex-garland-writing-and-directing-is-reportedly-real/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><strong>Update 22/05/2025:</strong> Bandai Namco released a statement on its <a href="https://x.com/BandaiNamcoUS/status/1925699586640707708">official US X account</a> regarding the Elden Ring movie, saying "<em>We're thrilled to announce that Bandai Namco Entertainment Inc. and A24 are teaming up with writer and director Alex Garland to bring FromSoftware Inc.'s world-renowned video game Elden Ring to life as a live-action film.</em>"</p>
<p>"<em>We're truly excited to bring the world of Elden Ring to fans in a new form, outside the game. Stay tuned. The path ahead is only beginning</em>."</p>
<p><strong>Original Story:</strong></p>
<p>A report from <a href="https://deadline.com/2025/05/elden-ring-alex-garland-directing-a24-movie-1236408999/">Deadline</a> has confirmed that the previously rumored Elden Ring movie with A24 producing and Alex Garland set to write and direct, is in fact real. No word on when it is happening, but Garland is leading the project with Bandai Namco set to collaborate.</p>
<p>The idea of an Elden Ring movie or TV adaptation has been brought up twice before by George R.R. Martin, who mentioned it <a href="https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-movie-is-being-discussed-says-george-r-r-martin/">early last year</a> and then again in <a href="https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-movie-or-tv-series-seemingly-being-teased-by-george-r-r-martin/">summer 2024</a>, though there's been no word on whether it was really happening or not.</p>
<p>Weeks prior to Deadline's report, a <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/nexus-point-news-alex-garland-set-to-direct-%E2%80%98elden-ring%E2%80%99-film-for-a24.1182531/">rumor appeared online</a> that it would be Garland writing and directing it and that the movie was happening, but the original source took down their claim that the movie was being made, and that Garland and A24 were behind it.</p>
<p>The original claim's removal led many to speculate that it was a false claim, though Deadline's report today seals that the report last month was correct.</p>
<p>Peter Rice, Andrew Macdonald, Allon Reich, Vince Gerardis, and George R.R. Martin will produce the film. It's unclear when we'll hear about casting and when the film will start shooting, or what it could be about, but the previous rumor claimed that filming would begin in 2026.</p>
<p>Needless to say, it'll be interesting to see how this adaptation shapes up. It's unclear how involved FromSoftware will be, and there are large parts of Elden Ring's story that are purposely left ambiguous. Your journey through the worlds that FromSoftware creates is always part of the larger story the studio is telling, but players who deeply love digging into the lore for all of FromSoftware's games know that, for as much as you can discover, there will always be gaps in what you can say happened for certain, and what the real 'story' behind the characters you'll meet and fight is.</p>
<p>Which is also part of the fun of the story in FromSoftware games, that you can imagine your own version of events for characters, even if their ending is laid bare to you with their corpse lying at your feet after you rest at a bonfire/site of grace. Whatever Garland decides his take on an Elden Ring story will be, it will undoubtedly be food for discussion online.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>