<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 17:54:24 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Crew Grants All Fortnite Passes and More From December 1]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/fortnite-crew-grants-all-fortnite-passes-and-more-from-december-1/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-crew-grants-all-fortnite-passes-and-more-from-december-1.1040772/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/fortnite-crew-grants-all-fortnite-passes-and-more-from-december-1/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A <a href="https://x.com/FN_Assist/status/1859251588688162930?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1859251588688162930%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=" target="_blank" rel="noopener">huge change to the microtransactions</a> is coming in Fortnite, meaning that you can get a ton of content for a fixed price each month. As of <a href="https://wccftech.com/all-passes-in-fortnite-to-progress-simultaneously-by-earning-xp-coming-december-1/">December 1</a>, Fortnite Crew will give you access to all of the following for no additional cost as long as you are an active subscriber:</p>
<ul>
<li>Battle Pass</li>
<li>Music Pass</li>
<li>Lego Pass</li>
<li>Any other new Pass that arrives</li>
<li>1,000 V-Bucks</li>
<li>Monthly Crew Pack</li>
<li>Crew Pack legacy styles</li>
<li>Rocket Pass Premium</li>
</ul>
<p>To get all of this content and the premium tracks of each pass, you simply have to pay $11.99 a month. This is a huge change from what it was previously, where you'd have to pay for each pass separately. It hasn't been stated why this change has been made, but there is already a lot of positive buzz around it on social media. Of course, since this means that players will have to pay substantially less to be able to access all of the rewards available, players are beginning to wonder what the catch is. Why would a huge company be favorable towards the players?</p>
<p>So far, it seems that you have to consistently be subscribed to Fortnite Crew to be able to get the rewards, whereas previously, players found that they could pay for Fortnite Crew every other month to get rewards at half the price. However, the rules have been updated to stop Fortnite players from doing that.</p>
<p>It's been stated that for new subscribers to Fortnite Crew, premium rewards on the Battle Pass will only be available to claim if your Fortnite Crew subscription is active. This means that if you cancel it halfway through the pass duration, you won't be able to claim any of the Premium rewards. Instead, you'll now only be able to claim premium rewards from the Battle Pass until the end of your current billing period rather than the remaining duration of the pass.</p>
<p>However, for players who are currently subscribed to Fortnite Crew or subscribe before December 1, there will be no changes made to you can claim premium rewards on the Battle Pass. However, should you cancel your Fortnite Crew subscription after December 1 and then resubscribe after your previous subscription has expired, you'll then be considered a new subscriber and will be in line with the new rules for the pass system.</p>
<p>To get any premium rewards on the Music Pass and Lego Pass, an active Fortnite Crew subscription will be needed to get access to the premium tracks. This will also apply to any new battle passes that are added in the future.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>