<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 13:27:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ex Bloodlines 2 Creative Director Wanted to Call the Game Differently to Set the Correct Expectations]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ex-bloodlines-2-creative-director-wanted-to-call-the-game-differently/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ex-bloodlines-2-creative-director-wanted-to-call-the-game-differently-to-set-the-correct-expectations.1362676/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Nearly a month after the release of Vampire: The Masquerade - Bloodlines 2, former Creative Director and The Chinese Room Studio Head Dan Pinchbeck opened up on the game's development phase <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iyWDyNLAo1E" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in a video interview with YouTuber Cat Burton</a>. </p>



<p>The most interesting tidbit is that Pinchbeck really didn't want to call this game Bloodlines 2. As you might recall, The Chinese Room only came in to rescue the game from cancellation after publisher Paradox Interactive split with the original developer of the sequel, Hardsuit Labs. That also meant they didn't have enough time or money to make it the true sequel fans of the original might have wanted. Apparently, it was Pinchbeck who decided to make it a more focused, Dishonored-like game, due to the constraints the developers were forced to work with.</p>



<p><em>We used to sit there and go and have these planning sessions of how do we get them to not call it Bloodlines 2. That feels like the most important thing we do here, is to come at this and say this isn't Bloodlines 2. You can't make Bloodlines 2. There's not enough time. There's not enough money. Bloodlines 1 came out at a really interesting period in game development, when you could ship a really ambitious game that was full of bugs and holes, was totally flawed, but the ambition was really exciting. A lot of those games, they're real cult games now, but they really weren't very good when you actually broke them apart and analyzed them. Great ideas, wonderful ideas, players loved them. You couldn't get away with it now.</em></p>



<p><em>So, trying to recreate that magic in a different environment felt wrongheaded. No one would be happy. You wouldn't make people who love Bloodlines 1 happy and you wouldn't make people who didn't know about Bloodlines 1 happy, because they'd never get Bloodlines 2 and they'd always get a flawed game that was built too fast and with not enough money.</em></p>



<p><em>So we approached it from that point of view of, well, what can we do with the time and the money that's available, and at that point, I came in and went, 'we can't make Bloodlines 2, we can't make Skyrim, but we can make Dishonored.' We would look at something which is not an RPG and is not fully open world, but is really tightly focused and true to the mythos, and it's a good ride, we get a Bloodlines title out in the world, and then we'd started talking about saying, then what would the next big Bloodlines game look like after that, if that happened?</em></p>



<p>It's a sound strategy, in theory. Unfortunately, it doesn't seem like the game is going to sell enough to warrant a bigger, better sequel. According to estimates based on SteamDB data, only between 120K and 300K copies of the game have been sold so far via PC's most popular store. </p>



<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-greatly-uneven-but-still-worth-a-look/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">In my review of the game</a>, I concluded that Bloodlines 2 is worth playing despite its flaws, but only for fans of the setting and once the game is significantly cheaper than the launch price. However, that might happen very soon.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/ex-bloodlines-2-creative-director-wanted-to-call-the-game-differently/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Witcher IV and Cyberpunk 2077 Sequel Won’t Be Anything Like Baldur’s Gate 3]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-iv-not-like-baldurs-gate-3/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-witcher-iv-and-cyberpunk-2077-sequel-won%E2%80%99t-be-anything-like-baldur%E2%80%99s-gate-3.1362637/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Although it has provided some inspiration to The Witcher IV developer CD Projekt Red, future games from the studio won't be anything like Larian Studios' Baldur's Gate 3.</p>



<p>Speaking with <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/rpg/baldurs-gate-3-is-an-inspiration-for-cd-projekt-but-its-all-in-on-big-open-worlds-we-are-definitely-not-going-to-make-a-game-like-larian-did/">PC Gamer</a>, CD Projekt's joint CEO Michał Nowakowski confirmed that Baldur's Gate 3 provided the developer a lot of inspiration, but they will still stick to the open-world setting seen in games like The Witcher 3 and Cyberpunk 2077. Obviously, CD Projekt Red isn't going to simply create similar games with better graphics, as Nowakowski highlighted that the studio wants to <em>"innovate."</em></p>



<p>Although the CD Projekt's joint CEO did not elaborate on how they plan to innovate their open-world formula in games like <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-iv-new-trailer-ps5-60-fps-ray-tracing/">The Witcher IV</a> and the <a href="https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-sequel-new-chicago-city/">Cyberpunk 2077 sequel</a>, it seems that world interactivity will be enhanced over older games.</p>



<p><em>"That's the kind of game they can make,"</em> Michał Nowakowski said about Larian Studios' games like the Divinity: Original Sin series and Baldur's Gate 3. <em>"But a lot of stuff with how they can interact with the world and what it does was, for sure, some inspiration to us."</em></p>



<p>Much of Baldur's Gate 3's success resides, in my opinion, exactly in <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/baldurs-gate-3-review/">how the world feels incredibly dynamic and reactive</a>, so it's great to hear that The Witcher IV may take the best of Larian Studio's approach for the third entry in the beloved series and apply it to its open-world formula to improve the experience. As good as The Witcher 3 and Cyberpunk 2077 are, their open worlds adhere to traditional by-the-books design without shaking them up significantly, so I am very interested to see how much this influence will shape their sequels.</p>



<p>One thing The Witcher IV is not going to feature for certain is new contributions from Andrzej Sapkowski, author of the novels upon which the CDPR series is based. According to the author, <a data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-iv-wont-have-any-new-contribution-from-andrzej-sapkowski/">the developer rarely asks him for details nowadays</a>, but their relationship remains healthy after <a href="https://wccftech.com/cd-projekt-red-solidifies-relationship-with-andrzej-sapkowski-creator-of-witcher/">the signing of a new deal in December 2019.</a></p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-iv-not-like-baldurs-gate-3/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch First-Party Games Like Super Mario Odyssey Get Rare Discount For Black Friday 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-first-party-games-like-super-mario-odyssey-get-rare-discount-for-black-friday-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-first-party-games-like-super-mario-odyssey-get-rare-discount-for-black-friday-2025.1362601/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Nintendo first-party developed games rarely get discounts, but the Japanese publisher decided to briefly amend their pricing strategy just in time for Black Friday 2025, offering some of its best Nintendo Switch games at reduced prices.</p>



<p>Among the Switch games that can be purchased for reduced prices this week is <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Super Mario Odyssey</strong>, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B01MY7GHKJ/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">available for <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">$39.99</strong></a> (50% off the MSRP). The game is also fully playable on Nintendo Switch 2, so if you never played the game before and own any of the Switch systems, there's no better time to get it, and experience what is widely considered one of the best 3D Mario games ever.</p>



<p>Other notable Nintendo Switch Black Friday 2025 deals include <strong data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)">Splatoon 3, Princess Peach: Showtime, Donkey Kong Country Returns HD, The Legend of Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom</strong>, and many others. You can check out all the deals available this week by <a data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=nintendo+switch+games&amp;i=black-friday&amp;language=en_US&amp;crid=2AY0R6066IY62&amp;linkCode=sl2&amp;linkId=ad1a5b1f9f5ebcd44c4563e3b1540d00&amp;sprefix=ps5+g%2Cblack-friday%2C517&amp;tag=wccftech0a9-20&amp;ref=as_li_ss_tl">heading over to Amazon.</a></p>



<h2 id="h-should-you-go-for-these-nintendo-switch-black-friday-2025-deals-now-or-wait">Should You Go For These Nintendo Switch Black Friday 2025 Deals Now or Wait?</h2>



<p>As Black Friday 2025 is still a few days away, some additional deals are expected to become available as we get closer to November 28.</p>



<p>However, given Nintendo's historical stance on pricing and their previous Black Friday deals, it is doubtful you will be able to find better discounts than these in the next couple of days. Nintendo’s first-party titles are known to maintain their value for years. As such, you should definitely take advantage of these deals as soon as possible before stock runs out.</p>



<p>Looking for accessories or other games on sale? Check out our comprehensive <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/black-friday-2025-nintendo-switch-2-deals-save-on-console-accessories-and-games/">Nintendo Switch 2 (and original Switch) list of the best Black Friday 2025 deals </a>available this week.</strong></p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-first-party-games-like-super-mario-odyssey-get-rare-discount-for-black-friday-2025/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FromSoftware Spent More Time On The Duskbloods’ Gameplay Than Any Other Title, Including Elden Ring, Leak Claims]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/fromsoftware-the-duskbloods-gameplay-leak/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fromsoftware-spent-more-time-on-the-duskbloods%E2%80%99-gameplay-than-any-other-title-including-elden-ring-leak-claims.1362559/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			<div data-nosnippet="">
		
		<ul>
			<li>0-20%: Unlikely - Lacks credible sources</li>
			<li>21-40%: Questionable - Some concerns remain</li>
			<li>41-60%: Plausible - Reasonable evidence</li>
			<li>61-80%: Probable - Strong evidence</li>
			<li>81-100%: Highly Likely - Multiple reliable sources</li>
		</ul>
	</div>


			
			
			
			<p>As FromSoftware continues working on Elden Ring Nightreign, the Japanese development studio is also hard at work on The Duskbloods, which reportedly is a game the developer has spent time on fine tuning gameplay the most.</p>



<p>As reported in a new video shared by <a data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://www.youtube.com/@Ziostorm">Ziostorm</a>, a Chinese journalist who provided accurate information on <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://wccftech.com/review/elden-ring-make-way-for-the-elden-lord/">Elden Ring</a> before the game's release, recently revealed some small, exciting tidbits about FromSoftware's upcoming Nintendo Switch 2 exclusive. The game was reportedly greenlit even before the marketing campaign for <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/sekiro-shadows-die-twice/">Sekiro: Shadows Die Twice</a> started, and it is the game that FromSoftware has spent the most time on gameplay among all of their games.</p>



<p>All the time spent on prototyping The Duskbloods' gameplay is reportedly paying off, as the game, although PvEvP, features many innovative gameplay elements that the team is really proud of. So much so that the journalist speculates the game could influence games from other studios as much as the aforementioned Sekiro: Shadows Die Twice did, especially with the parry mechanics that are now prevalent in almost every action game.</p>



<p>Besides providing this small bit of information on The Duskbloods, the known Chinese journalist also revealed that we should see more of the <a href="https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-nightreign-dlc-the-forsaken-hollows-release-date/">Elden Ring Nightreign DLC, The Forsaken Hollow</a>, soon. Apparently, three more trailers should be released before the game launches on December 4 to showcase the two new Nightfarers - the Scholar and the Undertaker - and the new content in a final launch trailer. As the expansion is nearing release, these trailers, if they are indeed coming, shouldn't be more than a few days away.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="More FromSoftware News Just Dropped | Nightreign DLC Details, The Duskbloods Info, and MORE!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_lHUBWlGTgY?start=156&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p><a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://wccftech.com/fromsoftwares-the-duskbloods-announced-exclusively-for-nintendo-switch-2/">When it was revealed during the first Nintendo Switch 2 Nintendo Direct ever earlier this year</a>, many, including myself, jumped at the screen at the first footage of The Duskbloods, as the game looked like a sequel to the beloved <a href="https://wccftech.com/tag/bloodborne/">Bloodborne</a>. However, the Switch 2 exclusive is going to be a much different game, having been built from the ground up as a multiplayer experience, which left a few disappointed, as FromSoftware is primarily known for its single-player experiences with multiplayer elements sprinkled on top.</p>



<p>Hopefully, the game's supposed innovative gameplay elements will make it a compelling experience for all fans of the studio, possibly turning doubters' opinions around as much as <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/elden-ring-nightreign-conquering-the-night/">Elden Ring Nightreign did for me when it launched earlier this year on PC and consoles.</a></p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/fromsoftware-the-duskbloods-gameplay-leak/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FEROCIOUS Is an Indie Single Player FPS Where You Fight Dinosaurs But Also Control Them, And It’s Out on December 4]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ferocious-indie-fps-where-you-fight-dinosaurs-but-also-control-them/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ferocious-is-an-indie-single-player-fps-where-you-fight-dinosaurs-but-also-control-them-and-it%E2%80%99s-out-on-december-4.1362526/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Publisher tinyBuild has announced that the indie single player first-person shooter game FEROCIOUS will be released on December 4 for PC <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1645630/FEROCIOUS/?mc_cid=5e1f5669c5&amp;mc_eid=728a334a9c" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">via Steam</a>.</p>



<p>FEROCIOUS, powered by Unity, is the debut game of OMYOG, a small studio that features the expertise of both AAA game and film veterans. Leonard Saalfrank, inspired by King Kong, leads the vision, while Mark, ex-Far Cry and Battlefront II director, brings sandbox-level design expertise. Writers like Jörg Ihle and Dominik Hochwald add narrative depth from film, games, and theme parks.</p>



<p>In FEROCIOUS, players will find themselves stranded on a dangerous island and forced to survive against mercenaries, dinosaurs, and a vibrant yet hostile ecosystem. At every turn, they must face challenges in the form of savage predators, treacherous terrain, and limited resources. Careful exploration is vital to uncover hidden paths, secrets and essential gear. Furthermore, as shown in the release date trailer (embedded below), there's a twist in that a so-called 'dino control device' lets you turn the dinosaurs to your side, so that they might be used to attack enemies, open paths, or infiltrate guarded areas. </p>



<p>The lore explanation is that it scans the creature's brain and reproduces its vocal signals, not unlike what was shown in Jurassic Park 3, but with the usage of ultrasonic calls that only the lizards can hear. Once scanned, the player can get a dinosaur to follow them, move to a particular spot, attack a target, break obstacles, or even fetch items. The commands depend on the species; some are more obedient (or smarter) than others. Not every dinosaur in the game will be controllable, though.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="FEROCIOUS - Release Date Trailer | Dino Control Device🦖" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0N0h-Lhf1XI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>TinyBuild did not share the pricing yet, but given that it's an indie game, we expect it to be priced accordingly. The Steam page also includes the minimum and recommended PC system requirements for FEROCIOUS, by the way.</p>



<p><strong>Minimum:<br></strong>Requires a 64-bit processor and operating system<br>OS: Windows 10/11 64-bit<br>Processor: Intel Core i5 4th Gen or AMD equivalent<br>Memory: 12 GB RAM<br>Graphics: NVIDIA GTX 1060 / AMD RX 580<br>DirectX: Version 11<br>Storage: 25 GB available space</p>



<p><strong>Recommended:<br></strong>Requires a 64-bit processor and operating system<br>OS: Windows 10/11 64-bit<br>Processor: Intel Core i7 or Ryzen 5 3600 and up<br>Memory: 16 GB RAM<br>Graphics: NVIDIA RTX 2060 / AMD RX 5600<br>DirectX: Version 11<br>Storage: 25 GB available space</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/ferocious-indie-fps-where-you-fight-dinosaurs-but-also-control-them/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>