<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:10:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aliens Fireteam Elite 2 Gets Delayed to Q3 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/aliens-fireteam-elite-2-gets-delayed-to-q3-2026/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/aliens-fireteam-elite-2-gets-delayed-to-q3-2026.1350898/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>In July 2024, a leaked presentation practically <a href="https://wccftech.com/aliens-fireteam-elite-2-leak/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">confirmed</a> the existence of Aliens Fireteam Elite 2, a sequel to the cooperative third-person shooter game released by Cold Iron Studios in 2021. The presentation revealed several details about the game, such as the availability of five character archetypes (Swift, Deadly, Silent, Commander, Ranger), each with their own unique primary weapons and abilities, and the inclusion of Annihilation mode, which was said to be inspired by classic Horde modes with more variety in encounters and objectives.</p>



<p>It also stated that the studio's goal was to release the game in 2025, but there has been no such confirmation. Indeed, a few hours ago, Enad Global 7 (which had also published the first game) announced (as <a href="https://massivelyop.com/2025/11/11/eg7-q3-2025-palia-continues-to-be-daybreaks-shining-star-as-cold-irons-project-avo-is-delayed-to-q3-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">spotted by MassivelyOP</a>) that it is investing up to an additional $6.5 million in the next game developed by Cold Iron Studios, which now has an official release window of Q3 2026. Cold Iron is also going to invest an additional $1.2 million out of its own pockets.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://www.enadglobal7.com/press-releases/daybreak-advances-cold-iron-partnership-with-an-additional-investment-of-up-to-usd-6-5-million-and-updates-the-games-target-release-window-to-third-quarter-of-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">press release</a> does not actually name Aliens Fireteam Elite 2. Still, given the previous leak, the developer, and the fact that this upcoming title is also a 'co-op action shooter based on a major film IP franchise', it's fair to expect there will be no surprises in that regard.</p>



<p>The first game didn't exactly provoke thrilling emotions in franchise fans, or indeed genre fans. <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/aliens-fireteam-elite-against-one-horror-against-many-tragedy/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">In Wccftech's review</a>, Kai Tatsumoto gave it just 6 out of 10:</p>



<p><em>The Colonial Marines and military types of the Aliens universe would normally be a perfect fit for the style of co-op shooter that Cold Iron Studios was aiming for but unfortunately Aliens: Fireteam Elite misses the mark by a wide margin. Instead of celebrating the sheer power of the Colonial Marines, these three-man fireteams are simply trying to survive being mobbed down by waves of mindless, fast-moving zombies with the added ability of being able to crawl on walls. The potential of building up a badass Doc was quickly ruined with the realization that there just isn't much incentive to keep grinding away for minimal returns.</em></p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/aliens-fireteam-elite-2-gets-delayed-to-q3-2026/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aion 2 To Launch Globally in the Second Half of 2026; Monetization To Be Less Aggressive Than Throne and Liberty]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/aion-2-launch-globally-second-half-2026-monetization-less-aggressive/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/aion-2-to-launch-globally-in-the-second-half-of-2026-monetization-to-be-less-aggressive-than-throne-and-liberty.1350880/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>During its Q3 2025 quarterly report (as <a href="https://massivelyop.com/2025/11/11/ncsoft-q3-2025-guild-wars-2-delivers-solid-results-as-aion-2-sets-2h-2026-global-launch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">spotted by MassivelyOP</a>), NCSoft announced that Aion 2 will debut on the global stage in the second half of 2026. The MMORPG is set to launch in exactly a week from today in South Korea and Taiwan for PC and mobile devices.</p>



<p>Aion 2 is a direct sequel to the 2009 classic MMORPG. It's set roughly 200 years after the events seen in that game. Its massive game world is estimated to be around 1,200 square kilometers and features distinct biomes like dusty frontier towns, icy peaks, flowing rivers, and hidden labs. Just like in the original, flight mechanics are included both for exploration and aerial combat. Players can also look forward to eight classes, more than 200 dungeons (between the solo and group ones), various PvP modes (large-scale faction warfare between the Elyos and Asmodian, but also 1v1, 4v4, 8v8 arenas), and other systems like housing. In the investors' call, NCSoft promised that Aion 2 would feature less aggressive monetization compared to Throne and Liberty, which in turn should 'secure a bigger userbase'. As <a href="https://wccftech.com/aion-2-to-launch-globally-2026-with-dlss-4-multi-frame-generation/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">confirmed</a> a couple of weeks ago, the game, powered by Epic's Unreal Engine 5, will support NVIDIA DLSS 4 Multi Frame Generation.</p>



<p>2026 is poised to be a significant year for NCSoft, with the launch of Aion 2 and other key titles, including Cinder City, Limit Zero Breakers, and Time Takers. We covered Cinder City from Gamescom 2025; it's an intriguing open world third-person shooter with MMO-like elements coming in 2026 to PC and consoles. Check out our exclusive interview with the development team <a href="https://wccftech.com/cinder-city-preview-qa-open-world-shooter-mmo-like/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>.</p>



<p>Limit Zero Breakers, developed by VIC GAME STUDIOS, is a free-to-play anime-style cooperative action RPG due in 2026 for PC (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3764400/LIMIT_ZERO_BREAKERS/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steam</a>) and mobile. In the game, a team of adventurers known as 'Breakers' explores a fragmented, corrupted world from atop a powerful airship, searching for the mythical 'Library of the Gods'. During battle, players unleash stylish attacks and combinations against enormous creatures lurking in ancient dungeons, striving to restore peace to the continent of Seraphia.</p>



<p>As for Time Takers, it's a third-person team-based shooter for PC (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3596040/Time_Takers/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steam</a>) and consoles that features Time Energy as a unique resource that players can spend on reviving teammates or upgrading skills, for example. </p>



<p>Arguably, though, the most exciting game in NCSoft's whole upcoming lineup could be the one set to be announced tomorrow at G-Star 2025. According to rumors, it might be the <a href="https://wccftech.com/horizon-mmo-game-reportedly-in-the-works-supposedly-made-by-sony-and-ncsoft/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Horizon </a>MMO we first heard about three years ago. Earlier this year, another rumor <a href="https://wccftech.com/horizon-mmo-canceled/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">claimed</a> it had been canceled, but that might have been incorrect. We'll know for sure in a few hours.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/aion-2-launch-globally-second-half-2026-monetization-less-aggressive/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[27″ PlayStation Gaming Monitor Announced, Will Launch Next Year in the US and Japan]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/27-inch-playstation-gaming-monitor-announced-will-launch-next-year/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/27%E2%80%B3-playstation-gaming-monitor-announced-will-launch-next-year-in-the-us-and-japan.1350850/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>During the State of Play Japan broadcast that aired a few hours ago, Sony announced a 27-inch PlayStation Gaming Monitor that will launch next year in the United States and Japan. No pricing has been revealed yet, but we do know its specifications:</p>



<ul>
<li>Quad High Definition (QHD) IPS display with a resolution of up to 2560 x 1440, allowing players to game at a comfortable viewing distance from their desk.</li>



<li>High Dynamic Range (HDR) support with Auto HDR Tone Mapping, which automatically adjusts HDR settings during setup on PS5 and PS5 Pro consoles, ensuring a rich and vivid picture quality.</li>



<li>Variable Refresh Rate (VRR) support and refresh rates of up to 120 Hz for smooth and seamless gameplay on PS5 and PS5 Pro consoles, and 240 Hz on compatible PC and Mac devices.</li>



<li>Built-in Charging Hook for a DualSense or DualSense Edge wireless controller (sold separately), making it easy for players to get right into gaming.</li>
</ul>



<p>The PlayStation Gaming Monitor is equipped with two 2.1 HDMI IN ports and one 1.4 DisplayPort IN port for compatibility with PlayStation 5, PC, Mac, or other devices. The 2.1 HDMI IN ports support up to 2560×1440 resolution, 240Hz frame rate, Fixed Rate Link (FRL), and VRR; the 1.4 DisplayPort IN port supports up to 2560×1440 resolution, 240Hz frame rate, and Display Stream Compression (DSC).</p>



<p>You'll also find two USB Type-A and one USB Type-C port that can be used with PlayStation Link Adapters or other devices. The display is compatible with select VESA mounting systems to mount it on a wall, for instance. When it comes to audio, there's a built-in stereo speaker and 3.5mm audio output, but Sony recommends pairing it with the upcoming <a href="https://wccftech.com/sony-unveils-pulse-elvate-wireless-speakers-built-in-mic/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pulse Elevate Wireless Speakers</a>. This set features planar magnetic drivers and a built-in microphone, and it's also due to launch in 2026.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="27&quot; Gaming Monitor with DualSense Charging Hook - Teaser Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mRHgZ_l94F0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Spec-wise, the PlayStation Gaming Monitor is undoubtedly a step down from <a href="https://wccftech.com/sony-inzone-m10s-oled-m9-ii-gaming-monitors-launched-up-to-4k-480hz-with-dp-2-1-support/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sony's Inzone M10S OLED and M9 II monitors</a> released last year. However, it's also likely to be significantly more affordable, although we'll have to wait for official pricing news to know exactly how much it will cost.</p>



<p>During the aforementioned State of Play, Sony also announced a new, <a href="https://wccftech.com/sony-launching-cheaper-japanese-language-only-digital-ps5-in-japan/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">cheaper Japan-only version of the PlayStation 5</a>. Publisher Bandai Namco also <a href="https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-nightreign-dlc-the-forsaken-hollows-release-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">unveiled a DLC for Elden Ring: Nightreign</a>.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/27-inch-playstation-gaming-monitor-announced-will-launch-next-year/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>