<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 16:07:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Crisis Events in Civilization 7 Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/how-to/crisis-events-in-civilization-7-explained/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/crisis-events-in-civilization-7-explained.1104978/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/how-to/crisis-events-in-civilization-7-explained/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>One of the newer features added to the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1295660/Sid_Meiers_Civilization_VII/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">latest iteration</a> of Sid Meier's Civilization is the inclusion of Crisis Events. This also includes Crisis Policies, which are held on the same page as the Social Policies that you can choose for your empire. If you're getting stuck in Civilization 7 and aren't sure what the Crisis Events have in store for you, this guide will explain everything you need to know about Crisis Policies and the Crisis Events themselves in Civilization 7.</p>
<p>For more Civilization 7, check out our other guides.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/how-to/how-to-disperse-an-independent-power-in-civilization-7/">How to Disperse an Independent Power</a></li>
<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/how-to/how-to-raise-settlement-cap-in-civilization-7/">How To Raise Settlement Cap&nbsp;</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>What Are Crisis Policies?</h2>

<figure></figure>

<p>For every unique Crisis Event in Civilization 7 comes a unique set of Crisis Policies that you will have to choose between. While some of them may seem like they could be beneficial, a lot of the time, the negative effects of the Policies will be very obvious during your playthrough. The Crisis Policies exist to try and help mitigate the dangers of the ongoing crisis rather than help to resolve it entirely. There will be some difficult choices you'll have to make, and as the Crisis evolves, you'll have to choose more Crisis Policies.</p>
<h2>What are Crisis Events in Civilization 7?</h2>
<p>Crisis Events happen through the Antiquity and Exploration Age typically, where you can have anything from a nonstop invasion to the Plague ravaging your empire and nearby cities. Unfortunately, you&nbsp;<strong>cannot stop</strong> these events from happening. They are guaranteed to happen, but it may just take a while for them to happen. Below are the events that could happen in the Antiquity Age and Exploration Age, respectively.</p>
<p><strong>Revolts</strong> - The rising unhappiness of your population has reached an all-time high. Your settlements go into open revolt, and they want to tear you down.</p>
<p><strong>Invasion</strong> - Independent Powers will begin to overwhelm your lands and assault your troops and cities. You'll need a strong military for this one.</p>
<p><strong>Plague</strong> - The plague is self-explanatory but can be incredibly difficult to handle during this age, as there are minimal medical breakthroughs at this point.</p>
<p>Moving on to the Exploration Age there are two different events that can happen in the Exploration Age, but the Plague can also happen here, too.</p>
<p><strong>Wars of Religion</strong> - Nations begin to spread their religions, but this leads to conflict between different religions that believe in their own tenets. You can choose whether or not you think tolerance of other beliefs can exist.</p>
<p><strong>Revolution</strong> - The Bourgeoisie and the middle class begin to rise up and ask for a change in power, which shocks the noble people. You have the option to dampen their revolution efforts or lead a Revolutionary Government.</p>
<p><strong>Plague</strong> - The Plague can also happen in the Exploration Age. There are more ways to handle it, such as having Medical staff available during this time, but it is significantly more dangerous and more contagious.</p>
<p>While you can't prevent the Crisis Events from happening, if you were to start a new Civilization 7 game, you can <strong>choose to toggle them off</strong>, so you don't have to deal with them in a new playthrough.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 Units May Already Be in the Hands of Some; Console Could Be Priced at Around $350 – Rumor]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-units-out-priced-350/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-units-may-already-be-in-the-hands-of-some-console-could-be-priced-at-around-350-%E2%80%93-rumor.1104894/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-units-out-priced-350/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 could already be in the hands of some users, according to some new online reports.</p>
<p>As reported on Bluesky by Necro Felipe, the same user on the Xiaohongshu forums who shared the console's CAD model <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-design-pictures-specs/">a few months back</a> claims to have obtained a real Nintendo Switch 2 unit, most likely via illegal means. If this is true, we should expect more information on the system to surface online before the April 2nd Direct and the hands-on events that will be held worldwide in the coming months.</p>
<blockquote data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:5uw2zrybj37wnkkc5ku4fxyu/app.bsky.feed.post/3lht5vqyzlp2x" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreia2unbnwu4mqgh2dve44seg5vprp5hrle7hjgbjia2bdaqryv4voa">
<p lang="pt">Usuário que compartilhou o modelo CAD do Switch 2 anteriormente no fórum Xiaohongshu afirma que obteve um Switch 2 real agora (provavelmente de forma ilegal)</p>
<p>Ele avisa aos interessados por acessórios que o contate para testes com o aparelho</p>
<p>(thx Kysen)</p>
<p><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:5uw2zrybj37wnkkc5ku4fxyu/post/3lht5vqyzlp2x?ref_src=embed">[image or embed]</a></p>
<p>— Necro Felipe • Universo Nintendo (<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:5uw2zrybj37wnkkc5ku4fxyu?ref_src=embed">@necro.universonintendo.com</a>) <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:5uw2zrybj37wnkkc5ku4fxyu/post/3lht5vqyzlp2x?ref_src=embed">February 10, 2025 at 1:37 PM</a></p></blockquote>

<p>Among the many things we still don't know about the Nintendo Switch 2 is how much the system will cost, as the Japanese company has not said much on the matter yet other than the fact that they are considering multiple factors for the system's price, including inflation, exchange rate and the price range that consumers expect for Nintendo products. As reported by <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/02/rumour-placeholder-retail-listing-suggests-switch-2-price-might-be-cheaper-than-expected">Nintendo Life</a>, according to two images showing Costco Canada's backend product listing and a printed sign with an obvious misspelling recently shared on the <a href="https://famiboards.com/threads/future-nintendo-hardware-technology-speculation-discussion-st-new-staff-post-please-read.55/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Famiiboards forums</a>, the console could cost 499 Canadian dollars, around 350 US dollars, which would be an excellent price for the system, although a direct conversion may not be very accurate, looking at the current Switch pricing in different regions.</p>
<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 will launch later this year worldwide. As already mentioned, the next look at the system will come during a dedicated Nintendo Direct scheduled for<a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-officially-revealed-with-a-new-trailer-dedicated-direct-confirmed-for-april/"> April 2nd.</a></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grand Theft Auto VI Could Lose Over 40% of Sales Skipping PC Release This Year; Game Will Meaningfully Drive Console Sales]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-skipping-pc-lose-40-sales/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grand-theft-auto-vi-could-lose-over-40-of-sales-skipping-pc-release-this-year-game-will-meaningfully-drive-console-sales.1104822/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-skipping-pc-lose-40-sales/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Grand Theft Auto VI skipping PC at launch could result in over 40% sales, according to Take-Two's CEO Strauss Zelnick.</p>
<p>Speaking with <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/take-two-boss-unconcerned-by-plummeting-ps5-and-xbox-sales-insists-gta-6-will-cause-a-meaningful-uptick-in-console-sales-in-2025">IGN</a> ahead of the publisher's <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-is-still-scheduled-to-release-this-fall-take-two-full-expects-to-support-the-nintendo-switch-2/">recent financial results</a> about the game skipping PC at launch, Zelnick essentially said that the highly-anticipated game will unsurprisingly eventually release on PC, highlighting that, historically, Rockstar has started with some platforms before moving on to others, so even a game as anticipated as the next entry in the popular series is not going to break this trend.</p>
<p>Still, PC sales make up a large amount of total sales for almost every multiplatform game, and it won't be any different for Grand Theft Auto VI, as, according to the Take-Two CEO, the PC version of any multiplatform game can generate over 40% of overall sales. On the other hand, launching on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X and S only is likely to drive console sales out of the current slump, as Zelnick believes this is what is going to happen this year with the release not only of GTA VI but of other games as well, even in the United States despite tariffs not making things any easier.</p>
<p>Grand Theft Auto VI is launching this Fall on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S worldwide. However, the game's ambitious scope could cause a delay, which wouldn't be the first for Rockstar Games.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>