<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 18:41:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dungeon Stalkers Final Beta Test Is Live Now on Steam]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/dungeon-stalkers-final-beta-test-is-live-now-on-steam/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dungeon-stalkers-final-beta-test-is-live-now-on-steam.1228347/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The third-person PvPvE dungeon crawler RPG Dungeon Stalkers is now hosting its final beta test ahead of its launch <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2468730/Dungeon_Stalkers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">on Steam</a>. Interested fans can simply join the playtest by requesting access via the store page.</p>
<p>This final beta, which will close on Tuesday, July 1st at 6:59 PM Pacific Time, includes the following improvements over previous test phases:</p>
<ul>
<li>New stalkers Liyan and Shinobu added (total 9 stalkers available)</li>
<li>Light extraction rule (no item loss upon death) implemented for quick match and PvE mode</li>
<li>New rune system that allows stalker growth</li>
<li>New Camp system that allows item crafting and upgrade</li>
<li>Stalker ultimates have been improved</li>
<li>Running is now available for a more enjoyable game experience</li>
<li>Kill camera and report system added</li>
</ul>
<p>In Dungeon Stalkers, players choose one of the nine playable characters, each with their own story, personality, and skills, and descend into the Witch's cursed dungeon. They can enter alone or with trusted companions in teams of up to three. As they explore, gather loot, and fight off corrupted monsters and rival Stalkers, their ultimate goal is to escape alive. But no two runs are alike due to the Witch's Curse system, which alters the dungeon conditions dynamically with each session, changing the odds and the challenges.</p>
<p>As characters take damage, this is visually represented by degraded armor, which enemy players can spot, adding tension and strategic depth as well as influencing how and when players engage in PvP combat. Two modes are available: a more casual PvE experience focused on fun or a hardcore, competitive PvPvE dungeon run.</p>
<p><iframe title="[Dungeon Stalkers] Developer gameplay test video" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GyjseQAix4Y?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The system requirements are very tame, as you can read below.</p>
<p><strong>Minimum:</strong><br>
OS: Windows 10 64-bit<br>
Processor: Intel Core i3-3225<br>
Memory: 8 GB RAM<br>
Graphics: NVIDIA GeForce GTX 1060<br>
DirectX: Version 12<br>
Network: Broadband Internet connection<br>
Storage: 10 GB available space</p>
<p><strong>Recommended:</strong><br>
OS: Windows 10 64-bit<br>
Processor: Intel Core i7-2700K<br>
Memory: 16 GB RAM<br>
Graphics: NVIDIA GeForce RTX 2060<br>
DirectX: Version 12<br>
Network: Broadband Internet connection<br>
Storage: 10 GB available space</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/dungeon-stalkers-final-beta-test-is-live-now-on-steam/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The FTC Will Send More Than $126 Million In Refunds To Players Over Unwanted Fortnite Purchases, Reopens Claims Process For Two More Weeks]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-ftc-will-send-more-than-126-million-in-refunds-to-players-over-unwanted-fortnite-purchases-reopens-claims-process-for-two-more-weeks/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-ftc-will-send-more-than-126-million-in-refunds-to-players-over-unwanted-fortnite-purchases-reopens-claims-process-for-two-more-weeks.1228245/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The FTC <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/news/press-releases/2025/06/ftc-sends-126-million-refunds-fortnite-players-who-were-charged-unwanted-items-reopens-claims?utm_source=govdelivery">announced today</a> that it will send refunds to players who made unwanted purchases in Fortnite, with the refunds totaling over $126 million. The agency will also reopen the process for players and their parents or guardians to make claims for further compensation from now until <strong>July 9, 2025</strong>.</p>
<p>This latest batch of refunds is a follow-up from the 629,344 refunds issued in <a href="https://wccftech.com/epic-games-users-refunds-are-being-issued-by-the-ftc-following-settlement-of-fortnite-case/">December 2024</a> over what the FTC described as "<em>deceptive</em>" practices from Epic that led to players making unwanted purchases in the first place.</p>
<p>While the agency disclosed the average refund amount in December to be $114 per person, it does not disclose what the average refund will be this time around, perhaps due to the fact that there's still time for people to submit claims. Beginning today, however, either through PayPal or a check, the FTC will begin delivering <strong>969,173</strong> refunds.</p>
<p>If you selected to receive a check on your claim form, the FTC recommends you cash it within 90 days. PayPal recipients should redeem their refund within 30 days.</p>
<p>Including today's batch of refunds, the FTC has now provided players with more than <strong>$200 million</strong> as part of the FTC's punitive action against Epic Games.</p>
<p>This claims process began in <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/news/press-releases/2023/09/ftc-announces-claims-process-fortnite-players-who-were-charged-unwanted-items">September 2023</a> and is part of the $245 million Epic was fined for its practices regarding microtransactions in Fortnite. The first claims process lasted from September 2023 to January 2024, though if you missed that window, you now have an extra two weeks to get your cut of the refunds from Epic Games.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/the-ftc-will-send-more-than-126-million-in-refunds-to-players-over-unwanted-fortnite-purchases-reopens-claims-process-for-two-more-weeks/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>