<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 19:53:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Soldier Of Fortune RTX Remix Path Tracing Mod Breathes New Life Into Classic Shooter]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/soldier-of-fortune-rtx-remix-path-tracing-mod/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-soldier-of-fortune-rtx-remix-path-tracing-mod-breathes-new-life-into-classic-shooter.1347319/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>The original Soldier of Fortune was a Raven Software title that was released on PC in the year 2000, and if you look at gameplay from the original title, it's a clear showcase of just how far we've come since those days. However, thanks to modder 'Pathtraced Paradise,' a new RTX Remix mod currently in development breathes new path-traced life into the classic first-person shooter.</p>



<p>Spotted by <a href="https://www.dsogaming.com/videotrailer-news/take-a-look-at-this-soldier-of-fortune-rtx-remix-path-tracing-mod/">DSOGaming</a>, the modder currently has YouTube videos uploaded of the first two levels, though<a href="https://www.moddb.com/mods/solider-of-fortune-rtx-remix-mod-wip-demo"> files for the tutorial and first three levels have been compiled so far</a>. It is still a work-in-progress, though, so you'll have to wait for Pathtraced Paradise to finish developing the mod to play the whole game in this new light. There's currently no download link available for the mod.</p>



<p>That said, what they've shared of the first two levels already looks like strong work, as you can see from the videos below.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Soldier of Fortune (2000) - RTX Remix Mod - Level 1 Playthrough" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-wBXc-_Tdw0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>It's always fun to see old games like Soldier of Fortune get another chance at life with mods like this, which easily make going back to classic titles a much more enjoyable experience than they otherwise would be if you had to deal with the original graphical settings.</p>



<p>Other recent RTX remix mods that added path-tracing to older games include <a href="https://wccftech.com/max-payne-2-rtx-remix-path-tracing-soon/">a recent Max Payne 2 mod that looks incredible</a>, a <a href="https://wccftech.com/take-look-path-traced-gta-4-rtx-remix-test-build/">Grand Theft Auto IV RTX remix mod</a>, and an <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-elder-scrolls-iii-morrowind-path-tracing-rtx-remix/">Elder Scrolls III: Morrowind path-tracing mod</a>.</p>



<p>There's also path-tracing mods worth checking out <a href="https://wccftech.com/fallout-new-vegas-rtx-mod-path-tracing/">for Fallout: New Vegas</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/half-life-remake-black-mesa-path-tracing-30-fps-rtx-5080/">the Half-Life remake, Black Mesa</a>. Also, it should be noted that the same creator behind the aforementioned GTA IV path-tracing mod has made successful path-tracing mods for <a href="https://wccftech.com/call-of-duty-4-rtx-remix-path-tracing-mod/">Call of Duty 4: Modern Warfare</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/portal-2-rtx-remix-path-tracing-mod/">Portal 2</a>, and <a href="https://wccftech.com/left-4-dead-2-path-tracing-rtx-5080-obliterates-performance/">Left 4 Dead 2</a>.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Soldier of Fortune - RTX Remix Mod - Level 2 Playthrough" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5mpNe2XJCgk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>There's unfortunately no word on when Pathtraced Paradise will be done modding the rest of the game, but at least for now, these videos provide a sneak peek at what we can look forward to, especially considering the fact that these aren't even representative of what the mod will look like when it's finished.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/soldier-of-fortune-rtx-remix-path-tracing-mod/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anonymous Rockstar Employee Says There Were No Leaks and the Layoffs Were Indeed Union Busting]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/anonymous-rockstar-employee-says-there-were-no-leaks-layoffs-union-busting/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/anonymous-rockstar-employee-says-there-were-no-leaks-and-the-layoffs-were-indeed-union-busting.1347253/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>After Grand Theft Auto and Red Dead Redemption developer Rockstar fired 30-40 employees, the studio <a href="https://wccftech.com/gta-developer-accused-union-busting-after-firing-dozens-of-employees/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">was accused of union busting by the Independent Workers Union of Great Britain</a>. Rockstar denied the accusations through a spokesperson and maintained that these employees <a href="https://wccftech.com/rockstar-says-fired-gta-developers-had-been-leaking-information/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">had leaked information on a public forum</a>.</p>



<p>The latest chapter of the story saw an anonymous employee of the award-winning game development studio <a href="https://gtaforums.com/topic/1004182-rockstar-games-alleged-union-busting/?do=findComment&amp;comment=1072605777" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">write a lengthy post on GTAForums</a>, the biggest public forum dedicated to the series of best-selling open world videogames. This poster's identity was allegedly verified by a moderator at GTAForums.</p>



<p>In the post, this employee claims that the fired workers were practically ambushed by the HR department, which called them over 'for a quick chat' and then handed a termination letter accusing them of misconduct related to Discord discussions, but provided no evidence or further details about the supposed offense. Those physically present were reportedly forced out within minutes. Others who were not at the office received a brisk phone call of less than two minutes and were notified that they would receive the aforementioned letter. Some of them were sick, even recovering from surgery, or on family leave, and this sudden termination leaves them financially vulnerable.</p>



<p>The anonymous employee adds that Rockstar fired critical staff, such as leads, artists, designers, programmers, and producers, many of whom had long tenures and clean records at the studio. Moreover, he counters the official statement, clarifying that the Discord channel in question was strictly for employee and union discussions about working conditions, not for game leaks; all those who got terminated were union members. The timing, the employee says, was clearly aimed at sabotaging union recognition, just as the union group had reached the size needed to initiate formal negotiations for better pay and working conditions.</p>



<p>The post concludes with a warning that if Rockstar gets away with this, it may do it again without facing repercussions. The employee also urges fans to support the fired workers by making a donation <a href="https://actionnetwork.org/fundraising/support-rockstar-workers-fighting-unfair-dismissals/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">via the Action Network</a>.</p>



<p>The controversy arises in the same week that brought us to yesterday, when Rockstar announced the second delay of Grand Theft Auto VI, <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-6-delayed-to-november-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">now slated for release on November 19, 2026</a>.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/anonymous-rockstar-employee-says-there-were-no-leaks-layoffs-union-busting/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Thrasher, The Follow-Up From The Artist and Composer Behind Thumper, Is Now Out On Steam]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/thumper-follow-up-thrasher-makes-steam-debut-vr-non-vr/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/thrasher-the-follow-up-from-the-artist-and-composer-behind-thumper-is-now-out-on-steam.1347193/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Thumper is an intense rhythm game loved by VR and non-VR fans alike, for its soundtrack, incredible lighting, and engaging gameplay. It's also nearly a decade old, but in the meantime, artist and composer behind Thumper, Brian Gibson, hasn't been sitting on his hands. Gibson, alongside Mike Mandel under their new developer label, Puddle, released a follow-up to Thumper titled Thrasher in July 2024.</p>



<p>The only problem with Thrasher is that when it arrived last July, it was only available as a VR title for Meta Quest and Apple Vision Pro users. That's officially changed, however, with Thrasher making its Steam debut today, November 7, 2025. It's playable in PC VR, but non-VR users will be happy to know it is also playable as a regular-old flatscreen game.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="THRASHER Steam Release Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ilm63FtWc4U?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Unsurprisingly, it's another cornucopia of lights and sounds blending to create what could be just as transcendent an audiovisual experience as Thumper before it. There's no indication yet if Thrasher will come to Xbox consoles as a flatscreen game and to PlayStation as a flatscreen and VR game with PS VR2, but with the bulk of the work done to make Thrasher work as a flatscreen game for PC, hopefully, those ports are on the horizon.</p>



<p>In the meantime, players on PC can jump into the 27 levels in Thrasher across its nine main stages and three game modes, and if you're already a fan of Gibson's work (and you have Thumper in your Steam library), <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2702300/view/595164831678464806?l=english">then you're entitled to a special discount on Thrasher</a>. If not, then no need to fret as the game is also available at a 10% launch discount for a limited time.</p>



<p>If you're looking for more games like Thumper and Thrasher, then keep your eyes peeled for <a href="https://wccftech.com/lumines-arise-hands-on-sgf-2025-impressions/">Lumines Arise, which Wccftech's Kai Tatsumoto got to preview at this year's Summer Game Fest</a>.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/thumper-follow-up-thrasher-makes-steam-debut-vr-non-vr/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>