<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 18:18:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Splash Damage Enters Consultation Process Impacting All Staff, More Layoffs Incoming]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/splash-damage-enters-consultation-process-impacting-all-staff-layoffs/</link>
            <guid>1365655</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>A short two months after <a href="https://wccftech.com/developer-splash-damage-no-longer-owned-by-tencent-acquired-by-private-equity-investors/">it was acquired by an unnamed private equity group</a>, veteran support studio Splash Damage has announced it has entered a consultation process that will impact all staff members. While all current staff could potentially be laid off, it's unclear at the time of this writing how many will be impacted.</p>



<p>"<em>Today we announced to our teams that we are entering a studio-wide consultation process affecting all roles</em>," a post on the <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/splash-damage_an-update-from-splash-damage-activity-7399486098588196864-pz0I/">studio's LinkedIn page began</a>. "<em>This was a difficult step for us to take, but we believe it is necessary so Splash Damage can remain agile and adaptable in what has been a very challenging market. We know this kind of change is emotionally tough, and we will do what we can to guide our people through this process with honesty and care. We're committed to exploring every option to retain talent and making sure those affected have meaningful support throughout</em>."</p>



<p>After quietly pulling away from its previous parent company in September, Tencent, though the studio's future was unclear, there was a bit of a sense that it could fare better away from Tencent than under it. Now, however, it's clear that's not the case, and if the consultation process wraps up before the end of the year, <a href="https://wccftech.com/splash-damage-ends-development-of-transformers-reactivate-lays-off-staff/">it'll be the studio's second layoff in 2025</a>.</p>



<p>Since 2020, Splash Damage has only been able to ship one game, Outcasters, which launched and died with Google Stadia. It supported games like Star Wars Hunters and Gears Tactics, but has been unable to get a game over the finish line since Outcasters. Its last major project, Transformers: Reactivate, was cancelled, which led to the layoffs in January 2025. </p>



<p>It's unfortunate to see Splash Damage struggle like so many other studios, especially because if this does end with the studio essentially shutting down, it'll be the latest veteran studio to be killed off. Splash Damage has been around for 20 years now, and that kind of staying power isn't easy to obtain. </p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/splash-damage-enters-consultation-process-impacting-all-staff-layoffs/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PS Plus Essential Subs Get Five Games for December 2025, Including Neon White and LEGO Horizon Adventures]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ps-plus-essential-five-games-december-2025-lego-horizon-adventures-neon-white/</link>
            <guid>1365562</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Since the beginning of the PlayStation Plus subscription service, one of the baseline features has always been that subscribers get three free games with their subscription every month. Now, under the new system, that feature has stayed for all subscribers, though players at the higher PS Plus Extra and Premium tiers get more than just three games per month. For December 2025, PlayStation has added two more games for PS Plus Essential subscribers as a holiday treat.</p>



<p>Announced in a <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/11/26/playstation-plus-monthly-games-for-december-lego-horizon-adventures-killing-floor-3-the-outlast-trials-more/">PlayStation Blog post,</a> next month players subscribed to PS Plus Essential (and higher) will be able to add five games to their library of PS Plus games, including two games that were released this year with Killing Floor 3 and Synduality Echo of Ada, and three major 2024 releases with The Outlast Trials, Neon White, and LEGO Horizon Adventures.</p>



<p>"<em>To mark the year’s end and to start the holiday celebrations early, we’re pleased to make December’s PlayStation Plus Monthly Games lineup a special one, with additional bonus titles available to PS Plus members* in select regions</em>," writes Adam Michel, director of game services and content at Sony. </p>


<figure>
<div>

<figure>
<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/67c829ffb3a8e09228068c8b23a0e4b7b31169ec.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image credit: PlayStation</em></figcaption></figure>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/0c042b28e730042fb6f86cef73e5824f602c9a24.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image credit: Angel Matrix</em></figcaption></figure>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/c8e5638f175f8fcf23f3560de40421f54b619324.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image credit: Red Barrels</em></figcaption></figure>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/d6c452c6d1f9816acfcc3a270d631e2b24123ec0.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image credit: Bandai Namco</em></figcaption></figure>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/b2fd40a318959bbc6f39a3816bd6c7aa65c19e22.png"></a><figcaption><em>Image credit: Tripwire Interactive</em></figcaption></figure>
</figure>
<div>
				    		
				    		
					    	<p><span>2 of 9</span>
				    	</p></div>
</div>
</figure>



<p>All five games will be available for players to add to their libraries on December 2, 2025, which means that December 1 will be the last day for players to add the November 2025 games to their library: Stray, EA Sports WRC 24, and Totally Accurate Battle Simulator (TABS).</p>



<p>With Essential-tier players getting two extra games, it'll be interesting to see if there's a similar treat in store for Extra and Premium-tier subscribers. November 2025 was a highlight month for Extra-tier players, with games like <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-v-pacific-drive-still-wakes-the-deep-ps-plus-extra-game-catalog-november-2025/">Grand Theft Auto V, Pacific Drive, and Thank Goodness You're Here all in the lineup</a>. Hopefully, there's something special prepared for the lineup of Extra and Premium games for December 2025.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/ps-plus-essential-five-games-december-2025-lego-horizon-adventures-neon-white/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>