<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 07:34:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Gameplay Trailer Drops for Lost Skies, Showcasing Floating Islands & More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/new-gameplay-trailer-drops-for-lost-skies-showcasing-floating-islands-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-gameplay-trailer-drops-for-lost-skies-showcasing-floating-islands-more.1099077/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/new-gameplay-trailer-drops-for-lost-skies-showcasing-floating-islands-more/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A new trailer has been released by Bossa Games and Humble Games for Lost Skies, an <a href="https://wccftech.com/lost-skies-is-an-open-world-co-op-game-based-on-worlds-adrift/">open-world cooperative PvE survival game</a> that takes place among floating islands. This game will be available during February's Steam Next Fest, where players will get to take part in a multiplayer demo. The demo is expansive, offering players the opportunity to play five to six hours of the game. Lost Skies is home to ancient ruins that can be explored, a fully customizable skyship, and intricate puzzles that need to be solved. If this sounds like something you're interested in, you can choose to play the game on your own and go solo, or you can team up with up to six friends. Check out the gameplay trailer below to see what you can expect from Lost Skies.</p>
<p><iframe title="Lost Skies: Cinematic Trailer | Bossa Studios ☁️" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zVgbYFWSOZ0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Instead of building a base on a planet or island, you have your very own Skyship that you can customize and evolve over time. You get to take your base around the world with you as you explore, helping you explore safely and gather any resources you may need. It will also help keep you safe against the elements and threats in the skies.</p>
<p>Compared to other survival games, Lost Skies is considered a "Survival Lite," allowing you to get to grips with the survival elements of the game without feeling like you're punished for not doing things in a certain order or grinding materials off the bat.</p>
<p>There will be tons to explore, from ruins, ancient civilizations, and colossal creatures that you will have to take down. There will be plenty of variety across the many floating islands in the sky, where you can use a grappling hook to interact with the world around you, also providing you with a way to traverse and soar through the sky.</p>
<p>If this game sounds like something you're interested in, you can <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1931180/Lost_Skies/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wishlist the title on Steam now</a> or try out the free-to-play <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2102670/Lost_Skies_Island_Creator/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Island Creator</a>, where you can design your very own floating island that can be played. You can create your own island full of puzzles, traps, and stories. It's entirely up to you how you decorate and create your island, and it can then be released to other players via the Steam Workshop.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy VII: Rebirth Had Great Steam Launch, Best-Selling Game of the Week Ending Jan 25]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-had-great-steam-launch-best-selling-game-of-the-week-ending-jan-25/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-had-great-steam-launch-best-selling-game-of-the-week-ending-jan-25.1099050/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-had-great-steam-launch-best-selling-game-of-the-week-ending-jan-25/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>It's hardly surprising that Final Fantasy VII: Rebirth did well on Steam. Final Fantasy is a beloved series, with Final Fantasy VII being regarded as one of the best in the franchise. After being a PlayStation exclusive, it makes total sense that people would be scrambling to get the next iteration in the remake on Steam.</p>
<p>Three titles in the Final Fantasy VII remake have been released, with the remake of Crisis Core considered to be a spin-off rather than part of the main story of the remake. These are all relatively bulky games, with some major changes from the original story. It isn't a precise remake of the story, and adds in some new info as well as removing some from the original. Of course, this has left some fans feeling jilted about it, as a lot of fans were hoping for a faithful remake that was a copy of the original but with improved graphics and combat.</p>
<p>Despite that, across physical and tracked digital sales, Final Fantasy VII: Rebirth was the best-selling game of the week ending January 25 in the US market. Along with that, the Final Fantasy VII Remake &amp; Rebirth Twin Pack were ranked third in sales, as confirmed by <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:bhqrrxt7yyfpwguioa7rwa7x/post/3lhc3xrqq7k2z?ref_src=embed" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mat Piscatella on Bluesky</a>.</p>
<p>This is good news for Square Enix, and it helps solidify their decision to move away from releasing exclusive games. The company found that by doing so, it <a href="https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-xvi-underperformed-disappointing-profits/">lost out on a lot of revenue and buzz</a> for the titles than it would have if it had been released on <a href="https://wccftech.com/square-enix-unveils-new-business-plan-with-aggressive-multiplatform-strategy-and-quality-over-quantity-focus/">multiple platforms</a>. Since the release of both Final Fantasy VII: Rebirth and Final Fantasy 16, Square Enix has stated that it will be shifting away from console exclusives and trying to release the titles on as many platforms as possible.</p>
<p>While these titles are now available on both PC and PlayStation 5, it's left fans on both Nintendo Switch and Xbox wondering if the titles will ever be released for those consoles. A release for Xbox is likely, but considering the hardware of the Nintendo Switch, it seems a bit more unlikely that it would be released for the Switch. However, anything is possible, and the ball is entirely in Square Enix's court.</p>
<p>The information from Piscatella helps reaffirm that Final Fantasy VII: Rebirth did sell well and did better than people were thinking, as the CCUs on Steam suggested that the game didn't do as well as people thought, as it reached approximately 40k at the peak of the release. The CCU did go down but stayed consistently above 20k, with the 24-hour peak being 31k.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>