<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 21:56:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South of Midnight – Where To Find All Notes – Chapter 10]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/how-to/south-of-midnight-where-to-find-all-notes-chapter-10/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/south-of-midnight-%E2%80%93-where-to-find-all-notes-%E2%80%93-chapter-10.1170810/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/how-to/south-of-midnight-where-to-find-all-notes-chapter-10/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>There are more than 100 notes to find in <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/south-of-midnight-boring-combat-drags-down-a-beautiful-and-emotional-story/">South of Midnight</a>, and it's worth your time to seek out all of them beyond just doing it to get the achievement.</p>
<p>Arguably, the storytelling in South of Midnight is its strongest aspect, and each note adds strong context to the storytelling that would otherwise be missed. Of course, you can still have a great time with the story if you didn't find all of them, but the experience is so much more enhanced if you do.</p>
<p>This guide will show you where to find all of the notes hidden in Chapter 10.</p>
<h2>South of Midnight - Where To Find All Notes - Chapter 10</h2>
<p>Thankfully, it's easy to clear all the notes in Chapter 10 as there are only five to find.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p><strong>Hope's Crossing Homecoming</strong> - Soon after the first combat encounter of the level, you'll reach a point where you'll see a hole for Crouton to enter to your right. Go left instead, and you'll find this note and a Floof knot waiting for you.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p><strong>Sleep and Smoke</strong> - After Crouton grabs your first Spindle, grapple across the gap and stick to the right past some exploding mushrooms. This note will be on the wall as blue art in the broken house.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p><strong>A Close Call</strong> - After interacting with the first firefly tree, follow the strands left and see a set of echo stairs to enter an old house. Enter the house and you'll find this note on the wall to your right.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p><strong>A Grand Wedding</strong> - From the first firefly tree, go right and turn right again when you reach a bushel of exploding bramble. Directly ahead, you should see a grapple point leading to a broken-down house, where you'll find this note on the wall on the left.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p><strong>The Flower Child</strong> - Once you're inside Honey's home, you'll find this final note on the back wall of his cave.</p>
<p>That's where all five notes are found in Chapter 10. What's especially helpful here is that most of these notes are on the main path anyway; you just have to pay attention to the walls around you as they're all notes in the form of the blue art that's seen throughout South of Midnight.</p>
<p>If you've followed along with the rest of these guides, then you'll have found 74 notes out of 103. Only 29 more to go.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aloft Surpasses 200K Sales In Early Access, Celebrates With Earth Day Initiative]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/aloft-surpasses-200k-sales-in-early-access-celebrates-with-earth-day-initiative/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/aloft-surpasses-200k-sales-in-early-access-celebrates-with-earth-day-initiative.1170744/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/aloft-surpasses-200k-sales-in-early-access-celebrates-with-earth-day-initiative/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Astrolabe Interactive announced that the studio's co-op sandbox survival game <a href="https://wccftech.com/aloft-by-astrolabe-interactive-scheduled-to-launch-into-early-access-on-january-15th/">Aloft</a> has surpassed 200,000 copies sold in early access since its launch in January 2025.</p>
<p>Astrolabe has partnered with <a href="https://www.coolearth.org/act-now/stream-for-cool-earth/">Cool Earth</a> to celebrate the milestone and will donate 5% of the revenue it earned during the Earth Appreciation Festival on Steam to the Cool Earth Initiative. Astrolabe and Cool Earth are also working with content creators and streamers to stream Aloft today, livestreaming the game in charity streams, and the proceeds will also go to the Cool Earth Initiative.</p>
<p>Cool Earth is an organization working to protect the world's rainforests and support the indigenous peoples who have been living and working with them, instead of against them, for generations.</p>
<p>In a press release, Astrolabe's creative director, Manuel Bergeron, discussed how Cool Earth's work and Earth Day directly relate to what Astrolabe wanted players to learn when playing Aloft.</p>
<p>"<em><span data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">One of our goals in Aloft was to offer a chance for players to learn about the fragile balance of ecosystems and have a direct positive impact on their environment</span>. <span data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">It's our honor to contribute to the environment by giving to the Cool Earth Initiative.</span></em>"</p>
<p>Aloft's first major update in early access, Critters and Wonders, launched this past March. According to the studio's <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1660080/view/543345713449272665?l=english">roadmap</a> for 2025, more major content updates and plenty of feature improvements are planned for the year, though specific release dates or windows around when that'll be have yet to be announced.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>