<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 08:48:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Path of Exile 2 Early Access Date Gets Pushed Back by Three Weeks]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/path-of-exile-2-early-access-date-gets-pushed-back-by-three-weeks/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/path-of-exile-2-early-access-date-gets-pushed-back-by-three-weeks.1021683/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/path-of-exile-2-early-access-date-gets-pushed-back-by-three-weeks/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Grinding Gear Games has announced a slight delay to the early access date of Path of Exile 2. The sequel to the highly popular free-to-play hack 'n' slash action RPG will now debut on December 6 instead of November 15 as previously <a href="https://wccftech.com/path-of-exile-2-early-access-on-november-15/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">revealed</a> at Gamescom 2024.</p>
<p>Game Director Jonathan Rogers <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V2zus8ux73s" target="_blank" rel="noopener">shared</a> the news in a brief video message and explained that it was caused by server-side shortcomings:</p>
<p><em>I'm really sorry about this one. People plan time off around our launches, but we just have to do it. So what happened? Well, it turns out it isn't really the game itself that we're behind on. It's a bunch of server side infrastructure work that has taken us a lot longer than we expected.</em></p>
<p><em>One of the key promises we made is that all your microtransactions will work across both Path of Exile 1 and 2. In order to do that, we have to integrate the account systems for not only Path of Exile 1 and 2 but also for the console realms as well. This meant changing a lot of things. Not only do we have to create a bunch of new systems, we have to make sure that only old data is backwards compatible with them as well.</em></p>
<p><em>When you start migrating databases that are this old and with this much data, you find all sorts of strange demons in there. How do multiple accounts get the same name? How do multiple accounts get the same email address? How do multiple accounts have the same steam IDs? Why is this person’s account name just random gibberish that doesn't even decode? We have to get everything perfect so that nobody loses anything they paid for and nobody has their account broken.</em></p>
<p><em>At the same time, because we're changing all this back-end code, we have to do a lot of load testing to make sure the whole thing doesn’t fall over when they could get the huge number of players that we're expecting at the Path of Exile 2 early access launch. I actually believe that we could possibly have made the original date, but I'm no longer confident we could do it without making mistakes, and these are the kind of mistakes we just can't let happen. With that in mind, we've decided to delay.</em></p>
<p>Rogers ended the message with news of an upcoming live stream that will delve deeply into everything that's going to be in the early access launch. The Game Director said it's going to be like the biggest League announcement they have ever done, and he added he's looking forward to sharing information on the endgame content players will find in Path of Exile 2.</p>
<p>For our impressions of the game, check out <a href="https://wccftech.com/path-of-exile-2-gamescom-hands-on-preview-improvements-aplenty/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this Gamescom hands-on preview</a>.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marathon Gets Small Developer Update from Bungie, Confirming Expanded Playtesting and Upcoming News in 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/marathon-gets-small-developer-update-from-bungie-confirming-expanded-playtesting-and-upcoming-news-in-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marathon-gets-small-developer-update-from-bungie-confirming-expanded-playtesting-and-upcoming-news-in-2025.1021500/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/marathon-gets-small-developer-update-from-bungie-confirming-expanded-playtesting-and-upcoming-news-in-2025/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, Bungie <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r8WgMQuPwRE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">shared</a> a small video developer update for their <a href="https://wccftech.com/marathon-bungie-ps5-xbox-pc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">upcoming extraction shooter</a> based on the sci-fi Marathon IP. <a href="https://wccftech.com/marathon-directed-valorant-director/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">New Game Director</a> Joe Ziegler (who previously worked on The Saboteur at Pandemic and Valorant at Riot) talked a bit about how the game is going to work:</p>
<p><em>We give you a lot of different tools to do a lot of different things inside the game. There is a ton of loot that you can find: weapons, equipment that you can equip that changes your stats or tweaks some of the things that you can do inside the game. There are utility consumables akin to mines or grenades, and there are even consumables to heal yourself and give you utility in that way.</em></p>
<p><em>Beyond that, there is also another layer: Runners. They are the template by which you equip all that stuff to. Each Runner has a small subset of abilities and on top of that, you get to customize however you want, thinking about what you want to accomplish. You might equip different types of gear to your Runner and then go on those runs with that gear in mind.</em></p>
<p><em>There's a lot of different ways a Marathon session can unfold with all those different pieces. There are also many objectives and things like that that exist inside the game. But of course, every single one comes with its own risk. And the risk is always present that if you don't get out alive, you will lose the things that you have on you.</em></p>
<p>In the latter half of the video, Ziegler said that Bungie has collaborated with some players and creators to iterate on the game over the past two years. Next year, fans can expect to learn a lot more about the game toward the middle of the year, likely during the regular May PlayStation Showcase. In 2025, Marathon will also greatly expand its player testing with each new milestone.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Windows Home Experience Is Available for Xbox Insiders]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/new-windows-home-experience-is-available-for-xbox-insiders/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-windows-home-experience-is-available-for-xbox-insiders.1021437/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/new-windows-home-experience-is-available-for-xbox-insiders/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Those who are signed up as an Xbox Insider will now have the opportunity to experience the new Windows Home experience in the <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-cloud-gaming-to-let-you-stream-your-own-games-next-month/">Xbox app</a>. It features a lot of changes and brings forward a new design that shows off the top games on Game Pass and Store tabs, as well as providing you with new games, news, and curated recommendations. For those who may not be able to splurge on new games, it also shows off free-to-play content for those looking for a new experience and game to play but don't want to sink any money into it.</p>
<p>This new experience comes after months of listening to feedback and trying out different designs internally. They have made this new Windows Home experience for Xbox Insiders to test out, hoping to make a faster and easier Xbox app on Windows, allowing those who utilize it to jump between Game Pass and Microsoft Store with ease and without having to flip between tabs constantly.</p>
<p>Walking through the highlights of the new Home experience, the main part is the featured content. This provides an at-a-glance view of upcoming game releases, events, and content that is available via Game Pass and sales. Alongside this, you'll be able to get the latest deals and discounts available to peruse, showing you the best deals and discounts on offer so that you don't have to pay full price for games and new experiences.</p>
<p>Additionally, there will now be curated collections and recommendations for you based on what games you've played previously. The games shown to you will include games from both Game Pass and the Store, depending on which way you prefer to access your games.</p>
<p>Microsoft has also added a 'Jump Back In' feature as part of the Game Pass tab experience. This features allows players in Compact Mode to click on a game card and will send them directly to the game hub, where you can press play and jump back into the game seamlessly. This feature has been in testing since May, and is now available as part of the new Home experience for all Xbox Insiders.</p>
<p>While it isn't widely available for those who aren't Xbox Insiders at the moment, you can join the Xbox Insider Program by downloading the <a href="https://support.xbox.com/en-US/help/account-profile/manage-account/xbox-insider-program" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Xbox Insider Hub</a>, which will give you access to new features and previews that Microsoft are working on to improve the Xbox experience.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>