<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 03:52:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2 Has Reportedly Sold Over 20M Copies, Most of Them on Steam]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/helldivers-2-has-reportedly-sold-over-20m-copies-most-of-them-on-steam/</link>
            <guid>1421398</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>If <strong>PlayStation</strong> needed another sign that its current push to put its first-party made and published games on both PC and <strong>PS5</strong> was a good idea, it certainly has it with the latest report from <a href="https://alineaanalytics.substack.com/p/helldivers-2-sells-20m-copies">Alinea Analytics</a>, which claims that the popular third-person shooter <strong>Helldivers 2</strong> has sold <strong>over 20 million copies</strong>, most of them coming from PC players on Steam.</p>



<p>When Helldivers 2 launched, despite its connectivity issues <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/helldivers-2-not-enough-patriotism/">that hindered the experience</a> and the controversy regarding <a href="https://wccftech.com/sony-cancels-mandatory-helldivers-2-psn-account-linking-update/">PC players initially being mandated to connect their PlayStation Network accounts to their Steam accounts to play the game</a>, it was immediately the standout hit multiplayer game of 2024. </p>



<p>It skyrocketed to the top of Steam's charts, and even though it hasn't sustained the same level of popularity it had two years ago, it has successfully carved its own dedicated community out of the swath of multiplayer games people can choose to play. Alinea Analytics even adds that in December 2025, Helldivers 2 had <strong>3.6 million monthly active users</strong> across PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X/S.</p>



<p>After Helldivers 2 arrived on PC and PS5 at launch, <a href="https://wccftech.com/helldivers-2-coming-to-xbox-summer/">it came to Xbox Series X/S consoles in summer 2025</a>, and <a href="https://wccftech.com/halo-coming-to-playstation-helldivers-2-warbond/">even ushered in the first instance of Halo coming to PlayStation</a> through a Halo and Helldivers 2 crossover, before <a href="https://wccftech.com/halo-remake-halo-campaign-evolved-coming-to-pc-xbox-ps5-2026/">Halo was actually announced as coming to PlayStation</a>.</p>



<p>So far, Helldivers 2 has sold <strong>1.6 million copies on Xbox</strong>, <strong>5.6 million copies on PS5,</strong> and the remaining <strong>13.1 million on PC</strong>. According to Alinea Analytics, it has generated over <strong>$700 million in revenue</strong> for developer <strong>Arrowhead Studios</strong> and publisher <strong>PlayStation Studios</strong>.</p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Helldivers-2-Sales-Alinea-Analytics.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image credit: Alinea Analytics</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>The game is nothing but a roaring success, and as Arrowhead continues to update it with new content, it's likely that we're due for a spike in Helldivers 2 popularity from a new expansion, similar to what the <a href="https://wccftech.com/helldivers-2-into-the-unjust-update/"><strong>Into the Unjust</strong> update</a> did for it last year. Though the most recent update to get excited about was exclusively for PC players, as <strong>Sony's </strong>internal PC porting house, <strong>Nixxes</strong>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/helldivers-2-install-size-on-pc-shrinks-by-85-percent-thanks-to-nixxes/">figured out how to shrink the game's install size by <strong>85%</strong>, freeing up a lot of storage space on players' SSDs</a>.</p>



<p>Interestingly, as far as previously console-exclusive third-person shooters go, when comparing how <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/gears-of-war-reloaded-surpasses-1-million-players-three-days-after-launch/">Gears of War Reloaded</a></strong> did on PS5 versus Helldivers 2 on Xbox, <a href="https://wccftech.com/helldivers-2-xbox-sells-more-gears-of-war-reloaded-ps5/">Helldivers 2 is the clear winner, selling more on Xbox than Gears of War has done on PS5</a>.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/helldivers-2-has-reportedly-sold-over-20m-copies-most-of-them-on-steam/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>