<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 16:16:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[European Gamers Spend More on Microtransactions than North Americans, says Newzoo, but they’re also More Likely to Buy Something on Sale]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/newzoo-tebex-european-gamers-spend-more-on-microtransactions-north-american/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/european-gamers-spend-more-on-microtransactions-than-north-americans-says-newzoo-but-they%E2%80%99re-also-more-likely-to-buy-something-on-sale.1268127/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://newzoo.com/">Newzoo</a>, the global data firm for videogame industry sales has collaborated with <a href="https://www.tebex.io/">Tebex</a>, a monetization platform that videogame studios use for in-game purchases to publish a report that dives into player spending in North America and Europe. </p>



<p>The <em><a href="https://newzoo.com/resources/trend-reports/newzoo-tebex-unlocking-games-revenue-player-behavior-and-payment-trends">Unlocking Games Revenue: Player Behavior and Payment Trends in the West</a></em> report has more than a few interesting revelations about player spending in North America and Europe, like how players in those two regions are the minority of the world's gamers but <a href="https://wccftech.com/20-of-worlds-gamers-drive-nearly-half-global-gaming-spend-north-america-europe-newzoo/">drive nearly half of all spending in the videogame industry</a>.</p>



<p>But the videogame industry is not what it was 20 years ago, where spending trends would be mostly based on players buying individual games. Microtransactions are the name of today's game in the modern videogame landscape, and there are some interesting differences between North American players spending on microtransactions versus European players.</p>



<p>At a top-level look, players in Europe spend on microtransactions than players in North America, with sports games being the top genre in Europe, while shooters are the top genre in North America. "<em>Microtransactions make up nearly half of PC and one-third of console gam revenues in Europe</em>," according to Newzoo and Tebex.</p>



<figure><figcaption>Image credit: Newzoo and Tebex</figcaption></figure>



<p>In both North America and in Europe, however, consoles are the only platforms where premium game purchases still account for over 50% of player spending. </p>



<figure><figcaption>Image credit: Newzoo and Tebex</figcaption></figure>



<p>But when it comes to why players are spending their hard-earned cash, the reason for hitting the 'buy now' button is very different for players in North America and players in Europe. 28% of European players, according to Newzoo and Tebex, will choose to spend their money in the videogame industry if something is on sale or at what they deem to be a 'good price.' Whereas North American players top reason for buying anything is so that it gives them access to extra or exclusive playable content.</p>



<p>Buying something because it's on sale is the fifth of the top-five reasons listed for North America.</p>



<figure><figcaption>Image credit: Newzoo and Tebex</figcaption></figure>



<p>As far as what microtransactions players are buying in North America and Europe, however, those lists are much closer. Four out of the top five categories of in-game microtransaction purchases are the same between North American and European players, with players in both regions prioritizing expansions, power-ups, in-game currencies, and in-game subscriptions.</p>



<p>Loot boxes or gacha, as they're listed by Newzoo and Tebex, are at the bottom of the list for both North America and Europe, but that feels at least slightly misleading, since it seemingly means loot boxes purchased directly with real money, rather than a player buying an in-game currency to then spend on loot boxes.</p>



<p>For all the new statistics and bits of information shared in Newzoo and Tebex's report, one element that isn't news to anyone is, to the chagrin of some players, microtransactions and virtual currencies are not going anywhere, anytime soon.</p>



<p>"<em>Virtual currencies and microtransactions are no longer just revenue streams</em>," writes Liam Wiltshire, head of payments and compliance at Tebex. "<em>They're becoming strategic levers for retention and differentiation</em>."</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/newzoo-tebex-european-gamers-spend-more-on-microtransactions-north-american/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[20% of the World’s Gamers Drive “Nearly Half of Global Gaming Spend,” says Newzoo, with those Players Annually Spending $325M on Average]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/20-of-worlds-gamers-drive-nearly-half-global-gaming-spend-north-america-europe-newzoo/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/20-of-the-world%E2%80%99s-gamers-drive-%E2%80%9Cnearly-half-of-global-gaming-spend-%E2%80%9D-says-newzoo-with-those-players-annually-spending-325m-on-average.1268046/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A new report from global data firm <a href="https://newzoo.com/">Newzoo</a>, created in collaboration with Tebex, a monetization platform that videogame studios use for in-game spending, has a few major revelations based on data collected in the past six months on the modern gaming landscape about the spending habits of gamers. </p>



<p>The report, titled, <em><a href="https://newzoo.com/resources/trend-reports/newzoo-tebex-unlocking-games-revenue-player-behavior-and-payment-trends">Unlocking Games Revenue: Player Behavior and Payment Trends in the West</a></em>, shares that according to Newzoo's findings, North American and European gamers spend an annual average of $325 million on videogames per year. All that spending comes from only 20% of the global videogaming population, or as Newzoo puts it, "<em>A small share of players, a large share of spend</em>."</p>



<p>Newzoo also predicts that the global videogame market will balloon to $188.9 billion, with 46% of that spending coming from North America and Europe.</p>



<figure><figcaption>Image credit: Newzoo and Tebex</figcaption></figure>



<p>For clarification, as you can see in the graph below, Newzoo defines a player in this case as "<em>All people who play (digital) games on a PC, console, mobile device, or cloud gaming service in the past six months</em>." Another interesting tidbit that's not in the least bit surprising if you're even remotely aware of how most people play videogames nowadays, is that there are way more mobile gamers than PC and console gamers. According to Newzoo, there are 930 million PC gamers, 653 million console gamers, and 2,945 million mobile gamers. Or, to say it another way, almost 3 billion mobile gamers.</p>



<figure><figcaption>Image credit: Newzoo and Tebex</figcaption></figure>



<p>But for all that spending, is there any growth to it? In North America, from 2023 and looking into the future to 2027, Newzoo predicts a 1.1% annual growth. In Europe, it expects a 3.1% annual growth in that same time frame.  That's "<em>slower growth in mature markets</em>," according to Newzoo, who also says that to respond to the slow growth in such high spending markets, "<em>studios must look beyond new payer acquisition - evolving monetization strategies will be key to driving value and engagement</em>."</p>



<p>And that's one of the key takeaways from the report, according to Newzoo and Tebex. That studios need to look towards "<em>deeper monetization</em>" for the future of the industry. </p>



<p>"<em>With modest payer growth in North America and Europe, studios must shift focus from acquiring new payers to maximizing value from existing ones. Aligning monetization with how and why players choose to spend is essential to driving engagement and revenue</em>," Newzoo and Tebex write as the first key takeaway at the bottom of the report.</p>



<p>When Fortnite first launched in 2017, it was one of many videogames players could choose to spend their time with on their preferred platform, with the distinction of a platform in videogames generally meaning a specific piece of hardware. Fast-forward to 2025, and Epic couldn't care less whether you play Fortnite on your phone, your console, or PC, because Fortnite is the platform now.</p>



<p>Individual games are extracting more out of individual players than ever before, but how games go about doing that is what matters, as Newzoo and Tebex point out. Not every game can be successful trying to sell hundreds of thousands of microtransactions, nor can they all be successful premium releases. And with the <a href="https://wccftech.com/heres-why-gta-vi-likely-wont-be-priced-100-according-to-an-analyst/">uproar around rising prices</a>, increasing the buy-in for every game isn't the answer either.</p>



<p>"<em>Today's players want to know what they're paying for - and why</em>," writes Liam Wiltshire, head of payments and compliance at Tebex. "<em>How you monetize matters more than ever. Evolving monetization strategies are key to driving deeper engagement and long-term value</em>."</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/20-of-worlds-gamers-drive-nearly-half-global-gaming-spend-north-america-europe-newzoo/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>