<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 13:31:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stellar Blade 1.3.0 PC Patch Packs Photo Mode Improvements, Gameplay, Cutscenes and AMD FSR Changes and Fixes]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/stellar-blade-1-3-0-pc-patch-amd-fsr/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/stellar-blade-1-3-0-pc-patch-packs-photo-mode-improvements-gameplay-cutscenes-and-amd-fsr-changes-and-fixes.1261428/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A new Stellar Blade patch is now available on PC, introducing Photo Mode improvements as well as gameplay, cutscenes, and AMD FSR fixes and changes.</p>



<p>The 1.3.0 patch, which has gone live today, focuses on further polishing the PC version of the game released in June, and thus doesn't introduce any significant new features. Among the changes introduced by the patch is a Photo Mode improvement which displays a logo control indicator when selecting a logo, fixes for a variety of issues, including an issue that prevented players from exiting the shop after purchasing the Polarized Sunglasses from Clyde's shop, an issues where Eve's hair would not appear during the final Elder Naytibe cutscene when wearing the Fluffy Bear or Pink Bear outfits, Korean voice acting issues in a specific conversation with Clyde in the Great Desert and more. The new patch also changes AMD FSR so that players now need to restart the game to enable frame generation, and improves the save timestamp system so that the time since the last save is accurately displayed based on successful saves and not attempted saves. You can head over <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/3489700/view/535482242423588652?l=english">here</a> to check out the full patch notes.</p>



<p>Stellar Blade made its debut on PC one year after its launch on PlayStation 5 and it was, by all accounts, a rather successful launch, thanks to a solid port that runs well on many different system configurations. Though the port didn't need any major fixes, Shift Up supported the PC version wellafter launch with a few patches, including patch <a href="https://wccftech.com/stellar-blade-pc-1-20-patch-hard-mode-improves-vram/">1.2.0</a>, which introduced plenty of improvements and unlocked Hard Mode without completing the game first.</p>



<p>Stellar Blade is now available on PC and PlayStation 5 worldwide. You can learn more about the solid action RPG developed by Shift Up by checking out Kai's <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/stellar-blade-review-nearly-automatic-angel/">review.</a></p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/stellar-blade-1-3-0-pc-patch-amd-fsr/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nioh 3 Alpha Demo Feedback Report Highlights Gameplay, Visual and Performance Improvements Coming in The Final Release]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nioh-3-visual-performance-improvements/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nioh-3-alpha-demo-feedback-report-highlights-gameplay-visual-and-performance-improvements-coming-in-the-final-release.1261350/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Nioh 3 is getting a slew of gameplay, balance, and performance improvements based on the alpha demo that was made available on PlayStation 5 for a limited time only this past June.</p>



<p>Today, Team NINJA and Koei Tecmo published an Alpha Demo Feedback Report on the game's <a href="https://teamninja-studio.com/nioh3/uk/feedback.html">official website</a>, showing the results of the survey players were asked to complete after playing the demo, and confirming some of the improvements coming to the final game based on feedback. These include control improvements to make them more responsive and adding customization options, adjusting the balance of enemies considered too difficult, improving the quality of the environment, improving visibility and balance of stages, and the open field to make exploration elements easier to understand and more well-balanced. </p>



<p>Going into more detail on some of these planned improvements, Team NINJA also plans to improve Global Illumination behavior in stages, reduce the fog in some areas, adjust elements that look as if they have a matte texture, and better optimize the game for a more stable framerate. Considering how the Japanese developer's games <a href="https://wccftech.com/rise-of-the-ronin-is-yet-another-disappointing-pc-port-from-koei-tecmo/">often leave something to be desired in terms of performance even on PC,</a> gathering feedback from PC players as well would have been beneficial, but it's sadly unlikely an alpha demo will launch on the platform.</p>



<p>Nioh 3 was announced during the now traditional <a href="https://wccftech.com/nioh-3-announced-with-action-packed-trailer-launches-in-early-2026-on-playstation-5/">PlayStation State of Play June presentation</a>. While the game may not look too different from its predecessors at a glance, the third entry in the series will set itself apart by adding a new Ninja fighting style that can be switched on the flay, and a revamped level design. Even with its issues, the alpha demo showed that the series has taken a very interesting direction that is likely to improve the already engaging formula of the franchise, combining Soulslike stamina-based combat with an intricate loot system and mechanics more akin to pure action games.</p>



<p>Nioh 3 launches in early 2026 on PC and PlayStation 5.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/nioh-3-visual-performance-improvements/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Skyblivion Team Now on Its Final Stretch, Release Still Planned for 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/skyblivion-team-now-on-its-final-stretch-release-still-planned-for-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/skyblivion-team-now-on-its-final-stretch-release-still-planned-for-2025.1261347/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Yesterday, Skyblivion project lead Rebelzize <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3MH-BqXk2WA&amp;pp=ygUKc2t5Ymxpdmlvbg%3D%3D" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">posted</a> the sixth development diary for the full conversion mod project. The video is aptly titled 'The Final Stretch Toward Release', and Rebelzize assured fans that the goal is still to launch Skyblivion in 2025, as promised nearly two years ago.</p>



<p>That said, the team still needs volunteers to complete the project. Currently, they are seeking modders with expertise in scripting, quests, record editing, perks, NPC creation, level design, and 3D artists skilled in creating clothing and plant models.</p>



<p>Following this plea, the developer diary shows off the Gold Coast region, a vibrant zone located on the Western edge of Cyrodiil. The city of Anvil has been restructured around a central harbor basin, with expanded commercial, residential, and guild districts. The footage also shows Sutch, a town cut from the original Oblivion game before its release. Skyblivion restores this city to a state that balances decay and bandit occupation with expanded content, including adding a patron divine at a derelict chapel dedicated to Kynareth. Both the expansion of Anvil and the restoration of Sutch exemplify how this project differs greatly from the recently released <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-back-in-cyrodiil-19-years-later/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered</a>, which focused on a big visual overhaul and other tweaks, without, however, touching any original content.</p>



<p>On the other hand, the total conversion mod project reconstructs the entire game with new areas, gameplay enhancements, and environmental redesigns, making it feel like a fresh experience even for long-time players of the fourth mainline Elder Scrolls installment.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="The Final Stretch Towards RELEASE | SKYBLIVION Development Diary 6" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3MH-BqXk2WA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>This philosophy extends to the whole game, including the titular Oblivion realms, which have been expanded and diversified. For example, the Deadlands now include two biomes: The Burn is the one seen in the original game, while The Sever is brand new and was inspired by the zone's rendition in The Elder Scrolls Online and introduces novel environmental hazards and enemy types to enhance gameplay challenge and variety. Lastly, there are now eleven randomly selectable worlds, up from seven, again in an effort to improve variety.</p>



<p>The next Skyblivion developer diary will focus on the Imperial City, the capital of Cyrodiil and the Empire as a whole.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/skyblivion-team-now-on-its-final-stretch-release-still-planned-for-2025/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bloodborne Emulation Improvements Deliver 60 FPS on 4GB VRAM GPUs Like the RX 580]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/bloodborne-60-fps-4gb-vram-rx-580/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bloodborne-emulation-improvements-deliver-60-fps-on-4gb-vram-gpus-like-the-rx-580.1261326/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Bloodborne's emulation on PC with the ShadPS4 emulator has continued to improve in the past few months, so much so that the PlayStation 4 exclusive is now playable with few issues even on a dated 4 GB VRAM GPU like the RX 580.</p>



<p>A new video shared on YouTube by ProteinGaming shows the popular game by FromSoftware running on a fresh version of the excellent PlayStation 4 emulator with a few mods at 60 FPS, 768p resolution on the RX 580 GPU. Some of the improvements recently implemented in the <a href="https://github.com/shadps4-emu/shadPS4/actions/runs/16673907836">emulator</a> made running the game smoothly on a GPU with low VRAM possible, fixing the VRAM leaking issues that also caused stability issues on GPUs with higher VRAM. As such, Bloodborne is now more playable than ever across many different system configurations.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Bloodborne PC VRAM Leaks Fixed! - SHADPS4 0.10.1 60FPS RX 580 4GB" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_QKwj34IF6E?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>The latest official version of the ShadPS4 emulator that made playing Bloodborne on PC a reality is version <a href="https://wccftech.com/shadps4-0-10-0-major-new-feature-bloodborne/">0.10.0</a>. This version of the emulator packed <span>many improvements, which improved the emulation of several titles, including the FromSoftware game and The Last Guardian, another PS4 exclusive that has yet to be ported </span>to PC. In addition to emulation improvements, Bloodborne is receiving plenty of love from modders who have introduced many improvements to the game, including&nbsp;<a href="https://wccftech.com/bloodborne-remaster-improved-pointlights/">enhanced visuals</a>&nbsp;that wouldn't look amiss in a proper remaster.</p>



<p>More information on the ShadPS4 emulator can be found on its <a href="https://shadps4.net/">official website.</a></p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/bloodborne-60-fps-4gb-vram-rx-580/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>