<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:49:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty 2027 Will Introduce New Sub-Series Set In Late 90s/Early 00s, Says Leaker]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/call-of-duty-2027-introduce-new-sub-series-says-leaker/</link>
            <guid>1384879</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>It's no secret that Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 <a href="https://wccftech.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-trails-battlefield-6-eu-launch-sales-and-black-ops-6-launch/">has not been the big blockbuster hit that Activision expects</a> from its marquee series every year. Its release has gone so poorly that Activision has <a href="https://wccftech.com/call-of-duty-team-vows-no-more-back-to-back-releases-after-black-ops-7-flop/">even promised to change how it approaches future releases in the series</a> to avoid what happened this year. At this point, something new, something that's not Black Ops or Modern Warfare, feels like what the series needs to survive, and according to X (formerly Twitter) user GhostOfHope, that's what we're getting with Call of Duty 2027.</p>



<p>In a <a href="https://x.com/TheGhostOfHope/status/2000945365055394031">post on X (formerly Twitter)</a>, GhostOfHope, who has proven to be a reliable source of leaks regarding Call of Duty, claimed that the 2027 game will be made by Sledgehammer Games and that it will introduce a new sub-series to the annual shooter franchise. That means that, according to GhostOfHope, whatever the 2027 Call of Duty game is, it won't be a new entry in either the Modern Warfare or Black Ops sub-series of games.</p>



<p>A new sub-series also means a new set of characters, and a new setting, as this game is reportedly set sometime between the late 90s and early 00s. </p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>EXCLUSIVE: COD2027 made by Sledgehammer Games will be a new sub franchise with completely new characters set in the late 1990s/early 2000s. </p><p>- Omnimovement with NO Tac Sprint is currently planned for the game</p><p>- Pick 10 returning is a big discussion happening</p><p>- Zombies… <a href="https://t.co/2SbZ4ZlfVk">pic.twitter.com/2SbZ4ZlfVk</a></p></div>— Hope (@TheGhostOfHope) <a href="https://twitter.com/TheGhostOfHope/status/2000945365055394031?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 16, 2025</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>The leaker also claims that this new entry will include some major gameplay changes, as it'll feature omnimovement but with no tactical sprint, but perhaps the biggest change claimed by GhostOfHope is that the 2027 game may not feature a Zombies mode at all.</p>



<p>Right now, <a href="https://wccftech.com/activision-addresses-call-of-duty-identity-concerns-black-ops-6-carry-forward-black-ops-7/">considering how stagnant Call of Duty has felt over the last few years</a>, even with recent releases having bright spots that some players might point to, all of this makes it sound like we're in for a very different kind of game in 2027. But with how formulaic the series already is, it's difficult to imagine Activision and its studios straying too far from what's been proven to be successful.</p>



<p>We'll see how it all shakes out, especially after how next year's Call of Duty game goes. At this point, Activision has no choice but to stick with what it already has planned for 2026, unless it wants to try skipping a year for the first time in over a decade of Call of Duty games being annual releases. It'll be interesting, to say the least, to see how players react to next year's game, and how much actually gets changed in 2027. In the meantime, we can all keep playing Battlefield 6.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/call-of-duty-2027-introduce-new-sub-series-says-leaker/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Co-Op Roguelite Raiders of Blackveil from Former IOI Devs Is Out Now in Early Access]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/raiders-of-blackveil-out-now-early-access-pc-wombo-games/</link>
            <guid>1384786</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Raiders of Blackveil, a new co-op roguelite from Wombo Games, a studio founded by IO Interactive co-founder Janos Flösser, has launched into early access on PC. <a href="https://wccftech.com/io-interactive-co-founder-opens-new-studio-wombo-games-new-rogue-lite-raiders-of-blackveil-to-be-debut-project/">After announcing the studio</a> and Raiders of Blackveil back in April 2025, followed by the game's <a href="https://wccftech.com/co-op-roguelite-raiders-of-blackveil-former-io-interactive-devs-early-access-release-date/">early access release date last month</a>, this new Copenhagen-based team has hit the ground running and already has its debut project in players' hands.</p>



<p>Wombo Games is composed of former IO Interactive and Square Enix developers who've worked on titles like Tomb Raider, Deus Ex, Just Cause, and, of course, Hitman. It's clearly a very different kind of game compared to all of those titles, but it's always an exciting prospect to see seasoned developers go outside their comfort zone.</p>



<p>Raiders of Blackveil is a MOBA-inspired action RPG where you'll select your preferred champion and try to craft the best build possible across eight different classes, over 300 perks, and all of the best loot you can find. </p>



<figure><p>
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=k2e9P1lSv_s
</p></figure>



<p>"<em>Our journey to Early Access has been about one thing: refining the core experience and making sure the gameplay feels as it should,</em>" said Benjamin Flösser, executive producer at Wombo Games, in a press release. "<em>Now that this foundation is solid, we're excited to open Raiders of Blackveil to players once again. Early access is where Raiders of Blackveil truly starts to grow and we're looking forward to expanding Raiders of Blackveil in meaningful ways alongside players who have already shaped it so much</em>."</p>



<p>Wombo Games did not specify how long Blackveil is expected to remain in early access, but it did state that the game's 1.0 release will be out sometime in 2026.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/raiders-of-blackveil-out-now-early-access-pc-wombo-games/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>