<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 20:47:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Konami Shows Off Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater One Last Time Before Launch Next Week]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-launch-trailer-konami/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/konami-shows-off-metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-one-last-time-before-launch-next-week.1277613/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Konami has debuted the launch trailer for Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater, showcasing the game one last time ahead of its long-awaited release one week from today, on August 28, 2025.</p>



<p>It's one last hurrah for the remake that Metal Gear Solid fans might have, <a href="https://wccftech.com/metal-gear-solid-delta-mgs3-remake-original-trilogy-returning/">prior to its announcement</a>, hoped for, but never really believed would happen, since it seemed like Konami was letting its biggest series, like Metal Gear Solid and Silent Hill, rest for years without a new entry. Sure, leaks like the <a href="https://wccftech.com/nvidia-responds-to-geforce-now-database-leak-says-list-included-speculative-titles/">NVIDIA GeForce Now list</a> provided hope, but until we all saw it with our own eyes, it was tough to believe.</p>



<p>Which is what makes the fact that we're a week away from its launch all the more exciting and unbelievable, and adds to the excitement around the fact that this launch trailer makes it seem like fans of what many believe to be the best game in the iconic Metal Gear Solid series will not be disappointed by the remake.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="METAL GEAR SOLID Δ: SNAKE EATER - Launch Trailer | KONAMI" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4dNv19RmtVY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>There's even more to look forward to after its launch, with the revised <a href="https://wccftech.com/konami-debuts-metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-multiplayer-mode-fox-hunt/">Fox Hunt multiplayer mode</a> that will be out this fall. It's unfortunate that it <a href="https://wccftech.com/metal-gear-solid-fox-hunt-multiplayer-fall-no-crossplay/">won't feature crossplay between devices</a>, but we don't live in a perfect world.</p>



<p>If you've never played the original Metal Gear Solid 3: Snake Eater, you officially have one week to get through it if you want to experience it ahead of the remake's launch, and if you decide to go on that journey, you're in for a treat, since MGS3 is arguably one of the best videogames ever made.</p>



<p>Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater arrives on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X/S on August 28, 2025.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-launch-trailer-konami/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ys X: Proud Nordics Launches Outside Japan on Nintendo Switch 2 and PC in Early 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ys-x-proud-nordics-global-release-date-early-2026-nintendo-switch-2/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ys-x-proud-nordics-launches-outside-japan-on-nintendo-switch-2-and-pc-in-early-2026.1277550/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>NIS America has announced that Ys X: Proud Nordics will launch outside of Japan on Nintendo Switch 2 and PC sometime in early 2026. It first launched exclusively in Japan for Nintendo Switch 2 this past July 31, 2025.</p>



<p>Ys X: Proud Nordics is the "<em>definitive edition</em>" of Ys X: Nordics, according to NIS America, which launched <a href="https://wccftech.com/ys-x-nordics-is-out-october-25-in-western-countries/">last October outside Japan</a>. The most recent Ys release was <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/ys-memoire-the-oath-in-felghana-review-a-classic-reborn/">Ys Memoire: The Oath in Felghana,</a> which arrived earlier this year. </p>



<p>Ys X: Proud Nordics follows Adol, accompanied by Norman Karja, standing against an undying force called the Griegr. It's then up to Adol and Karja to bring a group of adventurers together to defeat the Griegr, and save the Obelia Gulf.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Ys X: Proud Nordics - Announcement Trailer (Nintendo Switch 2 and PC)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TjgJnBtV-j4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Proud Nordics will also launch with "<em>improved graphical performance and quality of life updates</em>," and include "<em>new mechanics and content"</em> not previously available in the original version of the game from last October.</p>



<p>When <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/ys-x-nordics-one-more-memorable-adventure/">Wccftech's Francesco De Meo reviewed Ys X: Nordics</a> last October, he called it "<em>one more memorable adventure</em>" in the long-running series. </p>



<p>"<em>While some of the changes made to the formula the series employed for 15 years may not sound too exciting on paper, they come together really well in Ys X Nordics, making it the first proper step forward for the franchise in quite a while. The increased focus on the narrative may put some long-time fans of the series off, as may the slight increase in complexity of its system, but if they manage to look past these non-issues, they will find an extremely solid ARPG and a worthy continuation of the long-running series by Falcom."</em> </p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/ys-x-proud-nordics-global-release-date-early-2026-nintendo-switch-2/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[James Gunn says there is “One Thing In Particular” He’s Excited About for Upcoming DC Games, But It’s All Still “Early Stages”]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/james-gunn-excited-about-one-dc-games-in-particular-still-early-stages/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/james-gunn-says-there-is-%E2%80%9Cone-thing-in-particular%E2%80%9D-he%E2%80%99s-excited-about-for-upcoming-dc-games-but-it%E2%80%99s-all-still-%E2%80%9Cearly-stages%E2%80%9D.1277517/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>James Gunn, who has been leading the comeback for DC alongside Peter Safran, spends most of his time focused on upcoming DC films, like the recent Superman movie he directed. His role does also involve him overlooking upcoming DC games, and on that subject he's admitted that there is "<em>one thing in particular</em>" that he's excited about, but the biggest projects all remain in "<em>early stages</em>."</p>



<p>In an interview with <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/entertainment/dc-tv-shows/after-years-of-silence-dc-boss-james-gunn-teases-dcus-gaming-plans-theres-one-thing-in-particular-im-excited-about-but-it-does-take-time/">GamesRadar</a>, Gunn vaguely spoke about what's to come for DC games, which is one of the four pillars along with <a href="https://wccftech.com/wb-games-has-restructured-into-divisions-focused-franchises-harry-potter-game-of-thrones-mortal-kombat-and-the-dc-universe/">Harry Potter, Mortal Kombat, and Game of Thrones that WB Games</a> is focusing its efforts on.</p>



<p>"<em>There's been some slight movement on different things,</em>" Gunn began. "<em>We have a couple of little DC games coming out. But we also have talked about – and in early stages of planning – some bigger things. One thing in particular I'm excited about, but it does take time. There's been some changes in Warner Bros Games, and so we're dealing with new people.</em>"</p>



<p>Of course, some of the changes Gunn is referring to include the restructuring of WB Games to focus on just four major franchises, along with the closing of <a href="https://wccftech.com/monolith-productions-is-no-more-wb-games-also-shuts-down-player-first-games-wb-games-san-diego/">Monolith Productions, Player First Games, and the cancellation of the Wonder Woman</a> game that was previously in the works.</p>



<p>At the time of this writing, the next major game featuring a DC character is <a href="https://wccftech.com/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-tt-games-gamescom-onl-2025/">LEGO Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight</a>, which was announced earlier this week during <a href="https://wccftech.com/topic/gamescom/">Gamescom ONL 2025</a>, and will arrive on PC and consoles sometime in 2026.  </p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/james-gunn-excited-about-one-dc-games-in-particular-still-early-stages/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pearl Abyss Announces Edania, a New Black Desert Online Region Available Now]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/pearl-abyss-announces-edania-a-new-black-desert-online-region-available-now/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pearl-abyss-announces-edania-a-new-black-desert-online-region-available-now.1277514/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Pearl Abyss has announced Edania, a new region for Black Desert Online that's available across all servers right now, at Gamescom 2025.</p>



<p>Edania's launch adds a new main story questline titled The Society of the Equilibrium, which will be available only to players at level 60 or higher. It'll also introduce seven branching questlines with the Edania Adventure Log, for players to further map their journey into the demon realm.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Edania Overview | Black Desert" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/v2n6C4ldR6U?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>There are also new PvE weekly challenges and a new PvP challenge that players can earn after they've defeated a regional boss. The update also adds new gear, enhancements, artifacts, consumables, and new enemies to fight across new lands to explore. The Azure Battlefield, Nymphamaré Castle, and Orbita Castle are the three new lands, each with unique enemies to fight and a regional boss to defeat.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="RISE IN FLAMES (Edania Main Theme) | Music Video | Black Desert" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1RhUHMfaFPc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>"<em>Edania is a high-risk, high-reward destination for the boldest of Adventurers," </em>Pearl Abyss writes in a press release. "<em>Whether you're a master of combat, a skilled craftsman, or a sovereign in the making—your legacy in the Demon Realm awaits.</em>"</p>



<p>Pearl Abyss added <a href="https://wccftech.com/pearl-abyss-reveals-black-desert-march-content-roadmap-including-games-first-hardcore-server/">Black Desert Online's first hardcore servers</a> earlier this year. Beyond Black Desert Online, Pearl Abyss is also working on Crimson Desert, which it recently delayed into <a href="https://wccftech.com/crimson-desert-delayed-to-q1-2026/">Q1 2026</a> ahead of the studio making an appearance at Gamescom 2025 with a <a href="https://wccftech.com/pearl-abyss-crimson-desert-gameplay-gamescom-2025-demo/">Crimson Desert demo</a> for attendees at the convention to try for themselves, just like they did last year.</p>



<p>The next major update for Edania will arrive on September 11, 2025.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/pearl-abyss-announces-edania-a-new-black-desert-online-region-available-now/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>