<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 23:19:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tango Gameworks Lives Again Thanks to Krafton]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/tango-gameworks-lives-again-thanks-to-krafton/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tango-gameworks-lives-again-thanks-to-krafton.1072137/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/tango-gameworks-lives-again-thanks-to-krafton/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>When Microsoft <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-shuts-down-arkane-austin-tango-gameworks-and-a-couple-more-bethesda-softworks-studios/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">closed down</a> Tango Gameworks alongside Arkane Austin, Alpha Dog Games, and Roundhouse Studios (the latter was actually rolled into ZeniMax Online Studios), the industry did not hide its displeasure.</p>
<p>The Japanese developer didn't deserve such a fate, especially after delivering the universally acclaimed rhythm action game Hi-Fi Rush, which <a href="https://wccftech.com/baldurs-gate-3-wins-navgtr-goty-marvels-spider-man-2-and-hi-fi-rush-win-7-and-6-prizes-respectively/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">won several awards last year</a>. On Wccftech, the game earned a 9 out of 10 score from reviewer Ule Lopez:</p>
<p><em>Hi-Fi Rush is a fantastic game that combines two very popular genres and makes a wonderful and innovative game with a low skill floor but a high skill ceiling. The game is both accessible to newcomers to rhythm games and very challenging for veterans looking to be tested in several other areas that don't necessarily have to do with just rhythm games. The combat is varied, the combos you learn are great to execute, and the music is a joy to listen to. Overall, a great success.</em></p>
<p>It was even more baffling because Microsoft had previously stated they wanted to add more Asian developers to their first-party roster. Regardless, it was not the end for Tango Gameworks, as PUBG maker Krafton <a href="https://wccftech.com/tango-gameworks-and-its-hi-fi-rush-ip-have-just-been-acquired-by-pubgs-krafton/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">swooped in</a> to acquire the studio and the Hi-Fi Rush intellectual property. In September, Krafton CEO Han 'CH' Kim said they know a sequel probably wouldn't sell a lot due to being a niche genre, but they would still try to do their best for fans.</p>
<p>Today, at the dawn of the new year, Tango Gameworks has r<a href="https://x.com/TangoGameworks/status/1874259495783981205" target="_blank" rel="noopener">esumed social media communications</a> with the following message to all its fans:</p>
<p><em><strong>A New Start </strong></em><br>
<em>Tango Gameworks studio has been reborn as Tango Gameworks Inc., proudly joining KRAFTON Inc. </em><br>
<em>We're excited to continue crafting games that bring joy to players around the world. </em><br>
<em>Thank you for your continued support as we embark on this new journey!</em></p>
<p>As a reminder, the Japanese studio previously also released <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/the-evil-within-review-lackluster-horror-forgotten/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Evil Within</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/the-evil-within-2-good-not-scary/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Evil Within 2</a>, and <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/ghostwire-tokyo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ghostwire: Tokyo</a>. Those franchises have stayed with Microsoft for now, but they don't appear to be&nbsp;used for the time being. As such, it's not inconceivable that Tango might ask for the license at some point in the future, though the current focus is undoubtedly on Hi-Fi Rush 2.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 Motherboard Pictures Leaked on the Web]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-motherboard-pictures-leaked-on-the-web/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-motherboard-pictures-leaked-on-the-web.1072107/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-motherboard-pictures-leaked-on-the-web/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Unsurprisingly, the first leak of the year is related to the Nintendo Switch 2. Three pictures of the upcoming console's motherboard have allegedly leaked <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NintendoSwitch2/comments/1hqu83a/switch_2_motherboard/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">on Reddit</a>.</p>
<p>The memory appears to be SK Hynix LPDDR5 48Gbit. The leaked images also show NVIDIA's logo, which is again entirely expected given that previous leaks all pointed to the Nintendo Switch 2 once again being powered by NVIDIA hardware. More specifically, it will use the <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-pro-successor-rumored-nvidia-tegra239-soc-confirmed-to-be-real-to-feature-8-core-cpu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tegra 239 System-on-Chip (SoC)</a>, which is based on the Orin SoC family. The CPU has eight cores and 12x ARM Cortex-A78AE cores, while the GPU, based on NVIDIA's Ampere architecture, includes 2048 CUDA Cores. The hardware reportedly supports Deep Learning Super Sampling Super Resolution and <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-ray-reconstruction/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ray Reconstruction</a>, the latter's inclusion confirming hardware ray tracing support.</p>
<p>According to previous leaks, it won't feature built-in Frame Generation. However, several console games have shipped with AMD FSR Frame Generation, and on PC, it is possible to mix DLSS Super Resolution with FSR Frame Generation. We might see that again from some developers making Nintendo Switch 2 games as a way to extract more performance.</p>
<p>DLSS Ray Reconstruction might be the <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-superiority-ray-reconstruction-reveal/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">only real advantage the hardware has over PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series S|X</a>. Otherwise, experts concur that the new console will be much weaker than even the Series S, and it is rumored to be <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-dock-4k-30-fps-only/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">limited to 4K resolution and 30 frames per second when docked</a>. Then again, it's nothing new for Nintendo fans - the last competitive console in this regard was the GameCube, which also flopped pretty hard from a sales standpoint.</p>
<blockquote><p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NintendoSwitch2/comments/1hqu83a/switch_2_motherboard/">Switch 2 motherboard</a><br> by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/MHN1994/">u/MHN1994</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NintendoSwitch2/">NintendoSwitch2</a></p></blockquote>

<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 will once again try to attract a large audience with its seamless combination of handheld and home console that worked so well for its predecessor. The Switch just <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-surpassed-playstation-2s-lifetime-console-sales-in-the-us/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">surpassed</a> the lifetime sales of Sony's PlayStation 2 in the United States. Globally, the PS2 is still ahead, but Nintendo's console might get very close before all is said and done.</p>
<p>The increasing pace of the leaks suggests a reveal might be really close. A previous rumor points to a <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-revealed-january-dock-image/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">January 8 unveiling</a> by Nintendo, while the accessories are <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-might-launch-on-march-28-says-italian-website/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">rumored</a> to be available on the market starting on March 28.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>