<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 15:36:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shuhei Yoshida Leaving Sony Interactive Entertainment on January 15 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/shuhei-yoshida-leaving-sony-interactive-entertainment-on-january-15-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shuhei-yoshida-leaving-sony-interactive-entertainment-on-january-15-2025.1046514/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/shuhei-yoshida-leaving-sony-interactive-entertainment-on-january-15-2025/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>In an official PlayStation podcast interview, Shuhei Yoshida made the announcement that he will be leaving Sony Interactive Entertainment after working there for 31 years. His official leaving date is January 15, 2025. He has had some truly <a href="https://wccftech.com/all-games-becoming-live-service-games-would-be-boring-sonys-shuhei-yoshida-says/">iconic moments</a> throughout his time at PlayStation. From <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tUY6qXiLFXA" target="_blank" rel="noopener">falling asleep during a monologue from David Cage</a> in 2013 to the iconic video demonstrating how to share games on PS4 right after Microsoft's failed Xbox One announcement. Throughout the years, he's become a very well-known face at the company, and in 2019, he made the decision to encourage indie developers to publish their games for PlayStation. As a result of his major contributions to the gaming industry, he was awarded the BAFTA Games Fellowship in 2023.</p>
<p>In the official PlayStation Podcast interview, he explained his decision to leave the company and some of the best moments he's had while working there.</p>
<p>"I've been with PlayStation from the beginning, and this is my 31st year with PlayStation. When I hit 30 years, I was thinking, it may be about time for me to move on. You know, the company's been doing great. I love PlayStation 5, I love the games that are coming out on this platform. And we have new generations of management who I respect and admire. And I'm so excited for the future of PlayStation. So you know, PlayStation is in really good hands. I thought, okay, this is my time."</p>
<p>At the moment, Yoshida has said that he has no plans for what's next, but that he would like to stay in the industry to continue to help independent game developers. For now, though, he has been traveling a lot, meeting with developers, and attending game events. He's also been looking at new and upcoming games while making sure to post about games that he has enjoyed throughout the year.</p>
<p>Yoshida originally joined Ken Kutanagi's team in February 1993 when they were still developing the original PlayStation. The team consisted exclusively of engineers, and Yoshida joined as the first person who wasn't in a technical role. In this role, he was in charge of talking to publishers and developers in Japan to try and get them to create games on PlayStation.</p>
<p>If you want to hear everything that Shuhei Yoshida has to say about his 31 years at PlayStation, you can listen to the podcast on Apple or Spotify. Alternatively, you can read the transcript between Sid Shuman and Shuhei Yoshida on the <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/11/26/all-good-things-a-look-back-at-shuhei-yoshidas-31-years-with-playstation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PlayStation blog</a>.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The 2K Launcher Is Gone Forever, So You Can Launch Everything from Steam and Epic Games Store]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-2k-launcher-is-gone-forever-so-you-can-launch-everything-from-steam-and-epic-games-store/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-2k-launcher-is-gone-forever-so-you-can-launch-everything-from-steam-and-epic-games-store.1046403/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/the-2k-launcher-is-gone-forever-so-you-can-launch-everything-from-steam-and-epic-games-store/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The 2K launcher is no more. Many PC gamers will undoubtedly be overjoyed about the prospect of launching their favorite 2K games without having to go through that launcher, especially since it was even <a href="https://wccftech.com/marvels-midnight-suns-pc-performance-can-reportedly-be-boosted-by-turning-off-2k-launcher/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">responsible</a> for performance drops in some cases.</p>
<p>However, there are some steps to take to remove the 2K launcher from the various supported games. Thankfully, they were outlined in a helpful article on the <a href="https://support.2k.com/hc/en-us/articles/34845053169939--2K-Launcher-Complete-Sunset#h_01JBCNYWH2Q8X3MAWETFS82N9A" target="_blank" rel="noopener">dedicated 2K support page</a>.</p>
<p><em><strong>Removing the Launcher</strong></em><br>
<em>The first thing is to try closing and reopening Steam - that means completely closing and not just using the X to minimize the platform. Rebooting your PC is a good way to be sure it happened. For Epic, just make sure you've downloaded the most recent update for the game.</em></p>
<p><em><strong>Click Play and Go!</strong></em><br>
<em>Bioshock Remastered, Bioshock 2 Remastered, Bioshock Infinite, The Quarry, and Marvel’s Midnight Suns will now all launch directly into the game as soon as you click Play.</em></p>
<p><em><strong>Mafia Trilogy Definitive Edition</strong></em><br>
<em>The Mafia Trilogy Definitive Edition games on Steam and the Mafia Trilogy Definitive Edition games on Epic will each have slightly different paths to getting into the games. Please see <a href="https://support.2k.com/hc/articles/34847163808403" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this article</a> for more information.</em></p>
<p><em><strong>Civilization VI</strong></em><br>
<em>Civilization VI on Steam had the 2K launcher removed earlier this year, so no additional steps are needed. </em><em>In the case of Civilization VI for Epic, it now directly opens into the game when launched from Epic. The version opened by default is the DirectX 11 version. If you would like to play the DX12 version, please see <a href="https://support.2k.com/hc/articles/32212020230163" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this article</a> for instructions on how to open that version at launch instead.</em></p>
<p><em><strong>Civilization V</strong></em><br>
<em>Civilization V now uses the Steam Launch options to open the game. The order is the same as was present in the previous 2K launcher, so the default (top) option is “Play Sid Meier’s Civilization V (DirectX 9)”, followed by “Play Sid Meier’s Civilization V (DirectX 10/11)”, and “Play Sid Meier’s Civilization V (Touch)”. As with all Steam games that have launch options, the desktop shortcut will always open the default option, in this case, the DirectX 9 version. For more details, <a href="https://support.2k.com/hc/articles/34890889538707" target="_blank" rel="noopener">read this</a>.</em></p>
<p><em><strong>XCOM 2</strong></em><br>
<em>XCOM 2 for Steam is a special case, as the 2K launcher included Mod support functionality. You </em><em>can read more about this <a href="https://support.2k.com/hc/articles/34883894563347" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>. Of note, these changes will let you enable mods on the Steam Deck! XCOM 2 on Epic will now open the Original XCOM 2 Mod Launcher, detailed in the linked article above.</em></p>
<p><em><strong>XCOM: Chimera Squad</strong></em><br>
<em>XCOM: Chimera Squad also has the Mod launcher as optional, with a secondary option available to directly launch the game. Mods are also available on Steam Deck for Chimera Squad as well, but please see our <a href="https://support.2k.com/hc/articles/34884258027411" target="_blank" rel="noopener">dedicated article</a> for some important information.</em></p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Portal 2 RTX Remix Path Tracing Mod Utterly Destroys Performance on An RTX 4080, Dropping from 200+ FPS to 20 FPS at 4K Resolution]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/portal-2-rtx-remix-path-tracing-utterly-destroys-performance-rtx-4080/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/portal-2-rtx-remix-path-tracing-mod-utterly-destroys-performance-on-an-rtx-4080-dropping-from-200-fps-to-20-fps-at-4k-resolution.1046376/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/portal-2-rtx-remix-path-tracing-utterly-destroys-performance-rtx-4080/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Portal 2 RTX Remix path tracing mod looks <a href="https://wccftech.com/portal-2-rtx-remix-path-tracing-mod/">incredible</a>, but its improvements come at a very high cost, as path tracing in the game is so demanding that it utterly destroys performance at 4K resolution on an RTX 4080 GPU.</p>
<p>A new comparison put together by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@MxBenchmarkPC" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MxBenchmarkPC</a> does a great job highlighting how demanding path tracing can be. At native 4K resolution, the framerate drops from around 200 and 300+ FPS to the low 20s and 30s range, depending on the scenario, on an RTX 4080 GPU, which should be more than capable of delivering higher framerates even with path tracing. For playable framerates, Portal 2 RTX Remix essentially requires NVIDIA DLSS and Frame Generation to push past the 60 FPS range at 1440p and 1080p resolutions in some scenarios.</p>
<p><iframe title="Portal 2 Path Tracing with RTX Remix On vs Off - Graphics/Performance Comparison | RTX 4080" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/a3BcYtKmmlE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>If you want to try out the Portal 2 RTX Remix mod yourself, you can download it by going <a href="https://github.com/xoxor4d/p2-rtx">here</a>. The mod was never intended to support the game, and the game effects are rendered using shaders, so you should expect to experience some other issues besides the low performance.</p>
<p>Portal 2 is the second entry in the series created by Valve, introducing a variety of improvements over its predecessor, including a separate two-player cooperative campaign. More information on the game can be found on its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/620/Portal_2/">Steam Store page.</a></p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Red Dead Redemption New Mods Introduce Historical Overhaul of Weapons, Upscaled Textures For Different Objects, First Person View Mode]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/red-dead-redemption-mods-overhaul-first-person-view/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/red-dead-redemption-new-mods-introduce-historical-overhaul-of-weapons-upscaled-textures-for-different-objects-first-person-view-mode.1046346/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/red-dead-redemption-mods-overhaul-first-person-view/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>New <a href="https://wccftech.com/red-dead-redemption-pc-comparison-8k-rtx-4070/">Red Dead Redemption</a> mods released online in the past few days offer various visual improvements, new gameplay features, and better historical accuracy for guns.</p>
<p>The first one of these mods is the <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/reddeadredemption/mods/454" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Upscaled Everything mod</a>, which doesn't yet upscale every texture in the game as the name would suggest but brings significant improvements to a variety of objects, such as wanted posters, blood splats, bullet holes, the moon, and John Marston himself. The mod creator also confirmed that every other texture yet to be upscaled eventually will, but it will require some time.</p>
<figure>
<div>

<div>
		
		
		<p><span>2 of 9</span>
	</p></div></div>
</figure>


<p>The second of these new Red Dead Redemption mods is one that gun buffs and those looking to make the game a more historically accurate experience should consider. <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/reddeadredemption/mods/461?tab=description">The Guns of the Old West Historical Overhaul mod</a> renames in-game weapons to reflect their real-life counterparts.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/06-1.webp"></a></figure>

<p>The third and final new Red Dead Redemption is the only one that introduces a new gameplay feature - <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/reddeadredemption/mods/451?tab=description">a first-person view mode</a> for increased immersion. As the game was never intended to be played in first person, there are some clipping issues, such as when riding a horse, but outside these issues, the game should be fully playable with a modded camera view. The modder also recommends using the<a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/reddeadredemption/mods/26" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> ClipTweaks - FPS-DOF-FOV mod</a> for a higher field of view if needed.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/07-1.webp"></a></figure>

<p>Red Dead Redemption is finally available on PC, 14 years after its original release on PlayStation 3 and Xbox 360. The game is also available on PlayStation consoles and Nintendo Switch and is fully playable on Xbox Series X and Xbox Series S via backward compatibility.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>