<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 19:17:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Playing GTA: Vice City In A Web Browser Is Now Possible, Thanks To DOS Zone]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/playing-gta-vice-city-in-a-web-browser-is-now-possible-thanks-to-dos-zone/</link>
            <guid>1388617</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>If you want to just relive your childhood in your free time, why not try Vice City in your browser?</p>



<h2 id="h-gta-vice-city-demo-is-now-directly-playable-in-a-web-browser-on-dos-zone-allowing-the-game-to-be-played-on-various-devices">GTA: Vice City Demo is Now Directly Playable in a Web Browser on DOS Zone, Allowing the Game to be Played on Various Devices</h2>



<p>While GTA: Vice City can be easily run on a potato PC, you will still need to download and install it via platforms like Steam. The game is also available for mobile devices based on Android and iOS, and will cost you a few bucks, but if you want to play it for free (and without downloading), you can now play it directly on your browser.</p>



<p>Originally released in 2002 on PlayStation 2 and later on PC and Xbox, Vice City is now playable on your browser, thanks to the DOZ Zone, which is currently hosting a technology demo on the website. The browser-playable version isn't an official release from Rockstar Games, but it's a fan-created port of the game. The project is powered by a technology demo built on WebAssembly and browser APIs, and uses open-source engine implementations like reVC to recreate Vice City's gameplay without installation.</p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/GTA-Vice-City-2.jpg"></a><figcaption>Image Credit: Wccftech</figcaption></figure>



<p>On the DOS Zone website, the game runs entirely in the browser and doesn't require any download or installation, unlike on a PC or mobile phone. As long as you have a modern browser like Chrome or Edge, you will be able to run it on any device of your choice. All you need to do is click on the "play demo" button, and you are good to go. On mobile, you will have dedicated touch interfaces, while on PC, you can play it via your keyboard/mouse or a controller. </p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/GTA-Vice-City-on-mobile.jpg"></a><figcaption>Image Credit: Wccftech</figcaption></figure>



<p>It should be kept in mind that the demo does not include the full original game assets. Players will be prompted to upload the files legally purchased from the Vice City copy in order to access the complete campaign. That said, you can still move around, drive a bike or car, and check out places to feel your childhood on the go. </p>

			<p>News Source: <a href="https://dos.zone/grand-theft-auto-vice-city/" target="_blank">Dos Zone</a></p>
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/playing-gta-vice-city-in-a-web-browser-is-now-possible-thanks-to-dos-zone/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA 6 Could Evolve Into an MMORPG as Many of Its Planned Features Belong to the Genre, Developer Has Heard]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/gta-6-could-evolve-into-an-mmorpg-as-many-of-its-planned-features-belong-to-the-genre-developer-has-heard/</link>
            <guid>1388473</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			<div data-nosnippet="">
		
		<ul>
			<li>0-20%: Unlikely - Lacks credible sources</li>
			<li>21-40%: Questionable - Some concerns remain</li>
			<li>41-60%: Plausible - Reasonable evidence</li>
			<li>61-80%: Probable - Strong evidence</li>
			<li>81-100%: Highly Likely - Multiple reliable sources</li>
		</ul>
	</div>


			
			
			
			<p><strong>GTA 6</strong> is the game that most of the industry has to deal with, one way or another. Its arguably unprecedented (but well deserved, given that GTA 5 is the second best-selling game of all time) hype means developers and publishers of all sizes are doing everything they can to steer clear of its launch date, which, however, has already shifted twice, disrupting many plans and <a href="https://wccftech.com/possibility-of-gta-6-delay-threatens-games-industry-some-companies-are-going-to-tank-if-wrong/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">threatening the very livelihood of certain companies</a>. It's a topic we covered often and in various nuances, including Goichi Suda's recent quip that his new game, Romeo Is a Dead Man, <a href="https://wccftech.com/winning-the-race-against-gta-6-by-not-taking-part-suda51-celebrates-romeo-is-a-dead-man-release-date-announcement/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">'won the game of chicken against GTA 6'</a>.</p>



<p>What we weren't really expecting to cover is Rockstar's game attached to the flailing <strong>MMORPG</strong> genre. And yet, that's what we must do following the statement of an industry veteran. <a href="https://wccftech.com/is-the-mmo-genre-dead-for-western-aaa-developers-we-asked-three-industry-veterans/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">In our fresh, exclusive interview about the state of the MMORPG among Western developers</a>, <strong>Rich Vogel</strong>, whose career credits include titles like Ultima Online, Star Wars Galaxies, Star Wars: The Old Republic, Doom (2016), New World, Halo Infinite, and Gotham Knights, revealed to have heard that many of GTA 6's planned features, if confirmed, would place it on a path to evolve into an MMORPG. </p>



<p>Here's the exact response we got from Vogel when we asked him (and other two MMO vets) whether there's still an audience for a big Western-made massively multiplayer online game:</p>



<p><em>Yes, I believe a large audience is waiting for the right MMORPG to emerge. Consider the millions of players who have played and continue to play WOW, SWTOR, ESO, UO, EverQuest, Fallout 76, and others. The problem is that no publisher is willing to invest the money and take the risk at this time. My instinct tells me that the next major MMORPG will likely come from Asia and/or Europe. <strong>If what I have been hearing about GTA 6's features and gameplay is true, it could evolve into an MMORPG, as many of its planned features are typically found in MMORPGs</strong>.</em></p>



<p>Now, first of all, he's obviously referring to the online mode. While Rockstar hasn't shared any actual details about the game yet except for the setting and the identity of the protagonists, it's a fair bet that there will be a traditional, narrative-driven single player campaign and a separate online mode, just like with GTA 5.</p>



<p>Secondly, Vogel makes no mystery of the fact that he didn't actually work on the next Grand Theft Auto game, so this is second-hand information and should be treated as a rumor. Does it even make sense as an evolution of GTA Online in GTA 6, though?</p>



<p>We'd argue so. GTA 5 has already made a big step toward an online persistent world compared to GTA 4's more limited, session-based multiplayer, and its success was so massive that it overshadowed everything else at the studio, foregoing any need for story-based DLCs like GTA 4's The Lost and Damned and The Ballad of Gay Tony, with new story beats instead deployed to GTA Online.</p>



<p>Moreover, a large hint that this might indeed be the direction Rockstar has taken is the studio's acquisition of <strong>FiveM</strong> maker Cfx.re <a href="https://wccftech.com/previously-banned-gta-5-fivem-and-rdr2-redm-creators-are-now-part-of-rockstar-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">back in August 2023</a>. FiveM, a community-driven modification of GTA 5's base multiplayer, introduced MMORPG-like features such as dedicated servers, far higher player count per session, and the ability to roleplay as a specific role, like a paramedic, a police officer, and many more careers. FiveM became so popular that at one point, it surpassed the concurrent player count of regular GTA 5 Online multiplayer on Valve's Steam. It also significantly contributed to making GTA 5 a consistently high ranking category on streaming platforms like Twitch.</p>



<p>The continued popularity of FiveM shows that there is indeed an appetite for a more persistent, roleplay-inspired experience with larger player counts among the GTA community. Of course, it is unlikely that GTA 6's Online mode will be anything like traditional MMORPGs such as Blizzard's World of Warcraft or even ZeniMax's more recent The Elder Scrolls Online. However, it is entirely possible and even likely that it may incorporate some of their features to engage players in a more seamless, persistent, and immersive living world.</p>



<p>It may not be until well into next year before Rockstar Games shares any official details. Meanwhile, though, we'll keep our ears to the ground for more rumors and leaks about next year's most anticipated game. </p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/gta-6-could-evolve-into-an-mmorpg-as-many-of-its-planned-features-belong-to-the-genre-developer-has-heard/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>