<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 16:49:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation 5 Pro Game Boost Falls Short of Promised 45% Performance Increase, Likely Due to Memory Bandwidth Constraints]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-pro-game-boost-falls-short-memory-bandwidth/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-5-pro-game-boost-falls-short-of-promised-45-performance-increase-likely-due-to-memory-bandwidth-constraints.1034802/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-pro-game-boost-falls-short-memory-bandwidth/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The PlayStation 5 Pro Game Boost feature isn't delivering the 45% improvements promised before launch likely due to memory bandwidth constraints.</p>
<p>Speaking during the latest episode of their weekly podcast, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@DigitalFoundry">Digital Foundry</a> commented on the system's features delivering, so far, only a 30%, 35% improvement in titles that did not receive a PS5 Pro Enhanced patch. While it is still not clear if Game Boost, which is essentially a compatibility mode, offers all the features and all the performance of the system, which seems unlikely, considering the Xbox Series X, powered by AMD hardware like Sony's consoles, offers the full GPU power when running Xbox One X using a similar compatibility mode, there's a very good chance that memory bandwidth constraints are limiting the improvements. This is similar to what happened on the PlayStation 4 Pro, as the 45% GPU upgrade over the base model was accompanied by only a 28% improvement in memory bandwidth, although the unbalance was way worse in the previous generation refresh system, which couldn't target 4K resolution in games even if the system had the shading power for it.</p>
<p>The PlayStation 5 Pro Game Boost feature being limited by memory bandwidth hypothesis is somewhat backed up by how AMD handles its GPU, as the increase in CU is parallel to an increase in memory bandwidth and memory controller improvement that allows larger cache GPUs to better handle high resolutions such as 4K. As such, there may be situations in the future where the PS5 Pro will be able to handle 1080p at 120 FPS with ease but struggle more at higher resolutions, as the higher the resolution, the more memory bandwidth is needed.</p>
<p><iframe title="DF Direct Weekly #188: Death Stranding Xbox, God of War Ragnarök PS5 Pro, Switch 2 Back Compat!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7rzR03knFfk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Despite unpatched games not seeing the improvements that some were expecting, the PlayStation 5 Pro seems to be delivering in PS5 Pro patched games, as in cases like<a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-pro-god-of-war-ragnarok-pssr-framerate-down/"> God of War Ragnarok</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-pro-final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-patch/">Final Fantasy VII Rebirth</a>, the visual and performance improvements are substantial. You can learn more about what else the recently released system is capable of doing in our <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/playstation-5-pro-hardware-the-next-gen-graphics-upgrade/">review.</a></p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout TV Series Benefited from Not Launching with a New Game, Says Phil Spencer]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/fallout-tv-series-benefited-from-not-launching-with-a-new-game-says-phil-spencer/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallout-tv-series-benefited-from-not-launching-with-a-new-game-says-phil-spencer.1034691/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/fallout-tv-series-benefited-from-not-launching-with-a-new-game-says-phil-spencer/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Fallout TV series creator Jonathan Nolan and Microsoft Gaming CEO Phil Spencer appeared earlier this week at the Paley International Council Summit during a panel titled Source Code: How Hollywood and Videogames Are Leveling Up Together.</p>
<p>At some point during the conversation (transcribed by Inverse), Phil Spencer <a href="https://www.inverse.com/gaming/fallout-season-2-jonathan-nolan-interview-phil-spencer-xbox" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> the outstandingly successful Fallout TV show might have actually benefited from not having another game launch in the same franchise at a similar time. The executive pointed out that the strategy is much more in-depth and long-term than merely using the adaptation to incentivize fans to buy a new game.</p>
<p><em>We didn't have a new game lined up for the launch. I actually think that gave us some creative liberty that we wouldn't have had if we tried to coordinate the production of two very different creative processes to land at the same time.</em></p>
<p><em>The play is much more long term than trying to drive some gift buying.</em></p>
<p>Fortunately, the days of tie-ins, when games were often rushed out of the door simply to be released alongside big-budget movies, are behind us. This has led not only to greater creative freedom but also to much better overall quality, as the creative process cannot be rushed. Plus, Fallout games did <a href="https://wccftech.com/fallout-tv-show-popularity-got-bethesda-at-least-80-million-says-report/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">get</a> a massive boost in sales anyway when the TV show dropped on Amazon Prime Video, even if they weren't newly released.</p>
<p>During the panel, Jonathan Nolan briefly discussed the show's <a href="https://wccftech.com/fallout-tv-series-officially-renewed-by-amazon-for-second-season/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">second season</a>, saying it will rely even more on flashbacks than season one.</p>
<p><em>For the most part, in games, it’s a little harder grammatically to flashback, right? Some games can do it very well. There are a couple of memorable flashbacks in Call of Duty and other franchises. But for the most part, you kind of lock the user into that first-person point of view across both space and time. In a show, you can flashback and you can explore that world beforehand. It’s one of the things I love the most about season one and we will be doing more of that in season two.</em></p>
<p>Fallout TV season 2 will start filming soon in California.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>