<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 18:19:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Callum Vinson Will Play Atreus in Amazon’s God of War TV Show]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/callum-vinson-will-play-atreus-in-amazons-god-of-war-tv-show/</link>
            <guid>1430167</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p><strong>Callum Vinson</strong>, who you might recognize from the <strong>Chucky</strong> TV series or the recent mini series, <strong>Long Bright River</strong>, has been tapped to play <strong>Atreus</strong> in <strong>Amazon's God of War TV series</strong>, a new report from <a href="https://variety.com/2026/tv/news/god-of-war-live-action-series-cast-callum-vinson-atreus-1236656985/">Variety</a> has confirmed.</p>



<p>It's the latest major casting announcement for the show, with Vinson joining the likes of <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/broadway-legend-mandy-patinkin-will-play-odin-in-amazons-god-of-war-tv-series/">Mandy Patinkin,</a> <a href="https://wccftech.com/warm-bodies-star-teresa-palmer-tapped-to-play-sif-in-amazons-god-of-war-tv-series/">Teresa Palmer</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/amazon-god-of-war-tv-series-max-parker-heimdall-thor-mimir/">Max Parker</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/amazon-adds-to-god-of-war-tv-cast-with-alastair-duncan-returning-as-mimir-and-two-new-picks-for-brok-and-sindri/">Danny Woodburn</a>,</strong> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/severances-olafur-darri-olafsson-tapped-to-play-thor-in-amazons-god-of-war-tv-series/"><strong></strong><strong>Ólafur Darri Ólafsson</strong>,</a> to name a few. That said, we'll mostly see Vinson alongside <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/god-of-war-tv-show-amazon-prime-ryan-hurst-kratos-cast/">Ryan Hurst</a></strong>, who is set to lead the show as <strong>Kratos</strong>.</p>



<p>The official character description and logline for the show, included in Variety's report, also give us a clearer picture as to where within the storyline the show will kick off. With Atreus described as only being 10 years old, it's clear that the plan is to start with the plot of the first game, before moving into the events of <strong>God of War Ragnarok</strong>.</p>



<p>That said, we know from several of the casting choices that, despite the logline describing the plot of the first game (Kratos and Atreus' journey to spread the ashes of their lost wife/mother), we'll see plenty of characters not included in the first game getting introduced in this first season.</p>



<p>With Mandy Patinkin (Odin), Teresa Palmer (Sif), Max Parker (Heimdall), and Ólafur Darri Ólafsson (Thor) all set to play characters we don't meet until Ragnarok, it'll be interesting to see how the show weaves the second game's narrative and characters into the first's.</p>



<p>Now that we know who will be taking on the role of Atreus, the remaining major roles left to be filled are <strong>Baldur</strong> and <strong>Freya</strong>, two characters that play major roles between both games that will almost surely play major roles in the show as well. </p>



<p>With the show expected to <a href="https://wccftech.com/amazon-god-of-war-tv-show-begins-filming-march-2026/">start filming sometime in <strong>March 2026</strong></a><strong>,</strong> we'll hopefully find out who will be stepping into both roles very soon. So far, Alastair Duncan and Ryan Hurst are the only two cast members who worked on the games that will also work on the show.</p>



<p>Here's the full cast list so far for Amazon's God of War TV series, led by <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/first-god-of-war-tv-series-details/">Ronald D. Moore</a></strong>:</p>



<ul>
<li>Ryan Hurst - Kratos</li>



<li>Callum Vinson - Atreus</li>



<li>Alastair Duncan - Mimir</li>



<li>Danny Woodburn - Brok</li>



<li>Jeff Gulka - Sindri</li>



<li>Teresa Palmer - Sif</li>



<li>Ólafur Darri Ólafsson - Thor</li>



<li>Max Parker - Heimdall</li>



<li>Mandy Patinkin - Odin</li>
</ul>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/callum-vinson-will-play-atreus-in-amazons-god-of-war-tv-show/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>