<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 10:34:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Matrix Creators Wanted Kojima to Make a Game Based on the IP, But Konami Refused]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-matrix-creators-wanted-kojima-make-a-game-on-the-ip-konami-refused/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-matrix-creators-wanted-kojima-to-make-a-game-based-on-the-ip-but-konami-refused.1336525/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>There's little doubt that The Matrix franchise is criminally underserved when it comes to videogame adaptations, despite being theoretically a perfect fit for the medium. In the 26 years since the original movie's theatrical debut, we only got two decent games: 2003's single player action/adventure game Enter the Matrix and 2005's MMORPG The Matrix Online. More recently, the interactive experience The Matrix Awakens <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-matrix-awakens-unreal-engine-5-trailer-photorealistic-keanu/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">was released in late 2021</a>, but it was really just a tech demo for Unreal Engine 5 and a tease at the level of quality that gaming fans of the IP never really got to fully experience. </p>



<p>That makes it all the harder to swallow the news that revered videogame designer Hideo Kojima (Metal Gear, Death Stranding) was once asked to make a game based on The Matrix. The revelation was shared by Christopher Bergstresser, the Senior Vice President of Strategic Planning &amp; Business Development at Konami between 1996 and 2002, <a href="https://www.timeextension.com/news/2025/10/they-were-big-fans-of-kojima-the-wachowskis-once-asked-the-metal-gear-creator-to-make-a-matrix-video-game" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in an interview with Time Extension</a>.</p>



<p>Bergstresser recounted an episode that occurred on August 25, 1999, the day of the Japanese theatrical debut of the original movie. The Wachowskis were fans of Kojima's work and, upon meeting him, asked if he'd want to make a Matrix game. However, former Konami CEO Kazumi Kitaue allegedly flat-out refused.</p>



<p><em>The Wachowskis were big fans of Kojima, so Kazumi Kitaue, Kojima, Aki Saito (who still works with Kojima), and I were at the Konami HQ, and we got a call from the Wachowskis, who wanted to come in and meet with Kojima. So they did! The two of them came in with their concept artist, and effectively they said to Kojima, ‘We really want you to do the Matrix game. Can you do that?’ Aki translated this into Japanese for Mr. Kitaue, and Kitaue just looked at them and told them plainly, ‘No’. We did still get to enjoy the Matrix Japanese premiere and afterparty, though.</em></p>



<p>Time Extension also claims to have talked about this with another former Konami employee, who reportedly added that Hideo Kojima continued to express a strong interest in the partnership after Kitaue's comment. Perhaps that means he subsequently petitioned the executive to allow it to happen, but alas, it was not to be. </p>



<p>We'll never know how such a project would have turned out, but it certainly makes us sad that it never came to light.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/the-matrix-creators-wanted-kojima-make-a-game-on-the-ip-konami-refused/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bully Online Mod Promises to Let You Roam Rockstar’s Classic with Friends]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/bully-online-mod-promises-let-you-roam-rockstars-classic-with-friends/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bully-online-mod-promises-to-let-you-roam-rockstar%E2%80%99s-classic-with-friends.1336513/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>A team of modders is working on Bully Online, a modification for the PC version of Bully: Scholarship Edition that promises to allow players to roam the grounds of Bullworth Academy and the nearby town with their friends. The Wii and Xbox 360 versions of Scholarship Edition did have a multiplayer mode, but it was limited to two players and only allowed them to face off in the class minigames. </p>



<p>According to community creator SWEGTA, Bully Online promises much more, including free roam support, solo and group minigames, and even a role-playing system. They were able to add a 'fully fleshed out inventory system' so that players can earn money through side objectives, minigames, or item finding/trading. Money can be spent on houses, weapons, vehicles, and various items. When purchasing a vehicle, the player will receive unique car keys, allowing them to lock vehicles so others cannot steal them.</p>



<p>There will also be some new minigames, such as Rat Wars, a team shooter mode where oversized cartoon rats wield guns, as well as racing, which includes custom vehicles and tracks. These minigames will be instanced, avoiding potential issues with griefing or mode conflicts. </p>



<p>In case you're curious, this online mod is made possible by the DSL script loader plugin, allowing the team to introduce features like server connectivity and custom scripting.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="BULLY Online is Happening!!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2J0_BnWKvEA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>The current plan is to open the private official server to <a href="https://ko-fi.com/bullyonline">Ko-Fi support</a><a href="https://ko-fi.com/bullyonline" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">e</a><a href="https://ko-fi.com/bullyonline">rs</a> starting in December. Besides early access, supporting the modding team also provides the following benefits:</p>



<ul>
<li>Developer updates: videos, screenshots, behind-the-scenes commentary</li>



<li>Custom name tag colors (blue for supporters, red for admins)</li>



<li>An in-game digital camera (10 photo slots, shareable with other players)</li>



<li>Priority access to join when the servers are full</li>



<li>Discord role and private chat to communicate with the dev team</li>
</ul>



<p>The goal is to eventually release Bully Online to the public after an early access period. However, the big question is whether the project will even reach that phase. We've seen Rockstar shutting down modding projects before, such as the <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-v-liberty-city-preservation-project-mod/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Liberty City Preservation Project</a>, which attempted to recreate GTA IV inside the GTA V engine.</p>



<p>As for Bully itself, we know that Rockstar started working on a sequel that was, however, eventually canceled. Dan Houser recently claimed that it was due a lack of 'bandwidth'.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/bully-online-mod-promises-let-you-roam-rockstars-classic-with-friends/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Loulan: The Cursed Sand Is a Chinese Hack ‘n’ Slash ARPG Where You Play as a Skeletal Warrior]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/loulan-the-cursed-sand-chinese-hack-n-slash-arpg/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/loulan-the-cursed-sand-is-a-chinese-hack-%E2%80%98n%E2%80%99-slash-arpg-where-you-play-as-a-skeletal-warrior.1336507/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>This morning, indie Chinese developer ChillyRoom unveiled Loulan: The Cursed Sand, one of the games funded through the PlayStation China Hero Project.</p>



<p>The game is a hack 'n' slash action RPG viewed from a Diablo-like camera. The setting is the ancient Silk Road, in China's Western Regions. Loulan: The Cursed Sand tells the tragic love story of an exiled royal guard who returns to the titular fallen kingdom amidst the chaos of war in search of his beloved princess.</p>



<p>Players will step into the game as the skeletal warrior known as 'The Cursed Sand', mastering the power of sand as they explore, solve puzzles, and engage in realistic melee combat against overwhelming odds, including powerful enemies. There's no release date yet, but the game will be released for PC (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3833280/Loulan_The_Cursed_Sand/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/loulan-the-cursed-sand-60d275" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Epic Games Store</a>) and, of course, PlayStation 5.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Loulan: The Cursed Sand Game Reveal Trailer | PC &amp; PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tICq__wjaZ0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>The PC store pages provide an overview of the features you'll find in Loulan: The Cursed Sand:</p>



<ul>
<li>A mysterious world inspired by the lost Kingdom of Loulan along the Silk Road awaits to be explored, with diverse regions and atmospheric, handcrafted levels.</li>



<li>Take control of the skeletal warrior, 'The Cursed Sand', and switch freely between bone and sand forms to experience different combat styles and story interactions.</li>



<li>Engage in dynamic, top-down, one-against-many melee battles where terrain design, enemy composition, and combat mechanics come together to test your skill and strategy.</li>



<li>Hone your skills and master unique sand abilities to solve puzzles, explore intricate levels, and experiment with a variety of combat styles and tactical approaches.</li>



<li>Prepare for thrilling one-on-one encounters with powerful elite enemies and colossal bosses that will test your skills and reflexes to the limit.</li>
</ul>



<p>Loulan: The Cursed Sand certainly looks worth following, although it may be a while before we get to play it. In the meantime, stay tuned.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/loulan-the-cursed-sand-chinese-hack-n-slash-arpg/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>