<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 15:47:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alan Wake 2 PlayStation 5 Pro Performance Improvements Are Being Researched, But They Will Take More Than a Few Weeks; Update 1.2.5 Released]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/alan-wake-2-playstation-5-pro-performance-improvements/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/alan-wake-2-playstation-5-pro-performance-improvements-are-being-researched-but-they-will-take-more-than-a-few-weeks-update-1-2-5-released.1045620/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/alan-wake-2-playstation-5-pro-performance-improvements/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>New Alan Wake 2 PlayStation 5 Pro improvements are being researched by developer Remedy Entertainment, but it will take the team weeks to implement them.</p>
<p>Following the release of today's new <a href="https://www.alanwake.com/story/alan-wake-2-update-notes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1.2.5 update</a>, which introduces some improvements to the base game and Night Springs and The Lake House expansions alongside some fixes, the Finnish studio commented on the lack of PlayStation 5 Pro-specific improvements, saying that player feedback is being heard, and more research is being done on how to improve performance. As the game's PlayStation 5 Pro support was the work of many months, it will take the team more than just a few weeks to implement changes and improvements.</p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">🛠️ A new update for Alan Wake 2 has been released. It includes (fingers crossed) fixes for the missing Pat Maine radio shows, and more fixes, improvements and additions.</p>
<p>As always, update notes are here: <a href="https://t.co/zqW9QhguFF">https://t.co/zqW9QhguFF</a></p>
<p>Please allow additional time for the update to… <a href="https://t.co/DO5Fyl2dnI">pic.twitter.com/DO5Fyl2dnI</a></p>
<p>— Alan Wake 2 (@alanwake) <a href="https://twitter.com/alanwake/status/1861394569448894731?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 26, 2024</a></p></blockquote>

<p>While the Alan Wake 2 PlayStation 5 Pro patch has the merit of finally bringing ray tracing to a console version of the game, the improvements are far from the best we have seen among all Pro-enhanced titles. PSSR, in particular, struggles to deliver significantly better image quality than on the base console, showing how the upscaler currently isn't a good fit for 4K resolution with a low internal resolution like that of the game. Hopefully, Remedy Entertainment will be able to work some of its magic in the future and enhance this version of the game to deliver better image quality and performance.</p>
<p>Alan Wake 2 is now available on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X, and Xbox Series S. You can learn more about the game by checking out my <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/alan-wake-ii-it-truly-was-an-ocean/">review.</a></p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>