<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 15:33:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 OLED Alleged Midframe Protoypes Surfaces Online]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-oled-prototypes/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-oled-alleged-midframe-protoypes-surfaces-online.1248804/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A Nintendo Switch 2 OLED model may have already been prototyped, as the alleged mid-frame of this system is available for purchase on a Chinese marketplace.</p>



<p>As spotted on the Gaming Leaks subreddit, a user on Xianyu, China's largest second hadn marketplace, is selling the <a href="https://www.goofish.com/item?id=949354611120&amp;spm=widle.12011849.copy.detail&amp;ut_sk=1.Z%2FH%2FPLIumhgDABcsA9HPUVaQ_21407387_1753096684884.copy.detail.949354611120.2219551622872">midframes</a> of an<a href="https://www.goofish.com/item?id=949406620126&amp;spm=widle.12011849.copy.detail&amp;ut_sk=1.Z%2FH%2FPLIumhgDABcsA9HPUVaQ_21407387_1753096684884.copy.detail.949406620126.2219551622872"> alleged Nintendo Switch 2 OLED model</a>, which have been <a href="https://www.goofish.com/item?id=949005279175&amp;spm=widle.12011849.copy.detail&amp;ut_sk=1.Z%2FH%2FPLIumhgDABcsA9HPUVaQ_21407387_1753096684884.copy.detail.949005279175.2219551622872">produced in 2024 </a>as a production sample, and are identical to that of the launch model with the exception of lettering on the side and the silver and white color of two of the midframes on sale. While there's nothing that indicates if these are really a production sample for a future Nintendo Switch 2 OLED model, the user has a lot of items on sale that are likely sourced from production factories, such as blank PlayStation 5 PCBs, spare original Switch and Switch 2 parts and more, so there's the chance that these shells are still legit, even if they are not meant for an OLED model. At the very least, they could indicate that more color variants for the new generation Nintendo system are being prototyped and could be coming at a later date.</p>



<p>Although an OLED display would bring some issues, especially for VRR, the Nintendo Switch 2 would greatly benefit from a better display, as the one featured in the launch model leaves much to be desired. Shortly after launch, it became evident that the display's quality is below average, has disappointing HDR support, and is worse than its predecessor's display in terms of motion quality. As Nintendo is likely aware of these issues, seeing a new model with a better display launch only a few years after the original model wouldn't be surprising.</p>



<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 is now available worldwide. You can learn more about the system by checking out Chris' <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/nintendo-switch-2-console/">review.</a></p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-oled-prototypes/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dying Light: The Beast Final Hands-On (PC) Preview]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/dying-light-the-beast-final-hands-on-pc-preview/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dying-light-the-beast-final-hands-on-pc-preview.1248734/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>As part of a world tour leading up to the launch of their latest entry in the zombie survival/parkour action series, Techland recently invited Wccftech and a small number of other content creators and journalists out to California to go hands-on with the opening hours of Dying Light: The Beast.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>While our earlier preview was focused on the protagonist Kyle Crane coming to terms with his newfound Beast powers, this session was more intimate, instead centered around the opening hours of the adventure in Castor Peaks (minus the introductory moments where Kyle breaks free from his decade-long captivity). You could consider these where Kyle Crane slowly gets his groove back, returning to the freerunning zombie slayer he once was.</p>



<p>Castor Peaks represents a much needed change in scenery from the concrete jungles of prior Dying Light games. While there are still scattered settlements with tightly clustered buildings to parkour across, much of the landscape is filled with nature and untouched areas free from human influence. Given Castor Peaks’ status as a nature conservation, this fits the setting and builds out the world into more of a playground where Kyle Crane can let his inner beast truly run wild.&nbsp;</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Given that Dying Light: The Beast carries off a decade from the original Dying Light, there has clearly been the passage of time where the protagonist wasn’t working on his wallclimbing or hammer throwing. In proper open-world gameplay fashion, this leads the player into a series of tutorial segments meant to both onboard the player and return Kyle Crane back to fighting condition. This means the usual gamut of learning how to wield a melee weapon as well as where and how to climb around the environment. White paint splashed across ledges and open windows serve as pathways for the player to traverse and thankfully they blend well enough into the backdrop of Castor Peaks that one might not even notice they’re present unless actively looking for them.</p>



<p>Dying Light: The Beast’s parkour system still takes some getting used to the intricate jankiness to truly appreciate. While it’s true that Kyle Crane can climb up and mantle over just about anything with a flat surface, some of the more puzzling sections can be an exercise in patience. Rather than moving and clamboring at the speed I’d want to move, sometimes I found myself needing to stop and look over at the ledge I wanted to mantle over to and wait for Kyle to stretch his arm out and indicate that he was locked onto the ledge and by jumping, he would automatically reach for it. There were a number of high stakes moments where the sense of urgency was pulled back by needing to wait for the precision to climb above. Given that Dying Light: The Beast is still an RPG at its core with a robust skill tree, I anticipate seeing some new abilities pop up that will mitigate my concerns with the traversal.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>At the same time, combat is the other key pillar to what makes the Dying Light series. Played out entirely in first-person (minus the third-person cutscenes and menus), players will experience the visceral combat through the eyes of Kyle Crane. Whether wielding a one- or two-handed weapon or firearm, zombies are constantly on the move for the protagonist’s flesh and won’t stop until their head is knocked clean off. Dying Light: The Beast features an overhauled dismemberment system and there is a gratuitous amount of gore as Kyle swings away with any implement he can get his hands on. And yes, once again, weapon durability is a constant stuggle to maintain but now that Kyle Crane has been around an apocalypse or two before, he’s skilled enough to repair his weapons on the go with a fair bit of scrap metal and other materials he’s scavenged up. No more having to trade out broken pipes every 90 seconds just because you tried to take on an entire zombie horde instead of taking the high road to run away.</p>


<figure>
<div>

<figure>
<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>
</figure>
<div>
			    		
			    		
				    	<p><span>2 of 9</span>
			    	</p></div>
</div>
</figure>



<p>As this session of Dying Light: The Beast was focused on the early hours of Kyle Crane’s revenge story, many of the more interesting upgrades and Beast powers were locked away for players to rediscover. One thing’s for certain though: years of captivity have turned Kyle Crane into a raging beast.</p>



<p>Dying Light: The Beast will launch on August 22nd, 2025 for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series S|X and PC for $59.99/$69.99 or as a free standalone DLC for those who purchased the Ultimate Edition of Dying Light 2.</p>



<p><em>[Editor’s Note: Travel and accommodations were provided by Techland to attend their preview event in Los Angeles, CA.]</em></p>





			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/dying-light-the-beast-final-hands-on-pc-preview/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ready or Not Soars Past 1 Million Copies Sold On Console In Four Days, Brings Total Sales Past 10 Million]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ready-or-not-past-1-million-copies-sold-consoles-10-million-total-copies-sold/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ready-or-not-soars-past-1-million-copies-sold-on-console-in-four-days-brings-total-sales-past-10-million.1248712/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>VOID Interactive's Ready or Not has surpassed 1 million copies sold on consoles, just four days after its console launch, which brings the game's total sales past 10 million, after it hit <a href="https://wccftech.com/ready-or-not-surpasses-9-million-copies-sold-ahead-of-its-console-launch-this-summer/">9 million copies sold on PC earlier this year</a>.</p>



<p>"<em>When we launched Ready or Not on PC, it took about 36 days to reach 1 million units sold. On console, it took about 3.6 days. I’m incredibly proud of the team and what we’ve accomplished together. It’s a huge moment — and one we don’t take for granted,</em>" said developer and publisher VOID Interactive's chief executive officer, Julio Rodriguez, in a press release. "<em>Game reviews are holding strong as we head into our first weekend, and the team is already hard at work ironing out issues and continuously improving the experience. To our players, partners, and everyone who believed in the project — thank you.</em>"</p>



<figure><figcaption>Ready or Not passes 1 million copies sold on consoles. Image credit: VOID Interactive</figcaption></figure>



<p>VOID Interactive's chief operating officer and creative director, Stirling Rank, added, "<em>The response from console players has completely blown us away. Going from the days of excitement from our Early Access trailer blowing up on PC to seeing the community grow globally so much across platforms &nbsp;is humbling, but &nbsp;testament to the incredible dedication of the entire VOID Interactive team to make this vision a reality for Ready or Not.</em>"</p>



<p>While the console launch has quickly been the next chapter of success in Ready or Not's story, it's also been another chapter marked with controversy. The console release came with an <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1144200/view/526472884483263337?l=english">update and changes</a> that some players considered to be censorship, with certain aspects of gore, nudity, and violence changed in both the console and PC versions of the game. VOID Interactive maintains that the changes were "<em>to support stability and align with policies enforced by global platforms and age rating bodies."</em></p>



<p>VOID Interactive has always emphasized that Ready or Not is a "<em>hyper-realistic tactical FPS,"</em> and the changes ranging from victims in one level being nude, to now being partially clothed, to a child no longer appearing as having been dismembered post-mortem seem to clash with what players believed the original vision of the game to be. </p>



<p>While players on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1144200/Ready_or_Not/#app_reviews_hash">Steam have taken to review-bombing</a> the game to show their displeasure, it's clear that this uproar hasn't had an overtly negative impact on sales. If you're also dissatisfied with the changes, a player released a mod that reverts the changes to how the game was pre-console launch just <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ready-or-not-modder-retcons-censorship-changes-within-an-hour-of-new-patch-going-live">20 minutes after the update went live</a>.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/ready-or-not-past-1-million-copies-sold-consoles-10-million-total-copies-sold/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>