<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 15:54:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Once Human To Get Three New Scenarios, Mobile Release Date Announced]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/once-human-to-get-three-new-scenarios-mobile-release-date-announced/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/once-human-to-get-three-new-scenarios-mobile-release-date-announced.1066317/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/once-human-to-get-three-new-scenarios-mobile-release-date-announced/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, the 2025 roadmap for Once Human was revealed, and with it came some very exciting details for those who play the game. The team behind this horror survival game shared details today on the release date for the mobile version of Once Human, new scenarios coming soon, custom servers, and more. If you want to watch the broadcast for yourself, make sure to check out the video below, where you can watch all of the announcements.</p>
<p><iframe title="Once Human | Nalcott New Year Stream" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EH9Z3B2bjkg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Since its initial release in 2024, Once Human has been highly successful; it has ranked among the top sellers on Steam, and the game has seen <a href="https://wccftech.com/once-human-august-update-out-includes-animal-ranching/">consistent updates</a> that add new content, luring players back into the game and providing them with new ways to enjoy the post-apocalyptic world of Once Human. Below is the official roadmap for 2025, where you can see all of the major updates they have planned for the year.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>Admittedly, the three new scenarios for Once Human won't be released until much later in the year, with a set release date during Q3 2025. However, the scenarios now have names, which are the following: Code: Purification, Code: Deviation, and Code: Broken. The details of the scenarios have also been announced so players can know what to expect from them when they are released.</p>
<p>Code: Purification is a scenario where the players must prevent pollution from taking over the environment by participating in dynamic events. Players will be tasked with teaming up to clear up the pollution and see the world clearly and unpolluted once more. This scenario has several endings that players can see, depending on the actions that they take during the scenario.</p>
<p>Code: Deviation revolves around the ally Deviations, who are the most popular characters in Once Human. In this scenario, players are tasked with hunting and capturing them, to then fuse them together to create new Deviations to battle against each other in a tournament.</p>
<p>Code: Broken is a PvP free-for-all, where players will get to battle over ten days with randomized events, resources, and apocalyptic superweapons that will cause absolute havoc on the battlefield. Much like Code: Purification, there are multiple endings for this event.</p>
<p>One of the other major announcements is that the mobile version of Once Human will be launching in April 2025. Currently, those who register their interest in the Once Human Mobile version <a href="https://tracking.us.nylas.com/l/6ce931d3de6e45e0ae0c615902ae457b/3/deaf88540e237b9a0062cc0ed5c4ad92a48dca5fd94a93e6393c76c69ba45504?cache_buster=1734626229" target="_blank" rel="noopener">via a link</a> will have the chance to win rewards, such as money, in-game rewards, or even an iPhone.</p>


			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation 5 Pro Cyberpunk 2077 Patch is Not Coming Likely Due to Lack of Real Path to Improve Image Quality on the System]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-pro-cyberpunk-2077-patch-lack-image-quality/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-5-pro-cyberpunk-2077-patch-is-not-coming-likely-due-to-lack-of-real-path-to-improve-image-quality-on-the-system.1066314/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-pro-cyberpunk-2077-patch-lack-image-quality/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Cyberpunk 2077 is not getting a PlayStation 5 Pro patch likely due to the lack of a real path to improve image quality on the system.</p>
<p>Replying to a supporter's question during their weekly podcast, the tech experts at <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@DFClipsChannel" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Digital Foundry</a> highlighted how developer CD Projekt Red may have decided not to release a PlayStation 5 Pro patch for their latest game because there was no clear way to offer better image quality, beyond using the console's bigger GPU to enhance the game's Dynamic Resolution Scaling, which is already done via the system's Game Boost feature.</p>
<p>Improving Cyberpunk 2077 ray tracing features could have been among the possibilities on PlayStation 5 Pro, but having been developed with an older SDK, CD Projekt Red didn't have access to certain ray tracing and hardware optimization, and would have had to upgrade SDK first before being able to introduce features like ray-traced reflections or global illumination, something that would have opened more issues and require an engineering effort. Introducing PSSR support, additionally, may not have been worth it, as it may not have offered any substantial improvement over AMD FSR.</p>
<p><iframe title="Cyberpunk 2077: Why Isn't There A PS5 Pro Patch - And What Enhancements Are Possible?" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lz5bowN_SLk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>While Cyberpunk 2077 will not get a PlayStation 5 Pro update, CDPR still hasn't abandoned the game entirely. A new update was released <a href="https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-update-2-2-adds-several-new-customization-features-and-improved-photo-mode/">last week</a>, introducing new features and improvements, such as new customization options for V, new Photo Mode options and more.</p>
<p>Cyberpunk 2077 is now available on PC, PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Xbox Series X, Xbox Series S and Xbox One. The <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/cyberpunk-2077-phantom-liberty-shiny-firmware-update/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Phantom Liberty expansion</a> is also available, but only on PC and current generation systems.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones and the Great Circle AMD FSR 3 Mod Released by PureDark]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-amd-fsr-3-mod-released-by-puredark/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-amd-fsr-3-mod-released-by-puredark.1066161/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-amd-fsr-3-mod-released-by-puredark/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Earlier this week, renowned modder PureDark <a href="https://www.patreon.com/posts/indiana-jones-01-118058876" target="_blank" rel="noopener">released</a> an AMD FSR 3 mod for Indiana Jones and the Great Circle. As usual, the mod is locked behind being a subscriber on his Patreon, and even PureDark told his community:</p>
<p><em>Note that the devs have announced that future updates will include official FSR3 implementation. Think twice before subscribing!</em></p>
<p>Indeed, developer MachineGames confirmed alongside the release of the <a href="https://wccftech.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-update-enables-path-tracing-on-nvidia-rtx-gpus-amd-fsr-to-be-added-later/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">second title update</a> that AMD FidelityFX Super Resolution would be added in a future patch. However, they didn't specifically state whether that would also include the frame generation component, which is indeed available in PureDark's mod and makes a big difference.</p>
<p>Not only that, it even works on portable devices like Valve's Steam Deck. YouTuber Grown Up Gaming tested it and noticed that the performance went from 20-25 frames per second to around 40 frames per second with the upscaling set to Quality. Lowering that to Performance mode provides another 10 frames or so, but at that point, the game doesn't look very good.</p>
<p><iframe title="Steam Deck Indiana Jones and the Great Circle FSR 3 Frame Generation Mod #steamdeck #fsr3" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4BE40VHIbs0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Granted, it is a miracle Indiana Jones and the Great Circle even works on the Steam Deck. The game's <a href="https://wccftech.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-is-the-first-game-to-require-hardware-ray-tracing-support-full-specs-released/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">system requirements</a> technically include hardware ray tracing support, and we all know that the Deck's ray tracing performance is not its strongest suit, to say the least.</p>
<p>It's certainly not like I would like to play this game. If I absolutely had to do it on the go, I'd prefer using GeForce NOW to stream it via cloud and still get ray tracing features and smooth performance. PureDark's mod will probably be more useful to all those desktop users who do not own an NVIDIA GeForce RTX 40 GPU, providing a way to essentially double the frame rate for free.</p>
<p>Whether you plan to use it or not, Indiana Jones and the Great Circle is absolutely worth playing, as I explained in my <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-indiana-at-his-finest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">review</a>:</p>
<p><em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle is an excellent adventure/action game that features one of the best Indiana Jones stories, great level design that rewards exploration, and awesome ray traced visuals. This might just be the best game dedicated to Dr. Henry Walton we've ever seen.</em></p>
<p>At least one story DLC titled The Order of the Giants is on its way, though there's no release window yet.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>