<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 15:32:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grand Theft Auto V Reportedly Heading Back to PS Plus Extra Catalogue]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-v-reportedly-heading-back-to-ps-plus-extra-catalog/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grand-theft-auto-v-reportedly-heading-back-to-ps-plus-extra-catalogue.1346917/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			<div data-nosnippet="">
		
		<ul>
			<li>0-20%: Unlikely - Lacks credible sources</li>
			<li>21-40%: Questionable - Some concerns remain</li>
			<li>41-60%: Plausible - Reasonable evidence</li>
			<li>61-80%: Probable - Strong evidence</li>
			<li>81-100%: Highly Likely - Multiple reliable sources</li>
		</ul>
	</div>


			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-6-delayed-to-november-2026/">Grand Theft Auto VI has been delayed</a>, which means we'll have to keep going back to Grand Theft Auto V to get a fix for Rockstar's best-selling franchise. If you're one of the handful of people who have yet to play one of the highest-selling video games ever, it looks like you'll get another chance, at least on PlayStation. According to <a href="https://www.dealabs.com/magazine/ps-plus-extra-grand-theft-auto-v-revient-bientot-dans-le-catalogue-de-jeux-60766">Billbil-kun at Dealabs</a>, Grand Theft Auto V is heading back to the PS Plus Extra games catalogue.</p>



<p>Billbil-kun and Dealabs have a strong track record when it comes to reporting PS Plus games, whether it's one of, or sometimes all three, of the three games offered for the Essential tier, or one of the games entering the catalogue at the Extra tier.</p>



<p>This report pertains to the latter, as we've already had the <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/10/29/playstation-plus-monthly-games-for-november-stray-ea-sports-wrc-24-totally-accurate-battle-simulator/">three games for November at the PS Plus Essential tier</a> revealed (<a href="https://wccftech.com/stray-playstation-plus-november-2025/">one of which Billbil-kun also correctly reported ahead of the official announcement</a>).</p>



<p>Billbil-kun also predicts that this coming Wednesday, November 12, we'll get the official reveal of what games are coming to the PS Plus Extra catalogue, which will include Grand Theft Auto V.</p>



<p>With GTA VI delayed, it lines up perfectly that GTA V would re-enter the PS Plus Extra catalogue, just to make it as accessible as possible for people wanting to remain immersed in the world of Grand Theft Auto on their consoles. It's already available on Xbox Game Pass, so having it back on PlayStation's subscription service just rounds out where players can find it.</p>



<p>Regarding the additional delay for GTA VI, Take-Two boss <a href="https://wccftech.com/gta-vi-delay-help-rockstar-exceed-expectations-take-two-ceo-never-regretted-delay/">Strauss Zelnick says the company has <em>"never regretted</em>" delaying a game</a>. At least it looks like we'll get another way to play GTA V in the meantime.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-v-reportedly-heading-back-to-ps-plus-extra-catalog/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Genshin Impact Developer miHoYo Will Go For Realistic Graphics For Its Unreal Engine 5 Open-World Game]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/genshin-impact-developer-mihoyo-will-go-for-realistic-graphics-for-its-unreal-engine-5-open-world-game/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/genshin-impact-developer-mihoyo-will-go-for-realistic-graphics-for-its-unreal-engine-5-open-world-game.1346827/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Chinese developer miHoYo, the studio behind the popular <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/genshin-impact-gacha-highjacked/">Genshin Impact</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/zenless-zone-zero-the-perfect-gacha-game-for-those-who-dont-like-gachas/">Zenless Zone Zero</a>, is working on a new game that will be much different from anything it has released so far.</p>



<p><span data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">As spotted on the&nbsp;<a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/mihoyo-is-working-on-new-open-world-game-mmo-pvp-ue5-ai.1346665/" target="_blank">ResetERA forums</a>, the developer is currently working on a fantasy open-world MMO featuring realistic graphics, PvP, an AI-stimulated ecological system, large-scale boss fights, and advanced AI-powered NPCs.</span> These new features will mark a significant shift in gameplay terms, and a considerable step forward from the games the developer is currently supporting.</p>



<figure><figcaption><em>The teaser shared by miHoYo as part of a recruitment effort for their Unreal Engine 5-powered new game</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Besides sharing the first information on the yet to be named game, miHoYo released a video providing a very early look at the visual style the studio is aiming for has also been released, and it looks more technically advanced than anything it has done to date. Hopefully, the developer will also be able to address the known performance issues that plague games powered by the engine to deliver an experience that can be on par with its previous games.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>The upcoming project from miHoYo, alongside other open-world games such as Where Winds Meet, which is <a href="https://wccftech.com/where-winds-meet-ps5-pc-release-date/">launching globally on November 14</a>, seems to signal a radical change for free-to-play open world games, which are doing away with colorful and stylized visuals to offer experiences that are edging ever closer to the PC and console premium AAA experiences. As such, it will be fascinating to see how players will react to these experiences, and if the realistic visuals and advanced AI-powered features will make these games as big a hit as Genshin Impact.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/genshin-impact-developer-mihoyo-will-go-for-realistic-graphics-for-its-unreal-engine-5-open-world-game/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>