<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 15:07:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 New Videos Provide Insightful Specs Comparison With Its Predecessor, CPU Analysis]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-specs-comparison/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-new-videos-provide-insightful-specs-comparison-with-its-predecessor-cpu-analysis.1105764/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-specs-comparison/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A couple of insightful Nintendo Switch 2 videos were shared online, comparing the new system's specs with those of its predecessor and other current generation systems and more.</p>
<p>The new videos, put together by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@FrameRated">FrameRated</a>, are a great way to learn more about the system's specs, how they compare with those of the other current-generation systems and its predecessor, how a comparable PC GPU, the RTX 2050 mobile, handles multiplatform games, what developers will be able to achieve with the system, and more.</p>
<p><iframe title="The Nintendo Switch 2 VS Switch 1: Hardware Specs Compared" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/t-iSleivk6w?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>A second video released a few days earlier also discusses the Nintendo Switch 2 ARM Cortex A78C CPU, whether it may be able to handle future tech, and how memory bandwidth could be a concern in certain cases. You can check out this second video below.</p>
<p><iframe title="The Nintendo Switch 2 CPU: ARM Cortex A78C - is it Powerful Enough?" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/b_PRdx02Slk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>While it is not yet known when the Nintendo Switch 2 will launch worldwide, some people online <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-units-out-priced-350/">claim</a> to have already obtained a unit, such as a Chinese user who obtained a CAD model of the system. If this user's claims are true, then we may be getting more information on the console sooner than early April, when Nintendo will properly unveil the new system in a dedicated Direct.</p>
<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 will be released later this year worldwide. We will keep you updated on the system as soon as possible, so stay tuned for all the latest news.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[God of War Greek Saga Remasters to Be Announced During This Week’s State of Play – Rumor]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/god-of-war-greek-saga-remasters-announced/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/god-of-war-greek-saga-remasters-to-be-announced-during-this-week%E2%80%99s-state-of-play-%E2%80%93-rumor.1105743/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/god-of-war-greek-saga-remasters-announced/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Remasters of the first three entries in the God of War series will be revealed soon, according to rumors circulating online.</p>
<p>According to Reddit user<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1im4gtf/comment/mc0td3a/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> Feeling-Examination6</a>, the three games will be announced during this week's yet-to-be-confirmed State of Play and will be released as part of a collection of some sort later this year. If these remasters are real and coming, it will be very interesting to see how much they will be improved over the already available PlayStation 3 remasters of the first two entries in the series and the remaster of the third released on PlayStation 4 ahead of the release of 2018's God of War.</p>
<p>While we have to take the news about these God of War remasters with a grain of salt, there's some reason to believe the information shared by Reddit user Feeling-Examination6. Just yesterday, the user revealed the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/s/17kFt49uUj" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hell is Us release date</a> before it was confirmed earlier than intended on the Xbox Store. The user also revealed that Ninja Gaiden would be coming back this year, although this could have been a lucky guess, considering the user talked about a reboot, which <a href="https://wccftech.com/ninja-gaiden-4-announced-for-pc-and-consoles-with-a-fall-2025-release-window-ninja-gaiden-2-black-now-available/">Ninja Gaiden 4</a> is not.</p>
<p>The latest entry in the popular series is <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/god-of-war-ragnarok-becoming-a-good-father/">God of War Ragnarok</a>, which is now available on PC and PlayStation consoles. The game was going to be followed by a live service game in development by Bluepoint Games, which was ultimately <a href="https://wccftech.com/god-of-war-live-service-canceled/">canceled</a> along with Bend Studio's next project.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur’s Gate 3 Custom Campaign ‘The Grand Theater – Sell your Lute to the Devil’ Gets First Playable Version]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/baldurs-gate-3-custom-campaign-the-grand-theater-sell-your-lute-to-the-devil-gets-first-playable-version/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldur%E2%80%99s-gate-3-custom-campaign-%E2%80%98the-grand-theater-%E2%80%93-sell-your-lute-to-the-devil%E2%80%99-gets-first-playable-version.1105683/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/baldurs-gate-3-custom-campaign-the-grand-theater-sell-your-lute-to-the-devil-gets-first-playable-version/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Following the <a href="https://wccftech.com/baldurs-gate-3-patch-7-out-now-on-pc-adds-mod-tools-manager-evil-endings-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">release</a> of the official Baldur's Gate 3 modding tools by Larian back in September 2024, the modding community has begun creating full-fledged custom campaigns for the award-winning cRPG. One of the first to get a playable version is '<a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/baldursgate3/mods/14914/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Grand Theater - Sell your Lute to the Devil'</a> by Moezilla. Here's the overview provided by the modder:</p>
<p><em>This is a custom modded campaign set nestled on the outskirts of Baldur's Gate, hidden from the prying eyes of the city, stands an imposing, yet strangely inviting structure: The Grand Theater. The flickering lights of lanterns and the alluring sound of music draw in travelers from far and wide, promising an experience of unparalleled entertainment. However, what lies beneath the polished veneer of extravagant performances and mesmerizing illusions is a darker, more sinister story.</em></p>
<p><em>The theater is owned and operated by a powerful faction known as the Red Wizards of Thay—arcane masters and manipulative schemers whose true intentions are often cloaked in secrecy. As they push their hidden agendas, they have crafted a show unlike any other: a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity for performers to showcase their talents... but at a cost.</em></p>
<p><em>In the halls of the Grand Theater, you’ll find that the show must go on—but the question remains: who will be the star of the final act, and what will they lose to secure their place under the spotlight?</em></p>
<p><em>This is a world where the Red Wizards hold the strings, and you’ll have to decide whether the cost of fame is worth the price of your soul. Will you play your part, or will the Devil demand his due?</em></p>
<p>The modder warns users that they should have finished the base Baldur's Gate 3 campaign first. This is because Larian has reportedly made it so that if you never encountered some NPCs in the default game, they won't appear in modded campaigns, either.</p>
<p>Additionally, version 1.0 is very limited in its feature set. Players will find around two thousand new lines of dialogue (text-only, no voice acting or lip sync), with six quests that can be started but only one that can be currently completed. There's also no combat yet, though the modder plans to add it to version 1.1.</p>
<p><iframe title="Baldur's Gate 3 Mods: This New DND Custom Campaign Just Dropped! | The Grand Theatre" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-mZB_PwAh2s?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Some of the most exciting Baldur's Gate 3 custom campaigns to look forward to include Path to Menzoberranzan by Lotrich (who just <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1oBlmSvi1So" target="_blank" rel="noopener">released</a> a video showing off the mod's progress) and <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/baldursgate3/mods/14844" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Forsaken</a>, which is set in the world of Warcraft, more specifically in the Undead starting zone of Tirisfal Glades. Forsaken is also currently very early, with only the starting area available.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>