<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 23:52:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silent Hill f – Everything We Know About the Brand New Chapter of KONAMI’s Horror Franchise]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/roundup/silent-hill-f-everything-we-know-brand-new-chapter-konami-horror/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/silent-hill-f-%E2%80%93-everything-we-know-about-the-brand-new-chapter-of-konami%E2%80%99s-horror-franchise.1254510/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
<p>After the <a href="https://wccftech.com/silent-hill-2-remake-sells-over-2-million-units-worldwide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">highly successful remake of Silent Hill 2</a>, KONAMI is about to launch Silent Hill f, a brand new installment in its acclaimed horror franchise. This is but one step in the Japanese company's grand plan for the IP, which includes the <a href="https://wccftech.com/silent-hill-remake-bloober/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">remake of the first title</a> (also to be developed by Bloober Team) and the spin-off <a href="https://wccftech.com/silent-hill-townfall-announced-annapurna-no-code-observer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Townfall</a>, which is being made by Screen Burn (formerly No Code). </p>



<p>But Silent Hill f is particularly significant because KONAMI felt that the series was progressively being westernized. This game, in development at Hong Kong-based studio NeoBards Entertainment, was instead conceived as a fully Japanese horror game.</p>



<h2 id="h-release-date-platforms-pricing-editions">Release Date, Platforms, Pricing, Editions</h2>



<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/silent-hill-f-announced-60s-japan-higurashi-ryukishi07/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Announced</a> on October 19, 2022 during that fateful Silent Hill transmission stream, Silent Hill f is <a href="https://wccftech.com/silent-hill-f-launches-on-ps5-xbox-series-x-s-and-pc-in-september-2025-new-gameplay-showcased/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">set to launch on September 25</a> for PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series S|X. Pre-orders are now open, granting all a White Sailor School Uniform costume, an Omamori: Peony equippable item, and an Item Pack that includes one Shriveled Abura-age, one Divine Water, and one First Aid Kit.</p>



<p>The Standard Edition is priced at $69.99, while the Deluxe Edition is $10 more expensive and provides access to the digital art book, the digital soundtrack, and a pink rabbit costume. Moreover, if pre-ordering the Deluxe Edition, users will get 48 hours of early access, which means they'll start playing on September 23.</p>



<h2 id="h-genre-setting-and-story-premise">Genre, Setting, and Story Premise</h2>



<p>Silent Hill f is a survival horror game, much like previous titles. However, it will be set in Japan for the first time. More specifically, it takes place during the 1960s in the fictional town of Ebisugaoka, which was inspired by the real-life Kanayama, Gero, in the Gifu Prefecture, where mountains and forests cover more than 91% of the city area.</p>



<p>Protagonist Hinako Shimizu is just a regular high school student in Ebisugaoka until the isolated town is suddenly enveloped by a dark, mysterious fog. Ebisugaoka suddenly becomes silent as a grave, and it will be up to Hinako to investigate what's going on.</p>



<p>The story was written by the renowned author Ryukishi07 ('<em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Higurashi_When_They_Cry">Higurashi When They Cry</a></em>'), who KONAMI handpicked because they wished for someone who understood the <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-silent-hill-f-deep-dive-digs-into-how-konamis-core-design-concept-of-find-the-beauty-in-terror-drove-the-games-development/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Japanese horror concept</a>. At its core, it is about terror possibly being found even within beauty: when something becomes too immensely beautiful and perfect, it becomes deeply unsettling. For his part, Ryukishi07 claimed that Hinako Shimizu (portrayed in the game by Japanese actress Konatsu Kato) is a protagonist who makes her own choices rather than simply being pulled along by the story. By the way, the story will be entirely standalone, although there will be some references to previous entries.</p>



<p>Fans rejoiced when they learned that historic composer Akira Yamaoka would return for Silent Hill f. Yamaoka has since revealed that he focused on infusing the game's music with the series' Japanese "essence," reflecting his own cultural identity into the work as much as possible. We also know that the sound team traveled to the aforementioned town of Ebisugaoka to record its unique soundscape.</p>



<h2 id="h-gameplay">Gameplay</h2>



<p>Not much has been said or indeed shown about the gameplay of Silent Hill f. We do know it will follow the series tradition of offering players a variety of complex puzzles to solve, as well as many grotesque-looking monsters to deal with. We also don't know its estimated length, but we'll be sure to update this article if the developers provide any indications.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="SILENT HILL f | Release Date Trailer (4k: EN/ESRB) | KONAMI" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/l38Q1XJ2HO8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<h2 id="h-tech-and-specs">Tech and Specs</h2>



<p>Like the Silent Hill 2 remake, Silent Hill f is powered by Unreal Engine 5. The PC system requirements were <a href="https://wccftech.com/silent-hill-f-gets-new-trailer-details-and-pc-requirements/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">revealed</a> in March and don't seem too taxing on paper, although we'll have to test the game ourselves to see if it runs well. The requirements also include confirmation that NVIDIA DLSS and other similar upscaling technologies (presumably AMD FSR and possibly Intel XeSS) will be included. However, we don't know yet if the game will also support frame generation techniques.</p>



<p><strong>Minimum:<br></strong>Requires a 64-bit processor and operating system<br>OS: Windows 11 x64<br>Processor: Intel Core i5-8400 / AMD Ryzen 5 2600<br>Memory: 16 GB RAM<br>Graphics: NVIDIA GeForce GTX 1070 Ti or AMD Radeon RX 5700<br>DirectX: Version 12<br>Storage: 50 GB available space<br>Sound Card: Windows-compatible audio Device.<br>Additional Notes: Playing on minimum requirements should enable playing on Performance quality settings at 30 at 720p. SSD is recommended.</p>



<p><strong>Recommended:<br></strong>Requires a 64-bit processor and operating system<br>OS: Windows 11 x64<br>Processor: Intel Core i7-9700 / AMD Ryzen 5 5500<br>Memory: 16 GB RAM<br>Graphics: NVIDIA GeForce RTX 2080 or AMD Radeon RX 6800XT<br>DirectX: Version 12<br>Storage: 50 GB available space<br>Sound Card: Windows-compatible audio Device.<br>Additional Notes: Playing on recommended requirements should enable playing on Performance settings at 60 FPS or Quality settings at 30 FPS at FullHD (or 4K using NVIDIA DLSS or similar technology). SSD is required.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/roundup/silent-hill-f-everything-we-know-brand-new-chapter-konami-horror/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Phantom Blade Zero Gets Fresh New Gameplay from S-PARTY 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/phantom-blade-zero-new-gameplay-s-party-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/phantom-blade-zero-gets-fresh-new-gameplay-from-s-party-2025.1254462/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>This week, Chinese developer S-GAME hosted S-PARTY 2025, a two-day event in Beijing during which fans could get hands-on with the highly anticipated Phantom Blade Zero. IGN India has posted a 22-minute gameplay video from this new demo that shows some hidden boss fights, secret item discoveries, and new weapons. We've embedded it below.</p>



<p>Phantom Blade Zero is undoubtedly one of the most eagerly awaited games in the action RPG/Soulslike genre, although as you might recall, the developers <a href="https://wccftech.com/phantom-blade-zero-not-soulslike/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">stressed</a> that it is not to be considered a pure Soulslike game.</p>



<p>Last month, S-GAME CEO Soulframe <a href="https://x.com/pbzero_official/status/1937262120418312391" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">clarified</a> exactly what he thinks the game is:</p>



<p><em>Phantom Blade Zero is neither a Soulslike game nor a traditional action game. I've always admired the creators who defined these genres. I spent years immersed in their work, drawing inspiration and learning from their brilliance. But in the process of making this game, we stumbled onto a path we never expected:<br>At first, we just wanted to make a game that brought 'hack and slash' Into a multi layered map. But once the animations and environmental assets came together, everything was "stitched together" by a strong cultural aesthetic — creating something that felt deeply familiar to us, yet is rarely seen or experienced in games.</em></p>



<p><em>Broadly speaking, it falls under the category of ARPGs. But more specifically, maybe it could create a new identity that is Wuxia Action Games? Because here you'll get to experience:</em></p>



<ul>
<li><em>Leaping across rooftops under a rain of arrows; </em></li>



<li><em>Fighting off pursuers atop a speeding carriage;</em></li>



<li><em>Uncovering the truth behind an incident that shocked the world years ago; </em></li>



<li><em>And even more iconic cinema moments.</em></li>
</ul>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Phantom Blade Zero | Exclusive Gameplay Footage | IGN India" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/q5eTmj0gDzQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Soulframe also added that Phantom Blade Zero will feature three difficulty settings (Wayfarer, Gamechanger, and Hellwalker, although the latter is only unlocked for a second playthrough with New Game+), unlike traditional Soulslike titles.</p>



<p>The game still has no release window, but we might learn more at Gamescom, where S-GAME is set to bring a large presence with a massive 500 m² booth in Hall 6 (B-050G) featuring over 60 demo stations. The demo is said to be the most comprehensive shared publicly to date, a full 1-hour playable experience featuring all-new boss battles, striking level design, immersive storytelling, and visceral blade-to-blade combat.</p>



<p>We'll be at Gamescom and look forward to checking out the new demo after <a href="https://wccftech.com/phantom-blade-zero-gamescom-hands-on-preview-brutally-engaging/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reporting on last year's Phantom Blade Zero hands-on</a>.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/phantom-blade-zero-new-gameplay-s-party-2025/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>