<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 18:34:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones Might Get a Sequel, Hints Phil Spencer, Though He Certainly Sounds More Interested in Owned IPs]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/indiana-jones-might-get-a-sequel-hints-phil-spencer-though-he-certainly-sounds-more-interested-in-owned-ips/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiana-jones-might-get-a-sequel-hints-phil-spencer-though-he-certainly-sounds-more-interested-in-owned-ips.1167102/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/indiana-jones-might-get-a-sequel-hints-phil-spencer-though-he-certainly-sounds-more-interested-in-owned-ips/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>During a wide-ranging interview <a href="https://variety.com/2025/gaming/news/microsoft-phil-spencer-minecraft-movie-fallout-season-2-1236352653/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">with Variety</a>, Microsoft Gaming CEO Phil Spencer also discussed the success of Indiana Jones and the Great Circle. The executive appeared to hint at the potential for a sequel, but he also made it clear that he'd like Microsoft-owned studios to work first and foremost on owned franchises (which Indiana Jones is obviously not, being licensed by Disney).</p>
<p><em>I will say, we’re really happy with “Indy” and the players and the reception. We do think there’s life in that franchise, and I’m just gonna leave it at that. We’re launching on PlayStation here pretty soon. I think that’ll be a cool moment. I was really inspired by Machine Games taking someone else’s IP and doing something so unique, and I’m inspired about what that team can do next. Certain people were kind of pushing them on the first person versus third person. And I think once you play it, you realize you are Indy. But going forward, I also want to give the teams the ability to do our own games and our own franchises. We have a lot of room to tell new stories, as well. And I want to make sure that’s an option for us.</em></p>
<p>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle has just launched on Sony's PlayStation 5 console, around four months after its debut on PC and Xbox Series S|X. PlayStation 5 Pro <a href="https://wccftech.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-playstation-5-pro-global-illumination-improvements/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">offers the best way to play the game on consoles</a>, although the PC version with path tracing enabled remains superior for those with the hardware to run it.</p>
<p>A story DLC called The Order of Giants is scheduled to be released later this year. Of course, a full-fledged sequel is what fans really want after playing the <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-indiana-at-his-finest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">excellent base game</a>. It sounds like it could happen, provided that Disney reaches a deal with Microsoft.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Wars Outlaws: A Pirate’s Fortune DLC Arriving Next Month, Leaked Trailer Reveals]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/star-wars-outlaws-a-pirates-fortune-dlc-arriving-next-month/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/star-wars-outlaws-a-pirate%E2%80%99s-fortune-dlc-arriving-next-month-leaked-trailer-reveals.1167072/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/star-wars-outlaws-a-pirates-fortune-dlc-arriving-next-month/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The release date and trailer for <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-star-wars-outlaws-patch-drops-forced-stealth-missions/">Star Wars Outlaw's</a> next DLC expansion, A Pirate's Fortune, have leaked online ahead of its scheduled reveal during Star Wars Celebration tomorrow, with the currently unlisted trailer appearing on <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/star-wars-outlaws-a-pirates-fortune-reveal-trailer-launches-on-may-15th.1167036/">ResetEra</a>. Since publishing, Ubisoft has taken the trailer down.</p>
<p>Both the trailer and the video's description spoil the surprise that players will be able to step back into the boots of Kay Vess and experience an adventure with fan-favorite character Hondo Ohnaka on <strong>May 15, 2025</strong>, with the DLC including its own season pass, just as the first DLC, Wild Card, did.</p>
<p>A press release from Ubisoft also reveals that a demo for Star Wars Outlaws will be made available starting today on PS5, Xbox Series X/S and PC. The demo will be approximately three hours long, featuring "<em>parts</em>" of the full game, hinting that you'll likely get to jump around in the game's story so you can experience major aspects like open-world exploration, ship battles, and stealth missions. Save data from the demo will not carry over to the full game, should you choose to pick it up.</p>
<p>The new expansion will also feature cosmetic items inspired by the recent television series Star Wars: Skeleton Crew, including an outfit for Nix, a trophy for the speeder, and trinkets for your speeder and Kay's ship, the Trailblazer.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>This new trailer doesn't reveal too much about the story for A Pirate's Fortune, only that you'll be pitted against Stinger Tash and her band of Rokana Raiders while you race against them to do a bit of tomb raiding in the Khepi Tomb.</p>
<p>A Pirate's Fortune is the second of two planned DLCs for Star Wars Outlaws, after which Ubisoft is likely to announce that it has moved on to future projects, especially when considering that, by Ubisoft's admission, Outlaws did not have the <a href="https://wccftech.com/star-wars-outlaws-has-only-sold-1-million-copies-since-launch-learning-curve-assassins-creed-shadows/">commercial performance</a> Ubisoft was expecting from it.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[F1 25 to Support Path Tracing (only on PC), Improved Facial Animations with NVIDIA Audio2Face]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/f1-25-to-support-path-tracing-only-on-pc-improved-facial-animations-with-nvidia-audio2face/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/f1-25-to-support-path-tracing-only-on-pc-improved-facial-animations-with-nvidia-audio2face.1166988/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/f1-25-to-support-path-tracing-only-on-pc-improved-facial-animations-with-nvidia-audio2face/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Codemasters announced today that <a href="https://wccftech.com/f1-25-announced-for-may-30-launch-pc-requirements-released/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">F1 25</a> will join the extremely elite club of games supporting path tracing. Just like with all the others (Cyberpunk 2077, Alan Wake 2, Black Myth: Wukong, Indiana Jones and the Great Circle, Portal with RTX), the feature is a PC exclusive.</p>
<p>On the subject, the developer said:</p>
<p><em>Expanding on Ray Tracing technology and available as a new “Ultra Max” option in the graphics settings, light now follows every bounced path, including that from indirect lighting and multiple reflections. Shade, light, and colours dynamically shift as they would in real-life, whether you’re racing under the thousands of lights in Bahrain or navigating the castle section on Baku at sunset.</em></p>
<p><em>If you have a PC capable of experiencing it, Path Tracing is the most realistic simulation of light on track that we’ve ever delivered.</em></p>
<p>These aren't the only visual and technical improvements that fans will find in F1 25. Tonemapping and light balance improvements promise a more dramatic effect in all types of weather, with better representation of changes in cloud cover. There are also some enhancements to the track surface shader, which now displays more pronounced tyre and lock-up marks as well as physical changes based on other collected real-world data.</p>
<p>The addition of light detection and ranging scanning (LIDAR) makes tracks far more accurate overall. LIDAR also helped trees and foliage better match the species, placement, size, and shape of their real-life counterparts, with new additions such as cherry blossom trees in Suzuka.</p>
<p><iframe title="F1 25 Authenticity and Customization Deep Dive" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/w2E_sML5CfY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Codemasters also introduced NVIDIA Audio2Face. This technology (already seen in STALKER 2: Heart of Chornobyl) improved the facial animations that players will see during modes such as Career and Braking Point. The reintroduced press interviews now capture drivers delivering their responses in a more authentic fashion, with this technology extending to facility heads in My Team. Lastly, PS5 Pro console users will enjoy split-screen racing at 60 frames per second in this year's edition of the official F1 racing game.</p>
<p>Codemasters hasn't shared the system requirements for path tracing usage on PC, but we'll let you know once it does. F1 25 will be available on May 30 across PC and consoles.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>