<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 13:36:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GeForce NOW Gets Native Steam Deck App]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/geforce-now-gets-native-steam-deck-app/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/geforce-now-gets-native-steam-deck-app.1201473/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/geforce-now-gets-native-steam-deck-app/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>NVIDIA announced today that the GeForce NOW native Steam Deck application, previously announced at CES 2025, is now <a href="https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/geforce-now/download/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">available for download</a>.</p>
<p>It was already possible to run GeForce NOW on the Steam Deck via the built-in browser. However, that wasn't an optimal solution. Even the installation has been streamlined, as users can just download the app from the official website and follow the instructions to install it on their portable device. NVIDIA says that playing a game via its cloud gaming platform can consume up to 50% less battery life compared to running the same game natively on the Steam Deck.</p>
<p>GeForce NOW on the Steam Deck supports streaming at up to 1440p 120 FPS when connected to a<br>
monitor or 4K 60 FPS when connected to a TV. NVIDIA will further improve the GeForce NOW<br>
streaming experience and is looking to add new features, including support for 90 FPS in a future update.</p>
<p>HDR10 is supported on GeForce NOW for premium members (those subscribed to the Ultimate or Performance tier). It works when using the Steam Deck in handheld mode (provided that you've got a <a href="https://wccftech.com/steam-deck-oled-announced-reservations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam Deck OLED</a>, since the original model does not support HDR10) or when connected to a TV or monitor. Of course, if you're subscribed to those tiers, you'll also enjoy RTX features such as ray tracing/path tracing, NVIDIA DLSS 4, and Reflex on supported games.</p>
<p>Speaking of games, today's GeForce NOW Thursday also reveals six new PC games to the ever-growing GeForce NOW library:</p>
<p>● Nice Day for Fishing (New release on Steam, May 29)<br>
● Cash Cleaner Simulator (Steam)<br>
● Tokyo Xtreme Racer (Steam)<br>
● The Last Spell (Steam)<br>
● Tainted Grail: The Fall of Avalon (Steam)<br>
● Torque Drift 2 (Epic Games Store)</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Death Stranding 2: On the Beach May Not Get Any Additional Episodic DLC, as Hideo Kojima Thinks Releasing This Type of Content Has Become Outdated]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-no-dlc-plans/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-may-not-get-any-additional-episodic-dlc-as-hideo-kojima-thinks-releasing-this-type-of-content-has-become-outdated.1201389/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-no-dlc-plans/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Kojima Productions currently has no plans to release episodic DLC content for Death Stranding 2: On the Beach, as Hideo Kojima thinks releasing this type of content is no longer a trend.</p>
<p>Speaking during the 19th episode of his KOJI10 radio show, as reported on X by <a href="https://x.com/naven0m" target="_blank" rel="noopener">NV</a>, the legendary game designer discussed the possibility of the second entry in the series getting paid DLC expansions after launch, confirming that there are currently no plans for this sort of content, as he thinks it is no longer a trend to release this sort of content. Plans, however, may change in the future in this regard. For now, Kojima-san revealed that the studio plans to support the game after launch with bug fixes and improvements, possibly adding something that didn't exist in the first entry in the series.</p>
<p>During the latest episode of the KOJI10 radio show, Hideo Kojima also revealed that Death Stranding 2: On the Beach originally featured some sort of hair system. This system involved Sam cutting his hair and shaving his beard, which would both grow back as time passed. Players could trim the beard, dye the hair, and so on by standing in front of a dedicated mirror. The system, however, eventually ended up getting scrapped as Sam isn't just a customizable, player-created avatar.</p>
<p>During the radio show, Hideo Kojima also discussed the original concept of Death Stranding 2: On the Beach, which he confirmed <a href="https://wccftech.com/kojima-gaming-hardware-will-ultimately-vanish-death-stranding-2-was-rewritten-to-resonate-more-with-players/">a few years back</a> to have changed following the COVID pandemic in 2020. Initially, he planned on releasing a 1.5 expansion of the original that would be centered around exploring the other continents in a world where flight is impossible. As the idea of DLC became outdated, however, the plan was scrapped, and he began working on a full-fledged sequel that was also scrapped due to the pandemic, and the only thing that has been kept of the original concept is the opening, which was originally meant to be something like a post-credits scene for Death Stranding Director's Cut to bridge the gap between the first and the second entry in the series.</p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Episode 19 of <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/KOJI10?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#KOJI10</a> «Let’s Answer Questions About Death Stranding 2»</p>
<p>Hair System Removed, Pre-COVID Storyline, DLCs? <a href="https://t.co/CG2frbVZz0">pic.twitter.com/CG2frbVZz0</a></p>
<p>— NV (@naven0m) <a href="https://twitter.com/naven0m/status/1927303228393148572?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 27, 2025</a></p></blockquote>

<p>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach launches on PlayStation 5 on June 26th.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Persona 4 Remake Won’t See the Return of Another Beloved Voice Actress]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/persona-4-remake-wont-see-the-return-of-another-beloved-voice-actress/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/persona-4-remake-won%E2%80%99t-see-the-return-of-another-beloved-voice-actress.1201371/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/persona-4-remake-wont-see-the-return-of-another-beloved-voice-actress/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The rumored Persona 4 remake will likely feature an entirely new voice cast, as another actress won't be returning to voice one of the main characters.</p>
<p>Speaking on Bluesky, Erin Fitzgerald, who voiced Chie Satonaka in every Persona 4 game except the original PlayStation 2 release, confirmed they were not asked to reprise the role. With Yuri Lowenthal also <a href="https://wccftech.com/persona-4-remake-seemingly-confirmed-by-spider-man/">confirmed</a> not to play Yosuke in the remake, it's looking more and more like the remake will have a brand new voice cast, which wouldn't be surprising, considering the same happened in <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/persona-3-reload-review/">Persona 3 Reload,</a> the remake of the third entry in the series developed by ATLUS released last year.</p>
<blockquote data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:ww224eri4xcmzrjaoc3ijje4/app.bsky.feed.post/3lqbi6257w22d" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreic3etwz7clazoedao6oc7j3zdz2i6d72xwplcjkymvwhtkthqnzdq" data-bluesky-embed-color-mode="system">
<p lang="en">For those asking, I have not been asked to reprise my role as Chie Satonaka in the Persona 4 remake.</p>
<p>RIP 😭😭😭😭😭😭</p>
<p>I am blessed to have recorded as many Persona 4 games as I did playing her.</p>
<p><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:ww224eri4xcmzrjaoc3ijje4/post/3lqbi6257w22d?ref_src=embed">[image or embed]</a></p>
<p>— Erin Fitzgerald still on strike (<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:ww224eri4xcmzrjaoc3ijje4?ref_src=embed">@erinfitzgerald.bsky.social</a>) <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:ww224eri4xcmzrjaoc3ijje4/post/3lqbi6257w22d?ref_src=embed">May 29, 2025 at 2:39 AM</a></p></blockquote>

<p>A Persona 4 remake has been rumored to be in the works for a while, but an official announcement has yet to be made. If the game is launching before Persona 6, however, it will likely be announced before long, possibly during any of the upcoming not-E3 summer showcases. These include the annual Summer Game Fest showcase on June 6th, of which the series' publisher SEGA is one of the <a href="https://wccftech.com/summer-game-fest-has-record-setting-60-partners-for-this-years-showcase/">partners</a>, and the Xbox Games Showcase on June 8th.</p>
<p>According to rumors, the Persona 4 remake isn't the only project that will bring back older entries of the series to modern gaming platforms. A remaster of Persona 2 is <a href="https://wccftech.com/persona-4-remake-persona-2-remaster-development/">reportedly</a> also in the works, and it will feature not only both entries in the series, Innocent Sin and Eternal Punishment, but also a new translation. This remaster should be released on all current generation consoles, including the Nintendo Switch 2.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA Rumored to Be Laying Off Another 400 Developers]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ea-rumored-to-be-laying-off-another-400-developers/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-rumored-to-be-laying-off-another-400-developers.1201365/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/ea-rumored-to-be-laying-off-another-400-developers/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Yesterday, Electronic Arts (EA) <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-report-reveals-ea-canceled-black-panther-game-and-shut-down-cliffhanger-games/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> the closure of Cliffhanger Games, a Seattle-based studio <a href="https://wccftech.com/ea-new-studio-led-by-middle-earth-shadow-of-mordor-veteran-kevin-stephens/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">founded</a> six years ago by Kevin Stephens, who previously worked as Vice President and Studio Head on Middle-earth: Shadow of Mordor. Cliffhanger Games was working on an original Black Panther game.</p>
<p>Exactly a month ago, EA <a href="https://wccftech.com/ea-has-canceled-another-incubation-project-at-respawn-layoffs-reportedly-hit-the-apex-legends-star-wars-jedi-and-incubation-teams/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">laid off</a> around 300–400 employees at Respawn Entertainment, too, and it may not be over yet. <a href="https://x.com/eXtas1stv/status/1927820651370271111?t=55cOa-shSeAFKbqb3REK9A&amp;s=19" target="_blank" rel="noopener">According to the Spanish insider eXtas1s</a>, the publisher could be preparing to shut down Codemasters' central headquarters, removing another 400 developers or so.</p>
<p><em>I have learned that around 400 more layoffs are coming at EA, the total closure of Codemasters' headquarters, and that those developers will be integrated into EA Sports (F1) and a new Need For Speed that is already in development.</em></p>
<p>This would be another major blow to the games industry, which has suffered many closures and layoff rounds in the first half of 2025 after a couple of tough years.</p>
<p>EA <a href="https://wccftech.com/codemasters-might-be-actually-acquired-by-ea-instead-of-take-two-according-to-a-new-report/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">surpassed</a> Take-Two as the buyer of Codemasters on the finishing line. Take-Two had offered nearly a billion dollars, but Electronic Arts closed the deal at $1.2 billion. After the acquisition, Codemasters CEO Frank Sagnier <a href="https://wccftech.com/codemasters-ceo-ea-is-like-our-cinderella-shoe-a-perfect-fit-they-listen-but-dont-force-us/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">claimed</a> Electronic Arts was a perfect fit.</p>
<p>However, Codemasters suffered major restructuring in the last four years at the hands of its new owner. Three years ago, the Cheshire-based team <a href="https://wccftech.com/codemasters-cheshire-will-join-criterion-to-work-on-need-for-speed/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">was merged with Criterion</a> to work on Need for Speed. In late 2023, EA <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-world-interactive-suffers-embracers-restructuring-codemasters-also-hit-by-layoffs-at-ea/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">performed</a> a first round of layoffs at Codemasters. Just a few weeks, we also <a href="https://wccftech.com/codemasters-shows-off-f1-25-gameplay-confirms-wrc-games-are-on-pause/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">learned</a> that the studio won't be making any more WRC games, as the license was reacquired by <a href="https://wccftech.com/nacon-is-once-again-publishing-wrc-games-new-wrc-series-in-development/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nacon</a>.</p>
<p>It appears that EA is positioning Codemasters to be solely focused on making new Formula 1 games. On that note, F1 25 was just released, and you can read Chris Wray's take on it <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/f1-25-review/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>:</p>
<p><em>F1 25 is a good game, make no mistake about that. With a near-flawless presentation, improved my team mode, and additional features, there's a lot to do. There are a few pitfalls here and there, but nothing that takes away from what is another genuinely good release by Codemasters.</em></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former Sony Exec Labels Microsoft’s Approach to Gaming Subscriptions as ‘Dangerous’]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/former-sony-exec-labels-microsofts-approach-to-gaming-subscriptions-as-dangerous/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/former-sony-exec-labels-microsoft%E2%80%99s-approach-to-gaming-subscriptions-as-%E2%80%98dangerous%E2%80%99.1201332/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/former-sony-exec-labels-microsofts-approach-to-gaming-subscriptions-as-dangerous/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Former Sony executive Shuhei Yoshida was interviewed by the website <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/shuhei-yoshida-warns-subscription-services-could-become-dangerous-for-developers" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Game Developer</a> during the recent Gamescom LATAM event, where he spoke, among other things, about the different approaches that Microsoft and Sony have to gaming subscriptions like Game Pass and PlayStation Plus. Yoshida, who was president of Sony's Worldwide Studios group for eleven years (2008-2019) and <a href="https://wccftech.com/shuhei-yoshida-leaving-sony-interactive-entertainment-on-january-15-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">left the company in January,</a> called Microsoft's stance 'dangerous' for developers:</p>
<p><em>If the only way for people to play games is through subscriptions that's really dangerous, because what type of games can be created will be dictated by the owner of the subscription services. That's really, really risky because there always must always be fresh new ideas tried by small developers that create the next wave of development. But if the big companies dictate what games can be created, I don't think that will advance the industry.</em></p>
<p><em>I believe the way Sony approached subscriptions is healthier. You know, not to overpromise and to allow people to spend money to buy the new games. After a couple of years, there won't be many people willing to buy those games at that initial price, so they'll be added to the subscription service, and there'll be more people to try those products in time for the next game in the franchise to come out.</em></p>
<p>Of course, it's unsurprising that he would align more with Sony's policy against adding day-one first-party games to subscriptions. However, it should be noted that Microsoft has stressed on many occasions that they have absolutely no intention of ever removing the customer's ability to purchase games separately from Game Pass. It was always designed as an additive way to engage, not a complete replacement of direct purchases.</p>
<p>Following his departure from Sony, Yoshida also talked about other topics. A few months ago, he <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-studios-ceo-is-not-forcing-teams-to-work-on-live-service-games-shuhei-yoshida-says/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">stressed</a> that the man who replaced him as the head of PlayStation Studios, Hermen Hulst, isn't forcing any of the first-party studios to work on live service games.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, he <a href="https://wccftech.com/ghost-of-yotei-will-be-even-better-than-tsushima-says-shuhei-yoshida/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">shared</a> that he played quite a bit of Ghost of Yōtei before leaving Sony, and it's shaping up to be even better than Ghost of Tsushima. Ghost of Yōtei is now set to <a href="https://wccftech.com/ghost-of-yotei-release-date/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">launch</a> on October 2.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>