<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 13:22:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nioh 3 is The Culmination of Every Team NINJA Action RPG – Hands-On Preview]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nioh-3-is-the-culmination-of-every-team-ninja-action-rpg-hands-on-preview/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nioh-3-is-the-culmination-of-every-team-ninja-action-rpg-%E2%80%93-hands-on-preview.1360606/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>The Nioh series has long been considered as one of the best Soulslike around, but the franchise created by Team NINJA couldn't be much different from the vast majority of games inspired by FromSoftware's Souls series. <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/nioh-review-a-samurai-epic-with-souls/">With a bigger focus on mechanical complexity and action gameplay features</a>, the two entries in the series played more like pure action games, with a loot system reminiscent of the Diablo series sprinkled on top to deliver a very engaging experience for those willing to put in the time and effort to understand the franchise's many interwoven mechanics.</p>



<p>Although the second entry in the series improved on pretty much every element of its predecessor, <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/nioh-2-the-complete-edition-grave-no-bar/">Nioh 2 felt more like an expansion of the original</a>, rather than a proper sequel. At a glance, the differences between the two games were minimal, and overall, the experiences they offered were somewhat similar. Only the most advanced players would notice, and appreciate, the many mechanical improvements made to the original's framework.</p>



<p>This is definitely not what will happen with Nioh 3 when it launches in a few months on PC and PlayStation 5. Though the third entry in the series retains many of the franchise's familiar features, it spices them up considerably with some significant tweaks that have the potential of making it not only the best entry in the series, but also one of the best "masocore" action role-playing games developed by Team NINJA.</p>



<figure><figcaption><em>Nioh 3 open-field map design sets the game apart the most from its predecessors</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>The most significant change Nioh 3 will feature over its predecessors is a different level design philosophy, which is evident right from the get-go. Instead of featuring self-contained missions which can be selected from a main map, the new entry in the series introduces the concept of open fields - much bigger maps which offer plenty of rewards for those willing to explore them fully. As highlighted during a presentation I attended last week in Paris, Nioh 3 isn't an open-world game: although the maps are bigger than ever before, their size is small, compared to the maps of modern open-world games, and don't offer the same amount of side activities such games may offer.</p>



<p>To be honest, I wasn't too thrilled to learn that Nioh 3 would be moving away from its predecessors' progression system. I always felt the older setup of picking missions from a map, though dated,  was more immediate and worked great in the context of the game, allowing the player to focus more on understanding and utilizing the combat, skills, and loot mechanics to their full potential to take down the most powerful of enemies. However, after spending around 4 hours exploring a never-before-seen map set in the Bakumatsu era (1853-1867), I couldn't help but appreciate how the open-field design of the new maps presents the main and sub-missions in a more immersive way, which remain the core of the experience.</p>



<p>While the general design felt standard fare for a game developed by Team NINJA, many of the new mechanics related to the open-field maps make exploration feel fun and rewarding. As players explore every corner of the map, collecting items, completing the Myths sidequests given by various NPCs, conquering Enemy Bases, and defeating the powerful Crucible Wraiths, the region's Exploration Level will increase, providing a variety of permanent buffs, including base stats increases and an enhanced map showing the entire area and markers for exploration spots and collectibles. </p>



<p>As the rewards for engaging with these new exploration mechanics also include items and gear, of which there's a lot in true Nioh tradition, skill points required to unlock weapon-specific and general skills via the game's different skill trees, and buffs offered by friendly Yokai and the new Jizo Statues which can provide a variety of blessings exploring maps in Nioh 3 is set to be as much as a big part of the experience as combat is.</p>



<figure><figcaption><em>The Bakumatsu map offers plenty of exploration opportunities in Nioh 3</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>The presence of open-field maps, however, doesn't mean that Nioh 3 lacks the closed-off areas featured in past entries in the series. Each of the maps will also feature a Crucible level where players must defeat a powerful boss to purify the area, a task made more difficult by the Life Corrosion mechanics, which temporarily reduce maximum life while inside a Crucible. To offset this, the Amrita Gauge fills up faster, giving players faster access to the powerful Living Artifact form, which makes a return from past entries in the series. </p>



<p>The design of these Crucible levels is reminiscent of the design of the main missions in the past entries in the series, featuring somewhat intricate layouts which are made more dynamic by some new mechanics, such as the ability to jump, reminiscent of <a data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://wccftech.com/review/wo-long-fallen-dynasty-shadows-dont-die-twice/">Wo-Long: Fallen Dynasty</a>, which give locations better verticality and the Spirit Veins, which can be used with a corresponding Guardian Spirit to explore locations further.</p>



<p>Although exploration and traversal are seeing the biggest improvement in Nioh 3 over its predecessors, combat has also undergone some rather significant changes, which players were already able to appreciate a few months back with <a href="https://wccftech.com/nioh-3-visual-performance-improvements/">a PlayStation 5-exclusive timed demo</a>. </p>



<p>The addition of the Ninja fighting style, on paper, may have felt like a needless complication, but in reality, it adds up a lot of effective combat options, the ability to use Ninjustsu more freely than in past entries in the series, and use a total of four weapons, two per fighting style. With a major focus on agility and "trickier" weapons like the Tonfa and Kusarigama, the Ninja fighting stance essentially works as another Stance that can be as effective as the Samurai fighting style.</p>



<figure><figcaption><em>Nioh 3 new combat mechanics up the game's complexity and fun-factor considerably</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>With its three stances and focus on hard-hitting weapons like hammers and the Odachi, the Samurai fighting style will instantly feel familiar to anyone who played the previous entries in the series. However, significant changes have been implemented in this fighting style as well. For starters, the High Stance attacks are slightly slower than in Nioh 2, and generally riskier to use. </p>



<p>Although I didn't have the time for thorough testing, I replayed Nioh 2 extensively again before this hands-on opportunity, and the difference was immediately noticeable. Deflection mechanics, which essentially involve a well-timed block, are also a significant focus of this fighting style. With the visual better highlighting when one has been performed, a reactive playstyle definitely seems viable.</p>



<p>Besides the two fighting styles, the biggest change Nioh 3 brings to the combat experience is the introduction of Martial Arts mechanics. These special techniques performed with different button combinations or at the end of combo strings which were already present in the previous entries in the series, can be chained one after the other once the new Arts Gauge has been filled and the Arts Proficiency mode enabled by using a Strong Attack or Martial Arts to create devastating combos that can keep even bosses stunlocked for their duration. </p>



<p>Don't expect this to be a free-win mechanic, however, as Martial Arts still use Ki, and players need to manage it to keep their combo going. This system is heavily reminiscent of <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/stranger-of-paradise-final-fantasy-origin/">Stranger of Paradise: Final Fantasy Origin</a>'s combat mechanics, and are a welcome addition that will make it easier for players of all skill levels to unleash the complex combos advanced players have discovered in Nioh 2.</p>



<p>As I wasn't used to these new mechanics, it took me a few minutes to move beyond what the muscle memory developed in Nioh 2 was making me do, but once I started getting used to them, they made combat more engaging, and taking on both returning and new Yokai was exhilarating. Particularly interesting was the final boss battle of the build against Takasugi Shinsaku, a real samurai who contributed heavily to the Meiji Restoration. Armed with a not exactly historically accurate gun, the samurai's fighting style is rather peculiar, which forced me to put the new mechanics to good use quickly. In true series tradition, the battle was challenging, but after a few tries, and a little bit of luck, I was able to take him down.</p>


<figure>
<div>

<figure>
<figure><figcaption><em>Nioh 3 promises to be even more intense than its predecessors, thanks to a slew of new gameplay mechanics</em></figcaption></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>
</figure>
<div>
				    		
				    		
					    	<p><span>2 of 9</span>
				    	</p></div>
</div>
</figure>



<p>Weaving together the core Nioh series mechanics with features inspired by Stranger of Paradise: Final Fantasy Origin, Wo-Long: Fallen Dynasty and even <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://wccftech.com/review/rise-of-the-ronin-neo-edo-open-world/">Rise of the Ronin</a>, Nioh 3 feels like the culmination of all the masocore action RPGs developed by Team NINJA. How the exploration mechanics will hold up for dozen hours remains to be seen, but the first proper taste of the experience has undoubtedly made me even more excited about the game, and I cannot wait for <a href="https://wccftech.com/nioh-3-new-trailer-provides-new-quick-look-at-story-and-gameplay-confirms-release-date/">February 6, 2026 when Nioh 3 launches on PC and PlayStation 5</a> to appreciate better the depth of the combat mechanics, which promise to outdo anything Team NINJA has done to date.</p>



<p><em>Travel and accomodation expanses for the Paris preview event covered by the publisher.</em></p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/nioh-3-is-the-culmination-of-every-team-ninja-action-rpg-hands-on-preview/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Friday 2025 Nintendo Switch 2 Deals: Save on Console, Accessories and Games]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/black-friday-2025-nintendo-switch-2-deals-save-on-console-accessories-and-games/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-friday-2025-nintendo-switch-2-deals-save-on-console-accessories-and-games.1360510/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 has only been out for a few months by now, but the new generation Nintendo console is already set to become one of the most successful modern gaming systems. If you have yet to become a proud owner of the system, or if you are looking into getting some new accessories or games, some Black Friday 2025 deals will allow you to do all this while saving money.</p>



<p>Below, you’ll find our comprehensive list of every Nintendo Switch 2 Black Friday 2025 deal worth your time across the console, accessories and games, as well as any deal for the original Switch, its accessories and games that can be played on the new system via backward compatibility.</p>



<div><h2>Table of contents</h2><ul><li><a href="#h-nintendo-switch-2-consoles-black-friday-2025-deals" data-level="2">Nintendo Switch 2 Consoles Black Friday 2025 Deals</a></li><li><a href="#h-nintendo-switch-2-accessories-black-friday-2025-deals" data-level="2">Nintendo Switch 2 Accessories Black Friday 2025 Deals</a></li><li><a href="#h-nintendo-switch-2-games-black-friday-2025-deals" data-level="2">Nintendo Switch 2 Games Black Friday 2025 Deals</a><ul><li><a href="#h-a" data-level="3">A</a></li><li><a href="#h-b" data-level="3">B</a></li><li><a href="#h-c" data-level="3">C</a></li><li><a href="#h-d" data-level="3">D</a></li><li><a href="#h-f" data-level="3">F</a></li><li><a href="#h-l" data-level="3">L</a></li><li><a href="#h-m" data-level="3">M</a></li><li><a href="#h-o" data-level="3">O</a></li><li><a href="#h-p" data-level="3">P</a></li><li><a href="#h-r" data-level="3">R</a></li><li><a href="#h-s" data-level="3">S</a></li><li><a href="#h-t" data-level="3">T</a></li><li><a href="#h-w" data-level="3">W</a></li><li><a href="#h-u" data-level="3">U</a></li><li><a href="#h-x" data-level="3">X</a></li></ul></li></ul></div>



<h2 id="h-nintendo-switch-2-consoles-black-friday-2025-deals">Nintendo Switch 2 Consoles Black Friday 2025 Deals</h2>



<p>Unlike the PlayStation 5 and the Xbox Series X|S, there's only a single Nintendo Switch 2 model available on the market. Having only been released earlier this year, any significant deal is unlikely to be available during Black Friday 2025. Make sure to check back often if any become available at some point.</p>



<ul>
<li>No deals available yet!</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-nintendo-switch-2-accessories-black-friday-2025-deals">Nintendo Switch 2 Accessories Black Friday 2025 Deals</h2>



<p>A wide selection of Nintendo Switch and Nintendo Switch 2 accessories is available for purchase, including additional Joy-Con controllers, Pro controllers, cases and screen protectors, USB-C cameras, and more. Here are the best Black Friday 2025 deals for official and third-party Nintendo Switch 2 accessories</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B01N7RUZ49/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">Nintendo Switch AC Adapter: $30.99 (11% off) on Amazon</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07VGGLB2W/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">PDP Travel Case with Wrist Strap for Nintendo Switch: $28.29 (29% off) on Amazon</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C2B8CCR1/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">SanDisk 1 TB microSDXC Licensed for Nintendo Switch: $114 (23% off) on Amazon</a></li>



<li><a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07QD6R5L7/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">SanDisk 512 GB microSDXC Licensed for Nintendo Switch: $54.99 (8% off) on Amazon</a></li>



<li><a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07QD6R5L7/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">SanDisk 256 GB microSDXC Licensed for Nintendo Switch</a>: <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07QD6R5L7/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">$26.99 (16% off) on Amazon</a></li>



<li><a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07KXQX3S3/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">SanDisk 128 GB microSDXC Licensed for Nintendo Switch: $17.49 (13% off) on Amazon</a></li>



<li><a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C2JP88N4/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">SanDisk 64 GB microSDXC Licensed for Nintendo Switch</a>: <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C2JP88N4/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">$14.39 (22% off) on Amazon</a></li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-nintendo-switch-2-games-black-friday-2025-deals">Nintendo Switch 2 Games Black Friday 2025 Deals</h2>



<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 launched with a plethora of great games, ranging from titles developed directly by Nintendo's studios to third-party ports that allow users to enjoy some of the best games of the current console generation on the go. And with these deals, you will be able to get many of them, as well as original Switch games, at reduced prices.</p>



<h3 id="h-a">A</h3>



<ul>
<li><a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D7DWX9SH/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">Ace Attorney Investigations Collection (Nintendo Switch): $24.99 (38% off)</a> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D7DWX9SH/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">on Amazon</a></li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-b">B</h3>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D7J4X75B/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">Balatro Special Edition (Nintendo Switch): $19.99 (33% off) on Amazon</a></li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-c">C</h3>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DPGQBYJC/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">CAPCOM Fighting Collection 2 (Nintendo Switch): $24.99 (38% off) on Amazon</a></li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-d">D</h3>



<ul>
<li><a data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(16, 80, 126, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(16, 80, 126, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D71SHR5B/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">DRAGON QUEST III HD-2D Remake (Nintendo Switch): $34.99 (42% off) on Amazon</a></li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-f">F</h3>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DCKFWW1V/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">Final Fantasy I-VI Collection Anniversary Edition (Nintendo Switch): $39.99 (47% off) on Amazon</a></li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-l">L</h3>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DW9LWS1K/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">Legacy of Kain Soul Reaver 1&amp;2 Remastered (Nintendo Switch): $19.99 (33% off) on Amazon</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0FDT6LHV6/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">Little Nightmares III Standard Edition: $29.99 (25% off) on Amazon</a></li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-m">M</h3>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0F6481V7V/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">Madden NFL 26: $29.99 (57% off) on Amazon</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CXW2C84K/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">Monster Hunter Stories Collection (Nintendo Switch): $24.99 (31% off) on Amazon</a></li>



<li><a data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(16, 80, 126, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0FKCXCHRP/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">Mario + Rabbids Dual Pack (Nintendo Switch): $14.99 (50% off) on Amazon</a></li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-o">O</h3>



<ul>
<li><a data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(16, 80, 126, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(16, 80, 126, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0FK8SHB29/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">Once Upon a Katamari: (Nintendo Switch) $29.99 (25% off) on Amazon</a></li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-p">P</h3>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0FK7YV5RB/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">PAC-MAN WORLD 2 Re-PAC: $19.99 (33% off) on Amazon</a></li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-r">R</h3>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0FPRNCXKB/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">Red Dead Redemption (Nintendo Switch): $24.99 (17% off) on Amazon</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0F3KMTVYQ/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">Rune Factory Guardians of Azuma: $49.99 (17% off) on Amazon</a></li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-s">S</h3>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CWN17C4L/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">Shin Megami Tensei V: Vengeance Standard Edition (Nintendo Switch): $17.99 (70% off) on Amazon</a></li>



<li><a data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(16, 80, 126, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09TGH9D5T/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">Splatoon 3 Standard Edition (Nintendo Switch): $41.99 (30% off) on Amazon</a></li>



<li><a data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(16, 80, 126, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BVSF61J2/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">Splatoon 3 Expansion Pass (Nintendo Switch): $17.99 (30% off) on Amazon</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0F6423HHW/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">Split Fiction: $39.99 (20% off) on Amazon</a></li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-t">T</h3>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DFDX1VHM/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">Tales of Graces f Remastered (Nintendo Switch): $19.99 on Amazon</a></li>



<li><a data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(16, 80, 126, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0FMBHXHWR/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">Tales of Xillia Remastered (Nintendo Switch): $29.99 (25% off) on Amazon</a></li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-w">W</h3>



<ul>
<li><a data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(16, 80, 126, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CK1DRHVT/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">WarioWare: Move It! Standard Edition (Nintendo Switch): $39.99 (20% off) on Amazon</a></li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-u">U</h3>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CJ3ZGM7Y/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">Unicorn Overlord (Nintendo Switch): $24.99 (58% off) on Amazon</a></li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-x">X</h3>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0B1HMYB1V/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">Xenoblade Chronicles 3 Standard Edition: $41.99 (30% off) on Amazon</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0B9259PXG/?tag=wccftech0a9-20">Xenoblade Chronicles 3 + Expansion Pass (Nintendo Switch - digital code): $62.98 ( 30% off) on Amazon</a></li>
</ul>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/black-friday-2025-nintendo-switch-2-deals-save-on-console-accessories-and-games/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed IV: Black Flag Remake Is Reportedly Targeting March 2026 Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-iv-black-flag-remake-targeting-march-2026-launch/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-iv-black-flag-remake-is-reportedly-targeting-march-2026-launch.1360495/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			<div data-nosnippet="">
		
		<ul>
			<li>0-20%: Unlikely - Lacks credible sources</li>
			<li>21-40%: Questionable - Some concerns remain</li>
			<li>41-60%: Plausible - Reasonable evidence</li>
			<li>61-80%: Probable - Strong evidence</li>
			<li>81-100%: Highly Likely - Multiple reliable sources</li>
		</ul>
	</div>


			
			
			
			<p>The remake of Assassin's Creed IV: Black Flag is just a few months away from launching, according to a new rumor <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-black-flag-remake-set-to-launch-before-march/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">published by Insider Gaming</a>. </p>



<p>As part of Ubisoft's quarterly and half-year financial results (<a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-announces-imminent-closing-transaction-with-tencent-minority-stakeholder-vantage-studios/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">covered here</a>), which were just released, the publisher confirmed an unannounced game in its lineup of titles due to be released before the end of the fiscal quarter (March 2026). According to Insider Gaming, this is indeed the remake of Assassin's Creed IV: Black Flag, the 2013 game that first introduced sea-based combat and exploration to the franchise, which later inspired the ill-fated standalone game Skull &amp; Bones.</p>



<p>The first rumors about this project <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-remake/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">started emerging in June 2023</a>. About a year later, Ubisoft CEO Yves Guillemot <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-remakes-inbound-ubisoft-boss-confirms/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">confirmed</a> that Assassin's Creed fans could look forward to some remakes, but did not specify which of the games would get this kind of treatment. In June 2025, though, it was actor Matt Ryan (who voiced the protagonist, Edward Kenway) who <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-remake-practically-confirmed-by-edward-kenways-actor/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">let slip</a> that fans might soon get to play as Edward all over again. Later, Ryan kind of regretted being this open because Ubisoft <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-edward-kenway-actor-threatened-with-lawsuit-by-ubisoft/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">threatened him with a lawsuit</a>.</p>



<p>Finally, in September, French website Jeux Video Magazine <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-assassins-creed-iv-black-flag-remake-major-changes-rumor/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">shared</a> some actual details about the remake. According to their sources, the Assassin's Creed IV: Black Flag remake will cut the modern-day sequences, which were among the weakest in the original, to replace them with more content featuring Edward Kenway. Moreover, it will be updated to incorporate the RPG mechanics that have been introduced with Assassin's Creed Origins and have since been featured in Assassin's Creed Odyssey, Assassin's Creed Valhalla, and the most recent installment, Assassin's Creed Shadows.</p>



<p>Insider Gaming reports that the game will launch 'the week of March 23', which falls just before the end of Ubisoft's fiscal year. If the launch is really this close, an official announcement at The Game Awards, due to air on December 11, 2025, appears to be inbound. There, we might also see new gameplay of the Prince of Persia remake, which is also scheduled to launch before the end of March 2026.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-iv-black-flag-remake-targeting-march-2026-launch/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>