<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 09:45:51 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Black Flag Remake Practically Confirmed by Edward Kenway’s Actor]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-remake-practically-confirmed-by-edward-kenways-actor/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-black-flag-remake-practically-confirmed-by-edward-kenway%E2%80%99s-actor.1231509/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The long-rumored Assassin's Creed Black Flag remake has been practically confirmed by Matt Ryan, who voiced protagonist Edward Kenway in the original game. </p>



<p>Ryan, who also played DC's John Constantine in various live action and animated shows, spontaneously <a href="https://x.com/TheRealZephryss/status/1939392046151926243">told</a> a fan the following when signing autographs at a convention:</p>



<p><em>Have you beaten the game? Well, you may have to beat it again. Especially this one. There's a reason I say that, but I can't say anything.</em></p>



<p>The first time we heard about the Assassin's Creed Black Flag remake was exactly two years ago, when Kotaku <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-iv-black-flag-remake-rumor-skull-and-bones-dev/">reported</a> that Ubisoft planned to modernize the fourth mainline installment in the series, originally launched in 2013. Interestingly, that report also mentioned that Ubisoft Singapore would be helping the Montréal studio in crafting the remake. This makes sense, as Black Flag's excellent naval combat and exploration mechanics inspired Ubisoft Singapore's <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/skull-and-bones/">Skull and Bones</a> game.</p>



<p>In October 2024, insider Tom Henderson <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-remake-is-reportedly-closer-than-we-thought/">revealed</a> that the project was even further in development than previously thought. Ubisoft originally planned for Assassin's Creed Shadows to be released in late 2024 and the Assassin's Creed Black Flag remake in November 2025, but the delay of Assassin's Creed Shadows to February 2025 also impacted the remake, which is now likely to launch in 2026.</p>



<p>Even so, we might not be far from an official announcement, especially with Matt Ryan teasing it so openly. Chances are it may be revealed at a dedicated Ubisoft event or, more likely, between Gamescom Opening Night Live and The Game Awards 2025 in December.</p>



<p>How excited are you for the Assassin's Creed Black Flag remake? Let us know in the comments!</p>





			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-remake-practically-confirmed-by-edward-kenways-actor/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>