<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 15:44:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Respect The Player’s Time’: Lords of the Fallen II Game Director James Lowe Discusses Key Principles Defining The Game – Interview]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/respect-the-players-time-lords-of-the-fallen-ii-game-director-james-lowe-discusses-key-principles-defining-the-game-interview/</link>
            <guid>1393663</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Lords of the Fallen, the soulslike created by CI Games and Hexworks, is among the many hardcore action RPGs released in the past few years. <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/lords-of-the-fallen-frustration-your-side/">Even with some critical flaws</a></strong>, the game managed to capture the attention of fans of the genre with a unique dual world setup and a <em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">"player first"</em> approach which became evident following the game's launch in September 2023. This approach led to the launch of multiple updates that <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-lords-of-the-fallen-2-0-is-a-massive-improvement-over-the-launch-version/"><strong>addressed many of the game's launch flaws and added a significant amount of new features.</strong></a></p>



<p>The development of <a href="https://www.lordsofthefallen.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Lords of the Fallen II</strong></a> seems to be anchored to a similar respect. While adding new features on top of the foundation led by its predecessor, the new game will respect player's time by providing an overall better experience right from launch.</p>



<p><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed"><a data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" href="https://wccftech.com/lords-of-the-fallen-ii-gets-first-look-at-gameplay-in-new-trailer/">Following the gameplay reveal at this year's The Game Awards</a></strong>, we sat down with James Lowe, Game Director of Lords of the Fallen II, to discuss the sequel’s more brutal combat, the evolution of the Umbral realm, and the core philosophy guiding development this time around.</p>



<h3 id="h-the-brutality-of-dismemberment">The Brutality of Dismemberment</h3>



<p><strong>Q: The new feature that seems to define the game is the dismemberment system, which is a rare mechanic for a Soulslike. How did the idea for this system originally come about? </strong></p>



<p><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">A:</strong> The dismemberment system grew out of a desire to make combat feel more physical, more brutal, and more reactive to the player’s actions. We wanted enemies to visibly reflect the damage they’ve taken, rather than simply falling to the floor when dispatched. When we were exploring ways to push the game’s darker tone while also reinforcing combat viscerality, dismemberment felt like a natural extension. We want players to finish encounters, look back and see the limbs of their foes scattered across the landscape.</p>



<h3 id="h-a-more-invasive-umbral-realm"><strong>A More Invasive Umbral Realm</strong></h3>



<p><strong>Q: The new Umbral realm has been defined as "more sinister," and that it will "step into you." What does this thematically and mechanically mean for the player? </strong></p>



<p><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">A:</strong> Thematically, Umbral represents a much more invasive force this time around. It’s not simply a parallel world you observe, it’s something that actively intrudes on the player’s experience, reinforcing the sense that the world itself is hostile.</p>



<p>On the mechanical front, Umbral applies more constant pressure. It reacts more aggressively to player presence, influences combat and exploration more directly, and creates a heightened sense of tension the longer you remain within it. Visually, we’ve also pushed to ensure that Umbral feels distinct from Axiom in every region, with greater variation in mood, structure, and environmental storytelling.</p>



<h3 id="h-addressing-enemy-density-and-world-navigation"><strong>Addressing Enemy Density and World Navigation</strong></h3>



<p><strong>Q: One major piece of feedback from the original was that high enemy density often felt frustrating rather than challenging. How have you re-evaluated enemy placement and spawn logic? </strong></p>



<p><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">A:</strong> The feedback around enemy density was taken very seriously. Difficulty should come from intentional encounter design, not from overwhelming the player with sheer numbers or unavoidable ranged pressure. In <em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Lords of the Fallen II</em>, enemy placement and spawn logic have been reworked to emphasize clarity, spacing, and purpose. Encounters are designed around specific combat challenges... the result is difficulty that feels demanding but fair, and far less arbitrary.</p>



<p><strong>Q</strong><strong data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)">: How has world design evolved to address concerns about confusing map layouts and navigation?</strong> </p>



<p><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">A:</strong> World readability was a key focus for the sequel. Environmental landmarks, improved flow between areas, and more intuitive spatial logic all contribute to a world that still feels dense and mysterious, but far less confusing to navigate. And as a last resort if players are truly lost, we’re bringing back the Umbral Lamp guidance mechanic... which directs players to the next vestige.</p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Lords-of-the-Fallen-2-Player-First-scaled.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>The shortcomings of the original are being used to make Lords of the Fallen II a better experience right from launch</em></figcaption></figure>



<h3 id="h-narrative-and-player-progression"><strong>Narrative and Player Progression</strong></h3>



<p><strong>Q: It has been said that the sequel will feature a "more accessible and character-driven" approach. How are you achieving this without sacrificing the deep lore the genre is known for? </strong></p>



<p><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">A:</strong> The narrative approach is more mission driven this time, which helps ground the story emotionally and provide clearer motivations for the player. However, we’ve been careful not to sacrifice the genre’s strengths. The aim is clarity without over-explanation, giving players stronger narrative anchors while still rewarding curiosity and interpretation.</p>



<p><strong>Q: The original was criticized for upgrade mechanics that disincentivized experimentation. How does the sequel tackle this? </strong></p>



<p><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">A</strong>: In the sequel, we’ve taken steps to reduce friction around upgrades and progression so that trying something new feels exciting rather than risky. The goal is to maintain meaningful choices while removing unnecessary barriers.</p>



<h3 id="h-technical-stability-and-post-launch-support"><strong>Technical Stability and Post-Launch Support</strong></h3>



<p><strong>Q</strong><strong data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-processed">: Given the stuttering issues with some Unreal Engine 5 titles, what has been implemented to guarantee a smooth day one experience?</strong> </p>



<p><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">A:</strong> Our experience launching one of the earliest UE5 titles gave us valuable insight... these learnings have informed how we approach optimisations in <em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Lords of the Fallen II</em> from day one of production. We’re also working very closely with our partner, Epic, to proactively design around known constraints.</p>



<p><strong>Q: If you could distill all the learning from the community's feedback into one key principle that defines the development of Lords of the Fallen II, what would it be?</strong> </p>



<p><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">A:</strong> Respect the player’s time. That means clearer systems, stronger onboarding, great performance, and an overall experience that challenges as opposed to frustrates. Everything we’ve built in <em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Lords of the Fallen II</em> is guided by that idea.</p>



<p><strong data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(232, 230, 227, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-processed">Thank yo</strong><strong>u</strong><strong data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(232, 230, 227, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-processed"> for your time!</strong></p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/respect-the-players-time-lords-of-the-fallen-ii-game-director-james-lowe-discusses-key-principles-defining-the-game-interview/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Potato Mode Incoming’: Monster Hunter Wilds Could Be Coming to Nintendo Switch 2, and the Community’s Reaction Doesn’t Disappoint]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/potato-mode-incoming-monster-hunter-wilds-could-be-coming-to-nintendo-switch-2-and-the-communitys-reaction-doesnt-disappoint/</link>
            <guid>1393630</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>While opinions may vary on how Monster Hunter Wilds evolves the series' signature formula and gameplay, there's no denying that the game's performance on PC and consoles isn't where it should be. <span data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-processed"><a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://wccftech.com/the-performance-improvements-of-monster-hunter-wilds-title-update-4-are-set-to-make-a-significant-difference/" target="_blank"><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Title Update 4 is a step in the right direction for sure</strong></a>, but more work is needed besides&nbsp;<a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://wccftech.com/over-100-performance-improvements-are-coming-to-monster-hunter-wilds-next-week/" target="_blank"><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">the over 100 performance improvements introduced</strong></a>&nbsp;to finally address what is, sti</span>ll today, one of the game's biggest issues, if not the biggest.</p>



<p>Besides working on improving Monster Hunter Wilds' performance, however, some datamined information suggests that CAPCOM could be working on something else as well: <strong>a Nintendo Switch 2 port of the game.</strong></p>



<p>As reported on the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/monsterhunterleaks/"><strong>Monster Hunter Leaks subreddit</strong></a>, some dedicated users took a good look at the aforementioned Title Update 4, discovering some information on the potential arrival of <strong>Tempered Gogmazios</strong> and additional content in the future. The most interesting discovery, however, is the addition of some platform information mentioning a <strong>"nsw2UpgradeEdition"</strong>, possibly referencing a Nintendo Switch 2 release for the game.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Considering how Monster Hunter Wilds runs on PC and consoles, the community's reaction didn't disappoint. <span><em>"Game barely runs on PC properly, and they expect it to port to Switch 2?"</em>&nbsp;said <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1pxx67z/comment/nwe8ta9/"><strong>Ayyzeee</strong></a> on the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/"><strong>Gaming Leaks and Rumors subreddit</strong></a>, echoing what most of the community thinks about this port, which looks more impossible than the solid <a href="https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-nintendo-switch-2-pc-settings-excellent-port/"><strong>Cyberpunk 2077</strong></a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/this-is-an-incredible-port-final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade-nintendo-switch-2-demo-leaves-community-stunned-with-near-ps5-visual-fidelity/"><strong>Final Fantasy VII Remake Integrade</strong></a> Nintendo Switch 2 ports.</span> </p>



<p><em>"The Steam Deck can barely run this as is, and now we have a SW2 port? </em><span><em>Good luck,"</em>&nbsp;said <strong><a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-tu4-datamine-has-references-to-switch-2.1393483/post-149415472">Kindekuma on the ResetERA forums</a></strong>, further highlighting how the community doesn't think bringing Monster Hunter Wilds to Nintendo Switch 2 is the b</span>est idea.</p>



<p>Other users didn't miss the chance to joke on what could be expected out of this Nintendo Switch 2 port. <em>"Now at a blistering 480p/20fps"</em>, <em>"Are they going to upscale 160 × 144px to 1080p?"</em> said ResetERA users <strong><a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-tu4-datamine-has-references-to-switch-2.1393483/post-149414158">Mars People</a></strong> and <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-tu4-datamine-has-references-to-switch-2.1393483/post-149415184"><strong>Melhadf.</strong></a> <em>"Potato Mode"</em> is also a recurring joke, as highlighted by <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-tu4-datamine-has-references-to-switch-2.1393483/post-149419351"><strong>Dale Copper's image</strong></a>.</p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Monster-Hunter-Wilds-Nintendo-Switch-2-potato-mode.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>This is the level of visual fidelity the community expects in the potential Monster Hunter Wilds Nintendo Switch 2 port</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Jokes aside, <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">how possible is a Monster Hunter Wilds Nintendo Switch 2 port?</strong> As the Nintendo console already proved to be a more than capable system with some <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><a data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-star-wars-outlaws-well-docked/">excellent multiplatform ports</a></strong>, there's no denying that getting the latest entry in the series to run properly on the system can be a challenge. </p>



<p>Currently, the Steam Deck struggles to run the game properly, even with aggressive upscaling, so the game would require significant optimization for the system to achieve a stable 30 FPS. Still, as the <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-nvidia-dlss-impress-rog-ally-x-comparison/"><strong>Nintendo Switch 2 supports NVIDIA DLSS</strong></a>, this port could be surprisingly good, especially if performance continues to improve on other platforms as well.</p>



<p>Besides performance, which continues to remain a significant issue, Monster Hunter Wilds also suffered from a very low challenge level. This issue, thankfully, was addressed by the game's post-launch updates, <span>to the extent that the game's director, Yuya Takuda, hopes&nbsp;<a href="https://wccftech.com/i-would-appreciate-it-if-you-could-pick-it-up-again-monster-hunter-wilds-director-pleads-with-lapsed-players-to-return/" target="_blank"><strong>lapsed players will return to the game</strong></a>, which, in my opinion,&nbsp;<a href="https://wccftech.com/review/monster-hunter-wilds-peak-hunting/" target="_blank"><strong>still deserves to be played</strong></a>, despite</span> its issues.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/potato-mode-incoming-monster-hunter-wilds-could-be-coming-to-nintendo-switch-2-and-the-communitys-reaction-doesnt-disappoint/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>