<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 19:54:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Talos Principle: Reawakened – In The Beginning – Flying Cubes Puzzle Guide]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/how-to/talos-principle-reawakened-flying-cubes-puzzle-guide/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-talos-principle-reawakened-%E2%80%93-in-the-beginning-%E2%80%93-flying-cubes-puzzle-guide.1166193/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/how-to/talos-principle-reawakened-flying-cubes-puzzle-guide/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/the-talos-principle-reawakened-launches-on-april-10-for-playstation-5-xbox-series-pc/">The Talos Principle: Reawakened</a> came with a new expansion for players to dig their puzzle teeth into called In the Beginning, on top of everything else in the remaster.</p>
<p>The 18 puzzles in the new expansion are some of the toughest in the entire Talos Principle series, which is a credit to developer Croteam and the Talos Principle community since 16 of those 18 puzzles were designed <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=31026X886738&amp;isjs=1&amp;jv=15.7.1&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwccftech.com%2Fhow-to%2Fthe-talos-principle-reawakened-in-the-beginning-eclipse-puzzle-guide%2F&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.steampowered.com%2Fnews%2Fapp%2F2806640%2Fview%2F519709875052217858&amp;xs=1&amp;xtz=240&amp;xuuid=856e40b29b36265e272b3ed9bb5c7e57&amp;xjsf=other_click__auxclick%20%5B2%5D">in collaboration with members of the game's community</a>.</p>
<p>This guide will walk you through completing the Flying Cubes puzzle in the Egypt section of the In the Beginning expansion in The Talos Principle: Reawakened.</p>
<h2>The Talos Principle: Reawakened - In the Beginning - Flying Cubes Puzzle Guide</h2>
<p>Flying Cubes is a fun puzzle until it's suddenly not, and you're stuck trying to fit the last piece of it together so you can walk out of the puzzle area with your tetromino in tow. 3/4 of the puzzle is relatively easy for any Talos Principle veteran to solve. It's that last bit that takes a little extra finagling you might not immediately think of.</p>
<p>If you just want a hint, I'll say that crossing the beams is your friend here. If you want the solution, read on.</p>
<h3>Phase One</h3>
<p>As in many Talos Principle puzzles, you first need to acquire all the tools you need to solve the rest of the puzzle.</p>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>After entering the puzzle area, look immediately to your left and climb the ladder, where you'll find a jammer and a pressure switch. Grab the jammer, step on the switch, and watch a cube fly through the air onto another pressure switch. Now you understand where the puzzle gets its name and the final objective. You need to get four boxes to fly through the air, land on the four pressure switches, and open the tetromino gate.</li>
</ul>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>Jammer in hand, walk off the ledge, fall back to the ground, and then head further into the rest of the puzzle area, where you'll see two blue barrier shields, one to your left and one in front of you. Use the jammer on the one to your left. Walk past the barrier you just jammed, and you'll see the other two items you need to solve the puzzle. One connector is just out in the open, and another is trapped behind a blue barrier shield.</li>
</ul>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>Use the connector out in the open to free the trapped one by connecting the blue beam with the blue node that turns off the barrier trapping the other connector. Once the shield is down, grab the connector. For simplicity, from here on, I'll be saying C1 for connector 1 and C2 for connector two.</li>
</ul>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>Place C1 on the pressure switch that sits immediately in front of the red laser and connect it to the red beam. Grab C2 and connect it to C1 and the other two red nodes in your immediate vicinity. One of those nodes will make your jammer redundant, as they keep the same shield barrier off. Now you can pick up the jammer and bring it to the other side of the barrier so that you have the jammer, C1, and C2 on the same side of the barrier.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Phase Two</h3>
<p>All right, at this point, you have all the tools you need for the puzzle in one place. As you read through the rest of this guide, you'll see that you can do these next parts in whatever order you want, but the way I'm going to lay it out is that you'll do the most confusing part first, so you can breeze through everything else.</p>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>You'll notice that the red nodes you have lasers connected to are both keeping shield barriers off. Take the jammer and walk it across the opposite side of the far shield barrier, the one that leads to a corner of the puzzle area, where you'll find two fans blocking your path to a box and a blue laser behind a window connecting to a blue node that keeps one of the fans operational. Use the jammer to redundantly keep the same shield barrier down that the red laser is already disabling. Make sure you're using it on the inside of the puzzle area with the fans and the box, so you can walk both C1 and C2 to where the jammer is, as you'll need them both for these next steps.</li>
</ul>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>Pick up C1, connect it to the far red node, and place it on the opposite side of the wall where it would directly clash with the blue beam keeping one of the fans on.</li>
</ul>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>Pick up C2 and connect it to where the blue beam is coming from and C1. When you put it down, you'll create a loop that cuts off the beam keeping one of the fans on.</li>
</ul>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>Grab the jammer, and jam the other fan so you can grab the box with both fans turned off. Use the jammer and both connectors to bring the box to the main puzzle area by going through the same steps you used to get to the box in the first place. Then use the jammer to turn off the shield barrier at the top of the stairs.</li>
</ul>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>Walk the box to the top of the stairs and place it directly in front of the fan before stepping on the pressure switch to the right of the fan to activate it. This will send the box flying, where it will land on one of the four pressure switches, which will open the gate to the tetromino.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Phase Three</h3>
<p>Grabbing that box and getting it to its pressure switch final destination took me the longest to figure out and is the most confusing part of this puzzle. Everything from here on out is pretty simple and also pretty easy to spot now that you've been around the whole of the puzzle area.</p>

<ul>
<li>Use the jammer to disable the shield barrier on the left side of the main puzzle area, where you went to grab C1 and C2. You can leave the jammer as is the for the rest of the puzzle.</li>
</ul>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>The last two boxes are sitting on top of elevated towers, and they're already ready to be launched by fans activated by blue and red laser nodes. Grab C1 and connect it to the blue laser and the blue node on the far right side of the puzzle to launch the first box.</li>
</ul>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>Grab C1 and place it in front of the red beam on the pressure switch and connect C1 to the red laser. Grab C2 and connect it to C1 and the red node on the left side of the main puzzle area to launch the final box.</li>
</ul>

<figure></figure>

<p>With all four boxes on the elevated pressure switches, the gate to the tetromino will drop, and you can grab your prize.</p>
<p>You can check out our review for more on <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/the-talos-principle-reawakened-i-know-im-a-person-but-not-a-genius/">The Talos Principle: Reawakened</a>.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bloober Team Showcases First Look At Cronos: The New Dawn Gameplay]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/bloober-team-showcases-first-look-at-cronos-the-new-dawn-gameplay/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bloober-team-showcases-first-look-at-cronos-the-new-dawn-gameplay.1166028/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/bloober-team-showcases-first-look-at-cronos-the-new-dawn-gameplay/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>After surprising everyone with its better-than-expected remake of <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/silent-hill-2-restless-dreams-town/">Silent Hill 2</a>, Bloober Team's next project, a brand-new game called <a href="https://wccftech.com/cronos-the-new-dawn-gets-deep-dive-from-bloober-team/">Cronos: The New Dawn</a>, looks like it's the next survival horror game players should keep their eyes on.</p>
<p>Bloober Team showcased our first honest look at gameplay from Cronos: The New Dawn in a new gameplay trailer, where fans of survival horror titles will see some similarities to popular games in the genre like Dead Space, but that's not to say Cronos: The New Dawn isn't doing anything new.</p>
<p>Like merging, for example. Enemies in Cronos: The New Dawn can 'merge,' meaning your job isn't done once you've shot an enemy dead. You need to burn the body. Otherwise, another enemy will take that dead bit of flesh on the ground and merge with it to make itself even stronger.</p>
<p>Suddenly, you're facing a bigger, badder enemy than you were before. If you keep letting enemies merge with the ones you thought you already took out, you can quickly find yourself in an even more terrifying situation. It's an additional layer of combat that means you'll always have to be on your toes between managing the enemies walking towards you and those you've already put down.</p>
<p><iframe title="Cronos: The New Dawn | Official Gameplay Trailer |  DON'T LET THEM MERGE" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZblwGH-C7eg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>In a press release, co-director and producer on Cronos: The New Dawn, Jacek Zięba, writes, "<em>Imagine this: a distorted mix of sci-fi, time travel, retro-futuristic dread, and body horror—all set against the gritty backdrop of&nbsp; 80s Poland. What a ride, right? And whatever you do… don't let them merge.</em>"</p>
<p>Co-director and designer Wojciech Piejko adds, "<em>How do you fight them? Fire! Burn the </em><br>
<em>fallen before they merge with living creatures. The merge changes the game, adding a </em><br>
<em>whole new layer of strategy to combat. Push your survival instincts to the max.</em>"</p>
<p>When we get our hands on Cronos, it'll be interesting to see how merging impacts combat, and what else the game has in store for survival horror fans. After all, Bloober Team has declared that it won't be making "<em><a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/bloober-team-claims-its-finished-making-shitty-games/">shitty</a></em>" games anymore.</p>
<p>Cronos: The New Dawn doesn't have an official release date yet, but we know it'll arrive on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X/S sometime in 2025. This means it'll be the studio's first new title to test that declaration.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Outer Worlds 2 Has Way More Expansive Worlds Filled with Fun Stories and Cool Stuff to Find, Says Obsidian]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-outer-worlds-2-has-way-more-expansive-worlds-filled-with-fun-stories-and-cool-stuff-to-find-says-obsidian/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-outer-worlds-2-has-way-more-expansive-worlds-filled-with-fun-stories-and-cool-stuff-to-find-says-obsidian.1166025/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/the-outer-worlds-2-has-way-more-expansive-worlds-filled-with-fun-stories-and-cool-stuff-to-find-says-obsidian/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>In today's new The Outer Worlds 2 video published as part of April's IGN First, Obsidian Entertainment revealed that the RPG sequel will feature 'way more expansive worlds' than the original (which is great news, as that was <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/the-outer-worlds-obsidian-never-changes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">one of my pet peeves with The Outer Worlds</a>). In classic Obsidian fashion, they will also be filled with fun stories and cool gear or collectibles to find.</p>
<p>Art Director Daniel Alpert explained:</p>
<p><em>We're definitely going more expansive than the first game. In the first game, we were very confined to smaller hubs and overland areas. Now that we're utilizing Unreal Engine 5, we can have way more expansive worlds. From point A to point B, there is a much larger territory that we can cover, and in between those areas, we have lots of little POIs (points of interest) that we can explore.</em></p>
<p>Game Director Brandon Adler added:</p>
<p><em>One of the very first things that we were targeting when we started The Outer Worlds 2 was to make these big, large, expansive areas. It's what players told us that they wanted the most. Working with Daniel and the other directors, we sat down and came up with a plan to how we were going to go do that. We made sure that we had big open sightlines and that we spent a lot of time and effort on making really cool-looking points of interest at a distance to really draw people and also maybe bring them off the beaten path a little bit. When they're heading over there, we made sure that as you're rounding corners or you're doing things like that, you see little points of interest. Another element that was also really important as we're kind of doing all of this stuff is making sure that it was very interesting when you get there, so we made sure that we blanketed all of our areas with just cool, fun stuff to go do, nice loot to go find, and cool stories to go unfold.</em></p>
<p><iframe title="The Outer Worlds 2: A Look at Its Expansive Worlds – IGN First" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fKj1UUIH0a4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Yesterday, IGN also <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-the-outer-worlds-2-lets-you-go-wild-with-rpg-character-building-ign-first" target="_blank" rel="noopener">posted</a> an interview that dived into the changes and improvements made to the underlying RPG formula of The Outer Worlds 2. The developers are trying to avoid a situation where by the end of the game, the main character is essentially good at everything. They're also removing respec to make sure that choices truly matter.</p>
<p>Lead systems designer Kyle Koenig said:</p>
<p><em>We would often see characters good at everything, which by the end of the game, minimized your personal experience with your character. We wanted to focus on making each individual level-up and investment really important. There's less confusion on when I should invest in one Skill or the other. If I want to be a player that's all about guns and using medical devices, I know which Skills I really need to care about. By having them separated and not in groupings, it lets characters be more specialized.&nbsp;By removing respec, we really incentivize it to be your experience. It is a part of your experience that no one else had, and I think that's really special about RPGs and something that respec tends to lessen.&nbsp;</em></p>
<p>The Outer Worlds 2 will also feature a full-fledged stealth system, as <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-outer-worlds-2-gets-first-gameplay-video-and-info/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">revealed</a> last week. More info should be coming throughout April, though the big showcase is scheduled to air <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-games-showcase-set-for-june-8-the-outer-worlds-2-gets-direct-presentation-immediately-after/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">after the Xbox Games Showcase on June 8</a>. The game will launch on PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series S|X.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>