<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 13:54:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Where Winds Meet Launches on PS5 and PC in the West in November 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/where-winds-meet-ps5-pc-release-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/where-winds-meet-launches-on-ps5-and-pc-in-the-west-in-november-2025.1275510/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Where Winds Meet, the free-to-play open-world action-adventure RPG from Everstone Studio and NetEase will launch in the Western world on PS5 and PC this coming November 14, 2025, Everstone and NetEase have announced.</p>



<p>The game initially launched on PC in China in December 2024, followed by an iOS and Android launch this past January. It's been a long time coming to PS5, as lead designer Chris Lyu explains in a <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/08/20/where-winds-meet-launches-november-14/">PlayStation Blog post</a> that the November date will be the culmination of five years worth of work at Everstone Studio.</p>



<p>"<em>We’ve crafted this game with care, pouring our hearts into every detail over the past five years, and we’re beyond excited to share it with the world," </em>Lyu writes.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Where Winds Meet - Release Date Trailer | PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UjKjY6jkYLg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>The final PC and PS5 test for Where Winds Meet was <a href="https://wccftech.com/where-minds-meet-final-test-july-24-31/">held last month</a> ahead of this November launch, and around that time, <a href="https://wccftech.com/where-winds-meet-final-test-qa-everstone-unveils-its-living-world-wuxia-action-rpg-offering-single-player-and-mmo-like-features/">Wccftech's Alessio Palumbo got the chance to speak to Everstone Studio</a> and, more specifically, today's PS Blog author, Chris Lyu, about the coming title. </p>



<p>At the time, Lyu told Wccftech, "<em>Our main goal has always been to share the world of Eastern martial arts in a way that feels new, exciting, and approachable for players everywhere. We want to present something truly different, but also make sure it’s easy for everyone to connect with, using familiar language and storytelling styles."</em></p>



<p>It'll be interesting to see how that resonates with players when it arrives on PC and PS5 on November 14, 2025.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/where-winds-meet-ps5-pc-release-date/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[STALKER 2: Heart of Chornobyl Arrives on PS5 This November]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyl-ps5-release-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyl-arrives-on-ps5-this-november.1275441/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>STALKER 2: Heart of Chornobyl developer GSC Game World has announced that its latest adventure into the zone will arrive on PS5 on <strong>November 20, 2025</strong>, with the standard version available for $59.99.</p>



<p>We first learned that STALKER 2: Heart of Chornobyl would be making the jump to <a href="https://wccftech.com/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyl-ps5-release-late-2025/">PlayStation last month</a>, with a short teaser trailer that featured some of the characters in-game vying for who could have the chance to sit down at the TV and play STALKER 2 on a zone-looking PlayStation controller. </p>



<p>Now we not only have a release date to look forward to, but players who are still looking to collect physical copies can rejoice that there will be a physical copy of STALKER 2 releasing alongside its PS5 launch. There's even a special collector's edition coming called the Ultimate Habar Pack, though per the <a href="https://www.stalker2.com/news/ultimate-habar-pack-update">game's website</a>, the Habar Pack won't be arriving until sometime "<em>in early 2026</em>."</p>



<figure><figcaption>STALKER 2: Heart of Chornobyl Ultimate Habar Pack. Image credit: GSC Game World</figcaption></figure>



<p>Unfortunately, this announcement came with no specific details on how the PS5 version of the game will run and what graphical modes will be available, nor are there any details about what experience PS5 Pro owners might be getting in STALKER 2, but there's still plenty of time between now and November. We likely just have to wait a little longer to see what kind of experience PlayStation players will get when STALKER 2 arrives in November.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyl-ps5-release-date/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>