<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 16:48:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds PC Performance Issues May Be Caused By GPU Streaming Issues; Barely Hits The 60 FPS Mark At 4K Resolution on an RTX 5080]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/monster-hunter-wilds-gpu-streaming-issues-barely-60-fps-rtx-5080/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-pc-performance-issues-may-be-caused-by-gpu-streaming-issues-barely-hits-the-60-fps-mark-at-4k-resolution-on-an-rtx-5080.1122030/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/monster-hunter-wilds-gpu-streaming-issues-barely-60-fps-rtx-5080/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>While Monster Hunter Wilds is a more than worthy new entry in the series, the game leaves a lot to be desired in terms of image quality and performance on all platforms, and the massive performance issues many are experiencing on PC may be caused by how the game handles streaming data to the GPU.</p>
<p>Earlier today, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@DigitalFoundry" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Digital Foundry</a> released their first look at the PC version of the game, highlighting how the positive first impressions one may get from the detailed graphics settings are soon turned around by bad image quality, low-quality textures that likely suffer from texture decompression issues, and subpar performance. From the testing conducted by the tech experts, there's a very good chance the performance issues are caused by how the game handles data streaming data to the GPU, as it has been noted that frametime gets really bad on mid and low-range GPUs by turning the camera around quickly, whereas frametime remains acceptable without moving the camera or turning it slowly in the same identical scenario with very little going on. The same issue is found on more powerful GPUs, although it is more mitigated and slightly less of an issue.&nbsp; Given how the same issue still happens with low texture quality, Digital Foundry surmises that these Monster Hunter Wilds performance issues may not be caused by VRAM usage but by data streaming to the GPU, as there's the chance that the game could still be streaming things in and maybe decompressing textures in an unnecessarily aggressive manner.</p>
<p><iframe title="Monster Hunter Wilds PC - Profound Perf Problems Must Be Addressed" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0yhacyXcizA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>It's not just mid- and low-range GPUs that cannot run Monster Hunter Wilds with decent performance, but also more powerful high-end GPUs like the recently released RTX 5080. A new video put together by MxBenchmarkPC highlights how the second most powerful GPU currently available on the market can barely hit the 60 FPS mark at 4K resolution, highest setting, which is truly baffling, considering the game doesn't push visual quality boundaries in any way.</p>
<p><iframe title="Monster Hunter Wilds on the RTX 5080 - A Solid Candidate for the Most Unoptimized Game of 2025" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kUsLUP4tsSw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The Monster Hunter Wilds PC performance issues outlined above align with my experience, as the game is not running smoothly at all on my RTX 4080. It is a shame that the game's launch is marred by these issues, as it is a very solid game. You can learn more about the new entry in the CAPCOM series with my <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/monster-hunter-wilds-peak-hunting/">review.</a></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds – How to Use Layered Armor]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/how-to/monster-hunter-wilds-how-to-use-layered-armor/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-%E2%80%93-how-to-use-layered-armor.1121934/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/how-to/monster-hunter-wilds-how-to-use-layered-armor/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Monster Hunter Wilds features a lot of different armor pieces, all coming with different skill combinations and stats that can be used to improve your hunter's abilities to overcome the many challenges you will find in the Forbidden Lands. All armor in the game also comes with a different appearance, but thankfully, there's no need to sacrifice functionality for looks, thanks to the game's layered armor system.</p>
<p><strong>To use layered armor</strong> in Monster Hunter Wilds, all you need to do is access the<strong> Base Camp Menu</strong> and select the <strong>Equipment Appearance</strong> option in the <strong>Appearance Menu</strong>, indicated by the first icon to the right of the menu bar. Once in the menu, you will see options to apply layered armor for the Head, Chest, Arms, Waist and Legs gear. Select the armor piece you want to apply a specific look to, pick among the available options, make sure the toggle is set to on, and you are good to go. In addition to applying the specific look of some gear onto your currently equipped gear, you can also modify the pigment of the layered armor, allowing you to make your hunter's look even more unique, toggle your undershirt and tights on or off, and change the look of your pendants. Layered armor is also available for your Palico via the Palico Equipment Appearance option also found in the Appearance Menu.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/20250228162355_1-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>While Monster Hunter Wilds offers right away the ability to use layered armor, you are not going to have any available option for the duration of the main campaign, as you can only unlock the layered armor look of any armor piece by crafting the High Rank version of it, which cannot be crafted until the main story has been completed and the first High Rank monsters have been hunted. If you have bought the game's Deluxe Edition, however, you will have a few layered armor options from the beginning of the game for both the hunter and your Palico. These additional layered armor sets are also available for purchase individually.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>