<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 02:32:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ARC Raiders – Everything We Know About The Latest Hot Extraction Shooter]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/roundup/arc-raiders-everything-we-know-about-the-latest-hot-extraction-shooter/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arc-raiders-%E2%80%93-everything-we-know-about-the-latest-hot-extraction-shooter.1362334/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="overview">
			
<p>Following the mixed reception to its debut title, the free-to-play arena shooter game The Finals, Embark Studios returns stronger than ever with ARC Raiders, a PvPvE third-person extraction shooter title. Here's an overview of everything we know about this game.</p>



<h2 id="h-release-date-platforms-pricing-editions">Release Date, Platforms, Pricing, Editions</h2>



<p>ARC Raiders was actually <a href="https://wccftech.com/arc-raiders-a-free-to-play-coop-shooter-is-embarks-debut-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced</a> before The Finals, during The Game Awards 2021. Back then, Embark conceived it as a free-to-play cooperative (PvE) third-person shooter game, but it was eventually <a href="https://wccftech.com/arc-raiders-is-now-a-pvpve-extraction-shooter-closed-alpha-test-starts-this-summer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reworked to be a buy-to-play PvPvE game</a>. This, of course, meant a delay over the original plan. </p>



<p>At Summer Game Fest 2025, Embark finally <a href="https://wccftech.com/arc-raiders-arrives-on-ps5-xbox-series-x-s-and-pc-in-october-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced</a> the final launch date: October 30, 2025. The game is available in two purchase options. The Standard Edition is priced at $39.99. For those seeking extras, a Deluxe Edition is offered at $59.99. This version of the game provides 2,400 Raider Tokens (used as in-game currency) as well as "The Wanderer" Pack, which includes the Valente Outfit, Pathfinder Backpack, and Blanket Roll. Inside the game, there are paid options for cosmetic-only purchases and battle pass-style content via Raider Tokens.</p>



<h2 id="h-genre-setting-and-story-premise">Genre, Setting, and Story Premise</h2>



<p>As mentioned briefly earlier, the final version of ARC Raiders is a third-person PvPvE extraction shooter. The game takes place in a post-apocalyptic Earth, with the devastated landscape specifically centered on the Italian coast. Humanity has been forced to retreat underground after a catastrophic event: an invasion by ARC units, mysterious mechanical enemies that descended from orbit in overwhelming numbers. The few survivors now huddle in the subterranean city of Toledo in the District of Speranza and surface only when necessary to scavenge and survive among the ruins above.</p>



<p>Arguably, what really sets ARC Raiders apart visually is its retro-futuristic vision, blending Cold War analog tech with advanced robotics and rich atmospheric detail. The world is streaked with neon, battered by fog and synth-heavy soundscapes, and every corner tells a story of a society that once was.</p>



<p>Just like most extraction shooters, ARC Raiders does not feature a traditional story campaign. The game does, however, include narrative bits that the players can discover through environmental clues, NPC interactions, and evolving background quests. Players are "Raiders," those few resourceful survivors that risk the dangers of the topside in search of loot (mechanically) and answers, such as what happened with the ARC invasion and the fate of Earth's vanished elite. </p>



<h2 id="h-gameplay">Gameplay</h2>



<p>The core gameplay experience of ARC Raiders revolves around raiding, scavenging, and ultimately extracting. Each expedition on the surface is a tense, half-hour race against time, as players band together in squads of three or two players (although it is also possible to queue solo) to delve into dangerous zones, whose environments range from crumbling cities and derelict bunkers to the rusting debris of fallen spacecraft.</p>



<p>Players must carefully navigate the post-apocalyptic maps, being wary of both the hostile ARC robots and other human players who are also hunting the same vital resources. Tactics, aim, and squad coordination are essential, not least because at any moment a failed fight can mean the loss of everything not safely stored. The game’s extraction mechanic adds another strategic layer, requiring Raiders to find and reach specific extraction points before time—or luck—runs out. Extraction can be accomplished via elevators, metro stations, or secure hatches that require special keys and offer safer withdrawal, but each method presents its own risk and reward trade-offs.</p>



<p>The constant tension of loss and reward is what drives progression. Upon a successful extraction, teams return with valuable materials and equipment, which can be used to upgrade gear and base facilities for future runs. Anything not successfully extracted is, however, forfeit. Collaboration is therefore both supported and encouraged, as squads must rely on careful coordination to contend with unpredictable PvP encounters and environmental hazards, ranging from dynamic enemy spawns to changing weather and toxic zones. Notably, the game features a "Match Journey" system, which chronicles the story of each run.</p>



<h2 id="h-tech-and-specs">Tech and Specs</h2>



<p>ARC Raiders utilizes Unreal Engine 5 to deliver its sophisticated visuals. The PC version <a href="https://wccftech.com/arc-raiders-geforce-rtx-50-series-bundle-available-game-supports-dlss4-rtxgi/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">supports NVIDIA's RTX Global Illumination, DLSS Super Resolution, DLSS Frame Generation, DLSS Multi Frame Generation, and Reflex</a>. The game also supports AMD FidelityFX Super Resolution 3.1, Intel XeSS 1.3, TAAU, TSR, and AMD FSR Frame Generation.</p>



<p>You can find the official system requirements below.</p>



<p><strong><em>Minimum:</em></strong></p>



<ul>
<li><em><strong>OS:</strong>&nbsp;Windows 10 64-bit or later (latest update)</em></li>



<li><em><strong>CPU:</strong>&nbsp;Intel Core i5-6600K or AMD Ryzen R5 1600</em></li>



<li><em><strong>RAM:</strong>&nbsp;12 GB</em></li>



<li><em><strong>GPU:</strong>&nbsp;NVIDIA GeForce GTX 1050 Ti, AMD Radeon RX 580, or Intel Arc A380</em></li>



<li><em><strong>VRAM:</strong>&nbsp;4 GB</em></li>



<li><em><strong>Shader Model:</strong>&nbsp;6.0</em></li>



<li><em><strong>Storage:</strong>&nbsp;100 GB (SSD or HDD)</em></li>
</ul>



<p><strong><em>Recommended:</em></strong></p>



<ul>
<li><em><strong>OS:</strong>&nbsp;Windows 10 64-bit or later (latest update)</em></li>



<li><em><strong>CPU:</strong>&nbsp;Intel Core i5-9600K or AMD Ryzen 5 3600</em></li>



<li><em><strong>RAM:</strong>&nbsp;16 GB</em></li>



<li><em><strong>GPU:</strong>&nbsp;NVIDIA GeForce RTX 2070 or AMD Radeon RX 5700 XT or Intel Arc B570</em></li>



<li><em><strong>VRAM:</strong>&nbsp;8 GB</em></li>



<li><em><strong>Shader Model:</strong>&nbsp;6.0</em></li>
</ul>



<p>ARC Raiders lack native support for HDR (High Dynamic Range) displays.</p>




		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/roundup/arc-raiders-everything-we-know-about-the-latest-hot-extraction-shooter/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>