<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 20:41:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Acclaim Returns With Nine Titles At PlayAcclaim Showcase, Including 2D Action-Horror Game Katanaut Which Launched Today]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/acclaim-returns-playacclaim-showcase-nine-titles-katanaut-launch-today/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/acclaim-returns-with-nine-titles-at-playacclaim-showcase-including-2d-action-horror-game-katanaut-which-launched-today.1294152/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>After <a href="https://wccftech.com/acclaim-returns-from-the-dead-with-a-focus-on-supporting-indie-studios-and-original-ip/">announcing its return earlier this year</a>, 90s videogame publisher Acclaim is no longer just a former publisher from the 90s, but a modern-day publisher in today's videogame industry. Today, the company hosted its first PlayAcclaim showcase, where it revealed nine games it is currently publishing, including a 2D action-horror game, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3032830/Katanaut/">Katanaut</a>, that launched today alongside the showcase.</p>



<p>The other eight titles include a top-down 2D rhythm game called <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3243370/GRIDbeat/">GRIDBeat!</a>, a combat-focused 2D roguelite called <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3815370/Talaka/">Talaka</a>, a 2D platformer called <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2725470/The_Prisoning_Fletchers_Quest/">The Prisoning: Fletcher's Quest</a>, a top-down PowerWash Simulator-like called <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2572060/Pixel_Washer/">Pixel Washer</a>, a classic arcade basketball game that lets you play through decades of NBA team rosters called <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/819630/Basketball_Classics/">Basketball Classics,</a> an action-roguelite bullet-hell called <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2570580/Ground_Zero_Hero/">Ground Hero Zero</a>, an isometric delivery game called <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3241560/Tossdown/">TossDown</a>, and last but certainly not least, a trick-focused, snowboarding game called <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3082730/HYPERyuki_Snowboard_Syndicate/">Hyper Yuki</a>.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="| #PlayAcclaim Showcase: September 10th, 2025 - Welcome to a New Era |" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bckTJ7o8xdk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Most of the titles, at least for now, are just being released on PC, though Basketball Classics is also available on Nintendo Switch. Here's a list of all nine games:</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3032830/Katanaut/">Katanaut</a>, developed by Voidmaw</li>



<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3243370/GRIDbeat/">GRIDBeat!</a>, developed by Ridiculous Games</li>



<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3815370/Talaka/">Talaka</a>, developed by Potato Kid</li>



<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2725470/The_Prisoning_Fletchers_Quest/">The Prisoning: Fletcher's Quest</a>, developed by Elden Pixels</li>



<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2572060/Pixel_Washer/">Pixel Washer</a>, developed by Valadria</li>



<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/819630/Basketball_Classics/">Basketball Classics</a>, developed by Namo Gamo</li>



<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2570580/Ground_Zero_Hero/">Ground Hero Zero</a>, developed by Rowan Edmondson</li>



<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3241560/Tossdown/">TossDown</a>, developed by Fer Factor</li>



<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3082730/HYPERyuki_Snowboard_Syndicate/">Hyper Yuki</a>, developed by Wabisabi Design</li>
</ul>



<p>"<em>We’re ecstatic to relaunch Acclaim with a lineup that captures our legacy of bold creativity and delivers fresh, unforgettable experiences</em>," added Alex Josef, chief executive officer of Acclaim. "<em>These games are just the beginning of our mission to redefine fun for players everywhere</em>."</p>



<p>While only one of the nine titles revealed in the showcase launched today, it's not the only one that's playable right now. Basketball Classics was released back in 2019; its publishing rights have just now been moved over to Acclaim. There's also demos for Katanaut and Pixel Washer you can download on Steam to check out either of those games right now.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/acclaim-returns-playacclaim-showcase-nine-titles-katanaut-launch-today/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Nightreign Gets a new “High Difficulty” Deep of Night Game Mode Tomorrow]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-nightreign-deep-of-night-high-difficulty-game-mode/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-nightreign-gets-a-new-%E2%80%9Chigh-difficulty%E2%80%9D-deep-of-night-game-mode-tomorrow.1294080/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>If you thought Elden Ring Nightreign was <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/elden-ring-nightreign-conquering-the-night/">difficult before</a>, then tomorrow's new "<em>high difficulty</em>" mode called Deep of Night won't improve your standing with the game. FromSoftware debuted the new game mode today ahead of its arrival tomorrow.</p>



<p>The new mode makes the whole experience more difficult with enemies that hit harder and Nightlords that you won't be able to prepare for by selecting them ahead of your session. You'll just have to be ready for whatever comes your way, and you'll also be continuously delving deeper into difficulty levels the longer you survive.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="ELDEN RING NIGHTREIGN | Deep of Night Overview Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/M-qY-Lb37eE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>All that said, you won't be left to fight these increased challenges with the same weapons you use in the rest of the game. Your weapons will also get a boost, but it'll come at a cost, since weapons you pick up will also have detrimental effects that could prove to do more harm than good.</p>



<p>The right build, however, that's smartly put together can help you steamroll even the more difficult enemies you'll face in the Deep of Night mode.</p>



<p>Depth Relics are another new element added to the Deep of Night game mode, and are only available in Deep of Night. These new, stronger relics can be used in combination with your other relics, since they are each slotted into three new places. </p>



<p>All together, Deep of Night is clearly only for those players looking for the next level of challenge in Elden Ring Nightreign. Try it out at your own risk.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-nightreign-deep-of-night-high-difficulty-game-mode/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>