<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 15:32:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 May Be Held Back by Software Limitations Like exFAT Support and Strict Certification Process, Developer Says]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-held-back-software-limitations-exfat/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-may-be-held-back-by-software-limitations-like-exfat-support-and-strict-certification-process-developer-says.1229085/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 is more likely to be held back by software limitations, some of them shared with its predecessor, than hardware limitations.</p>
<p>Speaking in the latest episode of the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@MooresLawIsDead" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Moore's Law is Dead</a>'s Broken Silicon podcast, Alderon Games founder Matthew Cassells commented on some of the Nintendo Switch 2 software limitations that could impact game performance. Among them are the FAT32 and exFAT file systems, which both the original Switch and the new generation system use. These dated file systems have all sorts of drawbacks over other file systems, such as the 4GB file size limit of FAT32, which leads to issues such as forcing developers to use smaller files, which can limit texture quality, or dividing files into chunks. Regarding this, the Alderon Games founder finds it baffling that Nintendo continues to use these dated file systems, as they also pay a licensing fee to Microsoft to use them with no concrete benefit. PlayStation consoles, for example, use their file systems based on Linux free file systems, and so have none of the limitations of FAT32 and exFAT.</p>
<p>This isn't the only software limitation the Nintendo Switch 2 has that the other consoles don't. While developers can work around the file size limit, Nintendo puts another limitation on top of it. Unlike Sony and Microsoft, Nintendo keeps a strict limit on how many times a game can write data on the NAND to prevent it from dying too soon, which is thoroughly checked in the rigorous approval process for both new games and updates. According to the Alderon Games founder, this is a limitation forced by the company's choice of cheap NAND, which poses the question of whether these limitations are worth the little Nintendo saves on these chips. Additionally, these limitations become even worse if other factors are considered, such as the system reserving a lot of resources for the OS and GameChat, and the massive usage of encryption and DRM, which is not surprising, considering Nintendo's stance on hacking and piracy.</p>
<p>Though this will likely become less of an issue down the line, the Alderon Games founder also lamented the lack of Nintendo Switch 2 devkits, which only a few developers own. As such, many developers who want to continue supporting their games on the new system have to do a lot of guesswork and hope the build they are submitting works flawlessly on it.</p>
<p><iframe title="PS5 Flaw Could Affect Millions, AMD Zen 6 Nears 7GHz, Switch 2 | Alderon Games | Broken Silicon 315" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KjR1uk9LI9c?start=3335&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>While some of these limitations could impact games more down the line, they are not exactly a problem right now for users, as the Nintendo Switch 2 is proving to be extremely successful, and has shown what it can do in the hands of expert developers such as CD Projekt Red with the Cyberpunk 2077 port. You can learn more about the system and how it is a significant improvement over its predecessor by checking out Chris's <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/nintendo-switch-2-console/">review.</a></p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-held-back-software-limitations-exfat/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40K Space Marine 2 New Patch Adds Siege Mode, NVIDIA DLSS 4, and Ray Traced Ambient Occlusion]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40k-space-marine-2-new-patch-adds-siege-mode-nvidia-dlss-4-and-ray-traced-ambient-occlusion/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40k-space-marine-2-new-patch-adds-siege-mode-nvidia-dlss-4-and-ray-traced-ambient-occlusion.1228983/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Patch 8.0 has <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2183900/view/500576552635859479" target="_blank" rel="noopener">dropped</a> today for Warhammer 40K Space Marine 2, adding several features and new content. The main addition is <a href="https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40k-space-marine-2-outlines-2025-roadmap/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Siege Mode</a>, a new PvE mode that expands on the existing Operations mode to include endless enemy waves that can challenge even the strongest teams. When players are overwhelmed, they can call for reinforcements. They'll engage in intense battles across three distinctive sectors, each requiring a different strategy. Side objectives emerge during combat, providing the resources needed to summon either elite Space Marines or the formidable Dreadnought, which can drastically shift the balance of power on the battlefield.</p>
<p>Compared to the build previously available for testing on the Public Test Server, Saber Interactive has reworked the wave timer limit so that, instead of having a limited timer per wave that can become very short on higher waves, there is now a timer for the entire session. Each time players beat a wave, the timer increases.</p>
<p>The developers of Warhammer 40K Space Marine 2 have also adjusted the difficulty curve of infinite waves, meaning that enemies will become stronger more quickly after the 15th wave. These changes will ensure players die in fair combat rather than due to the timer. Additionally, the timer may be entirely removed in the future. Moreover, an option has been introduced to disable bot spawning in Private Mode.</p>
<p>Warhammer 40K Space Marine 2 also received some major technical improvements for the PC version. There's now an experimental ray traced ambient occlusion feature (RTAO) that can be toggled on in the graphics settings, and NVIDIA DLSS 4 with Multi Frame Generation is now fully supported, delivering better visuals with the latest transformer model and faster frame rates on GeForce RTX 50 graphics cards.</p>
<p><iframe title="Space Marine 2 - Siege Mode Teaser Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NDScTIUHlnc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>There are also many other balance tweaks and additions in the patch. Last but not least, Saber said they are preparing a significant update to the customization system, which will let players reuse chapter champion armor parts on other classes (with lore accuracy, clipping, and technical restrictions). This will be in a future update.</p>
<p>As a reminder, Warhammer 40K Space Marine 2 has <a href="https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40k-space-marine-2-has-sold-7-million-units/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">surpassed</a> 7 million units sold, and the developers have already <a href="https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40k-space-marine-3-is-officially-in-development-will-offer-even-more-spectacular-large-scale-battles/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> Space Marine 3.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40k-space-marine-2-new-patch-adds-siege-mode-nvidia-dlss-4-and-ray-traced-ambient-occlusion/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[System Shock 2: 25th Anniversary Remaster Launches Onto GeForce Now, New Elder Scrolls Online Rewards, We Happy Few, And More Added To GFN]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/system-shock-2-25th-anniversary-remaster-launches-onto-geforce-now-new-elder-scrolls-online-rewards-we-happy-few-and-more-added-to-gfn/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/system-shock-2-25th-anniversary-remaster-launches-onto-geforce-now-new-elder-scrolls-online-rewards-we-happy-few-and-more-added-to-gfn.1228980/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>NVIDIA has <a href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/geforce-now-thursday-elder-scrolls-online-member-reward/">announced</a> the latest additions to its GeForce Now cloud service, with five new games being added to the library of playable titles, and a new batch of in-game rewards for Elder Scrolls Online players.</p>
<p>Nightdive Studio's System Shock 2: 25th Anniversary Edition is out today, and it's also playable on GeForce Now as one of the five titles added to the GFN library. Here's the full list of the games that now have GFN support:</p>
<ul>
<li>System Shock 2: 25th Anniversary Remaster</li>
<li>We Happy Few</li>
<li>Broken Age</li>
<li>Easy Red 2</li>
<li>Sandwich Simulator</li>
</ul>
<figure>
<div>

<div>
		
		
		<p><span>2 of 9</span>
	</p></div></div>
</figure>


<p>GeForce Now users who also dip into the Elder Scrolls Online will get 24-hour early access to the mythical Grand Gold Coast Experience Scrolls reward, which boosts the XP you'll earn by 150% for one hour.</p>
<p>Today is also when Steam's Summer Sale is due to start, which will last from today, June 26, to July 13. You can make sure that the games you might be looking to pick up on Steam have GeForce Now support by scrolling through the sale on the GFN app. You can even save on your GeForce Now membership, with a six-month Performance membership now on sale for 40% off.</p>
<p>If you don't want to commit to the six months right away, you still have a day left to pick up the previously announced <a href="https://wccftech.com/geforce-now-gets-40-discount-on-performance-day-pass/">Performance Day Pass</a>, which is on sale for 40% off as well until tomorrow, June 27, 2025.</p>
<p>Last week, the entire <a href="https://wccftech.com/borderlands-franchise-lands-on-geforce-now-bl4-will-be-supported-at-launch/">Borderlands franchise</a> (save for <a href="https://wccftech.com/borderlands-4-wont-cost-80/">Borderlands 4</a>) was added to GeForce Now, along with new releases like <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/rematch-review-an-excellent-football-game-thats-been-tackled-at-the-knees/">Rematch</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/fbc-firebreak-review-in-progress-dont-forget-to-shower/">FBC: Firebreak</a>.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/system-shock-2-25th-anniversary-remaster-launches-onto-geforce-now-new-elder-scrolls-online-rewards-we-happy-few-and-more-added-to-gfn/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>