<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:46:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghost of Yotei Leaves a Lot of Performance on the Table on PS5 Pro With Capped Framerates]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ghost-of-yotei-performance-ps5-pro/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ghost-of-yotei-leaves-a-lot-of-performance-on-the-table-on-ps5-pro-with-capped-framerates.1363855/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>The new Ghost of Yotei 1.100 patch introduces significant performance improvements on PlayStation 5 Pro by enabling 120 Hz VRR across all of the game's display modes.</p>



<p><span data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">These performance improvements are showcased in a new comparison video shared by&nbsp;<a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://www.youtube.com/@RajmanGamingHD/videos" target="_blank">RajmanGaming HD,</a>&nbsp;which compares the game running with and without VRR enabled, using all of the game's display modes: Ray Tracing Pro, Balanced Ray Tracing Pro, Ray Tracing, Performance, Balanced, and Quality.</span> The comparison makes it clear how a significant amount of performance is left on the table on the PlayStation 5 Pro with the frame rate capped, as framerates are higher across all display modes with VRR and uncapped framerate.</p>



<figure><table><tbody><tr><th>Display Mode</th><th>VRR OFF / Capped Framerate</th><th>VRR ON / Uncapped Framerate</th></tr><tr><td><strong>Ray Tracing Pro</strong></td><td>40 FPS</td><td>60 FPS (Average)</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Balanced Ray Tracing</strong></td><td>40 FPS</td><td>60 FPS (Average)</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Ray Tracing</strong></td><td>30 FPS</td><td>40 FPS</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Performance</strong></td><td>60 FPS</td><td>Up to 95 FPS</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Balanced</strong></td><td>40 FPS</td><td>Up to 60 FPS</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Quality</strong></td><td>30 FPS</td><td>40 FPS</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Ghost of Yotei - PS5 Pro 120hz VRR Frame Rate Performance (Patch 1.100)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rrE93VUqttU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Ghost of Yotei also supports 120 Hz VRR on base PlayStation 5 with the new patch, but no performance comparison has been conducted to date, so it's not yet known how much performance was untapped with capped framerates on the system.</p>



<h2 id="h-1-100-patch-is-more-than-just-performance-improvements">1.100 Patch is More Than Just Performance Improvements</h2>



<p>Besides introducing 120 Hz VRR support and the new Balanced display modes, the new Ghost of Yotei 1.100 patch introduces a lot of new features that enhance the experience considerably, such as the ability to auto-loot items, an option to turn off fall damage, new Photo Mode features, a New Game+ mode, replayable endgame content, balance changes, and more. You can learn more about the new content and changes with the <a href="https://support.suckerpunch.com/hc/en-us/articles/43659450672795-Patch-1-100">official patch notes.</a></p>



<p>Ghost of Yotei, the sequel to the popular Ghost of Tsushima, launched last month on PlayStation 5. You can learn more about the game by checking out <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/ghost-of-yotei-exploring-the-price-of-vengeance-in-17th-century-ezo/">Alessio Palumbo's review.</a></p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/ghost-of-yotei-performance-ps5-pro/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>