<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 21:02:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wccftech’s Best Adventure Games of 2025 – Weird and Wondrous Tales]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-adventure-games-of-2025-weird-and-wondrous-tales/</link>
            <guid>1392730</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>It's safe to say that our top five list of best adventure games released in 2025 <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-adventure-games-of-2024-all-kinds-of-journeys/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">tops last year's</a>, thanks to the greater variety of mechanical experimentation and enhanced emotional depth offered by the new releases.</p>



<p>From philosophical claymation nightmares to puzzle mansions that redefine established conventions, these developers, often unable to unload a triple-A budget during production, proved that the adventure genre is at the very forefront of gaming's narrative and artistic ambitions, delivering incredibly varied experiences that focus more on letting the players think instead of mashing buttons.</p>



<p><em>Other Best Games of 2025 per Category: <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-fighting-games-of-2025-old-and-new-challengers/"><strong>Fighting Games</strong></a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftech-best-sports-and-racing-games-2025/"><strong>Sports &amp; Racing Games</strong>,</a> <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-role-playing-games-of-2025-another-incredible-year/"><strong>Role-Playing Games</strong></a></em>, <em><a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-horror-games-of-2025-a-year-of-frights/"><strong>Horror Games</strong></a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-platformers-of-2025-jumping-and-smashing-to-victory/"><strong>Platformers</strong></a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-indie-games-of-2025-the-year-of-the-indie/"><strong>Indie Games</strong></a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-action-games-of-2025-a-relentless-year/"><strong>Action</strong></a></em>, <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-dlc-expansion-of-2025-expanding-the-fun/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>DLC/Expansion</em></a></strong>, <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-shooter-games-of-2025-firing-has-never-felt-so-good/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Shooter Games</em></a></strong></p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Blue-Prince-Key-Art-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<h2 id="h-blue-prince">Blue Prince</h2>



<p>Primarily developed by a single developer called Tonda Ros, Blue Prince emerged as 2025's most critically acclaimed game across its first quarter, surpassing AAA launches and establishing itself as an early contender for the end-of-the-year awards. The game was in development for nine years, but the wait was definitely worth it.</p>



<p>The room-drafting system is the main attraction. As the heir to Mt. Holly Estate in search of the elusive Room 46 (the stipulation made by the deceased great uncle for protagonist Simon P. Jones to gain access to his inheritance), players don't simply navigate a static environment; they modify it. Upon encountering a closed door, players choose from a pool of available room cards. These decisions fundamentally alter the puzzle landscape: a Library provides ladders and hidden passages, a Workshop grants access to gear puzzles, and a Drawing Room allows for redrafting adjacent rooms. The act of selecting room types becomes the core puzzle, not just a narrative device.</p>



<p>It sounds deceptively simple, but there's hidden complexity at play here. Each room has orientation mechanics, connection rules, and specific puzzle prerequisites. Ambitious chambers demand seven preceding room types, forcing players to plan runs with chess-like precision. At the same time, the randomized draft pool ensures no two playthroughs feel identical. There are ways to retain items between runs. You can also gain permanent upgrades. These provide extra steps, gems, or coins at the start of a run.</p>



<p>The main narrative weaves seamlessly through mechanical gameplay, and there are also side mysteries to tackle, such as the disappearance of kids' author Marion Marigold. Ultimately, there's little doubt that Blue Prince is the year's most successful puzzle adventure game, not to mention one that will be celebrated and remembered for a very long time.</p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/the-midnight-walk-keyart-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<h2 id="h-the-midnight-walk">The Midnight Walk</h2>



<p>The Midnight Walk, the debut game from MoonHood, a Swedish indie developer founded by ex Zoink developers who worked on Lost in Random, is a first-person adventure set in a world consumed by darkness and rendered entirely through stop-motion craft—utilizing yarn, papier-mâché, felt, and paint. Here, two characters, the player character known as the Burnt One (a charred husk of a being who rises from a grave) and the companion known as Potboy (a small candle-like being whose flame illuminates darkness and attracts ravenous creatures desperate for its warmth), eventually meet. The Burnt One lacks sight and hearing initially and so pairs with Potboy as the two cover each other's weaknesses.</p>



<p>Together, they journey toward Moon Mountain to restore the sun. Through the six chapters, the developers tell self-contained stories that unveil what happened to these haunted forests, ruined villages, and corrupted landscapes. Each story explores loss, regret, and the question: can we ever make things right?</p>



<p>Mechanically, it could be called a walking simulator. However, its delivery of the narrative is extremely effective: MoonHood employs stunning black-and-white short films, true visual poetry that conveys emotion without the need for dialogue. Indeed, somehow the game continues to elicit strong emotions from players throughout each chapter and without overstaying its welcome (the game takes between seven and eight hours to complete).</p>



<p>The Midnight Walk proves that the genre does not need combat at all to win over gamers, relying instead on sheer artistic and emotional value to provide a memorable experience that also tastefully explores profound themes. Playing it with a Virtual Reality headset offers the maximum level of immersion.</p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Keeper-Art.jpg"></a></figure>



<h2 id="h-keeper-6-5">Keeper (<a href="https://wccftech.com/review/keeper-review-shine-a-light/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">6.5</a>)</h2>



<p>After the critically acclaimed Psychonauts 2, Double Fine Productions returns four years later with Keeper, a visually gorgeous and thematically sophisticated adventure game. The premise sounds whimsical: an animated lighthouse walks across a bizarre landscape, eventually acquiring the ability to jump, float, and even manipulate time. But industry legend Tim Schafer and his colleagues leveraged that whimsy factor to explore how two fundamentally different beings, the lighthouse and a bird-like creature called Twig, can build trust and grow together.</p>



<p>The lighthouse manipulates light beams in two modes: unfocused (subtle environmental influence, triggering growth and reactions) and focused (precise puzzle-solving, object transformation, pathway revelation). Twig, on the other hand, assists by reaching perches, activating levers, and flagging secrets. Puzzles typically demand combining light manipulation and bird-enabled interactions—neither character is complete alone. A bit like in The Midnight Walk, this mechanical interdependence mirrors the narrative theme: one character's weakness is the other's strength.</p>



<p>The art direction is transcendent. Environments shift between color palettes that underscore emotional tone: lush greens for hope, ash-gray for desolation, and pink-mist valleys for surreal wonder. Do note that the game doesn't feature any traditional dialogue, and that's by design, as Double Fine wanted to leave Twig and the lighthouse's adventure entirely open to interpretation. As such, it might not be a game for everyone, as noted by Chris Wray in Wccftech's review. That said, it's certainly worth looking into, especially for its absolutely breathtaking art style.</p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Lost-Records-Bloom-Rage.jpg"></a></figure>



<h2 id="h-lost-records-bloom-amp-rage">Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage</h2>



<p>After the <a href="https://wccftech.com/banishers-and-jusant-underperformed-dont-nod-admits/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">unsuccessful commercial release</a> of the God of War-like action adventure RPG Banished: Ghosts of New Eden (<a href="https://wccftech.com/review/banishers-ghosts-of-new-eden-dont-nods-finest-action-game-yet/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">which I maintain was severely underrated</a>), Don't Nod returned to their narrative adventure roots with Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage, a game that clearly hearkens back to their most acclaimed work: Life is Strange. </p>



<p>The narrative framework is split across two timelines: 1995 and 2022. In the present day, Swann Holloway (the only playable character) returns to her hometown of Velvet Cove after 27 years, reuniting with childhood friends who haven't spoken since a shared traumatic event they collectively repressed. In the past, players watch these four girls (Swann and her friends Autumn, Nora, and Kat) during a transformative summer where friendship deepened into something supernatural. They form a band, the titular Bloom &amp; Rage, discover a mysterious glowing Abyss in the forest, and make a blood pact with unknowable consequences.</p>



<p>Just like in Life is Strange, the characters seen in this game aren't paper-thin archetypes; they're complex, contradictory human beings. Swann wrestles with artistic ambition versus belonging. Autumn struggles between family duty and personal authenticity. Nora navigates privilege and responsibility. Kat faces terminal illness and the question of legacy. </p>



<p>The mystery unfolds through fractured memories, and there is a distinctly different vibe in the two timelines: 1995 feels idyllic, while 2022 reveals trauma and unprocessed guilt. The writing and aesthetic also perfectly capture the era, including the pre-smartphone immediacy of friendship, and the intensity of teenage bonds that felt infinite until they abruptly ended.</p>



<p>The game was released in two episodes. The first, titled Tape 1, received almost unanimous praise, while the second turned out more divisive among Dontnod fans. That said, the game is proof that the studio hasn't lost its touch in portraying the teenage experience.</p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/dispatch-art-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<h2 id="h-dispatch">Dispatch</h2>



<p>Following the <a href="https://wccftech.com/telltale-games-closing-walking-dead/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">closure of Telltale Games in 2018</a>, several former employees established a new team called AdHoc Studio. It took a long time before their first game made it to the market, but <a href="https://wccftech.com/ex-telltale-devs-announced-release-date-new-dispatch-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dispatch</a> made a massive impact among adventure games when it arrived in 2025's final quarter, immediately establishing itself as a must-play game. Its premise is that Robert Robertson III, formerly the superhero Mecha Man, is drowning in desperation after the precious suit built by his grandfather gets seemingly destroyed beyond repair in a showdown with the villain Shroud.</p>



<p>Robert has no powers of his own and thus is unable to continue his lifelong fight against crime until a bona fide superhero, Blonde Blazer, approaches him about helping in another way: as a dispatcher for the Superhero Dispatch Network (SDN). Not only is Blazer offering a job, but she also promises that the SDN will fund repairs to the Mecha Man suit. The catch is that Robert gets assigned to the Z-Team, a group of reformed supervillains enrolled in the so-called Phoenix Program, a Hail Mary-type bet in an attempt to make superheroes out of them.</p>



<p>The narrative is woven with impressive expertise, shifting seamlessly between a funny workplace comedy with plenty of jokes and jabs and a deep meditation on redemption, found family, and trust. The writing is exceptional, making the characters feel three-dimensional and real, but the performances are a match, with renowned actors Aaron Paul and Jeffrey Wright delivering stunning works as Robert and Chase.</p>



<p>Mechanically, the game combines the rippling dialogue choices seen in Telltale's previous games with a workplace simulator/team management component, where players must choose which hero to dispatch on each day's missions, ensuring they are a good match to complete the task while also keeping them happy in the process. </p>



<p>AdHoc Studio crafted a setting that feels very refreshing compared to your usual superhero universes. Personally, I cannot wait to find out what's next for Robert, Blonde Blazer, and the others, though the next game might have to find a different core mechanics than dispatching heroes.</p>



<div id="democracy-1499" data-opts="{&quot;ajax_url&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/wccftech.com\/wp-admin\/admin-ajax.php&quot;,&quot;pid&quot;:1499,&quot;max_answs&quot;:0,&quot;answs_max_height&quot;:&quot;500&quot;,&quot;anim_speed&quot;:&quot;400&quot;,&quot;line_anim_speed&quot;:1500}"><p><strong>Best Adventure Game of 2025</strong></p></div>



<h2 id="h-honorable-mentions">Honorable Mentions</h2>



<p>There were several more adventure games launched in 2025 worth your attention. Here's another five to consider:</p>



<ul>
<li>The Drifter</li>



<li>Wanderstop</li>



<li>Amerzone: The Explorer's Legacy</li>



<li>Despelote</li>



<li>Spirit of the North 2</li>
</ul>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-adventure-games-of-2025-weird-and-wondrous-tales/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>