<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:02:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Gran Turismo 7 Has 2+ Million Monthly Users and Is Still Growing’, Reveals Series Creator]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/gran-turismo-7-has-2-million-monthly-users-is-still-growing-reveals-creator/</link>
            <guid>1389919</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Polyphony Digital's <strong>Gran Turismo 7</strong> may have been released nearly four years ago, but according to series creator and studio founder Kazunori Yamauchi, it's still doing extremely well.</p>



<p>In an interview with media outlets that attended the Gran Turismo World Series 2025 World Finals in Fukuoka, Japan, the legendary game designer (and racing driver) revealed that the game <strong>is regularly played by over two million players each month</strong>, and perhaps even more importantly, its player base is still growing. Here's the relevant quote <a href="https://www.gtplanet.net/gt7-2-million-monthly-users-20251221/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">as GTPlanet reported it</a>:</p>



<p><em>Gran Turismo 7 has been released for several years, but still, the active users are currently over 2 million people, and the new users are increasing. The status that Gran Turismo 7 is in now is probably the best of any Gran Turismo titles that we’ve had in the past. We’ve never experienced this phenomenon before, and neither has PlayStation.</em></p>



<p>Polyphony Digital experimented with live service in the previous entry, GT Sport, but it's clear that GT7 has received a much warmer welcome from series fans and continues to keep many players interested through various updates. The most recent one, Spec III (Update 1.65), launched on December 4 and introduced:</p>



<ul>
<li>Eight cars (Ferrari 296 GT3 ’23, Ferrari 296 GTB ’22, FIAT Panda 30 CL ’85, Gran Turismo F3500‑B, Mine's BNR34 GT‑R N1 base, Mitsubishi FTO GP Version R ’97, Polestar 5 Performance ’26, and Renault Espace F1 ’95).</li>



<li>Two tracks (Yas Marina Circuit and Circuit Gilles-Villeneuve).</li>



<li>The new Data Logger feature lets players load data from the previous attempt or replays to view and compare data such as racing lines, throttle and brake inputs, speed, and engine RPM, all in real-time.</li>
</ul>



<p>Alongside Spec III, Gran Turismo 7 players can also purchase the new Power Pack for $29.99. This premium DLC adds 50 new races across 20 themed categories, such as 24-hour races, six unique cars specially tuned by Gran Turismo, tail-to-nose battles with <a href="https://wccftech.com/gran-turismo-sophy-announced-by-sony-ai-and-polyphony-its-an-ai-breakthrough-capable-of-competing-against-top-players/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gran Turismo Sophy</a> 3.0, and is bundled with 5,000,000 in-game Credits.</p>



<p>The game's only real downside is the aggressive microtransactions system, which also caused its <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/gran-turismo-7-review/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">official Wccftech review score</a> to drop from 9 to 8/10. From the point of view of PC players, there's also the 'downside' that the game still isn't available, whereas most other PlayStation exclusives have already been ported. </p>



<p>Three years ago, a Yamauchi statement about a PC version being considered <a href="https://wccftech.com/gran-turismo-pc-ports-are-being-considered-by-polyphony-digital/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">was widely reported</a> in the press. However, a few weeks later, the founder of Polyphony rectified the statement, clarifying that the possibility was 'not zero' but that there was still nothing being actively done on that front yet. Unfortunately, as of the end of 2025, there are still no updates on the port.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/gran-turismo-7-has-2-million-monthly-users-is-still-growing-reveals-creator/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil Requiem – Everything We Know About the New Game in CAPCOM’s Beloved Horror Franchise]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/roundup/resident-evil-requiem-everything-we-know-about-the-new-game-in-capcoms-beloved-horror-franchise/</link>
            <guid>1389700</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="overview">
			
<p>Even though Monster Hunter has taken over as the best-selling series made by CAPCOM, the Japanese developer is still betting heavily on the success of <strong>Resident Evil Requiem</strong>, the ninth mainline game in the globally acclaimed horror series that has sold <strong>more than 178 million units</strong> throughout its thirty-year history.</p>



<p>With Resident Evil 7: Biohazard and Resident Evil Village, CAPCOM managed to reinvent the saga with a new protagonist, Ethan Winters, and a new perspective, first-person view, in both cases moving away from series staples such as military proficient playable characters and third-person perspective. In many ways, Requiem marks a new chapter that aims to connect elements from both the recent and the older games in the series.</p>



<h2 id="h-release-date-platforms-and-pricing">Release Date, Platforms, and Pricing</h2>



<p>The first rumors about Resident Evil 9 <a href="https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-9-monster-hunter-wilds-rumored-to-be-open-world/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">started circulating in March 2024</a>, although it wasn't until June 2025 that CAPCOM <a href="https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-9-revealed-officially-called-resident-evil-requiem-arrives-on-ps5-xbox-series-x-s-and-pc-in-february-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced</a> the final title. On this occasion, the studio also communicated the planned release date: <strong>February 27, 2026</strong>. Initially, the game was confirmed for a simultaneous release on Sony's <strong>PlayStation 5</strong>, Microsoft's <strong>Xbox Series S|X</strong>, and <strong>PC</strong> (via Steam and the Epic Games Store). A <strong>Nintendo Switch 2</strong> version was <a href="https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-requiem-confirmed-for-nintendo-switch-2-with-new-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">officially added a bit later</a>, during a Nintendo Direct presentation held in September 2025.</p>



<p>Pre-orders are now open. The Standard Edition is priced at <strong>$69.99</strong>, while a Deluxe Edition is available at <strong>$79.99</strong>. This provides access to the Deluxe Kit, composed of the following items:</p>



<ul>
<li>Grace's Costume: Dimitrescu</li>



<li>Grace's Costume: Film Noir</li>



<li>Leon's Costume: RE4</li>



<li>Leon's Costume: Apocalypse</li>



<li>Leon's Costume: Film Noir</li>



<li>Screen Filter: Apocalypse</li>



<li>Screen Filter: Film Noir</li>



<li>Four weapon skins, including S&amp;S M232 Weapon Skin: Apocalypse</li>



<li>Mr. Raccoon Charm</li>



<li>DSO Emblem Charm</li>



<li>Audio Pack: Raccoon City Classic</li>



<li>Files: Letters from 1998</li>
</ul>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/d193827c8fc26985d3e10075de5f81c6-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<p>Any pre-order of the game includes the bonus cosmetic item Grace's Costume: Apocalypse. Pre-ordering through the Epic Games Store also grants players access to the Grace Ashcroft Outfit exclusive cosmetics item in Fortnite. Additionally, CAPCOM is releasing a <strong>Nintendo Switch 2 Pro Controller</strong> themed after the game (<a href="https://fave.co/3Y7tNKD" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">priced at <strong>$99.99</strong></a>) and an <strong>amiibo of protagonist Grace Ashcroft</strong> in 2026.</p>



<h2 id="h-genre-setting-and-story-premise">Genre, Setting, and Story Premise</h2>



<p>In Resident Evil Requiem, CAPCOM seeks to offer fans of both <strong>action-horror</strong> and <strong>survival horror</strong> their slice of entertainment, thanks to the dual-protagonist structure.</p>



<p>The setting marks the long-awaited return to <strong>Raccoon City's iconic locations</strong>, including the police station featured in Resident Evil 2 and Resident Evil 3. However, Requiem presents the city in a never-before-seen state of ruin, being set thirty years after Raccoon City's nuclear bombing in RE3.</p>



<p>The narrative premise centers on <strong>Grace Ashcroft</strong>, an FBI agent with a sharp analytical mind, as the brand new playable character. Grace is assigned to investigate a series of strange deaths. The case ultimately leads her to Raccoon City, more specifically to the Wrenwood Hotel, where her mother Alyssa died eight years before the game's events. The developers have described Grace as a bit of a bookworm who doesn't much trust her own capability to handle dangerous combat scenarios. This choice was made to emphasize survival horror mechanics reminiscent of games like RE2 and RE7, where Grace will be forced to evade detection from various enemies while navigating horrifying environments. </p>



<p>For a long time, CAPCOM leaker Dusk Golem maintained that the game would also feature another playable character, fan-favorite DSO agent <strong>Leon S. Kennedy</strong>, previously seen in Resident Evil 2, 4, and 6. The developer <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-first-look-at-leon-s-kennedy-in-resident-evil-requiem-has-arrived-with-new-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">finally confirmed the rumor at The Game Awards 2025</a> with a new trailer, although the cat was already out of the bag since two days earlier <a href="https://wccftech.com/hes-really-here-leon-finally-confirmed-for-resident-evil-requiem-with-a-playstation-store-leak/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">due to a PlayStation Store leak</a>. The developers later revealed that there is a roughly even split between the two protagonists, with Leon's segments usually being <strong>combat-driven and action-focused</strong>, more akin to Resident Evil 4.</p>



<p>CAPCOM has stressed that this seamless interweaving of high-stakes cinematic action with survival elements represents their bold reinvention of the series, as they attempt to balance atmospheric horror with visceral combat scenarios. </p>



<h2 id="h-gameplay">Gameplay</h2>



<p>Notably, the project initially began development as a multiplayer-focused title with open world design (confirming earlier rumors), before being redesigned as a single-player, more linear experience. CAPCOM <a href="https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-requiem-started-as-an-open-world-game-before-capcom-realized-it-wasnt-what-fans-wanted-to-see-or-play/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">admitted</a> realizing that this wasn't what core fans of the horror franchise would have wanted.</p>



<p>Even so, Resident Evil Requiem does introduce at least one major innovation: the <strong>hybrid first-person and third-person perspective system</strong>, which allows players to dynamically switch between viewpoints for the first time in the series so that they'd be able to suit their playstyle. Those who prefer a more scary and immersive experience are likely to gravitate toward first-person, whereas action gamers and traditional fans will probably opt for third-person.</p>



<p>The core gameplay loop integrates classic Resident Evil mechanics with modern refinements: <strong>combat, investigations, puzzles, and resource management</strong>. The dual-character structure also aims to create <strong>distinct gameplay identities</strong> that, <a href="https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-requiem-complete-rollercoaster-ride-never-before/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in the words of Game Director Koshi Nakanishi</a>, will make players feel like they are <strong>on a rollercoaster ride</strong> like never before in Resident Evil. Nakanishi noted that it wouldn't do to keep the horror tension to the max throughout the whole game, because that would be quite exhausting for the player. As such, there will be a dynamic pacing curve that alternates between tense, horrific sequences and some release, exciting combat, and peaceful exploration, before gradually picking up again on the horror part of the curve. To further highlight the differences between Grace and Leon, Nakanishi recently <a href="https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-requiem-grace-ashcroft-series-most-fearful-character-leon-kennedy-series-strongest/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a> that Grace is the series' most fearful character yet, while the experienced Leon is the strongest.</p>



<p>A taste of playing as Grace was made available to press and fans alike in the Gamescom 2025 demo that Wccftech's Francesco De Meo <a href="https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-requiem-gamescom-hands-on-preview-turn-on-the-lights/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">praised in the <strong>hands-on preview article</strong></a>.</p>



<p>Furthermore, CAPCOM has deliberately designed Requiem to be <strong>accessible to series newcomers</strong> while rewarding veterans through familiar features, such as legacy enemy types and narrative callbacks. Thus, no need to worry if you haven't played all, or any, of the predecessors.</p>



<h2 id="h-tech-and-specs">Tech and Specs</h2>



<p>Resident Evil Requiem employs CAPCOM's <strong>proprietary RE Engine</strong>, which was named after the series and was first used in RE7. Nowadays, the RE Engine powers every game developed by the Japanese studio. In most cases, it delivered excellent visuals and solid performance, with the notable exceptions of Dragon's Dogma 2 and Monster Hunter Wilds, both of which were open world games.</p>



<p>Luckily, Resident Evil Requiem's final incarnation is not an open world game and is therefore unlikely to suffer major optimization problems. The developers themselves <a href="https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-requiem-wont-have-same-performance-issues-monster-hunter-wilds/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">told fans</a> there wouldn't be a repeat of the disappointing launch performance of Monster Hunter Wilds. </p>



<p>CAPCOM already shared the minimum and recommended system requirements for the PC version.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th>Requirement</th><th>Minimum</th><th>Recommended</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>OS</td><td>Windows 11</td><td>Windows 11</td></tr><tr><td>Processor</td><td>Intel Core i5-8500 / AMD Ryzen 5 3500</td><td>Intel Core i7-8700 / AMD Ryzen 5 5500</td></tr><tr><td>Memory</td><td>16 GB RAM</td><td>16 GB RAM</td></tr><tr><td>Graphics</td><td>NVIDIA GeForce GTX 1660 6 GB / AMD Radeon RX 5500 XT 8 GB</td><td>NVIDIA GeForce RTX 2060 Super 8 GB / AMD Radeon RX 6600 8 GB</td></tr><tr><td>DirectX</td><td>Version 12</td><td>Version 12</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>We also know that the PC version of Resident Evil Requiem <a href="https://wccftech.com/nvidia-dlss-4-supported-175-games-resident-evil-requiem-path-tracing/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">will support</a> <strong>NVIDIA DLSS 4 Multi Frame Generation</strong> and <strong>path tracing</strong>. Official performance specifications for the console versions have not been publicly disclosed yet. However, the developers briefly discussed the Nintendo Switch 2 version, the least powerful platform among those supported, to reveal that <a href="https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-requiem-devs-surprised-how-well-it-runs-switch-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">even they were surprised at how well it ran on the hybrid console</a>. If the Switch 2 doesn't have a problem, the other consoles should run Requiem even better.</p>
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/roundup/resident-evil-requiem-everything-we-know-about-the-new-game-in-capcoms-beloved-horror-franchise/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>