<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 15:27:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy Tactics – The Ivalice Chronicles – The Best Support Abilities for Max Physical Damage]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/how-to/final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles-the-best-support-abilities-for-max-physical-damage/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-tactics-%E2%80%93-the-ivalice-chronicles-%E2%80%93-the-best-support-abilities-for-max-physical-damage.1323628/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Job System in Final Fantasy Tactics - The Ivalice Chronicles offers unparalleled customization, but choosing the right Support Ability is critical for players focused on maximum Physical Damage. Here's the best Support Ability to maximize Physical Damage.</p>



<p><strong><em>NOTE: Guide based on damage tests conducted in Enhanced Mode's Tactician difficulty, repeated three times under the same conditions to verify consistency. Although enemy stats and damage values differ in Knight and Squire difficulties, the findings from the tests show consistent damage differences. Screenshots captured from the up-to-date Steam version of the game as of October 13, 2025.</em></strong></p>



<div><h2>Table of contents</h2><ul><li><a href="#h-all-support-abilities-that-boost-physical-damage" data-level="2">All Support Abilities That Boost Physical Damage</a></li><li><a href="#h-the-best-physical-damage-support-ability" data-level="2">The Best Physical Damage Support Ability</a></li><li><a href="#h-testing-methodology" data-level="2">Testing Methodology</a><ul><li><a href="#h-dual-wield-damage-testing" data-level="3">Dual Wield Damage Testing</a></li><li><a href="#h-doublehand-damage-testing" data-level="3">Doublehand Damage testing</a></li><li><a href="#h-monk-dual-wield-damage-testing" data-level="3">Monk (Dual Wield) Damage Testing</a></li><li><a href="#h-attack-boost-damage-testing" data-level="3">Attack Boost Damage Testing</a></li></ul></li></ul></div>



<h2 id="h-all-support-abilities-that-boost-physical-damage">All Support Abilities That Boost Physical Damage</h2>



<figure><figcaption><em>Doublehand is one of the four Support Abilities that increase Physical Damage in Final Fantasy Tactics - The Ivalice Chronicles.</em></figcaption></figure>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th>Ability Name</th><th>Description</th><th>Job</th><th>JP Cost</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><strong>Dual Wield</strong></td><td>Allows the unit to wield a weapon in each hand, even if not a Ninja. Certain weapons can be equipped in this manner, allowing the unit to attack twice each turn.</td><td>Ninja</td><td>1,000 JP</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Doublehand</strong></td><td>Allows the unit to wield a single-handed weapon with both hands. Certain weapons can be equipped in this manner, greatly increasing (2x) their attack power.</td><td>Samurai</td><td>900 JP</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Attack Boost</strong></td><td>Increase the unit's physical attack power (33% bonus)</td><td>Geomancer</td><td>400 JP</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Brawler</strong></td><td>Delivers more powerful bare-handed attacks, even if not a Monk.</td><td>Monk</td><td>450 JP</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="h-the-best-physical-damage-support-ability">The Best Physical Damage Support Ability</h2>



<p>If you are only interested in the definitive answer to maximize your unit's physical damage with the basic Attack command, here is the conclusion based on the extensive testing: <strong>Dual Wield is the best Support Ability for maximum Physical Damage as soon as you can deal 500 damage consistently in a single hit</strong>  If your unit is not yet hitting high damage totals, Doublehand and Barehanded damage with a Monk with high Bravery and Dual Wield Support Ability are better choices.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th>Scenario</th><th>Best Support Ability</th><th>Key Reason</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><strong>Absolute Maximum Damage</strong></td><td>Dual Wield</td><td>Allows two hits of up to 999 damage, resulting in maximum 1998 total damage, bypassing the single-hit cap.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>High-Level/Pre-Cap Damage</strong></td><td>Doublehand</td><td>Maximizes the power of your single best weapon, providing a higher overall damage multiplier until you consistently hit 500+ damage.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Barehanded Damage </strong>(Monk+Dual Wield Support Ability)</td><td>Dual Wield</td><td>A Monk's innate Brawler works on both barehanded strikes from Dual Wield, exceeding damage dealt by weapons the Ninja can natively equip.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Physical Skill</strong>s (Martial Arts, Holy Sword, Swordplay, Unyielding Blade)</td><td>Attack Boost</td><td>Applies the damage bonus to nearly all physical abilities (like Martial Arts, Holy Sword), which Dual Wield and Doublehand do not.</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="h-testing-methodology">Testing Methodology</h2>



<figure><figcaption><em>The Minotaur monster used as a test dummy</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>To conclude that Doublehand and a Monk using the Dual Wield ability are better choices before being able to hit an enemy for more than 500 damage in a single hit, I conducted some tests in a random battle set in the Zeklaus Desert map, using my level 55 Ramza with 97 Bravery right before the final gauntlet of battles at Orbonne Monastery in late Chapter 4. The enemy used as a test dummy was a Level 49 Virgo Minotaur, which had neutral compatibility with my Ramza's Aries Zodiac sign.</p>



<h3 id="h-dual-wield-damage-testing">Dual Wield Damage Testing</h3>


<figure>
<div>

<figure>
<figure><figcaption><em>Ramza Gallant Knight Dual Wield Build</em></figcaption></figure>



<figure></figure>
</figure>
<div>
				    		
				    		
					    	<p><span>2 of 9</span>
				    	</p></div>
</div>
</figure>



<ul>
<li>Dual Wielding two Defender Knight Swords (16 Physical Attack Power) with 15 Physical Attack, Ramza dealt 156 damage twice, for a total of 312 damage.</li>



<li><em>Note:</em> This ability, however, has some potential instability, as either of the two attacks may miss, significantly reducing the total damage.</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-doublehand-damage-testing">Doublehand Damage testing</h3>


<figure>
<div>

<figure>
<figure><figcaption><em>Ramza Gallant Knight Doublehand Build</em></figcaption></figure>



<figure></figure>
</figure>
<div>
				    		
				    		
					    	<p><span>2 of 9</span>
				    	</p></div>
</div>
</figure>



<ul>
<li>Wielding the Defender Knight Sword (16 Physical Attack Power) with 15 Physical Attack, Ramza dealt 313 damage, consistent with Doublehand's 2x damage multiplier.</li>



<li><em>Note:</em> This resulted in the highest single hit damage with no risk of total damage reduction from a miss.</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-monk-dual-wield-damage-testing">Monk (Dual Wield) Damage Testing</h3>


<figure>
<div>

<figure>
<figure><figcaption><em>Ramza Monk Dual Wield Build</em></figcaption></figure>



<figure></figure>
</figure>
<div>
				    		
				    		
					    	<p><span>2 of 9</span>
				    	</p></div>
</div>
</figure>



<ul>
<li>Changing Ramza's Job to Monk and using Dual Wield to make him attack twice (bare-handed), the character dealt 215 damage twice, for a total of 430 damage.</li>



<li><em>Note:</em> This combination achieved the highest total damage of all tests performed under the same conditions.</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-attack-boost-damage-testing">Attack Boost Damage Testing</h3>


<figure>
<div>

<figure>
<figure><figcaption><em>Ramza Gallant Knight Attack Boost Build</em></figcaption></figure>



<figure></figure>
</figure>
<div>
				    		
				    		
					    	<p><span>2 of 9</span>
				    	</p></div>
</div>
</figure>



<ul>
<li>Wielding the Defender Knight Sword (16 Physical Attack Power) with 15 Physical Attack and Attack Boost equipped, Ramza dealt 201 damage, the lowest total damage value of the test.</li>
</ul>


<figure>
<div>

<figure>
<figure><figcaption><em>Holy Knight Agrias: Damage comparison with and without Attack Boost</em></figcaption></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>
</figure>
<div>
				    		
				    		
					    	<p><span>2 of 9</span>
				    	</p></div>
</div>
</figure>



<p>While Attack Boost provides the lowest damage increase for the basic Attack command, it is invaluable for abilities that scale with Physical Attack. It applies a 33% bonus to the Physical Attack stat, resulting in a damage bonus for nearly all physical abilities (like Martial Arts, Holy Sword, Swordplay, and Unyielding Blade), where Dual Wield and Doublehand have no effect.</p>



<p>Now that you know how to optimize your Physical Attack damage, you are ready to take on some of the game's most powerful enemies, like the one waiting for Ramza inside <a href="https://wccftech.com/how-to/how-to-win-the-battle-at-riovanes-castle-keep-in-final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles-guide/">Riovanes Castle in Chapter 3</a>. If you need more help, check out our other <a href="https://wccftech.com/tag/final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles-guides/">Final Fantasy Tactics - The Ivalice Chronicles guides</a>.</p>





			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/how-to/final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles-the-best-support-abilities-for-max-physical-damage/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Legends: Z-A Has Started to Leak Online, Early Builds, Pokédex, and More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-leak-online-early-builds-pokedex-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-legends-z-a-has-started-to-leak-online-early-builds-pok%C3%A9dex-and-more.1323598/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Pokémon Legends: Z-A is due out on Nintendo Switch and Nintendo Switch 2 <a href="https://wccftech.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-launches-on-october-16-with-improved-graphics-and-frame-rates-for-the-nintendo-switch-2-version/">this coming Thursday, October 16, 2025,</a> and ahead of that launch, massive leaks are already starting to appear online. <a href="https://x.com/3clipse_tt">X (formerly Twitter) user 3clipse_tt</a> claims to have accessed an early build of the game and has been posting clips from what they've discovered, showing mechanics and features not in the final version. Another user, <a href="https://x.com/PokeVerse93">PokeVerse93</a>, is posting the full Pokédex to X (formerly Twitter).</p>



<p>And, as spotted by <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/spoiler-warning-pokemon-legends-z-a-leaks-have-started-ahead-of-its-release/">VGC</a>, you can head to Twitch, <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/search?term=pokemon%20legends%20z-a">including at the time of this writing</a>, and find users livestreaming the game.</p>



<p>Needless to say, if you're excited to play Pokémon Legends: Z-A and don't want to be spoiled on things like new Pokémon being introduced, new mega evolutions, and what you're missing out on because Nintendo and The Pokémon Company decided not to include it in the final game, stay away from the above links.</p>



<p>Earlier this year in July, we got our last major look at Pokémon Legends: Z-A with <a href="https://wccftech.com/pokemon-presents-legends-z-a-story-trailer-pokemon-friends-pokemon-champions/">a new story trailer that debuted at a Pokémon Presents event</a>. We also got the reveal of a Nintendo Switch 2 bundle for the game, which, if how Nintendo treated limited editions of the original Nintendo Switch is anything to go by, will surely be followed by a special, Pokémon Legends: Z-A-themed Nintendo Switch 2 console.</p>



<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 is also, unsurprisingly, the best place to play Legends: Z-A, as it is said to include "<em>improved graphics</em> <em>and frame rates</em>" compared to the version on the original Nintendo Switch. We'll see when it arrives, though, if that means that on Switch 2, Legends: Z-A runs at an acceptable, albeit low, frame rate, while on Switch 1, it runs like a slideshow. </p>

			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-leak-online-early-builds-pokedex-more/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Players Are Taking Advantage of XP Farms in Portal While EA Tries to Stop Them]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-players-advantage-xp-farms-portal-ea-tries-to-stop-them/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-players-are-taking-advantage-of-xp-farms-in-portal-while-ea-tries-to-stop-them.1323550/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Battlefield 6 has been out on PC and consoles for three days at the time of this writing, and already, players are getting frustrated with the XP grind to unlock new weapons and attachments. So, players have turned to an old workaround for Battlefield games: create a custom server in Portal, and farm XP in bot matches. EA, for its part, is trying to stop players from boosting by shutting down the more popular farms, but players can always make new ones.</p>



<p>Spotted by <a href="https://www.vg247.com/battlefield-6-fast-xp-farms-progression-times-portal-ea-response">VG247</a>, a select few Portal servers were popularized when YouTubers and content creators began making videos with titles like "<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4t5Df2dvxC0"><em>How to Unlock Weapons, Attachments, Gadgets, and Soldiers Faster in Battlefield 6</em>.</a>" Players on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Battlefield6/comments/1o4n1c3/removed_by_moderator/">Reddit</a> were also sharing codes to let other players find their XP-farming servers, as the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Battlefield6/comments/1o5f660/weapon_attachments/">community has seemingly rallied around the feeling</a> that earning XP for weapons, attachments, gadgets, and soldiers is <em>"ridiculously slow</em>."</p>



<p>In response to players using Portal for XP farming, EA seems to be shutting down the more popular servers, and players are now running into error messages telling them that <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Battlefield6/comments/1o5emdf/biggest_shit_take_of_all_launch/">EA's servers "<em>are at max capacity</em>," </a>stopping players from creating new servers.</p>



<p>Of course, this won't last forever, and EA can't exactly play an endless game of whack-a-mole with Portal servers to try and stop everyone from doing any amount of XP farming. It's also not like Battlefield 6 is the first Battlefield game where players have turned to Portal for this exact reason.</p>



<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/battlefield-6-battlefield-is-mostly-back/">Even in our review</a> of Battlefield 6, we noted that the grind for weapons and attachments, specifically those that can only be unlocked through certain situational challenges, wasn't something we particularly liked, even if it can be seen as a way of changing up the tried-and-true method of just levelling up your character and weapon to unlock everything. </p>



<p>Since theoretically, you could jump into matches and focus on only completing those challenges where possible. But that's not exactly the way to play if you're just trying to have a good time in Battlefield 6, or any multiplayer game, for that matter.</p>



<p>Hopefully, we'll see EA stop its whack-a-mole game and adjust some of the situational challenges and XP requirements so that players can unlock what they want, without too much hassle, and the game can find its meta more naturally. Rather than it becoming a case of 'players who farmed XP in Portal vs. players who didn't,' and since only one of those sides is going to have better and more weapons, attachments, and gadgets available to them, it's pretty clear which side is coming out on top.</p>



<p>For more help on the battlefield that doesn't require you jumping into Portal, you can check out our <a href="https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-pc-performance-benchmarks-wreck-havoc-break-stuff-with-solid-performance-on-all-gpus/">benchmarking</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/best/the-best-graphics-cards-for-battlefield-6/">graphics card</a> guides for Battlefield 6 on PC. You can also check out our <a href="https://wccftech.com/how-to/battlefield-6-guide-tips-to-rule-the-battlefield/">tips guide for how to get in the right mindset</a> for Battlefield 6, as well as the <a href="https://wccftech.com/how-to/battlefield-6-guide-best-early-weapons-and-loadouts-for-each-class/">best early game loadouts and weapons guide for your early hours</a>. Lastly, <a href="https://wccftech.com/how-to/battlefield-6-troubleshooting-guide-how-to-fix-common-pc-errors/">check out our troubleshooting guide</a> if you've been running into any of the launch bugs and errors on PC that have plagued the game's first few days. For everything else, you can check out all our Battlefield 6 <a href="https://wccftech.com/tag/battlefield-6/">coverage here</a>.</p>





			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-players-advantage-xp-farms-portal-ea-tries-to-stop-them/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>