<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 14:30:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NCSOFT’s Third-Person Battle Royale Time Takers Wants You To Have Ways To Win “Even If Your Aim Isn’t Perfect”]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/time-takers-ncsoft-ways-to-win-even-if-your-aim-isnt-perfect-gamescom-onl-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ncsoft%E2%80%99s-third-person-battle-royale-time-takers-wants-you-to-have-ways-to-win-%E2%80%9Ceven-if-your-aim-isn%E2%80%99t-perfect%E2%80%9D.1283994/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Time Takers is a new PvP third-person action-hero-shooter that was debuted by publisher NCSOFT and developer Mistill Games during <a href="https://wccftech.com/topic/gamescom/">Gamescom ONL 2025</a>. Instead of picking one side of combat, where you're either focused on melee or ranged engagements, Mistill Games wants you to have total freedom with how you play. The studio's chief executive officer and the game's director, Yongmin Jo, also calls it giving more players a chance to win "<em>even if your aim isn't perfect."</em></p>



<p>The game was revealed at Gamescom ONL 2025, with its debut trailer focused more on its fantastical setting, which is one where the heroes you play as are pulled from all different corners of time. A medieval-era knight fights alongside a futuristic astronaut monkey and a bionic samurai with insanely powerful robot legs. To call it a mash-up is almost an understatement.</p>



<p>More recently, a new developer video featuring Yongmin Jo digs into the core features of the game, showing how teamwork and the freedom to develop your own strategy is at the heart of real success in Time Takers, as you're constantly racing against the clock, trying to give yourself more time on the battlefield to be the last squad standing.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Time Takers | Dev Video : CORE GAME FEATURES" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/W9Bvd-iknp0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>As part of its teamwork focus, the core mechanic in Time Takers is the fact that you are always trying to take more time for yourself and your squad to survive. You'll constantly make decisions around your Time Energy, whether to save it to help you survive for longer, or to use it to charge your abilities and help you be more aggressive in each match.</p>



<p>It seems to be a mechanical way of trying to prevent each match from having a surplus of players that just  try to wait the whole match out and try to win by taking the final two fighting squads by surprise. It's a strategy you could surely employ, but you'd be doing so from a disadvantage, as you've had to spend your energy on staying in the game, instead of trying to win it.</p>



<p>If Time Takers looks like the kind of game you'd want to try, then you'll soon be able to, as there is an upcoming playtest you can <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3596040/Time_Takers/">currently sign up for on its Steam page.</a></p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/time-takers-ncsoft-ways-to-win-even-if-your-aim-isnt-perfect-gamescom-onl-2025/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valor Mortis Gamescom Hands-On Preview – An Amazing Standout, and One of the Show’s Best]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/valor-mortis-gamescom-hands-on-preview-an-amazing-standout-and-one-of-the-shows-best/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valor-mortis-gamescom-hands-on-preview-%E2%80%93-an-amazing-standout-and-one-of-the-show%E2%80%99s-best.1283889/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Like always, this year's Gamescom was accompanied by a slew of new game announcements. Among the new games revealed during one of the most important video gaming events of the year was <a href="https://valormortis.game/">Valor Mortis</a>, a first-person soulslike in development by One More Level, the Polish development studio known for the <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/ghostrunner-death-not-such-terrible/">Ghostrunner</a> series. Having appreciated some of the features of the first entry in the series, such as the amazing mobility of the main character and its uncompromising approach, but not being particularly keen on how restrictive the entire experience felt, I wasn't particularly thrilled about the new game, which looked at a glance like another take on the formula with an underused setting in video games. My first impression of the game was not only completely off the mark but turned upside down completely when I finally got to spend more time with it.</p>



<p>As mentioned above, Valor Mortis is a first-person soulslike where players take on the role of William, a soldier in the Grande Armée brought back from the dead to continue serving Napoleon and save Europe from the mysterious plague that is destroying the continent, corrupting its inhabitants beyond repair. The premise alone is more than enough to set the game apart from every other souslike on the market, as not only the setting is really unique, but the first person gameplay seems to harken back to the days of the King's Field series back when FromSoftware was still refining the formula that the studio would make popular with Demon's Souls and the first Dark Souls.</p>



<p>Going the soulslike route with their new game, One More Level doesn't seem to have forgotten its past games, as Valor Mortis' smooth gameplay has some echoes of the Ghostrunner games' experience. Controlling William is extremely smooth, and the experience feels past paced without being on steroids like in the studio's older franchise, as combat still retails the heaviness and positioning focus of a soulslike. What I really enjoyed in Valor Mortis is how the first-person perspective is allowing the developer to nail how proper soulslike combat encounters should be - duels, or fights against a smaller number of enemies - going the opposite direction of many developers who prefer to overwhelm the player with huge enemy numbers using a combat system not really suited for big enemy numbers. </p>


<figure>
<div>

<figure>
<figure><figcaption>Valor Mortis was without a doubt one of the best games I tried during this year's Gamescom</figcaption></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>
</figure>
<div>
			    		
			    		
				    	<p><span>2 of 9</span>
			    	</p></div>
</div>
</figure>



<p>Following a few minutes of adjustments to the new perspective, I was immediately hooked to the experience, fighting enemies with short-range weapons and guns, unleashing special abilities, dodging, and parrying attacks with ease. Ultimately, the experience seems to strike a good balance regarding challenge, but as the game is still far from release, it is difficult to say how challenging Valor Mortis will actually be. In terms of level design, Valor Mortis also seems to be on point. The devasted battlefield where the Gamescom demo was set featured an intricate design with plenty of shortcuts and alternate paths, including some optional locations featuring powerful enemies, so it feels like One More Level is placing a decent amount of focus on traversal as much as it is on combat.</p>



<p>After taking down many corrupted soldiers and dying a few times in the process, I reached a massive corrupted soldier who served as the demo's final boss. Comprised of two phases, this boss fight put my limited knowledge of the Valor Mortis mechanics to the test, offering another look at how guns can be used to hit weakpoints and make some fights a little easier. After learning the boss' attack patterns, parrying and dodging accordingly, I managed to take it down with a few minutes to spare, which a member of the development team used to show me another enemy encounter where the player can use ranged weapons to destroy the cannon carried by the enemy to deal tons of damage. Sadly, my time with Valor Mortis ended right after this small additional showcase, leaving me hungering for more.</p>



<p>In a market becoming a little saturated with average soulslike that fail to capture what makes this sort of game so compelling, Valor Mortis feels like a breath of fresh air, as No More Level has shown, with this demo, to understand what a proper soulslike should feature. As such, the game was easily one of the best I had the pleasure of trying during this year's Gamescom, and one I really cannot wait to get my hands on the final game. Thankfully, some players won't have to wait until the game releases next year on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X, and Xbox Series S to experience for themselves what makes Valor Mortis such a good game, as a playtest will be conducted soon.</p>





			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/valor-mortis-gamescom-hands-on-preview-an-amazing-standout-and-one-of-the-shows-best/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil Requiem Will Be a ‘Complete Rollercoaster Ride’ Like Never Before in the Series, Says CAPCOM]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-requiem-complete-rollercoaster-ride-never-before/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/resident-evil-requiem-will-be-a-%E2%80%98complete-rollercoaster-ride%E2%80%99-like-never-before-in-the-series-says-capcom.1283865/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Aside from Grand Theft Auto VI, which was not featured at Gamescom 2025, Resident Evil Requiem is undoubtedly among the most hyped upcoming titles, and the German convention confirmed it. The first public hands-on of the ninth mainline chapter in CAPCOM's horror franchise convinced press and fans alike, as <a href="https://wccftech.com/gamescom-2025-awards-resident-evil-requiem-capcom/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">evidenced by the many Gamescom awards won</a>.</p>



<p>During Gamescom, CAPCOM also discussed Resident Evil Requiem in greater depth throughout a few interviews. For example, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tooB3GgtU8Y" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">speaking with Gamesradar</a>, Game Director Koshi Nakanishi explained that the new game will feel like a complete rollercoaster ride thanks to much greater extremes when it comes to all the classic Resident Evil elements of horror, tension, action, and release.</p>



<p><em>I think the two recent titles, Resident Evil 4 remake and Village, are more on the action side of the series in terms of the mixture of elements that they have. Resident Evil Requiem is something different. If I had to compare it to past titles, it's more along the lines of Resident Evil 7 or the Resident Evil 2 remake. You could call it old school Resident Evil, you know, with exploration and backtracking and that kind of thing. It does, of course, feature all the classic core pillars of Resident Evil features that everyone knows and loves, such as combat, exploration, puzzle solving, resource management of limited number of items, and we've given it our own spin this time for Resident Evil Requiem's game atmosphere.</em></p>



<p><em>Speaking then to Resident Evil 7 and 2, I think they reflect a typical game design that we have for this series, where you can't keep the horror tension to the max through the whole game, because it's quite exhausting. So, you need to have this dynamic pacing curve where you'll have a a very tense, horrific sequence, and then we give you a bit of a release or a catharsis from that and let you come down from that with more slightly peaceful exploration or some exciting comba,t and then we gradually bring you back up the horror part of the curve.</em></p>



<p><em>Again, that's the standard practice for Resident Evil. The difference this time is there's a new system that I can't quite get into yet, but if you think of the difference between the tension and the release being a certain size of wavelength, as it were, of that curve, I want to make the distance between those aspects bigger than ever before in the series, and it just becomes a complete roller coaster ride between the different aspects of the series. I'm very excited for people to eventually understand what I mean by that.</em></p>



<p>Resident Evil Requiem is scheduled to launch on February 27, 2026 for PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series S|X. On PC, the game <a href="https://wccftech.com/nvidia-dlss-4-supported-175-games-resident-evil-requiem-path-tracing/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">will support path tracing</a> (the first RE Engine title to do so) and NVIDIA DLSS 4 Multi Frame Generation.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-requiem-complete-rollercoaster-ride-never-before/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater New Mod Addresses One of the Game’s Most Critical Issues]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-mod-critical-issues/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-new-mod-addresses-one-of-the-game%E2%80%99s-most-critical-issues.1283862/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A new Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater mod now available for download addresses one of the most critical issues found in the PC version of the game: the 60 FPS framerate cap.</p>



<p>The Better Uncap FPS mod, now available for download from <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/metalgearsoliddeltasnakeeater/mods/47?tab=description">Nexus Mods</a>, allows users to cycle between different FPS targets between 30, 60, 100, 120, 144, and uncapped, with the uncapped option being the default. In addition, the mod also features an experimental audio sync fix, disables Depth of Field, Motion Blur, Refraction Blur, Chromatic Aberration, Lens Distortion, Film Grain, and Tonemapper for cleaner and sharper visuals and fully supports Lossless Scaling. Before downloading the mod, you can check it out in action in the video below.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Better Uncap FPS v1.2 for METAL GEAR SOLID Δ: SNAKE EATER" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ypg27q2Xb4E?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Although this new Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater mod definitely goes a long way in improving the game, the new options are not enough to completely fix a game released in a rather bad state. Some of its visual elements, such as particle effects, cause some massive performance drops, as highlighted on X by Benchmarking, so it definitely looks like developer Virtuos has <a href="https://wccftech.com/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-patch-gameplay-issues-crashes/">a lot of work ahead</a> to fix a game that deserved to be released in a much better state on all platforms.</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Another issue I noticed in this broken game is that whenever particles (especially dust) spawn near the camera, performance drops significantly. <br>The only solution I found is to disable these particles entirely using:<br>[SystemSettings]<br>fx.EnableNiagaraSpriteRendering=0<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MGSDelta?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MGSDelta</a> <a href="https://t.co/BJClQuino6">pic.twitter.com/BJClQuino6</a></p>— BenchmarKing (@BMKing23) <a href="https://twitter.com/BMKing23/status/1961089149873623136?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 28, 2025</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater is now available on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X and Xbox Series S. You can learn more about the remake of one of the best entries in the series by checking out Kai's <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-ps5-review-based-on-a-hideo-kojima-game/">review.</a></p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-mod-critical-issues/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>