<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 17:54:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Epic Games Store Year in Review Released – Players Spend 2.68 Billion Hours Playing Third-Party PC Titles]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/epic-games-store-year-in-review-released-players-spend-2-68-billion-hours-playing-third-party-pc-titles/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/epic-games-store-year-in-review-released-%E2%80%93-players-spend-2-68-billion-hours-playing-third-party-pc-titles.1109826/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/epic-games-store-year-in-review-released-players-spend-2-68-billion-hours-playing-third-party-pc-titles/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Epic Games Store <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/news/epic-games-store-2024-year-in-review" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Year in Review</a> is now available, which provides a look back at 2024, as well as sharing what's to come this year, including some of the most anticipated features of the store and some massive releases. While there are a fair amount of PC gamers who don't favor the Epic Games Store, the community has continued to grow, with there being more than 295 million PC users (up by 25 million from 2023) and a total of 898 million Epic cross-platform accounts (up by 94 million from 2023.)</p>
<p>Additionally, players are engaging more with games than ever before, with the grand total being amassed to 2.68 billion hours of playtime with third-party games in 2024. With the use of Self-Publishing Tools and opt-in programs being available to up-and-coming developers, the Epic Games Store saw the catalog expand by a whopping 1,100 new games. Even for those who don't want to purchase games, the free games program provides a lot of new and fun titles for those who add them to their library, spanning from triple-A titles to hidden indie gems.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>December was a significant month for the storefront, with there being 74 MAU (Monthly Active Users) in December 2024, which was likely boosted thanks to the <a href="https://wccftech.com/epic-games-store-winter-sale-live-now-massive-discounts-for-many-great-games/">holiday sales</a> and the free games that were given away to celebrate the festive season. In total, Epic Games offered 89 free games over the span of 2024, with 595 million free games being claimed by Epic Games Store users. This led to a total value of $2,229 per player, with a 76% average score across all free games provided.</p>
<p>As Epic Games continues to grow and flourish, it has been confirmed that the Free Games Program will continue to run and will now continue on both PC and mobile, allowing players to experience games on handheld devices that they previously wouldn't be able to access.</p>
<p>While most PC gamers purchase their desired titles on Steam, $1.09 billion was spent by PC players in the Epic Games Store, with $255 million spent by players on third-party PC games that were available in the Epic Games Store.</p>
<p>Looking into 2025, Epic Games Store has some major plans for the year ahead. This includes focusing on the Epic Games Store Mobile App, which will allow for an enhanced App Library and Discover Experience with an ever-increasing catalog size. For the developers, there will be AAB file type support.</p>
<p>Additionally, as the storefront has continued to nurture new developers and help them publish games on the app, the store will also add mobile self-publishing tools, which are currently available on an invite-only beta.</p>
<p>There will be some major games coming to the Epic Games Store this year too, including Splitgate 2, 33 Immortals, Killing Floor 3, Borderlands 4 and Cronos: The New Dawn.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Heart Machine Reveals First Early Access Roadmap for Hyper Light Breaker]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/heart-machine-reveals-first-early-access-roadmap-for-hyper-light-breaker/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/heart-machine-reveals-first-early-access-roadmap-for-hyper-light-breaker.1109718/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/heart-machine-reveals-first-early-access-roadmap-for-hyper-light-breaker/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>After getting off to a slightly rocky start, Heart Machine has revealed its plans for Hyper Light Breaker in the game's first Early Access roadmap. The roadmap details a ton of changes coming to the game from February through to April. While a lot of the changes are minor additions in February and March, April will bring a major content update titled "Buried Below." Below is the Early Access roadmap - Spring Edition, which showcases some of the changes and additions you can expect to see in Hyper Light Breaker.</p>
<p>If you want to learn more about Hyper Light Breaker, check out our <a href="https://wccftech.com/hyper-light-breaker-preview-lo-fi-roguelite/">preview here</a>.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>For those who are excited about the new content, the first monthly content update for Hyper Light Breaker will be released on February 18, which will add in a new Breaker to play, new enemies, Holobytes, Affixes, and plenty of rebalances and performance updates to make sure that the game is fun but also provides a challenge to those who want it while playing this roguelite.</p>
<p>The Breaker being added to Hyper Light Breaker is named Ravona, who was previously codenamed "Crow." Along with this comes new SyComs for Ravona as well as new enemies to face off against, including a new Elite enemy if you find yourself needing a challenge in Hyper Light Breaker. As mentioned above, new Holobytes are being added in this update, such as "Hunter's Mark," as well as new Affixes that provide a new challenge to your playthrough. Ravona has been a highly-anticipated Breaker by the community, with the team saying that the community would request to see gameplay of the character daily since the Breaker was shown in the Gameplay Reveal Trailer.</p>
<p>Because Hyper Light Breaker was released in Early Access, Heart Machine is dedicated to taking on player's feedback and suggestions, where they have the potential to be integrated into the game. Whether that's to provide new content or make much-needed fixes, there will be plenty of updates during the Early Access period. This includes expanded control and graphics options, bug fixes, and a rework of the enemy aggro system.</p>
<p>One of the main fixes that will be added to the game includes a rework of the Medkit system, which was previously perceived as too harsh by the players. Instead, players will now be able to start with a Medkit in their runs.</p>
<p>Hyper Light Breaker is currently available in Early Access on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1534840/Hyper_Light_Breaker/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PC via Steam</a>.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft CEO Plans to Focus on Open World and Live Service Games]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-ceo-plans-to-focus-on-open-world-and-live-service-games/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-ceo-plans-to-focus-on-open-world-and-live-service-games.1109685/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-ceo-plans-to-focus-on-open-world-and-live-service-games/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Yves Guillemot has stated that Ubisoft plans to focus on Open World Action-Adventure games and live service games year-on-year. <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/ubisoft-ceo-says-the-plan-is-to-focus-on-open-world-and-live-service-games-year-after-year/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Originally posted by VGC</a>, Guillemot went on to confirm that the company's way of getting out of hot water was to continue exactly the way it has been. This information game during a Q&amp;A that followed after the company's financial results for Q3 of the 2024-25 financial year.&nbsp;In this presentation, a caller asked if the executives could provide more information on what the development pipeline looks like for the future.</p>
<p>In response to this, CEO Yves Guillemot said that the focus would be on open-world adventures, such as the longstanding franchise Assassin's Creed, as well as live service games such as Rainbow Six Siege. The choice to include live-service games definitely comes as a surprise to some, considering its recent announcement to shutter the <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisofts-xdefiant-will-be-closing-down-for-good-in-june-2025/">live-service title XDefiant</a>, with the servers of this live-service game due to close in June 2025.</p>
<p>"We have been investing significantly for a big pipeline of products for the coming years along our two verticals, these being open-world action-adventure as well as 'Game as a Service'-native experiences," said Guillemot. "And that's what we want to deliver year after year."</p>
<p>In this presentation, games that have already been confirmed were discussed. This includes Assassin's Creed Shadows, which will be the latest open-world game ready to be released. However, this game has already caused a significant amount of controversy, and it hasn't been released yet. Initially set to be released last year, the game has received multiple pushbacks, with it set to release on 20 March, 2025.</p>
<p>"We've announced that Anno 117: Pax Romana will also come next year, as well as The Division: Resurgence on mobile. All this is coming along well. We haven't provided more color for FY 2026, but we'll have more to share by the time of May."</p>
<p>Guillemot also mentioned that Assassin's Creed Shadows pre-orders were in the same ballpark as those of Assassin's Creed Odyssey, which was the second most successful entry in terms of unit sales. Despite the controversy, it seems that Assassin's Creed Shadows may be in with a chance of helping provide redemption for the struggling company Ubisoft.</p>
<p>It's not much of a secret that Ubisoft has been struggling for a while, with there being studio closures and layoffs far too often. On top of that, all of the money that was funneled into Star Wars Outlaws wasn't beneficial to the company, as it didn't perform as well as Ubisoft had hoped.</p>
<p>Whether Assassin's Creed Shadows will be the saving grace of the company remains to be seen, with its tentative release date around the corner.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Nightreign Additional Network Test Sessions Are Being Considered Following Server Issues]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-nightreign-additional-test-sessions/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-nightreign-additional-network-test-sessions-are-being-considered-following-server-issues.1109682/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-nightreign-additional-test-sessions/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>More opportunities to test Elden Ring Nightreign may be coming today following the server issues that have prevented many from trying out the game in the very first testing session.</p>
<p>At the end of the first testing session, FromSoftware shared a message on <a href="https://x.com/fromsoftware_sp" target="_blank" rel="noopener">X</a> apologizing for the server issues and revealing that they are considering holding additional tests. Like many other PlayStation 5 users, I couldn't access the network test at all in the first hour or so due to the server going offline to fix issues, and I wasn't able to get into a single game once the server went back online. I was only able to wander around the Roundtable Hold and head into the new training area for a few minutes before the connection was lost.</p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="ja">ELDEN RING NIGHTREIGNゲームサーバーの障害によりプレイヤーの皆様にはご迷惑をおかけし誠に申し訳ございません。本日のネットワークテストは予定通り23時に終了とさせていただき、改善作業を進めます。本日分については追加でテスト開催を検討しております。ご理解ご了承をいただけますと幸いです。</p>
<p>— FROMSOFTWARE PLAYER SUPPORT (@fromsoftware_sp) <a href="https://twitter.com/fromsoftware_sp/status/1890398112071536834?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 14, 2025</a></p></blockquote>

<p>Being an online co-op-focused experience, it is definitely a good thing that FromSoftware is holding this Elden Ring Nightreign Network Test and that issues are surfacing now and not after the game has launched.<a href="https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-nightreign-release-date/">&nbsp;</a><span><a href="https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-nightreign-release-date/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Earlier this week</a>, we got a new look at the game with a new trailer and confirmation that it will be released on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X, and Xbox Series S on May 30th.</span> Together with the standard edition, multiple Elden Ring Nightreign special editions will also be released on the same day, including an exclusive collectible produced in limited quantities.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>