<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 11:41:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil 9 Still Reportedly Planned for 2025 Reveal and 2026 Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-9-still-reportedly-planned-for-2025-reveal-and-2026-launch/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/resident-evil-9-still-reportedly-planned-for-2025-reveal-and-2026-launch.1190997/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-9-still-reportedly-planned-for-2025-reveal-and-2026-launch/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>According to insider Dusk Golem, who is often well-informed about CAPCOM's roadmap, Resident Evil 9 should still be planned for a 2025 reveal and subsequent 2026 launch. Here's what the leaker <a href="https://twitter.com/AestheticGamer1/status/1922384237392523592?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1922384237392523592%7Ctwgr%5E82e2561ec4f34e05178b2da1d63217fb52be56fe%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamereactor.eu%2Frumour-resident-evil-9-will-be-announced-this-year-1544383%2F" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote on X</a>:</p>
<p><em>It's almost 100% for sure being revealed this year and releasing next year. Doubt they'll delay more. The question comes if its being revealed this summer or at TGA for example this year, &amp; if its releasing this fiscal year (ending March 31st, 2026) or next fiscal year late 2026.</em></p>
<p>Dusk Golem previously <a href="https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-9-signapore-island/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> that Resident Evil 9 would be set on a Singapore-inspired island, more specifically in a rural town. The rural town setting was already explored in Resident Evil 4 and Resident Evil Village, although of course, those took place in Spain and Romania, respectively. The Southeast Asian setting alone should provide some freshness.</p>
<p>Last year, Dusk Golem also <a href="https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-9-monster-hunter-wilds-rumored-to-be-open-world/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">claimed</a> that both Resident Evil 9 and Monster Hunter Wilds would be open world games. The latter was released in late February and was indeed an open world, so the insider was probably right about the next Resident Evil, too.</p>
<p>More recently, Dusk Golem <a href="https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-9-reinvention-series/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">clarified</a> why the new game is taking a long time. CAPCOM is reportedly reinventing the series and trying new things, much like it did with Resident Evil 4 and Resident Evil VII. Fans shouldn't expect it to play like Resident Evil Village. Whether that means a return to third-person view remains to be seen.</p>
<p>When it comes to the reveal, there are a number of options for the publisher, from the Summer Game Fest taking place next month to Gamescom in August and then finally Tokyo Game Show in September. Of course, it's also possible for CAPCOM to play coy until The Game Awards in December, but that would likely mean a release window in the latter half of 2026.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gears of War Film Will Be Directed by David Leitch]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/gears-of-war-film-will-be-directed-by-david-leitch/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gears-of-war-film-will-be-directed-by-david-leitch.1190913/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/gears-of-war-film-will-be-directed-by-david-leitch/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Gears of War film adaptation has found its director. Deadline <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/movies/movie-news/gears-of-war-movie-david-leitch-director-1236212544/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reports</a> that David Leitch has been selected for the job; he's also expected to produce alongside Kelly McCormick, his wife and producing partner, via their 87North Productions and alongside game developer The Coalition. Leitch is known for movies like Atomic Blonde, Deadpool 2, Fast &amp; Furious: Hobbs &amp; Shaw, Bullet Train, and The Fall Guy.</p>
<p>However, he won't be working on the Gears of War film right away. Leitch is currently in the pre-production phase of How to Rob a Bank, an upcoming bank robber movie featuring Nicholas Hoult, Anna Sawai, and Zoë Kravitz. Meanwhile,&nbsp;<span>as originally <a href="https://wccftech.com/gears-of-war-film-closer-to-fruition-after-bringing-on-board-dune-doctor-strange-writer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a> two years ago, Jon Spaihts (who is credited with Prometheus, Doctor Strange, Passengers, and the two Dune movies) is still&nbsp;writing the script for the Gears of War movie</span>.</p>
<p>The announcement of the adaptation <a href="https://wccftech.com/gears-of-war-netflix-film-animated-series/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">came in November 2022</a>. The movie will be distributed on Netflix, which secured the rights at a time when gaming adaptations weren't so in demand. After the outstanding reception of The Last of Us and Fallout, though, there are more on the way, including <a href="https://wccftech.com/god-of-war-tv-series-officially-coming-from-amazon-prime-video/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">God of War</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/mass-effect-tv-series-in-development-at-prime-video-with-fast-and-furious-9-writer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mass Effect</a>.</p>
<p>As for new game installments in The Coalition franchise, there's a lot on the way. <a href="https://wccftech.com/gears-of-war-e-day-prequel-announced-by-the-coalition/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gears of War: E-Day</a> is a prequel set on Emergence Day, when the Locust Horde swarmed the surface of the planet Sera, featuring younger versions of Marcus Fenix and Dom Santiago. It is being developed by People Can Fly alongside The Coalition; there's no release date yet, but we might very well learn more in a month during the yearly Xbox Games Showcase.</p>
<p>This Summer, <a href="https://wccftech.com/gears-of-war-reloaded-launches-on-pc-playstation-5-xbox-series-xs-this-summer-with-full-cross-progression-and-cross-platform-multiplayer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gears of War: Reloaded</a> will bring back the original game remastered and improved for the latest hardware. It will also mark the franchise's debut on Sony's PlayStation 5 console, now that Microsoft has shifted to a fully multiplatform strategy.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blue Protocol: Star Resonance Lives Again, Will Launch This Year on PC and Mobile]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/blue-protocol-star-resonance-lives-again-will-launch-this-year-on-pc-and-mobile/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/blue-protocol-star-resonance-lives-again-will-launch-this-year-on-pc-and-mobile.1190901/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/blue-protocol-star-resonance-lives-again-will-launch-this-year-on-pc-and-mobile/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>MMORPG fans can rejoice: <a href="https://wccftech.com/blue-protocol-to-launch-on-pc-first-in-japan-may-support-cross-play-additional-features-detailed/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Blue Protocol</a> lives once again. The anime-styled free-to-play MMORPG originally developed by Bandai Namco Online Studios flopped in Japan, was shut down there, and <a href="https://wccftech.com/blue-protocol-is-being-shut-down-in-japan-and-the-western-launch-is-canceled/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">had its Western release canceled</a>. That seemed to be the end for Blue Protocol, but a developer called Shanghai Bokura Network Technology Co.Ltd has grabbed the rights and is now reviving it for a planned launch this year globally on PC and mobile with cross-play. There's been no mention of consoles, which were planned for the game's original version.</p>
<p>The game is now called Blue Protocol: Star Resonance, although its feature set is essentially the same.</p>
<ul>
<li><em><strong>Anime-Styled Visuals</strong>: Stunning graphics create an immersive anime-style world while preserving&nbsp;<span>Blue</span>&nbsp;<span>Protocol</span>’s high-quality visuals.&nbsp;</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Dynamic Combat System</strong>: Class system, talent build, skill sets, and equipment enable personalized combat style customization, with iterative content updates actively diversifying the approaches.&nbsp;</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Open World</strong>: Explore expansive landscapes filled with quests, dungeons, and epic raids.&nbsp;</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Deep Character Customization</strong>: Expand character customization, enabling players to craft their own distinct personalities.&nbsp;</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Multiplayer Social Experience</strong>: Trade, guilds, and community events enhance the multiplayer experience.</em></li>
</ul>
<p><iframe title="Blue Protocol: Star Resonance | Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aI_qVWHiHnQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3681810/Blue_Protocol_Star_Resonance/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/blue-protocol-star-resonance-27bff9?lang=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a> pages also include the official system requirements for Blue Protocol: Star Resonance. You can find them below.</p>
<div>
<p><em><strong>Minimum:</strong></em></p>
<ul>
<li>
<ul>
<li><em><strong>OS:</strong>&nbsp;Windows 10 64-bit</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Processor:</strong>&nbsp;Intel i7-8700 or AMD Ryzen 5 3600 or better</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Memory:</strong>&nbsp;16 GB RAM</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Graphics:</strong>&nbsp;NVIDIA GeForce GTX 1060 6GB or AMD Radeon RX 580 or better</em></li>
<li><em><strong>DirectX:</strong>&nbsp;Version 11</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Network:</strong>&nbsp;Broadband Internet connection</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Storage:</strong>&nbsp;35 GB available space</em></li>
<li><em><strong>VR Support:</strong>&nbsp;Not supported.</em></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div>
<p><em><strong>Recommended:</strong></em></p>
<ul>
<li>
<ul>
<li><em><strong>OS:</strong>&nbsp;Windows 10 64-bit</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Processor:</strong>&nbsp;Intel i7-11700K or AMD Ryzen 7 5700X or better</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Memory:</strong>&nbsp;16 GB RAM</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Graphics:</strong>&nbsp;NVIDIA GeForce RTX 2060 or AMD Radeon RX 5600 XT or better</em></li>
<li><em><strong>DirectX:</strong>&nbsp;Version 11</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Network:</strong>&nbsp;Broadband Internet connection</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Storage:</strong>&nbsp;35 GB available space</em></li>
<li><em><strong>VR Support:</strong>&nbsp;Not supported.</em></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</div>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>