<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 18:22:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bungie Announces Marathon Delay, New Release Date To Be Revealed Sometime This Fall]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/bungie-announces-marathon-delay-new-release-date-to-be-revealed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bungie-announces-marathon-delay-new-release-date-to-be-revealed-sometime-this-fall.1221048/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/bungie-announces-marathon-delay-new-release-date-to-be-revealed/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Bungie has <a href="https://www.bungie.net/7/en/News/Article/marathon_update">announced</a> that its upcoming shooter, Marathon, has been delayed from its initial <a href="https://wccftech.com/bungie-showcases-marathon-gameplay-release-date-announced-for-september-2025/">September 23, 2025,</a> release date. No new release date was provided, instead Bungie said that the team would give players an update sometime this fall as to how the game's development is progressing, and would share a new release date at that time.</p>
<p>The news was announced with a <a href="https://www.bungie.net/7/en/News/Article/marathon_update">blog post</a> from the Marathon development team, and is the most significant communication the team has had with players <a href="https://wccftech.com/bungie-confirms-that-marathon-includes-art-assets-taken-from-an-artist-without-permission/">since a live stream event</a> where Bungie addressed that a former artist on the Marathon team had used assets from artist Antireal without her permission.</p>
<p>"<em>Thank you <span data-contrast="none">not only for your passionate feedback around the&nbsp;</span><span data-contrast="none">Marathon&nbsp;</span><span data-contrast="none">reveal and Alpha playtest, but also for your patience while we took the time to listen closely and chart our next</span></em> steps," Bungie began in the blog post.</p>
<p>"<em>Through every comment and real-time conversation on social media and Discord, your voice has been strong and clear. We've taken&nbsp;this&nbsp;to heart, and we know we need more time to craft&nbsp;Marathon&nbsp;into the game that truly reflects your passion.&nbsp;After much discussion within our Dev team,&nbsp;we’ve made the decision to delay the September 23rd release.</em>"</p>
<p>The post continues to say that the team will use the extra time from this delay to "<em>create the intense, high-stakes experience that a title like Marathon is built around</em>," and also specifies which areas of the game the studio will be immediately focusing on.</p>
<p>These areas include "<em>upping the survival game</em>," which Bungie clarifies to mean bringing "<em>more channeling and engaging AI encounters,</em>" as well as "<em>more rewarding runs, with new types of loot and dynamic events</em>," and&nbsp;<em>"making combat more tense and strategic</em>."</p>
<p>Bungie also adds that it will be "<em>doubling down on the Marathon universe</em>," which it describes as the team adding "<em>increased visual fidelity,"</em> along with "<em>more narrative and environmental storytelling to discover and interact with</em>," and "<em>a darker tone that delivers on themes of the original trilogy</em>."</p>
<p>Lastly, the studio also specifies that it will be working on improving the experience for solo and duo players, as well as adding proximity chat support to the game.</p>
<p>"<em>You'll hear from us again later this Fall when we can share the progress we've made, alongside the game's new release date</em>," Bungie continues. "<em>Thank you again for your patience and - much more importantly - your passion. Your continued feedback will help us make Marathon the incredible gaming experience we all know it can be</em>."</p>
<p>Realistically, this delay comes as no surprise. Beyond the fact that there were<a href="https://wccftech.com/marathon-rumor-of-no-marketing-plans-suggests-potential-delay/"> rumblings about a marketing campaign for the game</a> being canceled, the fact that there was clearly a significant amount of art assets used in designing the entire style and visual language of the game felt like a clear sign that it would take a lot of work to remove that and insert something that wasn't stolen.</p>
<p>Hopefully, when this fall rolls around, we can finally hear some good news about Marathon from Bungie, and not that the game continues to be in a development hellhole.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Announces Multi-Year Deal with AMD to Power Next-Gen Devices]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/xbox-announces-multi-year-deal-with-amd-to-power-next-gen-devices/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-announces-multi-year-deal-with-amd-to-power-next-gen-devices.1220931/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/xbox-announces-multi-year-deal-with-amd-to-power-next-gen-devices/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Xbox president Sarah Bond has just <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VOCtRanwXrA" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> a multi-year deal with AMD to power multiple gaming devices, including the successor of the Xbox Series X. Here's her complete statement from the brief video announcement:</p>
<p><em>At Xbox, our vision is for you to play the games you want, with the people you want, anywhere you want. That's why we're investing in our next-generation hardware lineup, across console, handheld, PC, cloud, and accessories. I am thrilled to share we've established a strategic multi-year partnership with AMD to co-engineer silicon across a portfolio of devices including our next generation Xbox consoles, in your living room, and in your hands.</em></p>
<p><em>Together with AMD, we're advancing the state of art in gaming silicon to deliver the next generation of graphics innovation to unlock a deeper level of visual quality and immersive gameplay and player experiences enhanced with the power of AI, all while maintaining compatibility with your existing library of Xbox games.</em></p>
<p><em>This is all about building you a gaming platform that's always with you, so you can play the games you want across devices anywhere you want, delivering you an Xbox experience not locked to a single store or tied to one device. That's why we're working closely with the Windows team, to ensure that Windows is the number one platform for gaming. The next generation of Xbox is coming to life, and this is just the beginning.</em></p>
<p><iframe title="Xbox + AMD: Powering the Next Generation of Xbox" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VOCtRanwXrA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>It seems like Microsoft wanted to confirm in an official capacity what insiders had <a href="https://wccftech.com/next-gen-xbox-rumored-to-support-backward-compatibility-at-hardware-level/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">already mentioned</a>, such as the fact that the next-generation Xbox will still be compatible with previous-generation games through backward compatibility. Interestingly, Sarah Bond did not reiterate <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-next-generation-largest-technical-leap-ever-seen/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">her previous remark</a> about the next generation Xbox console delivering the 'largest technical leap ever' for consoles, though it's hard to say whether that means fans should lower their performance expectations.</p>
<p>Whatever the case, Microsoft has bypassed the mid-generation refresh (unlike Sony with its PlayStation 5 Pro) and seems ready to get a headstart on the next generation. According to the latest rumors, the Series X successor might <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-next-release-2027-premium-handheld/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">launch</a> in a couple of years.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Epic Announces New PvE Mode LEGO Fortnite Expeditions Launching Tomorrow]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/epic-announces-new-pve-mode-lego-fortnite-expeditions-launching-tomorrow/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/epic-announces-new-pve-mode-lego-fortnite-expeditions-launching-tomorrow.1220886/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/epic-announces-new-pve-mode-lego-fortnite-expeditions-launching-tomorrow/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/epic-games-sues-fortnite-cheat-maker/">Epic</a> has officially <a href="https://www.fortnite.com/news/squad-up-and-save-the-day-in-lego-fortnite-expeditions">announced</a> LEGO Fortnite Expeditions, a new PvE mode that is launching tomorrow, on&nbsp;<strong>June 18, 2025</strong>.</p>
<p>Expeditions is a mission-based mode where you jump into various missions with three other players as a four-player co-op mode all with the aim of taking down a mysteriously masked villain, Mask Maker Daigo, who will destroy the world if you and your friends don't put a stop to his antics first.</p>
<p>You'll head out on these missions from your home base, the Supernova Academy, where you and the newly introduced heroes you'll play as, Shadow Caller, The Hunter, and Rift Ripper, are all training to become the next class of world-saving superheroes.</p>
<p>Epic also unveiled a gameplay trailer showing off each of the three hero classes in action, with Rift Ripper being extremely mobile and capable of reaching high areas with their Rift Jump and a Rift Dodge that works like a short-distance teleport.</p>
<p>Shadow Caller is very mobile in a different way, as they're able to hover above the ground while using magical projectiles to dispatch enemies. While The Hunter is a fast-moving ranged-focused class with a Bull's-eye Blade that can multiply the damage you do and make your attacks more accurate in battle.</p>
<p><iframe title="LEGO Fortnite Expeditions - Super Gameplay Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hMOPVQSHIic?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Beyond the core powers each class has, you'll also be able to increase your damage output with what Epic is calling the 'Tools in the Toolbox,' which gives you the choice between Dual Daggers, a War Hammer, or Plasma Pistols, to add an extra punch to combat.</p>
<p>LEGO Fortnite Expeditions will be available tomorrow and will be found in Discover in LEGO Fortnite, or it can be accessed from Odyssey and Brick Life using the Battle Bus Station.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>