<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:49:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grand Theft Auto: Vice City Nextgen Edition Looks Stunning With Path Tracing Mod]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vice-city-nextgen-edition-path-tracing/</link>
            <guid>1369387</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Grand Theft Auto: Vice City Nextgen Edition, <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vice-city-nextgen-edition/">an unofficial remaster of the classic entry in the series developed by Rockstar Games built in RAGE Engine</a>, looks better than ever before thanks to a new RTX Remix path tracing mod.</p>



<p>A new video shared by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@MxBenchmarkPC" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">MxBenchmarkPC</a> shows the unofficial remaster developed by Revolution Team <a href="https://wccftech.com/gta-4-rtx-remix-compatibility-mod-publicly-available-enjoy-path-tracing/">running with the custom RTX Remix runtime created for the RAGE Engine by Xoxor4d released last week to the public. </a></p>



<p>The side-by-side comparison shown at the beginning of the video highlights how the path tracing mod brings significant visual changes, but also a heavy performance hit, which is not surprising at all, considering how even <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://wccftech.com/max-payne-2-rtx-remix-mod-brings-stunning-path-tracing-but-a-very-high-cost-from-1200-to-36-fps-on-an-rtx-5080/">the best current gaming hardware has a hard time handling path tracing without serious optimization work</a>. In this case, the mod is reportedly one of the most CPU-intensive RTX Remix projects to date, which even the most powerful CPUs on the market, such as the <a href="https://wccftech.com/amd-ryzen-7-9800x3d-most-popular-zen-5-cpu-germany/">AMD Ryzen 7 9800X3D</a>, struggle to run at a steady 60 FPS.</p>



<p>The remainder of the MxBenchmarkPC video shows how Grand Theft Auto: Vice City Next-gen Edition performs with the RTX Remix mod at 4K and 1440p resolutions, utilizing NVIDIA DLSS in Performance and Balanced modes. Additionally, it highlights how Frame Generation is essentially required to achieve framerates higher than 60 frames per second.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="GTA Vice City Path Tracing with RTX Remix On vs Off - Graphics/Performance Comparison | RTX 5080" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/S-SaS_GVxSc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p><span data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">As the Grand Theft Auto: Vice City Nextgen Edition overhaul is no longer available for download from trusted modding websites, such as<a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://www.moddb.com/mods/grand-theft-auto-vice-city-the-next-gen-edition" target="_blank">&nbsp;mod.db</a>, only those who downloaded the overhaul before it was removed can test it out with the Xoxor4d compatibility mod.</span> Even so, there's no denying that ray tracing will be a central element of future entries in the series following its <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-v-enhanced-edition-preview-grand-theft-auto-vi/">implementation in Grand Theft Auto V</a>, as the two <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-6-trailer-quality/">Grand Theft Auto VI trailers</a> released to date heavily suggest the tech will likely be widely used in the highly anticipated next entry in the series.</p>



<p>Speaking of Grand Theft Auto VI, <a href="https://wccftech.com/rockstar-animator-seemingly-shared-grand-theft-auto-vi-animations-in-demo-reel/">another small glimpse of the game arrived today</a> via a leaked demo reel from a Rockstar Games animator. The footage, though very brief and unpolished, showcased new character animations—including bike rentals and actions involving the bed of a pickup truck. While the video doesn't feature much we haven't seen already, any new look at the game is still welcome to make the wait for the game's<a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-6-delayed-to-november-2026/"> November 2026 release </a>more bearable.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vice-city-nextgen-edition-path-tracing/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MARVEL Cosmic Invasion Ultimate Guide – Game Modes, Characters, Progression, Combat Mechanics Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/how-to/marvel-cosmic-invasion-ultimate-guide-game-modes-characters-progression-combat-mechanics-explained/</link>
            <guid>1369381</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>MARVEL Cosmic Invasion is the latest side-scrolling beat'em up from Tribute Games (the studio behind <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/tmnt-shredders-revenge-the-reason-online-netcode-is-important/">TMNT: Shredder's Revenge</a>), bringing together a cast of cosmic and street-level heroes to face off against Annihilus and save the universe.</p>



<p>The game offers deep combat mechanics, strong co-op options, and a satisfying progression loop that makes mastering your favorite hero a rewarding challenge.</p>



<div><h2>Table of contents</h2><ul><li><a href="#h-gameplay-overview" data-level="3">Gameplay Overview</a></li><li><a href="#h-starter-tips-for-beginners" data-level="3">Starter Tips for Beginners</a></li><li><a href="#h-play-modes" data-level="3">Play Modes</a></li><li><a href="#h-all-characters-and-how-to-unlock-them" data-level="3">All Characters and How to Unlock Them</a></li><li><a href="#h-moveset-fundamentals" data-level="3">Moveset Fundamentals</a></li><li><a href="#h-core-mechanic-the-cosmic-swap" data-level="3">Core Mechanic: The Cosmic-Swap</a></li><li><a href="#h-character-progression" data-level="3">Character Progression</a></li><li><a href="#h-additional-content" data-level="3">Additional Content</a></li><li><a href="#h-ready-to-dive-in" data-level="3">Ready to Dive In?</a></li></ul></div>



<h3 id="h-gameplay-overview">Gameplay Overview</h3>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/MARVEL-Cosmic-Invasion-Characters-scaled.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>MARVEL Cosmic Invasion's gameplay is deeply rooted in the classic side-scrolling beat'em up experience popular back in the 90s.</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>MARVEL Cosmic Invasion is a classic side-scrolling, four-player drop-in co-op beat'em up, but it introduces the unique <strong>Cosmic-Swap tag-team mechanic</strong> which radically changes the flow of combat. Teams consist of two heroes, allowing players to instantly switch characters to maximize combo potential, strategically avoid damage, or deploy powerful assist attacks.</p>



<h3 id="h-starter-tips-for-beginners">Starter Tips for Beginners</h3>



<ol>
<li><strong>Familiarize yourself with only a few characters first</strong>: the 15 heroes have very different fighting styles that may not be suited to your playstyle. Find at least two you find yourself confident with, and focus on learning the intricacies of their movesets. No matter the pair you pick for each stage, you won't miss any story content, and you can eventually return to complete stages to clear Challenges requires specific characters later on.</li>



<li><strong data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-processed">Use Cosmic-Swap to Escape:</strong> One of the most important technique to use is using <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Cosmic-Swap (L1/LB/L)</strong> to get out of trouble. If you are cornered, about to be hit by a boss attack, or immobilized by a grab, a quick swap tags in your partner, letting them get out of the fight to avoid additional damage and restore the red portion of their HP gauge.</li>



<li><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Farm Level 5 ASAP:</strong> The Passive Skill learned at Level 5 is crucial for most characters. Focus on replaying the first few Campaign stages a couple of times to hit Level 5 on your favorite heroes quickly. This can be a massive help to clear the most challenging stages of the campaign.</li>
</ol>



<h3 id="h-play-modes">Play Modes</h3>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/MARVEL-Cosmic-Invasion-Campaign-Mode-scaled.jpg"></a><figcaption><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">The Campaign mode offers 15 stages filled with enemies to defeat</em> <em>and challenges to complete</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>The game features two main modes, designed for different types of players:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Campaign Mode:</strong> Navigate a map and progress through 15 stages, each featuring unique hazards, a final boss, and three optional Challenges to complete. Completing certain stages unlocks new characters.</li>



<li><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">Classic Arcade Mode:</strong> A true throwback experience with no continues, replicating the difficulty and high-score pressure of an arcade cabinet. The ultimate test of mastery.</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-all-characters-and-how-to-unlock-them">All Characters and How to Unlock Them</h3>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/MARVEL-Cosmic-Invasion-Gameplay-scaled.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>The MARVEL Cosmic Invasion character roster is rather diverse</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>The roster spans the breadth of the Marvel Universe, featuring 15 powerful Earth and cosmic heroes.</p>



<figure><table><tbody><tr><th>Available from the Start</th><th>Unlocked via Campaign Progression</th></tr><tr><td>Beta Ray Bill</td><td>Phoenix (Blue Area of the Moon)</td></tr><tr><td>Black Panther</td><td>Phyla-Vell (Hala)</td></tr><tr><td>Captain America</td><td>Silver Surfer (Fort Galactus)</td></tr><tr><td>Cosmic Ghost Rider</td><td>Venom (Destromundo)</td></tr><tr><td>Iron Man</td><td></td></tr><tr><td>Nova</td><td></td></tr><tr><td>Rocket Raccoon</td><td></td></tr><tr><td>She-Hulk</td><td></td></tr><tr><td>Spider-Man</td><td></td></tr><tr><td>Storm</td><td></td></tr><tr><td>Wolverine</td><td></td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h3 id="h-moveset-fundamentals">Moveset Fundamentals</h3>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/MARVEL-Cosmic-Invasion-Movesets-scaled.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Every character has unique special attacks that define their fighting style</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>All heroes share a common control scheme, but their execution and effect vary widely. Understanding these core inputs is the first step to improve at the game.</p>



<figure><table><tbody><tr><th>Input</th><th>Description</th></tr><tr><td>Square/X/Y (Combo)</td><td>Basic combo string, often ending in a launcher or knockdown.</td></tr><tr><td>Triangle/Y/X (Special)</td><td>Unique attack utilizing self-regenerating resources or unique weapons.</td></tr><tr><td>Circle/B/A (Defense)</td><td>Used for either a <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Block</strong> (Captain America, Cosmic Ghost Rider, Iron Man, Nova, Phoenix, She-Hulk, Silver Surfer, Venom) or a <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Dodge/Evade</strong> (Beta Ray Bill, Black Panther, Phyla-Vell, Rocket Raccoon, Spider-Man, Storm, Wolverine).</td></tr><tr><td>Cross/A/B + Square/X/Y</td><td>Rising attack used to launch enemies into the air for subsequent aerial combos. (Beta Ray Bill, Black Panther, Captain America, Cosmic Ghost Rider, Iron Man, Phyla-Vell, Silver Surfer, Wolverine only)</td></tr><tr><td>Forward x2 + Square/X/Y </td><td>Rushing attack with a wide hitbox best used as a gap-closer and crowd-control move, perfect for escaping the corner, and hitting multiple enemies at once.</td></tr><tr><td>R1/RB/R (Ultimate)</td><td>Focus-consuming attack with full invincibility, perfect for massive damage and managing critical danger.</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h3 id="h-core-mechanic-the-cosmic-swap">Core Mechanic: The Cosmic-Swap</h3>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/MARVEL-Cosmic-Invasion-Cosmic-Swap-scaled.jpg"></a><figcaption>The Cosmic-Swap tag-team mechanics are the core gameplay mechanics of MARVEL Cosmic Invasion</figcaption></figure>



<p>The Cosmic-Swap is the heart of the combat system. Pressing <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">L1/LB/L</strong> allows for an immediate character switch (tag-in/tag-out) using a small portion of the Focus gauge. This is your primary tool for escaping hit-stun, managing incoming damage, and extending combos.</p>



<p>The mechanic deepens significantly with the assist system:</p>



<ol>
<li><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">Assist Attack:</strong> Hold <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">L1/LB/L</strong> and press an attack button to deploy your inactive character for combo attacks, aerial attacks, rushing attacks and, special attacks (Spider-Man's Webbings, Cosmic Ghost Rider Cosmic Blast and so on).</li>



<li><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">Dual Ultimate:</strong> If enough Focus is saved, you can unleash a powerful combination attack with both characters simultaneously by <strong>holding L1/LB/L and pressing R1/RB/R.</strong></li>
</ol>



<blockquote>
<p><strong data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-processed">A deep-dive guide detailing the absolute best Cosmic-Swap assist attack you shouldn't sleep on is currently in the works. It will be live soo</strong><strong>n</strong><strong data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-processed">.</strong></p>
</blockquote>



<h3 id="h-character-progression">Character Progression</h3>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/MARVEL-Cosmic-Invasion-Hero-Progression-scaled.jpg"></a><figcaption><em data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-processed">Leveling up characters unlocks a variety of upgrades for each</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Every character starts at Level 1 and can progress up to Level 10 by completing stages. Progression yields critical improvements:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">Stat Boosts:</strong> Increased HP and Focus capacity.</li>



<li><strong>Passive Skill (Level 5):</strong> Each character learns a unique, game-changing passive skill that defines their fighting style.</li>



<li><strong>Color Palettes (Level 10):</strong> Unlocks an additional color scheme for visual customization.</li>
</ul>



<blockquote>
<p><strong>You can max out heroes in a little over 5 minutes using a very simple trick in the New York mission. A deep dive into this trick will go live soon.</strong></p>
</blockquote>



<h3 id="h-additional-content">Additional Content</h3>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Marvel-Cosmic-Invasion-Additional-Content-scaled.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Nova Corps Files let you dive deeper into the history of the MARVEL Cosmic Invasion heroes</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>The Cosmic Matrix, accessed via the Vault, is where you spend the hidden Cosmic Cubes currency found throughout the Campaign and those obtained by increasing the total Team Level. This system unlocks additional content, such as:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">Nova Corps Files:</strong> Deep lore documents on characters.</li>



<li><strong>Hero Palettes:</strong> Additional visual customization beyond the Level 10 unlocks.</li>



<li><strong>Arcade Mode Modifiers:</strong> Unique options to spice up the Classic Arcade experience, such as unlimited continues, different enemy configurations, and more.</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-ready-to-dive-in">Ready to Dive In?</h3>



<p>Check out our<a href="https://wccftech.com/review/marvel-cosmic-invasion-review-somehow-marvel-returned/"> full review of MARVEL Cosmic Invasion</a> to get a critical perspective on this co-op beat'em up!</p>



<blockquote>
<p><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed"><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">The data and strategies presented in this guide are based on two Campaign playthroughs and multiple Arcade Mode runs over 15 hours completed in the Steam 1.0.0.12208 version</em></strong>.</p>
</blockquote>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/how-to/marvel-cosmic-invasion-ultimate-guide-game-modes-characters-progression-combat-mechanics-explained/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MARVEL Cosmic Invasion Review – Somehow, Marvel Returned]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/review/marvel-cosmic-invasion-review-somehow-marvel-returned/</link>
            <guid>1369378</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			<div><header>Game Info</header><div><div>
						<h5>MARVEL Cosmic Invasion</h5><p><span>December 1, 2025</span>
					</p></div><div>
							<h5>Platform</h5><p><span>PC (Steam), PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Xbox Series X, Xbox Series S, Nintendo Switch, Nintendo Switch 2</span>
						</p></div></div></div>			
			<p>Back in the 90s, the side-scrolling beat'em up genre dominated video games, with series like CAPCOM's Final Fight, SEGA's Streets of Rage, and Konami's licensed games such as Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles and The Simpsons gaining widespread success, which sometimes even surpassed traditional fighting games, thanks, for the most part, to the immediacy of their gameplay.</p>



<p>Despite its popularity, however, the genre quickly disappeared from the spotlight when 3D graphics became all the rage, leaving it to smaller, independent teams, to create new side-scrolling beat'em ups. However, the genre had some sort of resurgence following the launch of the <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(106, 175, 226, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-style-link dracula-processed" data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(106, 175, 226, 0.2)" href="https://wccftech.com/review/streets-of-rage-4-beautiful-brawl/">amazing Streets of Rage 4</a>, which led to the creation of a lot of excellent games that tributed the best games of the 90s while also innovating the classic formula, such as <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://www.youtube.com/shorts/HC51VgRPdY8">TMNT: Shredder's Revenge</a>, a fantastic game that easily stands head to head with the classics developed by Konami.</p>



<p>A few years after the release of the game, Tribute Games returned to side-scrolling beat'em ups with MARVEL Cosmic Invasion. Leveraging universally recognizable characters and the tag-team mechanics that fighting game fans associate with the Marvel name, the developer created a game with tons of personality that is very fun to play, despite not reaching the heights of Shredder's Revenge due to some design and balance flaws.</p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/MARVEL-Cosmic-Invasion-Cutscene-scaled.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>MARVEL Cosmic Invasion brings 15 heroes together to face a terrible threat</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>MARVEL Cosmic Invasion's story is relatively simple, but it does an excellent job of bringing together heroes from both Earth and the cosmic realms to fight against the super-villain Annihilus and prevent his Annihilation Wave from destroying the universe. Traversing a variety of battlefields, ranging from New York City to floating citadels and the Negative Zone from which Annihilus launched his invasion, Spider-Man, Captain America, Iron Man, Nova, Wolverine, Cosmic Ghost Rider and nine other heroes will fight the villain's forces and his closest allies such as M.O.D.O.K. and Taskmaster to save the universe in the most epic of clashes.</p>



<p>Involving some of the most established characters in media nowadays, MARVEL Cosmic Invasion doesn't reserve any huge surprises in terms of plot or character development. If you are a fan of Marvel Comics, you already know what to expect: humorous quips, tons of fun interactions, and all-powerful, arrogant villains brought down after tense battles. Much of this simple story, which is told via pixel art cutscenes and quick in-game dialogues happening before boss battles, merely serves as a credible background for all the intense action of the game, much like in classic side-scrolling beat'em ups, and in this sense, it does well the little it is supposed to accomplish.</p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/20251115122028_1-scaled.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>The MARVEL Cosmic Invasion story isn't the best, but it serves its purpose well</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Being a side-scrolling beat'em up, much of the success of MARVEL Cosmic Invasion hinges on its <a href="https://wccftech.com/how-to/marvel-cosmic-invasion-ultimate-guide-game-modes-characters-progression-combat-mechanics-explained/">combat mechanics and character roster</a>, which are solid, for the most part. However, some issues, as already mentioned, impact the experience, which is ultimately not as good as TMNT: Shredder's Revenge.</p>



<p>The highlight of the combat mechanics are the Cosmic-Swap tag-team mechanics. Before starting any of the game's stages, players select two among the 15 heroes available in the game, which can be swapped at pretty much every time, including when the controlled character is grabbed or in a hit-stun state, and unleash a selection of assist attacks that change depending on the button pressed together with the Cosmic-Swap button as long as enough Focus is available. This not only makes for an incredibly dynamic experience, but opens up some creative combo possibilities as almost the entire moveset of the two selected characters are available with the press of a few buttons.</p>



<p>Compounding these mechanics well is each character's moveset design. All of the 15 characters in MARVEL Cosmic Invasion have very different moveset deeply rooted in each character's history and unique characteristics. Some characters like Nova and Storm, for example, can fly. Others, like Spider-Man and Venom, can use their powers to glide across the screen. Others, like Cosmic Ghost Rider, Iron Man, and Rocket Raccoon, have excellent long-range fighting abilities, compounded by their extensive weapon arsenals.</p>



<p>Even defensive options are different, depending on the character. Some, like Captain America and Venom, can block and parry enemy attacks. Others like Black Panther and Wolverine can dodge and quickly reposition themselves thanks to their superior agility. These different offensive and defensive abilities add a layer of depth to team creation, forcing players to prioritize these abilities over simple personal preference for certain characters. With how some enemies are designed, especially bosses, you will definitely want to have two characters that cover all offensive and defensive options.</p>



<p>Although characters' movesets are quite diverse, their design is a little too safe, in my opinion. As if the tag-team mechanics wouldn't have been enough to make the game feel like a CAPCOM's Marvel series spin-off, the movesets of characters that appeared in a fighting game by the Japanese studio feel a little too familiar. So much so that I think this is a result of the desire to tribute the series in some way, and does not stem from a lack of inspiration.</p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/20251126165258_1-scaled.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>The Cosmic-Swap tag-team mechanics are among the game's best features</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>While the safety of the roster's movesets is not inherently an issue, as even so, their movesets synergize well together to create complex combos, other combat issues have a much bigger impact on the experience. Unlike Shredder's Revenge, which I feel strikes a good balance in terms of enemy density for both solo and multiplayer, MARVEL Cosmic Invasion seems to have been balanced with multiplayer in mind. Not counting the first few stages, players are constantly harassed by a swarm of enemies with different movesets that are sometimes frustrating to deal with while playing solo.</p>



<p>While one could make the argument that Cosmic-Swap tag-team mechanics forced this balancing approach, it still feels like Tribute Games may have gone a little too far. As a result, the last few stages are very frustrating to play solo, also due to the excessive number of environmental hazards, which make it difficult not only to avoid damage, but even to understand what is going on at certain times. Thrown in flying enemies that are really good at getting away from the player, and you get a very frustrating final hours or so of the experience when playing solo. I am usually someone who complains that games are way too easy nowadays, but there's a fine line between challenging and frustrating that MARVEL Cosmic Invasion, sadly, crosses too often.</p>



<p>Boss battles are also a great indication of how the game may have been balanced with multiplayer first in mind. Most of the end-stage enemies not only come with a damage-protecting "super armor" that must be depleted first before dealing real damage, but their attacks also have wide ranges, and they can also call regular enemies to help. In addition, there are times when they are not staggered, even when they should be in certain situations, which adds a degree of uncertainty to the experience and makes boss battles less enjoyable than they could have been.</p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/20251120182653_1-scaled.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Late stages in MARVEL Cosmic Invasion become frustrating quickly in solo play due to balancing choices</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Even in terms of content, MARVEL Cosmic Invasion disappoints somewhat. The light RPG mechanics that power character progression are not as meaningful as in Shredder's Revenge since characters don't learn new moves when they level up, but only get HP and Focus improvements and learn a Passive Skill, so they essentially play the same no matter their level. And while each stage presents its own set of challenges and collectibles that can be used to unlock new color palettes and additional content, the game doesn't offer much beyond its 4-hour-long story campaign and classic Arcade Mode.</p>



<p>With its gorgeous 2D graphics, MARVEL Cosmic Invasion is deeply rooted in the comic books that made these characters so iconic, but it's not just the visuals that give the game a ton of personality. Great care has been put into the interactions that all heroes have when using the Cosmic Swap tag-team mechanics, as each pairing has unique voice lines to address each other. This is a genuinely great touch that masterfully leverages the long history of these characters, enhancing the experience considerably for their fans with a generally solid presentation. </p>



<p>Unfortunately, outside of solid voice acting, audio leaves something to be desired. Not only does music sound generic and not really memorable, but the sound effects are also really thin, and prevent hits from being as impactful as they should be in a game that is centered on combat.</p>



<p>Although the good outweighs the bad, it is difficult to recommend MARVEL Cosmic Invasion to anyone but the most hardcore of Marvel Comics and beat'em up enthusiasts, due to the limited amount of content, and the asking price of $29.99/ €29.99. With games like Streets of Rage 4 and Absolum that offer a lot in terms of content and gameplay depth at similar or lower prices, MARVEL Cosmic Invasion definitely needed to be something more than a well-made tribute to the Marvel universe to have a broader appeal.</p>



<p><em>PC version tested. Review code provided by the publisher.</em></p>

						<p>You can find <a href="https://wccftech.com/how-we-test-video-games/">additional information about our standard review process and ethics policy here.</a></p>
			
			
				

						<div>
					
					
					<h2>MARVEL Cosmic Invasion</h2>
				</div>
			
						<section>
				<p>With its tag-team mechanics and well-designed characters, MARVEL Cosmic Invasion is a competent side-scrolling beat'em up that can offer plenty of chaotic fun, especially in multiplayer. However, some balancing issues that make the final few stages frustrating to play, especially solo, and the lack of content beyond the 4-hours long campaign limit the game's appeal to Marvel fans and beat'em up die hards looking for a few hours of simple fun.</p>
				<div>
												<ul>
							<h6>Pros</h6>
							<li>Gorgeous 2D visuals
</li><li>Solid tag-team mechanics 
</li><li>Diverse character roster whose movesets synergize together well with the tag-team mechanics
</li><li>Great leveraging of the history of Marvel Comics to deliver some nice interactions</li>						</ul>
																		<ul>
							<h6>Cons</h6>
							<li>Movesets are a little too safe, especially for characters that appeared in the CAPCOM Marvel games
</li><li>Balancing issues with excessive enemy and hazards density, especially in later stages
</li><li>Though the combat mechanics allow for creative tag-team combos, they are not really deep
</li><li>Too little content for the price</li>						</ul>
										</div>
				<a rel="sponsored nofollow noskim" href="">Buy for  from Amazon</a>
				<span>The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may
					earn from qualifying purchases.</span>
			</section>
			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/review/marvel-cosmic-invasion-review-somehow-marvel-returned/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 Loses Ground In EU Sales Charts In Second Week, Black Friday Sales Boost Older Titles]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-loses-ground-eu-sales-charts-black-friday-sales/</link>
            <guid>1369315</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 has been out for a little more than two weeks at the time of this writing, and according to the latest report of <a href="https://www.gamesalesdata.com/login">GSD Sales Data</a> from <a href="https://www.thegamebusiness.com/p/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-drops-to">The Game Business</a>, it has already lost some ground in the EU sales charts in its second week on the market. Meanwhile, games that haven't been in the charts for some time reappeared, thanks to favourable Black Friday sales.</p>



<p>In its launch week, Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 was able to reach the top of the charts, <a href="https://wccftech.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-trails-battlefield-6-eu-launch-sales-and-black-ops-6-launch/">though its numbers were 63% worse than Battlefield 6</a>. In its second week (November 17-23), it fell to the number two spot in the charts, with EA Sports FC 26 overtaking it on both the revenue chart and the units sold chart.</p>



<p>Battlefield 6, meanwhile, stayed within the top five, but made it in the number three spot, just behind Black Ops 7 on both charts. Other recent releases like Anno 117: Pax Romana and Pokémon Legends Z-A were able to keep their spots in the top ten for both lists, <a href="https://wccftech.com/football-manager-26-knocks-battlefield-6-out-of-eu-sales-charts-top-spot-with-the-biggest-launch-in-gsd-weekly-charts-history/">while Football Manager 26 has seemingly disappeared after its standout opening week</a>.</p>



<p>The only other new addition to the list with regard to newly released games is Kirby Air Riders, which barely scratched into the revenue list in the number ten spot. The rest of the new additions to either chart came from Black Friday sales, boosting older titles. Marvel's Spider-Man 2 and It Takes Two both reappeared in the charts due to the holiday sales.</p>



<p>Here's the full list of the top ten best-selling games by units sold in the EU per GSD Data for the week of November 17-23:</p>



<ol>
<li>EA Sports FC 26</li>



<li>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</li>



<li>Battlefield 6</li>



<li>Hogwarts Legacy</li>



<li>Red Dead Redemption 2</li>



<li>Grand Theft Auto V</li>



<li>It Takes Two</li>



<li>Anno 117: Pax Romana</li>



<li>NBA 2K26</li>



<li>Pokémon Legends Z-A</li>
</ol>



<p>Here's the full list of the top ten games by revenue in the EU per GSD Data for the week of November 17-23:</p>



<ol>
<li>EA Sports FC 26</li>



<li>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</li>



<li>Battlefield 6</li>



<li>Anno 117: Pax Romana</li>



<li>Pokémon Legends Z-A</li>



<li>NBA 2K26</li>



<li>F1 25</li>



<li>Marvel's Spider-Man 2</li>



<li>Ghost of Yotei</li>



<li>Kirby Air Riders</li>
</ol>





			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-loses-ground-eu-sales-charts-black-friday-sales/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>