<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 07:40:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Is Hosting a Super Mario Galaxy Movie Direct On Wednesday]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-announces-super-mario-galaxy-movie-direct-wednesday/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-is-hosting-a-super-mario-galaxy-movie-direct-on-wednesday.1349362/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Shortly after a new look at Yoshi and the reveal of Bowser Jr. in the film was <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-collab-with-pillsbury-leaks-first-look-yoshi-super-mario-galaxy-movie/">leaked by an image of a Pillsbury Cookie Dough box</a>, Nintendo announced that it will host a Nintendo Direct presentation focused on the Super Mario Galaxy Movie this coming Wednesday, November 12, at 6am PT / 9am ET / 2pm BT.</p>



<p>The news was <a href="https://x.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1988003740301787427">announced on X (formerly Twitter)</a> and in the Nintendo Today! app. The post on X (formerly Twitter) clarifies that there will be no video game-related news, so don't expect anything game-related. This Direct is specifically focused on the film, and that's it.</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Join us on Wednesday, Nov 12, at 6am PT for the Nintendo Direct featuring the world premiere of The Super Mario Galaxy Movie official trailer. Please note that no game information will be included in this presentation.</p><p>Watch here: <a href="https://t.co/KNSvfYk64l">https://t.co/KNSvfYk64l</a> <a href="https://t.co/PfTUJTyMQ3">pic.twitter.com/PfTUJTyMQ3</a></p></div>— Nintendo of America (@NintendoAmerica) <a href="https://twitter.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1988003740301787427?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 10, 2025</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>The news of this Direct isn't exactly surprising, considering that just last week, a report (that we now know was at least partially correct) <a href="https://wccftech.com/super-mario-galaxy-movie-trailer-reportedly-appear-before-wicked-for-good/">claimed that the first proper trailer for the film would be shown online soon</a>, since it would also be shown at upcoming screenings of Wicked: For Good, the highly anticipated part-two of the film adaptation of the Broadway musical.</p>



<p>We'll almost definitely see the first proper trailer for the film on Wednesday, and, if this Direct will be anything like the Direct event Nintendo <a href="https://wccftech.com/super-mario-movie-first-trailer-chris-pratt-voice/">did for the Super Mario Bros Movie</a>, we'll also likely find out the rest of the cast (save for those who are returning) and discover a little more about the film's plot.</p>



<p>The first Super Mario Bros. Movie was a massive hit at the box office, <a href="https://wccftech.com/super-mario-bros-movie-biggest-gaming-adaptation-ever-500-million/">making over $500 million in its first week</a>, and eventually eclipsing $1.3 billion globally. A <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-illumination-announce-a-new-super-mario-bros-film-due-in-april-2026/">sequel was confirmed soon after</a>, which, if it keeps its current April 3, 2026 premiere date, will arrive almost three years to the date from when the first film premiered.</p>




 
			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-announces-super-mario-galaxy-movie-direct-wednesday/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>