<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 17:00:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Sales Top 30 Million Units After 3 Years]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-sales-top-30-million-units-after-3-years/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-sales-top-30-million-units-after-3-years.1175595/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-sales-top-30-million-units-after-3-years/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, FromSoftware <a href="https://x.com/ELDENRING/status/1916855058097938564" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> that global sales of its most acclaimed game, Elden Ring, have topped 30 million units. The news comes three years and a couple of months after the February 2022 launch of the open world RPG, which later won many Game of the Year awards (<a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftech-awards-22-best-games-of-2022-and-most-anticipated-of-2023-from-staff-and-community/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">including ours</a>). Elden Ring also received a perfect score <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/elden-ring-make-way-for-the-elden-lord/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">from reviewer Francesco De Meo</a>:</p>
<p><em>I tried hard to find any faults in Elden Ring, but no matter how hard I tried, I couldn't find any outside of some technical issues that the developers could fix via patches. I firmly believe that perfection doesn't exist and that it is always possible to improve, but I really couldn't think of anything that Elden Ring could have done better. As such, the game wholly deserves a perfect score, an honor I would have given only to a couple of other modern games, not only for its extremely high quality but also for what it accomplished with its open world and for how it will surely influence video games as a whole in the future.</em></p>
<p>The combination of the perfected Soulslike formula in an open world and the worldbuilding by G. R. R. Martin enthralled millions of fans, who finally got more content last year with the release of the big <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-worthy-of-the-greater-wills-blessing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Shadow of the Erdtree expansion</a>. FromSoftware hasn't provided updated sales figures for the DLC, but we know from a previous report that Shadow of the Erdtree had sold <a href="https://wccftech.com/shadow-of-the-erdtree-has-sold-5-million-units-in-3-days/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">five million copies in just the first three days on the market</a>. At this rate, it's likely to be approaching ten million, for a potential attach rate of one-third.</p>
<p>More Elden Ring is coming soon to fans, albeit with a wholly different flavor. The cooperative multiplayer spin-off Nightreign is set to launch in about a month, and the developers have just <a href="https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-nightreign-pc-system-requirements/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">shared</a> the official PC system requirements. Meanwhile, you can read <a href="https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-nightreign-hands-on-preview-looking-forward-to-the-night/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">our hands-on preview from the recent beta test</a>.</p>
<p>FromSoftware has also <a href="https://wccftech.com/fromsoftwares-the-duskbloods-announced-exclusively-for-nintendo-switch-2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> a brand-new IP called The Duskbloods, which will be exclusive to the Nintendo Switch 2. They later clarified to worried fans that Nightreign and The Duskbloods (which also features multiplayer) <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-duskbloods-will-feature-over-12-playable-characters-fromsoftware-isnt-abandoning-single-player/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">are not a hint at the studio's desire to abandon single player games</a>.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yoko Taro Fears That 50 Years From Now, Generative AI Tech Will Replace Game Creators]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/yoko-taro-fears-that-50-years-from-now-generative-ai-tech-will-replace-game-creators/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/yoko-taro-fears-that-50-years-from-now-generative-ai-tech-will-replace-game-creators.1175580/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/yoko-taro-fears-that-50-years-from-now-generative-ai-tech-will-replace-game-creators/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Like many other creators, <a href="https://wccftech.com/yoko-taro-is-working-on-a-game-that-might-or-might-not-be-nier/">Yoko Taro</a>, creator and director of Nier Automata,&nbsp;fears that generative AI technology will advance to the point where it could replace game creators.</p>
<p>In an interview with <a href="https://www.famitsu.com/article/202504/40366">Famitsu</a>, Taro admitted his fears that game developers and creators could find themselves out of work in the next five decades, with how generative AI technology is evolving.</p>
<p>While speaking to Yoko Taro, Kotaro Uchikoshi, and Jiro Ishii, the topic of generative AI came up regarding how it could influence the video game industry and what its impact will be on creative industry's overall.</p>
<p>Uchikoshi began saying, "There are<em>&nbsp;a lot of new games I want to create, but with AI technology evolving at such a high speed, I fear that there is a possibility that AI-generated adventure games will become mainstream</em>."</p>
<p>Taro added, "<em>I, too, believe that game creators may lose their jobs because of AI. There's a chance that in 50 years, game creators will be treated like bards...I think that in the future, we will move from an era where we have to imitate the style of our favorite creators to an era where we can have our favorite scenarios generated.</em>"</p>
<p>"<em>AI will determine the preferences of users and skillfully generate route branchings that they would want to read, and the recommendation capabilities will continue to improve</em>."</p>
<p>It's understandable that Taro would have these fears, as it is for any creative to share these concerns, though it's not an inevitable fate. Generative AI may be constantly improving, but it's still a pipe dream to imagine that it would, in any genuine way, replace the best artists of our time. For video games, Yoko Taro is one of the best artists in the industry.</p>
<p>He'll still be regarded as such 50 years from now, and there will be a whole new crop of creators pushing the industry forward. Generative AI technology can and will improve as much as possible. Still, it won't ever be able to create anything new in the same way artists like Yoko Taro can.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nexon, Not Blizzard, Will Reportedly Be Making The Next Starcraft Game]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nexon-not-blizzard-will-reportedly-be-making-the-next-starcraft-game/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nexon-not-blizzard-will-reportedly-be-making-the-next-starcraft-game.1175511/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nexon-not-blizzard-will-reportedly-be-making-the-next-starcraft-game/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A report from Korean outlet <a href="https://news.mtn.co.kr/news-detail/2025042808165242317">MTN</a> (spotted by <a href="https://www.vg247.com/new-korean-starcraft-rights-ip-nc-soft">VG247</a>) marks the end of a rights battle between Nexon and Blizzard, seemingly resulting in Nexon, not Blizzard, leading development on the next major entry in the StarCraft series.</p>
<p>Blizzard will be working alongside Nexon to create this new StarCraft game, which could potentially be something besides a new RTS game, if Nexon really wanted to shake things up, that is. RTS games are incredibly popular in Korea, as is the StarCraft series. Moving away from the genre is a huge gamble, since the players who are looking for something to follow up 2013's Starcraft II: Heart of the Swarm are probably looking for another RTS game, not a different game set in the StarCraft world.</p>
<p>Nexon didn't just win the ability to make a new StarCraft game in its rights battle though, it also won the opportunity to make a mobile version of Overwatch for Japan and Korea, which has immense potential considering the popularity of mobile games in Asia.</p>
<p>In both cases, this amounts to a big loss for Blizzard, with Nexon now having the keys to what could be a very lucrative castle that Blizzard has arguably fumbled. Of course, we're still a while away from seeing if Nexon will be able to capitalize on its chance here properly, but the potential is still undeniable at this stage.</p>
<p>Especially if Nexon does come out with a StarCraft game that shows how Blizzard's behind in the genre. That both companies collaborated on the game won't matter to players if Nexon can demonstrate that it was their influence that helped make the next game a success, should it be a success, that is.</p>
<p>It's unfortunate for Blizzard that its track record of late has been other studios showing that they can take something Blizzard did and do it better. It arguably happened with <a href="https://wccftech.com/overwatch-2-adds-in-match-perks-the-biggest-gameplay-innovation-since-overwatch-launched-in-2016/">Overwatch</a> and how hero shooters have evolved since then. Many would argue that's what <a href="https://wccftech.com/path-of-exile-2-dawn-of-the-hunt-qa-throw-everything-you-knew-in-the-bin/">Path of Exile</a> has done with <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/diablo-iv-great-albeit-safe-hack-n-slash-action/">Diablo</a>, and Nexon coming in to do the same with StarCraft would be the next nail in the coffin.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 New Leaked Footage Showcase Impressive Destruction and Massive Maps]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-new-leaked-footage-destruction/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-new-leaked-footage-showcase-impressive-destruction-and-massive-maps.1175427/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-new-leaked-footage-destruction/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>New Battlefield 6 footage leaked online, providing a new look at the impressive destruction elements of the new entry in the series, ground vehicles, massive maps, and more.</p>
<p>The new footage, recorded during a recent alpha playtest conducted via the new testing environment Battlefield Labs, provides a great look at some of the features and mechanics that will be found in the next entry in the series, which has yet to be officially announced. The destruction mechanics, in particular, look quite impressive, as does the jet gameplay set in a map that looks outright massive.</p>
<blockquote data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Here’s our first look at Battlefield 6 pre-alpha jet gameplay! <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/battlefield6?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#battlefield6</a> <a href="https://t.co/vj6NrJT4LR">pic.twitter.com/vj6NrJT4LR</a></p>
<p>— Rebs Gaming (@Mr_Rebs_) <a href="https://twitter.com/Mr_Rebs_/status/1916588897246519765?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 27, 2025</a></p></blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Jet sound in battlefield 6</p>
<p>This from new test of battlefield Labs 🔥 <a href="https://t.co/iiDYHAG0mw">pic.twitter.com/iiDYHAG0mw</a></p>
<p>— goodboy (@alisaad40002) <a href="https://twitter.com/alisaad40002/status/1916142145603256654?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 26, 2025</a></p></blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">New battlefield 6 leakes 🔥 <a href="https://t.co/C5FtdhdCUz">pic.twitter.com/C5FtdhdCUz</a></p>
<p>— goodboy (@alisaad40002) <a href="https://twitter.com/alisaad40002/status/1916207980279718382?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 26, 2025</a></p></blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">New battlefield 6 leaks🔥<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/battlefield6?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#battlefield6</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/leaks?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#leaks</a> <a href="https://t.co/Qx3CKmT8mz">pic.twitter.com/Qx3CKmT8mz</a></p>
<p>— goodboy (@alisaad40002) <a href="https://twitter.com/alisaad40002/status/1916168520221466633?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 26, 2025</a></p></blockquote>

<p>The destructible elements have always been a very important part of the Battlefield experience, and they will be just as important as in the yet-to-be-officially-announced Battlefield 6. <a href="https://wccftech.com/ea-showcases-destruction-next-battlefield-game-and-it-looks-like-old-school-destructible-environments-back/">Earlier this month</a>, the development team provided an update on them, saying that their goals for destruction are <em>"centered around adding further gameplay depth by allowing you to reshape the environment and transform your surroundings toward a tactical advantage."</em>&nbsp; As highlighted by the new leaked gameplay, destruction is being designed around easily identifiable visual and audio language that will allow players to immediately understand what can be destroyed and altered, creating an intuitive and rewarding environment that players can easily shape.</p>
<p>Battlefield 6 is currently in development for unspecified platforms. A release date has yet to be confirmed, but the game should launch before the end of publisher Electronic Arts' fiscal year (March 2026).</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Nightreign Undemanding PC System Requirements Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-nightreign-pc-system-requirements/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-nightreign-undemanding-pc-system-requirements-revealed.1175424/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-nightreign-pc-system-requirements/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Elden Ring Nightreign <a href="https://x.com/ELDENRING/status/1916839982842450100" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PC system requirements</a> have been revealed today, detailing the system specifications needed to run the game at launch.</p>
<p>As expected for a multiplayer game aiming to get as many players on board as possible, the next game developed by FromSoftware is not going to be particularly demanding, as the developer recommends dated CPUs like the Intel Core i5-11500 and AMD Ryzen 5 5600 and GPUs like the GTX 1070 and Radeon RX Vega 56 to play the game, although it's not specified what resolution and framerate should be expected with the recommended specifications. Elden Ring Nightreign will also not require a lot of free storage space, as the game will only be 30 GB in size.</p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The minimum and recommended PC specifications for <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ELDENRING?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#ELDENRING</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NIGHTREIGN?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#NIGHTREIGN</a> are now available. <a href="https://t.co/pgfsTZzO1M">pic.twitter.com/pgfsTZzO1M</a></p>
<p>— ELDEN RING (@ELDENRING) <a href="https://twitter.com/ELDENRING/status/1916839982842450100?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 28, 2025</a></p></blockquote>

<p>When Elden Ring Nightreign was announced<a href="https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-nightreign-announced-by-fromsoftware-for-pc-and-consoles/"> last year</a>, I wasn't particularly excited about its multiplayer approach, but the Closed Network Test held earlier this year made me more interested in the game. The experience was extremely easy to get into and fun, especially when all involved players properly worked together, as I highlighted in my <a href="https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-nightreign-hands-on-preview-looking-forward-to-the-night/">preview.</a></p>
<p><em>The basics of Elden Ring Nightreign are really straightforward. From the iconic Roundtable Hold, players can decide to undertake expeditions with three other players, picking one of four Nightfarers, which will become eight in the launch version, all coming with unique special abilities, before getting thrown into one of the game's maps, where they need to survive for three days. At the end of the third day, the squad will get to fight one of the main bosses and will be rewarded with relics that represent the game's permanent upgrade system, which improves characters with a variety of different perks. Relics can also be obtained if the squad fails to get to the third day and defeat the final boss, so players still get something for taking part in expeditions.</em></p>
<p>Elden Ring Nightreign launches on PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X|S on May 30th.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>