<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 15:20:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Unreal Engine 5 Remake Could Be In The Works – Rumor]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remake-unreal-engine-5/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-unreal-engine-5-remake-could-be-in-the-works-%E2%80%93-rumor.1074705/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remake-unreal-engine-5/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion remake powered by Unreal Engine 5 could be in the works, judging from some recent findings.</p>
<p>As spotted by Timur222, a Technical Art Director at Chinese development studio Virtuos Games is listing among the games they have worked on an unannounced Unreal Engine 5 remake in development for PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X|S. While the fourth entry in the series by Bethesda is not mentioned anywhere on the online resume, Virtuos Games has long been rumored to be the developer behind the Oblivion remaster revealed back in September 2023 via some <a href="https://wccftech.com/oblivion-fallout-3-remasters-leaked-alongside-dishonored-3-ghostwire-tokyo-sequel-and-more/">leaked slides</a>, so there's the chance the remaster could actually be a full-blown remake. However, as Virtuos is also the studio behind Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater, an Unreal Engine 5-powered remake, there's also the chance the employee simply hasn't updated the resume since the game was officially announced. As such, we have to take this with a grain of salt until this project is officially revealed.</p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="und">Hmmm <a href="https://t.co/KfbZ9EYTIV">pic.twitter.com/KfbZ9EYTIV</a></p>
<p>— Timur222 (@bogorad222) <a href="https://twitter.com/bogorad222/status/1875975208810713172?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 5, 2025</a></p></blockquote>

<p>According to the aforementioned leaked slides, The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion isn't the only older game developed by Bethesda poised to return to modern hardware, as a Fallout 3 remaster is supposedly in the works as well. Both of these projects have yet to be officially revealed, however, so there's the chance that plans may have been changed since 2022, when the leaked slides were shared with the FTC.</p>
<p>If The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion never gets remade or remastered, however, fans will still be able to experience an updated version of the game with the <a href="https://wccftech.com/skyblivion-team-confirms-2025-launch-window-though-dlcs-will-come-later/">Skyblivion</a> mod. The total conversion project, which will recreate the game in Skyrim, will be released later this year, although it will lack the conversion of the DLC expansions, which will come at a later time.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>