<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 20:08:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ARC Raiders Continues Its Strong Launch, Hits 700K Concurrent Players Over The Weekend]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/arc-raiders-continues-strong-launch-hits-700k-concurrent-players/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arc-raiders-continues-its-strong-launch-hits-700k-concurrent-players-over-the-weekend.1349125/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>ARC Raiders continues to hit new heights of success for developer and publisher Embark Studios, which has confirmed that over the past weekend, across all available platforms, ARC Raiders surpassed 700K concurrent players.</p>



<p>Thanks to <a href="https://steamdb.info/">SteamDB</a>, we can get a look at any game's concurrent players to help gauge how it is doing popularity-wise and, to a lesser extent, sales. But neither PlayStation nor Xbox shares player numbers in the same way, so the number of players on console remains a mystery, for the most part.</p>



<p>So while we can't know exactly how many players ARC Raiders had on PlayStation and Xbox consoles over the weekend, looking at the SteamDB page for the game, we can see that most of those 700K came from PC, with <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1808500/charts/">a new peak of 462,488 players playing ARC Raiders on Steam alone just yesterday</a>.</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Hey Raiders!<br>It's been a little over one week since we opened up the tunnels for you to head Topside, and this past weekend we reached over 700,000 concurrent Raiders on the surface! 🥳<br>We're so happy to have you all here!<br>The many different ways you play and participate in ARC… <a href="https://t.co/Do6bAhWf4o">pic.twitter.com/Do6bAhWf4o</a></p>— ARC Raiders (@ARCRaidersGame) <a href="https://twitter.com/ARCRaidersGame/status/1987930324156678210?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 10, 2025</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>It's another milestone for the game, which has <a href="https://wccftech.com/arc-raiders-sold-2-5-million-copies-in-debut-week/">reportedly already surpassed 2.5 million copies sold</a> (most of those, unsurprisingly, coming from Steam), and has not fallen below 100K concurrent players on Steam since it launched on October 30, 2025.</p>



<p>Now that it has definitively had a strong launch, the question becomes whether Embark Studios can turn the strong launch into a strong month, into a strong first year, and beyond. For now, ARC Raiders is having its moment in the spotlight in the gaming industry, but that won't mean much if the game isn't around in a couple of years.</p>



<p>Not that it's likely to disappear anytime soon. Embark Studios has already proven it knows how to make a multiplayer game people want to play and keep it going with The Finals, and ARC Raiders is having a bigger launch than The Finals. </p>



<p>Either way, it'll be interesting to see how ARC Raiders continues to evolve. Embark <a href="https://wccftech.com/embark-studios-arc-raiders-2025-roadmap/">currently has the game roadmapped for the rest of 2025</a>, though there's nothing publicly on the schedule yet for 2026.</p>
 
			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/arc-raiders-continues-strong-launch-hits-700k-concurrent-players/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>