<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 22:21:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[STALKER-Like MMO Pioner Shows New Gameplay Trailer, Reconfirms 2025 Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/stalker-like-mmo-pioner-shows-new-gameplay-trailer-reconfirms-2025-launch/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/stalker-like-mmo-pioner-shows-new-gameplay-trailer-reconfirms-2025-launch.1140753/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/stalker-like-mmo-pioner-shows-new-gameplay-trailer-reconfirms-2025-launch/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>During the Future Games Show Spring Showcase, Belgrade-based developer GFA Games debuted a new gameplay trailer for its upcoming STALKER-like MMOFPS Pioner. We've <a href="https://wccftech.com/pioner-qa-2-devs-reveal-pve-pvp-mechanics-of-this-stalker-like-mmofps-confirm-beta-in-2023/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">covered</a> the game multiple times over the years, even featuring it on our <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-multiplayer-games-of-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">most anticipated multiplayer game list</a>. Despite the delays, the developers have <a href="https://wccftech.com/stalker-like-mmofps-pioner-shows-new-trailer-confirms-2025-launch-on-steam/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">again</a> confirmed the game's planned 2025 launch on PC, with a console version coming afterward.</p>
<p>Pioner is set in a haunting alternate reality where Soviet-era structures are abandoned on a desolate, post-apocalyptic island of more than 50 square kilometers. Powered by Unreal Engine 4, it will run on even modest hardware according to the official minimum and recommended requirements:</p>
<div>
<p><strong>Minimum:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<ul>
<li><strong>OS:</strong>&nbsp;Windows 10</li>
<li><strong>Processor:</strong> Intel Core i3-6100</li>
<li><strong>Memory:</strong>&nbsp;16 GB RAM</li>
<li><strong>Graphics:</strong>&nbsp;NVIDIA GTX 1060 6G</li>
<li><strong>Network:</strong>&nbsp;Broadband Internet connection</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div>
<p><strong>Recommended:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<ul>
<li><strong>OS:</strong>&nbsp;Windows 11</li>
<li><strong>Processor:</strong> Intel Core i5-8600</li>
<li><strong>Memory:</strong>&nbsp;16 GB RAM</li>
<li><strong>Graphics:</strong>&nbsp;NVIDIA RTX 2060</li>
<li><strong>Network:</strong>&nbsp;Broadband Internet connection</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<p><iframe title="PIONER - Collapse" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/B8O-GXdOT7g?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The developers of Pioner recently answered some lingering questions from the community:</p>
<ul>
<li>It will be possible to complete the story campaign without going to PvP zones and complete isolated missions without other players.</li>
<li>The game will feature voice and text chat. Global, divided by region, party, or clan.</li>
<li>Some quests can be completed in co-op, but not the entire storyline.</li>
<li>Only cosmetic in-game purchases are planned.</li>
<li>Thanks to the server mirroring system, there won't be any need for custom servers, as players can form a guild that allows them to create a similar enclave on existing servers.</li>
<li>Pioner will support cross-play only on consoles, not with PC, for the sake of balance.</li>
<li>GFA Games plans to release regular updates, including balancing patches, new content, and even major additions that significantly expand the game world.</li>
<li>The game will be available on Windows and Linux.</li>
<li>An anti-cheat is being worked on.</li>
<li>There are no plans to switch to Unreal Engine 5 before the game's release. The developers said that UE5 is very demanding on hardware, and they want as many players as possible to enjoy the game.</li>
<li>Pioner will be buy-to-play.</li>
<li>Players won't need to participate in PvP. Story-based activities and activities in which you can get beaten up by other players are separated by both distance and organization.</li>
<li>The left side of the island is dominated by PvE content, while the right side of the island is a PvP area. At the same time, there is only one region in the game where PvP is implemented everywhere - Shadowlands. Only partial areas with PvP rules are implemented in Middle Earth. The team also announced additional rules to avoid the bullying of solo players and respawn camping.</li>
<li>Getting the best equipment will be possible in PvE and PvP activities. The main item you need to have is blueprints and resources. The latter can be obtained in many activities, including PvE. In the world of PIONER, artifacts play a vital role in the economy and the equipment crafting process. Artifacts are expensive and difficult to obtain. The search for artifacts is almost always connected with anomalies, and you can only get an artifact if you have the appropriate equipment.</li>
</ul>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>