<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 17:24:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lynked: Banner Of The Spark Has Launched Out Of Early Access, Version 1.0 Available On PC, PS5, And Xbox Series X/S]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/lynked-banner-of-the-spark-has-launched-out-of-early-access-version-1-0-available-on-pc-ps5-and-xbox-series-x-s/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lynked-banner-of-the-spark-has-launched-out-of-early-access-version-1-0-available-on-pc-ps5-and-xbox-series-x-s.1196625/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/lynked-banner-of-the-spark-has-launched-out-of-early-access-version-1-0-available-on-pc-ps5-and-xbox-series-x-s/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/fuzzybot-unveils-new-title-lynked-banner-of-the-spark/">Lynked: Banner of the Spark</a> is launching out of early access today, with version 1.0 now available on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X/S.</p>
<p>The brightly colored, lighthearted rougelite action RPG with a bit of life-sim gameplay mixed in launched on PC in early access on October 22, 2024, and across more than 200 player reviews on Steam landed at a 'Very Positive' Steam rating. The 1.0 version will be available at the same price as its early access version at $24.99.</p>
<p>It's also the first game to be published by <a href="https://wccftech.com/blizzard-co-founders-new-studio-to-publish-lynked-preparing-to-announce-debut-game/">Dreamhaven</a>, the studio founded by Blizzard co-founder Mike Morhaime, and the debut game for its developer FuzzyBot. The 1.0 version of Lynked will include five chapters with 40 new missions for players to run through, five new bosses, and a new biome.</p>
<p>Lynked: Banner of the Spark is set in the year 30XX, with you playing as one of humanity's last survivors. Fighting in the resistance against Combot domination is one half of the gameplay, while the other is dedicated to rebuilding a new world with the robots that aren't trying to eradicate humanity.</p>
<p><iframe title="Lynked: Banner of the Spark | Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/x_6zU2ktIhQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>"<em>Bright worlds, expressive characters, and cooperative gameplay mark what we - and our players - love about games</em>," co-founder of FuzzyBot and creative director of Lynked: Banner of the Spark, Max Spielberg, said in a press release. "<em>Lynked reflects that vision. It's been player-driven from the start, and we've built on that with new challenges and surprises for the game's full launch.</em>"</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Next PlayStation State of Play Event Is Reportedly Planned For June – Rumor]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/next-playstation-state-of-play-event-is-reportedly-planned-for-june-rumor/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/next-playstation-state-of-play-event-is-reportedly-planned-for-june-%E2%80%93-rumor.1196481/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/next-playstation-state-of-play-event-is-reportedly-planned-for-june-rumor/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Contrary to<a href="https://wccftech.com/insider-suggests-a-playstation-event-wont-happen-until-september-rumor/"> previous rumors</a>, Sony may not skip this year's "Not-E3" season, as a PlayStation State of Play is reportedly scheduled for June.</p>
<p>Speaking during today's <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P-BnQ9OIHOg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Giant Bomb's Game Mess Mornings</a>, the ever-reliable Jeff Grubb commented on the next PlayStation event, saying that, like Nate the Hate, he didn't hear anything about a May event, because there is one planned for June. The event, however, will probably not be a big one. The publisher has been going back and forth between showcase and PlayStation State of Play for a while, and has probably settled on a State of Play event for next month. Interestingly enough, Jeff Grubb highlighted how "abnormally difficult" it was to obtain this information, so there's definitely something going on behind the scenes at Sony.</p>
<p><iframe title="Game Mess Mornings 05/22/25" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/P-BnQ9OIHOg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>It has been a while since Sony hosted big PlayStation showcases, so there's a solid chance that Jeff Grubb provided once again correct information. As for which games will be showcased during the next PlayStation State of Play event, no information has been provided, although it would be a safe bet to expect to see <a href="https://wccftech.com/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-controversial-kojima-mass-market/">Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/ghost-of-yotei-will-be-even-better-than-tsushima-says-shuhei-yoshida/">Ghost of Yōtei </a>during the event. As the PlayStation 5 port of Starfield is supposedly getting revealed, and shortly after released, <a href="https://wccftech.com/starfield-announced-playstation-5/">this year</a>, showing it during the event would make tons of sense, although this is mere speculation as the timing of the reveal is not yet known.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>