<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 15:55:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pearl Abyss Announces Black Desert Console Native Builds for PS5 and Xbox Series X|S]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/pearl-abyss-announces-black-desert-console-native-builds-for-ps5-and-xbox-series-xs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pearl-abyss-announces-black-desert-console-native-builds-for-ps5-and-xbox-series-x-s.1050750/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/pearl-abyss-announces-black-desert-console-native-builds-for-ps5-and-xbox-series-xs/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://www.naeu.playblackdesert.com/en-US/main/index" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pearl Abyss</a>, the developer and publisher of Black Desert has announced that they are officially developing native builds of the game for PlayStation 5, PlayStation 5 Pro and Xbox Series X|S. These native builds will offer enhanced visuals, smoother gameplay, and much-needed performance upgrades to make sure that the game runs smoothly and is tailored to next-gen consoles. This update will be free for all current Black Desert Console players.</p>
<p>If you prefer to get your news in the form of a video, General Manager Matt goes into detail about what you can expect from the console updates.</p>
<p><iframe title="Message from Black Desert Console Team" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oW6Ra1fNzwg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>As it stands, the PS5 version's development has been completed and is nearing platform certification, while the Xbox Series X development is currently ongoing. Pearl Abyss plans&nbsp; for both of the builds to launch in the first half of 2025, when there will then be additional updates to Black Desert Console, like the Land of the Morning Light expansion.</p>
<p>In addition to the native build development for both the PS5 and Xbox Series X|S, it's been confirmed by Pearl Abyss that there will be a ton of updates coming to Black Desert on December 12 to help keep players engaged in the interim between the native build release and the release of the Land of the Morning Light expansion.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://wccftech.com/black-desert-onlines-new-expansion-is-out-now/">Land of the Morning Light expansion</a> was released earlier this year on PC and took players to a new region of ancient Korea, with lots of stunning visuals, traditional Korean architecture, and beautiful scenery. The expansion is free for all players. The most common complaint about the expansion is that the amount of information thrown at you is overwhelming, especially if you are a new player in the game.&nbsp; Additionally, combat, which is a vital part of Black Desert, wasn't really explained as much in Land of the Morning Light, and those who had never played the game before would find it a bit of a struggle to figure out the systems.</p>
<p>On December 12, Kharazad Accessories will be added to the game, as well as an Accessory Exchange System that allows players to exchange parts of the Deboreka accessory set to get other parts of the set that they may need.</p>
<p>Additionally, there will be daily rewards and buffs to help players through the grind. Beneficial items like Mythical Censer and significant buffs that are added to the game will be running until March 2025. This includes a 50% buff to Training EXP, a 100% buff to Farming EXP, and Combat EXP being buffed to 500%.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>