<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 15:02:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[“The People in Charge are Psychopaths” Says Adam Jensen Voice Actor on Why There’s No New Deus Ex Game Coming in 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/deus-ex-actor-calls-embracer-group-psychopaths-for-not-making-new-deus-ex-game/</link>
            <guid>1395889</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p><strong>Elias Toufexis</strong>, a voice actor who you may recognize as the voice of Remi Letam from 2025's Hell is Us, but who you're more likely to recognize as the voice of <strong>Adam Jensen</strong> from <strong>Eidos Montreal's Deus Ex</strong> games, has a few strong words for those in charge of the immersive-sim franchise.</p>



<p>In a <a href="https://x.com/EliasToufexis/status/2006536614424859057">post on X (formerly Twitter)</a>, Toufexis shared four images to tell fans what he's working on in 2026. One of the photos was Marathon, while the other three were simple 'NDA' watermarks, indicating he's got at least four projects on the go and only one he can talk about.</p>



<p>Though if you were hoping one of those NDA'd projects would be a new Deus Ex game, that is unfortunately not the case. Toufexis followed up his initial post with a single-line shot directly at <strong>Embracer Group</strong> and its decision makers.</p>



<p>"<em>...No Deus Ex because the people in charge are psychopaths</em>," Toufexis wrote.</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">....no Deus Ex because the people in charge are psychopaths.</p>— Elias Toufexis (@EliasToufexis) <a href="https://twitter.com/EliasToufexis/status/2006536614424859057?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 1, 2026</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>The last two Deus Ex games, Human Revolution and Mankind Divided, are both excellent immersive-sim, third-person stealth games that were unfortunately never as commercially successful as they were critically. That said, the franchise has a long and important place in gaming history, and it's hard to imagine there's no desire for a new game in the series.</p>



<p>But that doesn't seem to be enough for the people actually making the call on whether to greenlight production on a new Deus Ex game. Embracer Group reportedly<a href="https://wccftech.com/deus-ex-revival-eidos-montreal-canceled-embrace-job-losses/"> shut down the revival project at Eidos Montreal in January 2024</a>. Another <a href="https://wccftech.com/deus-ex-new-game-pitched/">report from April 2025 claims that Eidos tried pitching a new Deus Ex game to multiple publishers</a> but got no traction on the idea because they were told the series is too much of a niche. </p>



<p>It seems clear that Eidos Montreal would be more than willing to return to the world of Deus Ex. Besides the fact that the studio was pitching a new entry in the series just last year, <a href="https://wccftech.com/deus-ex-may-return-embracer-outdo-cyberpunk-rumor/">it sees the series as an opportunity to "<em>do what Cyberpunk 2077 couldn't</em>."</a></p>



<p>But since Eidos voiced that goal, the studio <a href="https://wccftech.com/eidos-montreal-lays-off-75-employees-as-work-on-mandate-fable-ends/">has suffered multiple rounds</a> of <a href="https://wccftech.com/eidos-montreal-might-have-canceled-legacy-of-kain-game-new-layoffs-reported/">layoffs and project cancellations</a>, and the latest on what the team is actually working on <a href="https://wccftech.com/eidos-montreal-open-world-action-adventure-game-tomb-raider-team-out-next-year/">is a return to Tomb Raider and Lara Croft.</a></p>



<p>There technically is a Deus Ex game on the way, but it's a remaster of the original <a href="https://wccftech.com/deus-ex-remastered-delayed-indefinitely-pre-orders-refunded-aspyr-media/">that was just delayed indefinitely due to backlash and feedback from its reveal</a>. Still, fans of the franchise can only hope Eidos Montreal finds a path forward for a new adventure in the Deus Ex world.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/deus-ex-actor-calls-embracer-group-psychopaths-for-not-making-new-deus-ex-game/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘People Have to Take a Step Back and Understand How AI Can Be a Big Help to Developers and a Benefit for Players’, Says ARC Raiders Boss]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/people-have-to-take-step-back-understand-ai-can-be-big-help-developers-benefit-players-says-arc-raiders-boss/</link>
            <guid>1395847</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p><strong>ARC Raiders</strong> is, without a doubt, the <strong>#1 trending live service game</strong> at the start of 2026. As <a href="https://x.com/SteamDB/status/2006009965702492545" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">revealed by SteamDB</a>, it was the best-selling premium product on <strong>Steam</strong> during the Holiday week (December 23 to 30), beating even Valve's own <strong>Steam Deck</strong> and EA's <strong>Battlefield 6</strong>. It is also estimated that ARC Raiders is currently doing a better job of keeping its players engaged than Battlefield 6, as evidenced by the fact that the game developed by <strong>Embark Studios</strong> peaked at 428K concurrent users on Steam within the last 24 hours. In contrast, Battlefield 6 reached just 128K simultaneous players yesterday, despite technically having sold more units in total.</p>



<p>It's been an explosive launch, that's for sure. Publisher <strong>Nexon</strong> <a href="https://wccftech.com/arc-raiders-has-sold-4-million-units-nexons-most-successful-global-launch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">previously stated</a> that the game became its biggest launch ever, with <strong>over four million units sold in its first twelve days on the market</strong>. By now, it's likely not far off ten million units across all platforms, and it was even <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/arc-raiders-was-2025-most-searched-videogame-on-google-gta-vi-only-7th/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the most searched videogame on Google in 2025</a></strong>. The game also earned prestigious prizes, being crowned the <strong>Best Multiplayer Game</strong> launched last year <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-game-awards-2025-winners-full-list/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">at <strong>The Game Awards 2025</strong></a>.</p>



<p>But it's not been all roses for Embark Studios and Nexon. There was also <span><strong>controversy surrounding the game's use of AI-based text-to-speech technology</strong>, sparked by Eurogamer's review of ARC Raiders, which rated it 2 out of 5</span> stars specifically because of this. As you <span>may recall,&nbsp;<strong>Epic Games CEO Tim Sweeney</strong>&nbsp;<a href="https://wccftech.com/amidst-arc-raiders-success-embarks-use-of-gen-ai-voices-bubbles-over-even-epics-ceo-joins-the-fray/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">rallied to the studio's defense</a>, stating that political opinions should be expressed in</span> op-ed articles rather than reviews. Nexon CEO <strong>Owen Mahoney</strong> later <a href="https://wccftech.com/nexon-ceo-claims-we-should-assume-every-game-company-now-using-ai-game-devs-say-no/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">chimed</a> in that it was fair to assume every game company is already using AI, and while some developers denied that, there are plenty who agree. <strong>Level 5-CEO Akihiro Hino</strong> recently <a href="https://wccftech.com/if-we-create-the-impression-that-using-ai-is-evil-it-could-seriously-hinder-the-progress-of-modern-digital-tech-says-level-5-ceo/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">advocated for the usage of AI in game development</a>.</p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/5efec50d-61e2-4efb-be02-8228c2457887_2256x1494.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>'We could not have built the games that we've built or service the games that we've done... without some help from artificial intelligence.'</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Now, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vY3u7wOmm4w" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in an interview with GamesBeat</a>, Embark founder (and former CEO <span>of DICE)&nbsp;<strong>Patrick Söderlund</strong>&nbsp;returned to the thorny matter, urging people to reevaluate their stance on AI usage in games, as it can be a considerable boon for developers and</span> also a 'tremendous benefit' for players. For the record, Embark had already used the same technology in their previous game, the free-to-play competitive shooter <strong>The Finals</strong>.</p>



<p><em>I think people have misconceptions about what it means. We don't use artificial intelligence to not have to hire people, or replace people, or replace job groups. That's not the point. We have several voice actors that we work with that are on contract. We work with them continuously. We will continue working with them. They're of course a central piece of this puzzle, but artificial intelligence, you know, we will pay for their voices and sometimes using an artificial voice gets us to update the game a lot faster to make things. If you want a change to the game, we can submit it quickly.</em></p>



<p><em>I think people need to take a step back and look at this and understand what it is and what it can do and the fact that it could be a tremendous help to developers and hence a tremendous benefit to players. Obviously, used in the wrong way... I realize that it's an intricate subject and discussion, but at the same time, we feel that for us, it's never been about replacing people. It's been about making tedious, sometimes boring work parts disappear or be much faster. It's about putting people's time where it really makes sense. I really hope that that's not something that rubs people the wrong way. Shouldn't be.</em></p>



<p><em>[...] AI will have an impact on so many different types of areas of our society today, but I think we need to learn to maneuver that situation and maneuver what it means. I think it doesn't need to be something that's all bad at all. Now, for us, we could not have built the games that we've built or service the games that we've done. The Finals, for example, has been updated every single week once a week since the day we launched it. There's been substantial improvements and updates to the game. By the way, the game is free, so you can go in and not spend a single dollar in the game and we couldn't have done that without some help from artificial intelligence, but obviously most importantly through smart investment in tools and pipelines, technology, and incredible people. This is a people industry. I don't envision games being done automatically by some artificial intelligence.</em></p>



<p>Embark Studios is currently believed to employ <strong>around 350 developers</strong>. It certainly qualifies as a triple-A team, although it's not nearly as big as the teams behind Call of Duty or Battlefield, to name a couple of competitors.</p>



<p>Do you agree with Söderlund's assessment? Feel free to voice your opinion in the comments.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/people-have-to-take-step-back-understand-ai-can-be-big-help-developers-benefit-players-says-arc-raiders-boss/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Console Hacking Has Detonated An Explosive’: PlayStation 5 ROM Keys Leak Online, Opening the Door to Permanent Jailbreaks, Custom Firmware]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/console-hacking-has-detonated-an-explosive-playstation-5-rom-keys-leak-online-opening-the-door-to-permanent-jailbreaks-custom-firmware/</link>
            <guid>1395805</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Since the PlayStation 5's release in late 2020, console hackers have attempted to gain complete access to the system by discovering and exploiting vulnerabilities, using software exploits to access features not normally available to consumers.</p>



<p>But on <strong>New Year's Eve</strong>, console hacking groups detonated another sort of explosive that could have <strong>massive consequences</strong> for the PlayStation 5 hacking scene, opening the door for <strong>permanent jailbreak, custom firmware, emulation,</strong> and much more.</p>



<p>As detailed in an <strong><a href="https://thecybersecguru.com/news/ps5-rom-keys-leaked/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">extremely well-put-together report by <em>The CyberSec Guru</em></a></strong>, at the end of 2025, people in the PlayStation 5 hacking scene began discussing a <strong>massive data dump</strong> that appeared on <em>psdevwiki.com</em> and private Discord servers. This data dump contained the <strong>Level 0 BootROM keys</strong> for the system.</p>



<p>The <strong>BootROM</strong> is the first piece of code the PlayStation 5 runs when the system is turned on, the <strong>deepest level</strong> of the console's security architecture, which is used to decrypt and verify the initial stages of the system boot chain. As such, acquiring these keys, which are stored in a <strong>read-only chip</strong> and decrypted on boot by the system's APU, <strong><em>essentially means that anyone with these keys literally owns the system.</em></strong></p>



<p>Any exploit based on these keys would <strong>significantly surpass</strong> all software exploits available to date, as the code and keys in the BootROM <strong>cannot be modified</strong> with a software update.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><td><strong>Feature</strong></td><td><strong>Software Kernel Exploits (Previous)</strong></td><td><strong>Level 0 BootROM Leak (Current)</strong></td></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><strong>Patchability</strong></td><td><strong>Fixable</strong> via System Update</td><td><strong>Unpatchable</strong> (Silicon-bound)</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Persistence</strong></td><td>Lost after reboot</td><td><strong>Permanent</strong> Custom Firmware potential</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Access Level</strong></td><td>User/Kernel land</td><td><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">Root of Trust</strong> (Deepest)</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Hardware</strong></td><td>Varies by Firmware version</td><td><strong>All existing PS5 models</strong> vulnerable</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>While Sony will likely introduce a <strong>hardware revision (CFI-3000 series)</strong> to rotate these keys in future retail units, the <strong>60+ million consoles</strong> already in homes are now effectively <strong><em>'unlocked' for life.</em></strong></p>



<h3 id="h-what-does-this-mean-for-the-end-user"><strong>What Does This Mean For The End User?</strong></h3>



<p>This massive PlayStation 5 leak has significant implications. Even if any end user gets access to the leaked ROM keys, they would be able to do nothing with them. However, the ability to <strong>decrypt the bootloader</strong> will greatly <strong>accelerate the development of a Custom Firmware</strong> to let the system boot into a modified operating system permanently, without having to run software exploits every time, and with <strong>no risk</strong> of firmware updates patching the vulnerability.</p>



<p>In addition to accelerating the development of custom firmwares, the leaked ROM keys could be a <strong>boon for the emulation scene</strong>, providing emulator developers with the necessary information to enhance the emulator's <strong>compatibility and accuracy</strong>.</p>



<p>In addition, the PlayStation 5 could become an <strong>emulation powerhouse</strong> capable of running games released on various systems, potentially even running <strong>PlayStation 3 games natively via the <a href="https://wccftech.com/rpcs3-can-now-run-all-released-playstation-3-games/">RPCS3 emulator</a></strong>, which has been a long-standing community wish. Unfortunately, this could also <strong>pave the way for piracy</strong>, as a custom firmware could run pirated games on any system.</p>



<p><strong><em>'The PlayStation 5 you own today is not the same console it was yesterday. It is now an open book,'</em></strong> concluded <em>The CyberSec Guru</em> in their report, while the community jokes on Sony's HQ now being on fire, which probably is, at least figuratively, considering the severity of this leak.</p>



<p>No matter how the situation is addressed, it will be very interesting to see how the Japanese company will handle this <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">critical situation</strong> alongside other potentially crippling hardware issues like the <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://wccftech.com/all-ps5-consoles-will-eventually-require-maintenance-playstation-5-liquid-metal-degradation/"><strong data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)">liquid metal cooling issues</strong></a>, and what will come with what is set to become an <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">epochal leak</em></strong> for console security.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/console-hacking-has-detonated-an-explosive-playstation-5-rom-keys-leak-online-opening-the-door-to-permanent-jailbreaks-custom-firmware/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Triple-A John Wick and Saw Games Teased by Lionsgate]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/triple-a-john-wick-and-saw-games-teased-by-lionsgate/</link>
            <guid>1395751</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>It is somewhat of a mystery how, more than eleven years after the first <strong>John Wick</strong> film, there is still no triple-A action game based on the beloved character interpreted by <strong>Keanu Reeves</strong>. </p>



<p>2014's John Wick spawned not only sequels but a veritable universe for owner <strong>Lionsgate Studios</strong> to exploit, as seen recently with the <strong>Ballerina</strong> spin-off movie featuring <strong>Ana de Armas</strong>, the single-season prequel TV series, and two future spin-offs, in addition to the highly anticipated fifth mainline entry.</p>



<p>However, gamers were only treated to the indie turn-based strategy game John Wick Hex, a mix between X-COM and Superhot <a href="https://wccftech.com/john-wick-hex-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">developed by <strong>Mike Bithell</strong></a>. It was a great game in its own right, <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/john-wick-hex-action-choreography-masterclass/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">as outlined in Wccftech's review</a>, but it was certainly far removed from the cinematic spectacle that we've come to associate with the films. Hex <a href="https://wccftech.com/john-wick-hex-delisted/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">was actually delisted from all stores earlier this year</a>, so it's not even available for purchase any longer.</p>



<p>Back in November 2022, Lionsgate mentioned it was 'exploring' several pitches for a triple-A John Wick game. During the most recent investor call that followed their Q2 2026 report (a complete transcript is available <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/LION/earnings/LION-Q2-2026-earnings_call-372593.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">on Yahoo Finance</a>), <strong>Chairman of the Motion Picture Group Adam Fogelson</strong> provided a small update on this, as well as a game adaptation of the <strong>Saw</strong> horror franchise:</p>



<p><em>Our AAA game opportunities and other gaming opportunities around John Wick and Saw and some others that we'll be announcing soon, we're seeing increased interest and increased opportunity, and we remain on schedule. I think in totality, you are going to see a meaningfully additive financial opportunity coming in the coming years.</em></p>



<p>It is honestly unclear, based on the wording, whether the deals have already been signed between Lionsgate and some triple-A developer or not. Even in the best-case scenario, where they are already underway, triple-A game development typically takes at least four to five years nowadays, so <strong>we'd likely have to wait until 2030 or even longer</strong> to actually play these games. Still, both franchises have a lot of potential to become successful gaming adaptations.</p>



<p>Which developer would you like to see at the respective helms? Let us know in the comments.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/triple-a-john-wick-and-saw-games-teased-by-lionsgate/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>