<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 15:07:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Sinking City 2 Q&A – Frogwares on Renewed Combat Focus, UE5 Switch, and Continued War Impact]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-sinking-city-2-qa-frogwares-on-renewed-combat-focus-ue5-switch-and-continued-war-impact/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-sinking-city-2-q-a-%E2%80%93-frogwares-on-renewed-combat-focus-ue5-switch-and-continued-war-impact.1141374/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/the-sinking-city-2-qa-frogwares-on-renewed-combat-focus-ue5-switch-and-continued-war-impact/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Ukrainian developer Frogwares is currently <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-sinking-city-2-shows-off-gameplay-and-launches-kickstarter-campaign/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">seeking funds</a> for The Sinking City 2 on Kickstarter. After two weeks, and with another two left before the end, the <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/frogwares/the-sinking-city-2/description" target="_blank" rel="noopener">campaign</a> has so far gathered over €383K, nearly four times the minimum amount of €100K. Of course, the studio hopes that the momentum continues; according to <a href="https://kicktraq.com/projects/frogwares/the-sinking-city-2/#chart-exp-projection" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kicktraq projections</a>, it could land anywhere between €424K and €483K.</p>
<p>It has not been smooth sailing for Frogwares in the past few years. In 2019-20, their games were delisted from digital stores twice in the span of a year due to problems with French publishers <a href="https://wccftech.com/frogwares-claims-to-be-endangered-by-focus-home-interactive-policy-games-being-delisted/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Focus Home Interactive</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-sinking-city-delisted-from-storefronts-frogwares-cites-breach-of-contract-with-nacon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nacon</a>. Then there was the pandemic, of course, which affected everyone. Just as things were looking better, the Russian invasion of Ukraine suddenly happened in early 2022.</p>
<p>We <a href="https://wccftech.com/frogwares-ceo-talks-about-the-wars-tragic-impact-on-the-ukrainian-game-studio/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">talked with them</a> just a few days after the war started, learning of all their fear and day-to-day troubles. Thankfully, Epic <a href="https://wccftech.com/frogwares-receives-epic-games-megagrant-to-help-support-ukranian-developers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">awarded the studio a MegaGrant</a>, offering them a reprieve of sorts. Even so, they had to re-evaluate their roadmap and decided to develop <a href="https://wccftech.com/frogwares-announces-project-palianytsia-game-project-for-sinking-city-and-sherlock-holmes-fans/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Project Palianytsia</a>, which turned out to be Sherlock Holmes The Awakened, a reboot of the first entry in the franchise that was funded via Kickstarter. The ongoing war <a href="https://wccftech.com/sherlock-holmes-the-awakened-delayed-due-to-continued-russian-strikes-in-kyiv/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">caused</a> a short delay, but the studio still managed to release a solid game, as outlined in <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/sherlock-holmes-the-awakened-the-only-way-forward-is-the-abyss/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">our review</a>.</p>
<p>Now, the studio has returned to what it really wanted to make: The Sinking City 2. This one <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-sinking-city-2-announcement-ue5-horror-frogwares-deliver-ukraine-war/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">will be a full-fledged horror game</a>, whereas the first entry was more of an open world investigation game with horror undertones. Right in the middle of the Kickstarter campaign, we reached out once more to Sergiy Oganesyan, Publishing Director at Frogwares, to discuss how the project evolved over the past couple of years (including the switch to Unreal Engine 5), what fans can expect from it, and how the war is still affecting the development team.</p>
<figure><figcaption>'Our vision for The Sinking City 2 is a Lovecraftian survival horror game with deep investigation mechanics, and that hasn’t changed much. But there’s still a huge difference between the first vertical slice we created back in 2023 and the recent playable footage that we published for Kickstarter, and that, thanks to the feedback from playtests, has definitely shown us where we need to adjust our priorities.'</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Exactly a year ago, you <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-sinking-city-2-goes-to-kickstarter-soon-as-frogwares-needs-a-safety-net-from-the-war/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">told</a> fans the Kickstarter campaign would open up soon, but then you went dark for a while. Can you disclose what happened?</strong></p>
<p>A few things really. Over the past year, we made the decision to focus on giving ourselves some time to develop the game so we could showcase real gameplay for Kickstarter, rather than just concept art. Along the way, we also refined some of our designs to better fit actual gameplay, ensuring a stronger experience.</p>
<p>When we announced it in 2024, we had some closed playtests very soon after that with a group of our closest fans. Through their feedback, we started refining even more on where we should place our focus and efforts, which dictated a lot about how we’d present the game in our campaign. Much of what we showed in the gameplay and dev diary we just released is due to our work with our fans. Additionally, we took the time to carefully map out and design physical rewards for the campaign, making sure they are meaningful and high-quality for our backers. It’s the first time we've done something like that, and there was a lot of fog of war to deal with.</p>
<p>Lastly, we are all still mostly working remotely as a team due to the war. So, we work more around our team and their needs. We didn’t want anyone to feel rushed on the campaign. Progress on the game was the priority, and then getting what we needed for the launch of the Kickstarter came when everyone felt ready to help. So these factors all stacked up, but we’re glad we could take our time.</p>
<p><strong>How has your vision for The Sinking City 2 evolved since the game's announcement?</strong></p>
<p>Our vision for The Sinking City 2 is a Lovecraftian survival horror game with deep investigation mechanics, and that hasn’t changed much. But there’s still a huge difference between the first vertical slice we created back in 2023 and the recent playable footage that we published for Kickstarter, and that, thanks to the feedback from playtests, has definitely shown us where we need to adjust our priorities.</p>
<p>If you take combat, for example, we spent a lot of time improving the overall feeling of it. How enemies behave, how they react to being shot, how impactful the shotgun is, that kind of thing. There’s still a lot of work ahead, but we are happy to see that most people are satisfied with where this particular mechanic is going.</p>
<p><strong>How recent is the Pre-Alpha gameplay footage that you just shared? How much more polished do you expect the full game to be?</strong></p>
<p>Well, this is sort of the downside of a Kickstarter campaign—you often have to launch it at a time when you can’t really show anything totally final. Much of what we showed was recorded in&nbsp;late 2024, but in order to really understand how much things can change, we need to take into consideration how game development works.</p>
<p>For example, we create our levels in a vacuum of what we call Vitaras (visual targets) - separate maps inside the engine where you don’t have any real gameplay. So while the work on those continues, inside the real game you have placeholder assets, which, as you can imagine, are very far in terms of the quality of what we want to achieve. But when those Vitaras are fully migrated to the real game, you suddenly have beautiful meshes, materials, lighting and so on and the difference is like night and day. The same goes for your enemies and everything else, really. What I’m trying to say is that there wasn’t anything in the trailer that was truly final, locked, and won’t ever be touched again. Once we fully integrate our locations, combat, and other gameplay together, you’ll see the difference for the better.</p>
<p><strong>One of the big areas of focus for this sequel is combat. Can you talk about some of the improvements fans will see compared to the first game?</strong></p>
<p>Where do I even begin? I have already mentioned that we are putting a lot of emphasis on how combat feels because it must feel fun and convincing. You must enjoy landing a shot, and this is achieved through a number of things, primarily VFX, sound design, recoil, enemy hit reaction, etc. We mentioned a wound body system for our enemies in our recent dev diary - it’s essentially a second layer of muscle, ligaments, and blood mass underneath the skin, which reacts when hit. It’s all a bit gory, but in my opinion, very satisfying to see working under the hood.</p>
<p>So, a lot of work is being done on enemy visuals, animations, attacks, and, of course, enemy placement around each map to make this all come together. I’m not going to lie; combat is probably the most challenging aspect for us, especially since this is now a core focus of the game compared to the original. One enemy can take months of work, and that’s just the visual design, without any gameplay. But so far, the results we and our closed playtesters have seen prove we’re on the right track. We’ve still got a lot more work to do, and we’ll likely be refining this right to the end, but we’re really happy with the progress so far.</p>
<figure><figcaption>'You must enjoy landing a shot, and this is achieved through a number of things, primarily VFX, sound design, recoil, enemy hit reaction, etc. We mentioned a wound body system for our enemies in our recent dev diary - it’s essentially a second layer of muscle, ligaments, and blood mass underneath the skin, which reacts when hit. It’s all a bit gory, but in my opinion, very satisfying to see working under the hood.'</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Will players be able to dodge out of the way and perform some melee actions in combat?</strong></p>
<p>Yes, we are experimenting with some dodge and “last-resort” melee mechanics.</p>
<p><strong>In terms of narrative and atmosphere, how is The Sinking City 2 going to set itself apart from its predecessor? Are there going to be any easter eggs or even returning characters for fans of the original?</strong></p>
<p>So, the two games are set in the same universe and time setting. 1920s United States drenched in a gloomy, Lovecraftian horror vibe. And just like before, a supernatural flood has taken hold of a city and is changing it in unfathomable ways. But that’s mainly where the similarities end. The Sinking City 2 features a new, stand-alone story entirely separate from the one told in the original game. So we’re not going back to playing as Charles Reed, nor are we going back to the city of Oakmont in any way, and we made all these narrative and atmosphere choices for a reason. We wanted to create a story and setting that wasn’t burdened by what we created in the original game, especially since players have various endings they favor or consider the “true ending” to that story.</p>
<p>This way, we can let existing fans come back into this familiar world fresh, while anyone who never played the original can also step in without feeling like they are missing a big chunk of the story. So while we might have some small Easter eggs or hints here and there, they will be there mainly as a wink and nudge for us and our most devoted fans.</p>
<p><strong>You've said that while this isn't an open-world game, it will feature plenty of secrets and large explorable zones. Considering side content, how long should we expect the game to be?</strong></p>
<p>That’s not something we can answer right now, as there are still parts of the game we haven’t finalized yet. However, it’s a survival horror game, so it would be fair to look at some recent releases in the genre to get a ballpark idea.</p>
<p><strong>The Kickstarter campaign appears to have gone very well so far.</strong></p>
<p>Yup. Just yesterday we unlocked another stretch goal - a new giant monster type, the Shoggoth. Now, just to be clear, we already did promise a Shoggoth encounter in the game, but these are two very different enemies, both visually and mechanically. We’ll probably hit one more stretch goal after this one is funded.</p>
<p><strong>Will the game launch in early access or straight to full release?</strong></p>
<p>The game will launch in full on PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox X/S at the same time. At one point, we considered the Early Access route but decided we were better off using Kickstarter and closed playtests to help develop the game.</p>
<p><strong>Was it hard to transition to Unreal Engine 5? Are you leveraging all their technologies (Lumen, Nanite, etc.) to elevate the visuals?</strong></p>
<p>There was a learning curve for sure, but it was quite smooth. It was really helpful that we knew from the start that The Sinking City 2 was going to be made in Unreal 5. Speak to any team who made the transition, and almost all of them will tell you to make the switch at the start if you can. It will save you so much time and effort in the long run. So, we finished our last game on UE4 and started pre-production for TSC2 from scratch. All our internal tools were developed as separate plugins, so although the migration took some time, it was fairly straightforward. This also provided a great opportunity to get rid of a bunch of legacy code and finally perform a long-overdue refactor.</p>
<p>The tools UE5 brings have been amazing, for sure. Lumen has significantly improved our lighting and reflection systems, creating a more immersive and visually stunning environment. For us, especially where The Sinking City 2 has many wet surfaces, Lumen allows us to achieve much more realistic and dynamic lighting effects that were previously really difficult to attain.</p>
<p>With Metahuman, we were astonished at how fast, simple, and realistic the results were. After our initial tests, we reviewed our entire cutscene and dialogue creation process and reworked everything to better utilize these tools.</p>
<p>Nanite significantly changed our approach to asset creation, allowing us to use highly detailed models without compromising performance. This has been particularly beneficial for creating the much more detailed environments that were required for this game. Since we are going for that feeling of isolation and a more contained play space, we need the environment itself to do a lot of the immersion heavy lifting.</p>
<p>That said, while new technologies are fantastic and help solve old problems, they can also bring new issues to tackle. Nanite was no exception. For instance, in our previous projects, a single Static Mesh asset did not take up more than 200MB of disk space, but now it is pretty common. So, managing the increased asset sizes and optimizing our workflows to accommodate this change has been a significant task.</p>
<figure><figcaption>'The tools UE5 brings have been amazing, for sure. Lumen has significantly improved our lighting and reflection systems, creating a more immersive and visually stunning environment. For us, especially where The Sinking City 2 has many wet surfaces, Lumen allows us to achieve much more realistic and dynamic lighting effects that were previously really difficult to attain. [...] Lumen already supports software ray-tracing out of the box. Our team is also looking at the hardware one, but it’ll depend on the optimization.'</figcaption></figure><p><strong>Will you support ray traced effects like global illumination, reflections, etc.?</strong></p>
<p>Lumen already supports software ray-tracing out of the box. Our team is also looking at the hardware one, but it’ll depend on the optimization.</p>
<p><strong>Do you plan to prepare enhancements for the PS5 Pro console?</strong></p>
<p>It’s likely, but I can’t say which enhancements yet.</p>
<p><strong>Would you like to share anything about Ukraine's situation and how it's still impacting your daily work?</strong></p>
<p>Missile strikes and drone attacks almost every goddamn night. Just yesterday, around 20 drones attacked the city of Kropyvnytskyi. In Kyiv, you can’t fall asleep without listening to air defense fighting off another swarm of Russian drones. In a way, we have become used to it, but not exactly in a healthy way. You have to just accept it and try to keep living, not knowing if your luck will run out soon.</p>
<p><strong>Thank you for your time, and stay strong.</strong></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atomfall Review – Shadow of Cumbria]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/review/atomfall-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/atomfall-review-%E2%80%93-shadow-of-cumbria.1141275/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/review/atomfall-review/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			<div><header>Game Info</header><div>
							<h5>Platform</h5><p><span>PC, PlayStation 4 &amp; 5, Xbox One &amp; Series S/X</span>
						</p></div></div>			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/rebellions-atomfall-single-player-survival-action-game-is-out-on-march-27-2025/">Atomfall</a> is a game that came out of nowhere for me. I was browsing Steam a few weeks ago, having taken a little break after the gaming marathon of Civilization VII and Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2, and there it was: a post-apocalyptic game set in Britain. Considering I'm from Britain and have been to where this is based—that being Windermere—and I love Metro, S.T.A.L.K.E.R., Fallout, and other similar games, it was a no-brainer.</p>
<p>With people running around in masks, battering innocents to death with cricket bats, or using a shiv to watch the life bleed out of them as they mutter utter gibberish about returning to the soil before telling you to "fack off", Britain in 2025 is an interesting place. Then we get Atomfall, set in a fictional post-apocalyptic Britain following the Windscale disaster, not the current post-apocalyptic Britain hoping to recover from the incompetent Tory government only to have a new Tory Labour government, mercilessly taking from the poor and disabled while catering to their wealthy overlords.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>Taking place inside a quarantine zone following a disaster at a nuclear power station, it's not an open world but a connection of multiple open areas, Metro: Exodus style. Rebellion has captured the feel of the North-West quite well, to the point where I have been on Google Maps to figure out the exact location it's set in; I blame the road sign to Kendal for doing this to me. In terms of the story, there is more than just the nuclear accident, including a government coverup surrounding the accident and how it links to Oberon - the code name for a government project, which I won't spoil more of - and the impact on the surrounding area the combination of these have had.</p>
<p>The direct impact you will see is the area's abandonment and how quickly it delved into chaos. There are five open zones in the core playable area; Wyndham Village is controlled by the Protocol (the army) and is generally friendly and accessible except in a few places. Three of the other zones are controlled by the Raiders, Druids and Protocol, respectively, but parts of the areas are completely off-limits, and if you are spotted, you will be attacked. The remaining area is The Interchange, where the secrets of Atomfall are primarily revealed.</p>
<p>You'll find yourself moving between these areas, following clues and tasks from NPCs in the area, aiming to escape. You don't know why you're there, but you know you don't want to be. The way you move between the different objectives you find is how Rebellion has tried to differentiate Atomfall from other games. Rather than a quest log, you have "leads". It's a distinction with at least a little difference, as you have a collection of the notes and conversations to do with a "lead", and you can read through these to figure out exactly where and what you should be doing next, and more often than not the clues are reasonably obvious. What is more interesting is that you can frequently find the objective of a quest - or lead - before you've even seen the start, depending on your proclivity to explore.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>Through this and the interconnected maps, where shortcuts can be revealed to make your life easier, Atomfall rewards exploration in a way many larger games forget to do. I should clarify that even when doing a significant amount of exploration, as I have been, you'll find Atomfall may only take about twenty hours to complete. Now, there is replay value in the fact that you have various stories, many of which can collide and result in one being cut off early.</p>
<p>Two, for example, are scientists around at the start of everything. One is hiding in the village, infected, but working on a cure and weapon to stop the source. Another left has come back and has been imprisoned. If they work on both stories but tell the first where the second is, he kills her - spoiler warning. This cuts off one possible story on escaping the quarantine zone. I don't know exactly how many threads are in the game, but at least five lead towards an escape. Do they differ? I can't tell you; I am keen to find out.</p>
<p>If I have an issue with the leads system, there are a few where you can be left a little clueless about what you need to do. There are a few where you are more likely to stumble across the next step than intentionally find it. Also, as mentioned in the above example, a decision you make can result in a part of the story being completely cut off from you. I don't want to say "with no warning" because when you listen to the audio logs and read the notes surrounding the two characters, only a moron wouldn't be able to figure out the outcome. I said to myself "he's going to kill her", before I even gave him the location. Some people may argue you need it made a little too clear.</p>


<figure></figure>

<p>Outside of the exploration and story, Atomfall is still more than serviceable. Combat isn't too dissimilar to other titles. Melee and Ranged weapons will be found or picked up from the corpses of enemies, and you have a limited ammo capacity. When the respective skill is selected, I think the ammo capacity is expanded alongside the capacity of your materials used for crafting. Either way, it feels pretty balanced, mainly as you can only hold a limited number of items.</p>
<p>Often, I've found myself hoarding enough ammo to then go into one of the - I'll call them dungeons - when I get out of the other end, I'm low on ammo and even low on some crafting gear since I've been making Molotovs on the fly. I've rarely found myself in a position I can't get out of, one way or another, even if it's just trying to be stealthy to avoid people, then doing a runner. I want to say the options are limitless, but they never are. It's either fight, run, sneak, or a combination of two or more.</p>
<p>Combat feels quite responsive, though; I will certainly give it that. Aside from lobbing a Molotov Cocktail, the most valuable skill in your arsenal is the option to kick an enemy. If you unlock the ability that gives it a better stun and knockback, you become challenging to beat in close quarters. Some of the stronger enemies, the thralls, will eventually get to you, but it becomes instrumental in the areas you find them. Creating space to reload your shotgun, to pump some extra shells into their heads. Also, aim for the heads; it does the damage. Even better, though, get a good rifle, keep your distance, and go for the head.</p>
<p>Once you realise how useful it is, the crafting becomes quite essential. I didn't touch the crafting system for much of the game beyond creating random Molotovs or sticky bombs. However, since the materials don't use inventory space, strategic thinking becomes all the more critical. Why carry multiple bandages with you when you can craft some? Later, when you learn how to upgrade weapons, you need to. Improving their damage, range and aim is crucial to surviving the late-game events.</p>


<figure></figure>

<p>I won't argue that Atomfall will be the next Metro: Exodus or something like that. I don't think it is. Atomfall sits in the realms of the games that died out a while back but are in a resurgence. Your non-Triple-A games aren't budgeted to blow apart the biggest releases, but they can do well if they get it right. The original Kingdom Come: Deliverance is a similar title, and look at what happened with the sequel. Atomfall strikes me as a similar title, with a style designed to reach as broad an audience as possible.</p>
<p>That this is on last-gen systems is proof enough, though I have to say that when playing it on the PC, with settings to max, I have no issues with the visuals. I'd argue that the more colourful and less realistic style adds charm to Atomfall, and frankly, I would say it looks and plays better than any of Bethesda's post-apocalyptic output. Hell, even it's more space-faring production.</p>
<p>I've only encountered a small number of bugs while playing through Atomfall; a few characters have clipped into each other, and beating robot enemies is a chore once you realise you can break their paths by having them spot you, and then you disappear. Without fail, they never seem to be able to go back to their patrol. Also, the most glaring issue is that enemies cannot see you or shoot you through windows - I can't explain how or why, other than maybe Rebellion forgot windows are transparent and break when a bullet hits them.</p>
<p>If I have another criticism, the audio, specifically the voice acting, can also be off. I understand the army having a mixture of accents, but the residents and other locals of the area should sound like they're primarily from Cumbria. There's something just a little off, though the reality is that nobody outside of the North of England will ever notice. I can't say anything massive about the soundtrack, to be honest. It works as it doesn't stand out, but at the same time, it doesn't stand out. Other audio effects are generally strong; nothing stands out like it shouldn't be.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>As I've said, I can't honestly argue that Atomfall will be the next post-apocalyptic masterpiece. What I will say, though, is that it is a game I've had a fun and enjoyable time with. This is the sort of game you can pick up at a lower price-point (£45) than your traditional £60 "Triple-A" games, and you can have a good twenty-plus hours, or more, with it.</p>
<p>Atomfall looks good, plays well, and has a decent atmosphere. It has a reasonably interesting semi-open collection of maps to explore and the dungeons (for lack of a better word) that come with such a game. The combat doesn't feel janky, and the AI isn't terrible. It has an interesting story and tries something a little different with the quests system to enhance exploration. I hope this does well enough that we get the sequel treatment in the same vein as <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/kingdom-come-deliverance-ii/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kingdom Come: Deliverance II</a> because we could see the next leader of the post-apocalypse.</p>

				

						<div>
					
					
					<h2>Atomfall</h2>
				</div>
			
						<section>
				<p>Atomfall is a thoroughly enjoyable game which looks and plays well, and offers a compelling narrative with surrounding exploration to keep you entertained. It's well-polished, offers good replay value, encourages you to do things a little different, and isn't bad on the eyes either, with a good design that allows it to both look good and support last-gen consoles. The score likely doesn't reflect the game as well as it should, as I would heartily recommend this to anybody, with the added advantage that it's coming to game pass.</p>
				<div>
												<ul>
							<h6>Pros</h6>
							<li>An interesting story, adding to the generic "nuclear fallout" plot found in other similar titles.
</li><li>A "leads" system that successfully does quests a little different, adding to exploration.
</li><li>Good art design which enables it to look good, while also catering to last-gen consoles.</li>						</ul>
																		<ul>
							<h6>Cons</h6>
							<li>Can feature a few bugs with AI and pathfinding, here and there.
</li><li>Why can't enemies see you or shoot through windows?</li>						</ul>
										</div>
				<a rel="sponsored nofollow noskim" href="">Buy for  from Amazon</a>
				<span>The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may
					earn from qualifying purchases.</span>
			</section>
			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Xbox UI Image Shows Steam Label, Further Hinting At The Merging of the Best of Xbox and Windows]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/new-xbox-ui-image-shows-steam-label-further-hinting-at-the-merging-of-the-best-of-xbox-and-windows/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-xbox-ui-image-shows-steam-label-further-hinting-at-the-merging-of-the-best-of-xbox-and-windows.1141224/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/new-xbox-ui-image-shows-steam-label-further-hinting-at-the-merging-of-the-best-of-xbox-and-windows/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Xbox UI is set to change significantly in the future, and it may soon show Steam games that are installed on the system, judging from an image shared online that was promptly removed shortly after.</p>
<p>As reported by&nbsp;<a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/633478/microsoft-xbox-steam-games-support-ui" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Verge</a>, an image was shared in a new blog post titled&nbsp;<em><a href="https://developer.microsoft.com/en-us/games/articles/2025/03/gdc-2025-opening-a-billion-doors-with-xbox/">"Opening a Billion Doors With Xbox</a>," </em>which highlighted changes in the game industry and users now tending to engage with games across multiple devices, showing how the Xbox UI could change in the future to account for this tendency. What makes this new interface interesting is a clearly visible Steam label in all variants of the interface: TV, tablet and handheld. According to unspecified sources, Microsoft is working on an Xbox app update that will show every game installed on a PC, including games purchased on other digital storefronts like Steam and the Epic Games Store. As this Xbox app update is still in the early stages of development, however, the inclusion of all installed PC games in the interface may be scrapped as work continues.</p>
<p>Besides working on a new Xbox UI and app update, Microsoft is also hard at work on the hardware side of its <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-next-release-2027-premium-handheld/">next-generation plans</a>, which include a premium successor to the Xbox Series X and a handheld console. In addition, the company is also <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-handheld-project-kennan-is-reportedly-being-made-by-asus/">reportedly working with ASUS</a> on a handheld known as Project Keenan that will launch later this year. This handheld system, which will look markedly Xbox, will run full Windows with a focus on the Microsoft Store and PC Game Pass. As such, it will definitely be able to run games purchased on Steam and other digital storefronts, so it wouldn't be surprising for the new UI featuring the Steam label to launch alongside the system.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>