<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 15:20:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 Units May Already Be in the Hands of Some; Console Could Be Priced at Around $350 – Rumor]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-units-out-priced-350/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-units-may-already-be-in-the-hands-of-some-console-could-be-priced-at-around-350-%E2%80%93-rumor.1104894/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-units-out-priced-350/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 could already be in the hands of some users, according to some new online reports.</p>
<p>As reported on Bluesky by Necro Felipe, the same user on the Xiaohongshu forums who shared the console's CAD model <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-design-pictures-specs/">a few months back</a> claims to have obtained a real Nintendo Switch 2 unit, most likely via illegal means. If this is true, we should expect more information on the system to surface online before the April 2nd Direct and the hands-on events that will be held worldwide in the coming months.</p>
<blockquote data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:5uw2zrybj37wnkkc5ku4fxyu/app.bsky.feed.post/3lht5vqyzlp2x" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreia2unbnwu4mqgh2dve44seg5vprp5hrle7hjgbjia2bdaqryv4voa">
<p lang="pt">Usuário que compartilhou o modelo CAD do Switch 2 anteriormente no fórum Xiaohongshu afirma que obteve um Switch 2 real agora (provavelmente de forma ilegal)</p>
<p>Ele avisa aos interessados por acessórios que o contate para testes com o aparelho</p>
<p>(thx Kysen)</p>
<p><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:5uw2zrybj37wnkkc5ku4fxyu/post/3lht5vqyzlp2x?ref_src=embed">[image or embed]</a></p>
<p>— Necro Felipe • Universo Nintendo (<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:5uw2zrybj37wnkkc5ku4fxyu?ref_src=embed">@necro.universonintendo.com</a>) <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:5uw2zrybj37wnkkc5ku4fxyu/post/3lht5vqyzlp2x?ref_src=embed">February 10, 2025 at 1:37 PM</a></p></blockquote>

<p>Among the many things we still don't know about the Nintendo Switch 2 is how much the system will cost, as the Japanese company has not said much on the matter yet other than the fact that they are considering multiple factors for the system's price, including inflation, exchange rate and the price range that consumers expect for Nintendo products. As reported by <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/02/rumour-placeholder-retail-listing-suggests-switch-2-price-might-be-cheaper-than-expected">Nintendo Life</a>, according to two images showing Costco Canada's backend product listing and a printed sign with an obvious misspelling recently shared on the <a href="https://famiboards.com/threads/future-nintendo-hardware-technology-speculation-discussion-st-new-staff-post-please-read.55/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Famiiboards forums</a>, the console could cost 499 Canadian dollars, around 350 US dollars, which would be an excellent price for the system, although a direct conversion may not be very accurate, looking at the current Switch pricing in different regions.</p>
<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 will launch later this year worldwide. As already mentioned, the next look at the system will come during a dedicated Nintendo Direct scheduled for<a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-officially-revealed-with-a-new-trailer-dedicated-direct-confirmed-for-april/"> April 2nd.</a></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grand Theft Auto VI Could Lose Over 40% of Sales Skipping PC Release This Year; Game Will Meaningfully Drive Console Sales]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-skipping-pc-lose-40-sales/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grand-theft-auto-vi-could-lose-over-40-of-sales-skipping-pc-release-this-year-game-will-meaningfully-drive-console-sales.1104822/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-skipping-pc-lose-40-sales/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Grand Theft Auto VI skipping PC at launch could result in over 40% sales, according to Take-Two's CEO Strauss Zelnick.</p>
<p>Speaking with <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/take-two-boss-unconcerned-by-plummeting-ps5-and-xbox-sales-insists-gta-6-will-cause-a-meaningful-uptick-in-console-sales-in-2025">IGN</a> ahead of the publisher's <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-is-still-scheduled-to-release-this-fall-take-two-full-expects-to-support-the-nintendo-switch-2/">recent financial results</a> about the game skipping PC at launch, Zelnick essentially said that the highly-anticipated game will unsurprisingly eventually release on PC, highlighting that, historically, Rockstar has started with some platforms before moving on to others, so even a game as anticipated as the next entry in the popular series is not going to break this trend.</p>
<p>Still, PC sales make up a large amount of total sales for almost every multiplatform game, and it won't be any different for Grand Theft Auto VI, as, according to the Take-Two CEO, the PC version of any multiplatform game can generate over 40% of overall sales. On the other hand, launching on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X and S only is likely to drive console sales out of the current slump, as Zelnick believes this is what is going to happen this year with the release not only of GTA VI but of other games as well, even in the United States despite tariffs not making things any easier.</p>
<p>Grand Theft Auto VI is launching this Fall on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S worldwide. However, the game's ambitious scope could cause a delay, which wouldn't be the first for Rockstar Games.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Square Enix Video Games Profit Declined by 9.9%, Despite Higher Than Expected Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake Sales]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/square-enix-video-games-profit-declined-by-9-9-despite-higher-than-expected-dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake-sales/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/square-enix-video-games-profit-declined-by-9-9-despite-higher-than-expected-dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake-sales.1104774/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/square-enix-video-games-profit-declined-by-9-9-despite-higher-than-expected-dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake-sales/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Despite Final Fantasy XIV: Dawntrail and Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake doing better than anticipated, Square Enix still reported a drop in video game profits by almost 10% over the past year.</p>
<p>In its <a href="https://www.hd.square-enix.com/eng/ir/pdf/25q3slides.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">financial report</a> for the first nine months of the current fiscal year ending on March 31st, the Japanese publisher confirmed net sales for its Digital Entertainment sector have dropped 10.7% and operating income 9.9% due to the weak performance of mobile and browser-based games and to the low sales of games released this year compared to the sales of those released the previous fiscal year, including the Final Fantasy Pixel Remasters and Dragon Quest Monsters: The Dark Prince. Still, some of the publisher's new releases did well, as the Dragon Quest HD-2D Remake sold better than expected. The Final Fantasy XIV Dawntrail expansion also sold well and has driven an increase in the MMO segment profits over the previous year.</p>
<p>The results reported in the latest financial report aren't particularly surprising, considering how Square Enix reported last September how sales of<a href="https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-xvi-underperformed-disappointing-profits/"> Final Fantasy XVI and Final Fantasy VII Rebirth did not meet expectations</a>, expectations that were reportedly reasonable this time. Thankfully, the second entry in the Remake trilogy seems to be doing quite well on<a href="https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-had-great-steam-launch-best-selling-game-of-the-week-ending-jan-25/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> PC</a>, so there's the chance that sales will eventually meet the publisher's expectations. It definitely would be a shame for such a good game to be considered a failure in terms of sales.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>