<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 16:17:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 Pre-Orders Should Start Next Week in Canada]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-pre-orders-canada-april-23/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-pre-orders-should-start-next-week-in-canada.1164915/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-pre-orders-canada-april-23/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Nintendo Switch 2 pre-orders in Canada should start next week, according to a very reliable leaker.</p>
<p>Earlier today, known leaker <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/billbil-kun.bsky.social" target="_blank" rel="noopener">billbil-kun</a> revealed that from what they can see through some Canadian retailers, pre-orders for the next-generation Nintendo console and bundles launching this June will start next week, on April 23rd. Unfortunately, the leaker couldn't confirm if pre-orders in the United States will also begin next week.</p>
<blockquote data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:elj43u6btwgjlhencvmwvyoe/app.bsky.feed.post/3lmufkqku6c2c" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreibnr6uda65gdmnihfycqmofv2pzxqou6rv2ihnxtdbrzzkg3gnz24" data-bluesky-embed-color-mode="system">
<p lang="en">🚨 UPCOMING RELEASE 🚨</p>
<p>From what I can see through some Canadian retailers, Nintendo Switch 2 console &amp; bundle pre-orders should start from</p>
<p>📅 April 23rd, 2025 (valid in CA)</p>
<p>⚠️ Date subject to change. Can't confirm if it's the same for US</p>
<p>I'll keep you updated if it changes</p>
<p><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:elj43u6btwgjlhencvmwvyoe/post/3lmufkqku6c2c?ref_src=embed">[image or embed]</a></p>
<p>— billbil-kun (<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:elj43u6btwgjlhencvmwvyoe?ref_src=embed">@billbil-kun.bsky.social</a>) <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:elj43u6btwgjlhencvmwvyoe/post/3lmufkqku6c2c?ref_src=embed">April 15, 2025 at 5:32 PM</a></p></blockquote>

<p>Nintendo Switch 2 pre-orders in the whole of North America were supposed to start last week, but they were ultimately delayed in the United States first to <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-pre-order-not-april-9th-tariffs/">assess the potential impact of tariffs</a>. Pre-orders in Canada were later delayed in order to <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-pre-orders-have-been-delayed-in-canada-thanks-to-us-tariffs/">align with the timing of pre-orders in the US</a>, so there's a good chance that those living in the United States may be able to pre-order the console next week if pre-orders in Canada will indeed begin on April 23rd.</p>
<p>If the current situation doesn't change, there's little doubt that the tariffs will impact the Nintendo Switch 2 price, although it is not yet known in which capacity. An internal assessment memo from a major Apple and Nintendo supplier seen by Nikkei Asia suggests that the console is in<a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-price-increase-us/"> line for a significant price increase</a> as long as game consoles made in China will be subject to a 145% tariff in the United States. The PlayStation 5 could also see a price increase in the United States due to the tariffs, a price increase that would follow the one announced for the United Kingdom, Europe, Australia, and New Zealand <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-price-increased/">this week.</a></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Larian’s “Final Major Game Patch” For Baldur’s Gate 3, Patch 8, Is Out Now On All Platforms]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/larians-final-major-game-patch-for-baldurs-gate-3-patch-8-is-out-now-on-all-platforms/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/larian%E2%80%99s-%E2%80%9Cfinal-major-game-patch%E2%80%9D-for-baldur%E2%80%99s-gate-3-patch-8-is-out-now-on-all-platforms.1164774/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/larians-final-major-game-patch-for-baldurs-gate-3-patch-8-is-out-now-on-all-platforms/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Larian Studios' journey with <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/baldurs-gate-3-review/">Baldur's Gate 3</a> began in <a href="https://larian.com/support/faqs/general-information_46#:~:text=Baldur's%20Gate%203%20is%20using,game%20design%20in%20late%202016.">2016</a>, with a small team starting work on the game's design and story. Then, in 2020, the game launched in an early access state on PC before its full release three years later in 2023. Now, it's known as one of the best RPGs ever made.</p>
<p>Today, the journey has ended in a significant way, with Larian Studios releasing the "<em>final major game patch</em>" for Baldur's Gate 3, Patch 8, which is now live on PS5, Xbox Series X/S, Mac, and PC. This is the final patch Larian will release that includes new content, and every update after this will focus on continued maintenance and bug fixing.</p>
<p>"<em>We've told our stories the way we needed to tell them, and tried our best to make them impactful and engaging, and we're continuing to get better at handling our own chaos so that we can continue to create more chaos in the future,</em>" the studio wrote in a <a href="https://baldursgate3.game/news/the-final-patch-new-subclasses-photo-mode-and-cross-play_138">blog post</a> on its website.</p>
<p><iframe title="Baldur’s Gate 3: The Final Patch - An Animated Short" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CwCyTt8fSAU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>"<em>From patching in a way to change your appearance with the Magic Mirror, introducing Honour Mode for those of you looking for a hard time, and giving you new ways to make out with your romanced companion, to new cinematics for your most evil runs, and handing you the tools to create your own supported mods, Patch 8 now rounds off with cross-play, Photo Mode, and 12 new subclasses for you to enjoy.</em>"</p>
<p>Beyond the new <a href="https://wccftech.com/baldurs-gate-3-to-get-cross-play-12-new-subclasses-and-photo-mode-next-year/">subclasses</a>, cross-play functionality is one of the more significant features added in Patch 8, and it'll even work with most mods you might want to use. There are a few hang-ups, though, like the fact that all players will have to have the same version of the mods installed, and PC players squadding up with console players will need to be aware that only mods compatible with consoles will work when trying to use cross-play across PC and console devices.</p>
<p>If you're having trouble, Larian put together a handy <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qX4ffv7xLsI">video guide</a> to take you through the process. Larian even put together a video guide to help you learn the ropes with the newly included <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2RrZaWrZG-8">Photo Mode</a> to apply your photography skills to the world of Baldur's Gate 3.</p>
<p>You can find the full patch notes here to dig into every adjustment and change in Patch 8.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>