<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 12:33:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Shadows Has Passed One Million Players On Launch Day]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-shadows-one-million-players/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-shadows-has-passed-one-million-players-on-launch-day.1141119/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-shadows-one-million-players/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Assassin's Creed Shadows reached an important player number milestone on its first day of availability, Ubisoft confirmed.</p>
<p>A few hours after the latest entry in their series launched on PC and consoles, the publisher confirmed the game had passed 1 million players. While it's not clear how many have accessed the game via a Ubisoft + subscription, this is definitely an excellent result which bodes well for the upcoming weekend, when the number will likely get higher.</p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">It's not even 4PM here in Canada and Assassin's Creed Shadows has already passed 1 million players!</p>
<p>Thank YOU from the bottom of our hearts for joining this adventure in Feudal Japan. We are beyond excited to start this journey with you! 💝 <a href="https://t.co/1cqwABrQfN">pic.twitter.com/1cqwABrQfN</a></p>
<p>— Assassin's Creed (@assassinscreed) <a href="https://twitter.com/assassinscreed/status/1902802072640295067?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 20, 2025</a></p></blockquote>

<p>While not exactly attempting to push the boundaries of the open-world RPG formula established by Origins, Assassin's Creed Shadows is a more than worthy new entry in the series. Despite its often inaccurate recreation of Feudal Japan, it attempts to bring back stealth gameplay into the spotlight while not doing away completely with the combat-focused approach seen in Valhalla, making for a surprisingly varied experience. You can learn more about it in my <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/assassins-creed-shadows-a-gorgeous-dive-into-feudal-chaos/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">review</a>.</p>
<p><em>Assassin's Creed Shadows is one of the finest entries in the series, successfully bringing back stealth-oriented gameplay while retaining the RPG mechanics and refined combat mechanics seen in previous entries in the series, seamlessly integrating them with the dual protagonist setup and a well-paced story that doesn't overstay its welcome. While the game still features way more content and gameplay systems than necessary, its rendition of Feudal Japan is among the best ever seen in a video game, and it is well worth experiencing for the vast majority of players.</em></p>
<p>Assassin's Creed Shadows is now available on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X, and Xbox Series S worldwide.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game of Thrones: Kingsroad Enters Early Access on March 26]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/game-of-thrones-kingsroad-enters-early-access-on-march-26/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/game-of-thrones-kingsroad-enters-early-access-on-march-26.1141092/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/game-of-thrones-kingsroad-enters-early-access-on-march-26/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Yesterday, Netmarble Neo announced that the action/adventure RPG Game of Thrones: Kingsroad will debut on Steam Early Access in just a few days, on Wednesday, March 26. This follows the demo that <a href="https://wccftech.com/game-of-thrones-kingsroad-pc-demo-out-now-on-steam-full-release-in-q2-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">went live last month</a> as part of Steam Next Fest. Clearly, the developers received positive feedback and are ready to move on with the next step.</p>
<p>The game is planned to be in early access for at least four weeks, which would be an unusually brief timeframe. The <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3183280/Game_of_Thrones_Kingsroad/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">store page</a> provides several details on how the early access version will differ from the full release:</p>
<p><em>Much of Westeros will be available to explore during the Early Access phase. Players will be able to visit the major cities such as Winterfell, King's Landing and Highgarden and visit the surrounding areas. The Early Access version contains 50 chapters of the main storyline, hundreds of side missions and open world encounters, multiple co-op dungeons, and endgame PVE challenges. During Early Access, players will begin their journey in the northern regions of Westeros, exploring iconic locations such as Castle Black, Winterfell, and areas beyond The Wall, eventually making it to The Reach.</em></p>
<p>Following the early access phase, Netmarble will expand into the Stormlands region to introduce additional areas for Game of Thrones: Kingsroad players to explore. These new areas, such as Storm's End and Felwood, will feature new open-world content, new quests, and co-op dungeons. During early access, the developers will gather feedback to further refine elements such as game balance, graphics, UX/UI, and more.</p>
<p><iframe title="[Game of Thrones: Kingsroad] Steam Early Access Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hC-eVMvcRBQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>While the full game will be free to play, to play Game of Thrones: Kingsroad during the early access phase, players will have to purchase one of the Founder's Packs. The Standard Pack is priced at $24.99 and includes a Northern Outfit, the Emoji Pack - Jon Snow, and 350 Iron Bank Marks of currency. The Deluxe Pack is priced at $49.99 and includes the aforementioned in-game items plus the Battle Pass Premium, Wandering Crow Outfit, Darkcloud Mount, Nameplate Background: Ghost, Nameplate Frame: Harbinger, 750 Iron Bank Marks, and 50K Copper.</p>
<p><iframe title="[Game of Thrones: Kingsroad] Founder's Pack" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fgbRj-GotBo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The Ultimate Pack is the most expensive at $89.99, adding access to the Battle Pass Premium+, White Fang Mount, Brotherhood Without Banners Reins and Saddle (Horse) and Brotherhood Without Banners Saddle (Direwolf), Nameplate Background: Iron Throne, Nameplate Frame: Conqueror, 2K Iron Bank Marks and 200K Copper.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cronos: The New Dawn Gets Deep Dive from Bloober Team]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/cronos-the-new-dawn-gets-deep-dive-from-bloober-team/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cronos-the-new-dawn-gets-deep-dive-from-bloober-team.1141062/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/cronos-the-new-dawn-gets-deep-dive-from-bloober-team/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Bloober Team <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RuSJpd2c7UY" target="_blank" rel="noopener">aired</a> the first episode of the Cronos: The New Dawn developer diary series during the Future Games Show: Spring Showcase 2025. This episode saw the game's two directors revealing a few details, such as the inspiration, which came from Carpenter's The Thing but also Netflix's TV series Dark, as well as Dead Space, movies like 12 Monkeys, and surprisingly even the Dark Souls series of games was cited as Bloober reportedly seeks to push this game into a slightly more challenging direction.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://wccftech.com/cronos-the-new-dawn-is-bloober-teams-next-survival-horror-game/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cronos: The New Dawn</a>, you play as one of the Travelers. They are being sent to the ruins of human civilization to search for the time rifts and jump back in time to extract people who didn't survive the apocalypse. Travelers are the only ones who can travel to the past and survive the inevitable encounters with monsters. The suit's design looks like a diver because Travelers are not typical soldiers, but more like divers in time.</p>
<p>The setting is an alternative history when the world ends in the 1980s with an apocalyptic event that the team called The Change. Interestingly, the monsters are called the Orphans because they are what was left by humanity. They can take different forms, so players will face different enemies with different abilities. The important ingredient, Bloober Team said, is body horror, perhaps a little bit as an homage to The Thing. So, they are only created from human flesh.</p>
<p>At the end of the deep dive, the directors also replied to a few rapid-fire community questions:</p>
<ul>
<li>There will be ladders</li>
<li>There will be locations with huge walls of flash</li>
<li>There may be aliens</li>
<li>Yes, you can punch monsters in the face (if they have a face)</li>
<li>Fire is important in the game</li>
<li>Dismemberment is featured in Cronos: The New Dawn, but it doesn't work like in Dead Space, as the team implemented their own take on combat</li>
</ul>
<p><iframe title="Cronos: The New Dawn | Deep Dive Into The World - Bloober Team Dev Diaries" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RuSJpd2c7UY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Following the highly acclaimed launch of the <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/silent-hill-2-restless-dreams-town/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Silent Hill 2 remake</a>, Bloober Team's next project is undoubtedly much anticipated among horror fans. The game is scheduled to launch later this year on PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series S|X.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mount & Blade II: Bannerlord to Get War Sails Nautical Expansion This June]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/mount-blade-ii-bannerlord-to-get-war-sails-nautical-expansion-this-june/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mount-blade-ii-bannerlord-to-get-war-sails-nautical-expansion-this-june.1141047/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/mount-blade-ii-bannerlord-to-get-war-sails-nautical-expansion-this-june/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>During the Future Games Show: Spring Showcase 2025, TaleWorlds Entertainment announced that a new nautical expansion will launch this June for Mount &amp; Blade II: Bannerlord.</p>
<p>Called <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2927200/Mount__Blade_II_Bannerlord__War_Sails/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">War Sails</a>, it will introduce naval warfare for the first time, as well as a Viking-inspired faction and new explorable coastal regions. Players will be able to command fleets, engage in naval battles, board enemy ships, and enforce blockades, reshaping warfare on land and sea. According to TaleWorlds, the ability to explore by sea, conduct naval blockades, and engage in ship-based combat will influence battle strategies throughout Calradia, not just in the new territories. Beware, though: storms and attrition can undo even the best-laid plans.</p>
<p>Mount &amp; Blade II: Bannerlord Players will have to master wind and water physics, board or ram ships, and cripple enemies by smashing oars, sinking hulls, or tearing sails. There are 18 ships available, each with unique handling characteristics shaped by wind and waves. They can be upgraded with siege engines, sails, and rams. Throughout the gameplay, players will get to acquire new ships, upgrade ports or win ships and figureheads.</p>
<p>The Nords call the new Northern Kingdom home. In true Mount &amp; Blade II: Bannerlord style, players will be able to trade, recruit, or fight in this land of craggy peaks and icy fjords. The War Sails expansion also adds a northern sea, islands, rivers and open waters. Of course, players will also find new companions, Norse banners, hairstyles, tattoos, armor, unique weapons, new spears, swords, and axes.</p>
<p><iframe title="Mount &amp; Blade II: Bannerlord - War Sails - Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IA0YoFBX60M?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The release of the War Sails expansion, scheduled for June 17, will also be accompanied by the release of the free patch v1.3. The developers are also planning further updates to introduce new gameplay mechanics, including stealth and disguise systems for dungeons and hideouts, random events that will tie into the character trait system, a Parley feature, numerous combat improvements, new weapon types, and additional exciting improvements for players and modders alike.</p>
<p>In closing, TaleWorlds announced that Mount &amp; Blade II: Bannerlord has sold over five million units across all platforms since<a href="https://wccftech.com/mount-blade-ii-bannerlord-confirmed-to-launch-on-october-25th/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> its launch</a> a few years back.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>