<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:22:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New GeForce Hotfix Driver Resolves Lower Performance Bug Caused by Windows Update]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/new-geforce-hotfix-driver-resolves-lower-performance-bug-windows-update/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-geforce-hotfix-driver-resolves-lower-performance-bug-caused-by-windows-update.1358989/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>NVIDIA has <a href="https://nvidia.custhelp.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/5750" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">released</a> a new GeForce Hotfix display driver, version 581.94. This is based on the latest GeForce Game Ready driver, version 581.80, which <a href="https://wccftech.com/nvidia-launches-game-ready-driver-black-ops-7-ffvii-rebirth-adds-frame-generation/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">launched around two weeks ago</a> with day-one optimizations for Call of Duty: Black Ops 7, Europa Universalis V, and Anno 117: Pax Romana.</p>



<p>Following that Game Ready driver, users reported lower performance in some PC games after updating to Windows 11 October 2025 KB5066835 [5561605]. This GeForce hotfix driver resolves the issue, so if you've experienced that, you should download it right away. Otherwise, the fix will be rolled into the next Game Ready driver, anyway.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/new-geforce-hotfix-driver-resolves-lower-performance-bug-windows-update/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Krafton Strikes Back at Unknown Worlds Founder, Sharing Files with Racist Views on Korea]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/krafton-strikes-back-unknown-worlds-founders-sharing-files-racist-views-korea/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/krafton-strikes-back-at-unknown-worlds-founder-sharing-files-with-racist-views-on-korea.1358971/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>The fight between Krafton, the Korean company behind games like TERA, PUBG, and inZOI, and the founders of Unknown Worlds Entertainment (developers of Subnautica) continues even outside of court.</p>



<p>This morning, Krafton shared two files with the press. One of them is the sworn testimony of Unknown Worlds founder Chris Cleveland in the Delaware court, and the other is a document written by Cleveland as 'litigation help' while he prepared for the legal battle. Cleveland himself submitted the document into evidence, and now Krafton has underlined that several of his comments demonstrated racist views toward Korea and its people, as well as the unwavering conviction that the Korean developer would ultimately be seen as the 'villain' of this story. Here are a few excerpts:</p>



<p><em>Korea - they are the Joe Pesci of countries. Charming until they're incredible nasty. It goes to 11 quickly. No filter.</em></p>



<p><em>It can be emotionally draining dealing with this, especially as male westerners. [<span>Korean, seems to be implied</span>] Males might be more problem-solvers and bring less emotion - they're biological reasons for this. Making games is about problem solving.</em></p>



<p><em>Korea has been surrounded by enemies who want to kill them. They are fighters. It's small and nasty. Every year some big film star commits suicide because of sex, drugs, or something, hounded by press.</em></p>



<p><em>Delaware will say this is a bunch of sadistic Korean assholes (like Samsung - John Pleasance). They've cast as out as villains and it's done.</em></p>



<p><em>Delaware? Oh, they're fucked. You don't even need a Korean lawyer. History will remember that Krafton was bad. Even the Reddit crowd hates them because of Dark and Darker.</em></p>



<p><em>We’re playing the house’s money and we’re the home team. We don’t need to worry about these guys or our reputation. History will remember that Krafton was bad.</em></p>



<p>In the testimony, Cleveland admitted to saying last year that Unknown Worlds was no longer a place he really wanted to work at, and also that he was 'semi-retired' and only working on the Subnautica movie in some capacity. For their part, Krafton noted that he is now instead looking at being reinstated, and Cleveland replied that he is 'fired up now'.</p>



<p>It all started on July 2, when Krafton <a href="https://wccftech.com/subnautica-developer-unknown-worlds-changes-leadership-krafton/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">removed the original Unknown Worlds studio leadership</a> (Charlie Cleveland, Ted Gill, and Max McGuire). The fired founders <a href="https://wccftech.com/krafton-delayed-subnautica-2-2026-reportedly-to-avoid-250-million-bonus-pay/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">claimed the company purposely delayed Subnautica 2 to avoid paying them a $250 million bonus</a>, but the South Korean developer eventually <a href="https://wccftech.com/krafton-blames-founders-subnautica-2-delay/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">replied</a> that it was them who wanted to rush an unfinished version of the game out to get the payment, after neglecting their duties.</p>



<p>Since then, accusations have flown left and right. Just two days ago, it came to light that Krafton CEO Changham Kim <a href="https://wccftech.com/krafton-ceo-allegedly-asked-chatgpt-how-to-avoid-paying-subnautica-devs-bonus/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">had asked ChatGPT</a> if there was some way to avoid paying the three their big bonus. This came just days after the South Korean developer announced its shift toward being an 'AI-first company'.</p>



<p>Today's is likely to be one of many chapters in this controversial story. Stay tuned as we continue to cover it. For the record, Krafton did share a tidbit today about Subnautica 2's ongoing development:</p>



<p><em>We have made incredible progress in the past few months, and we are excited to share with all the Subnautica fans.</em></p>





			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/krafton-strikes-back-unknown-worlds-founders-sharing-files-racist-views-korea/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mafia: The Old Country Free Ride Update Adds Classic Difficulty, New Races, Combat Challenges, and More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/mafia-the-old-country-free-ride-update-adds-classic-difficulty-new-races/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mafia-the-old-country-free-ride-update-adds-classic-difficulty-new-races-combat-challenges-and-more.1358920/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Mafia: The Old Country receives its biggest update since launch today. The 'Free Ride' update introduces many new features and content, including Classic difficulty (which requires careful management of both health and ammunition), new horse and car races, new replayable combat challenges, an optional first-person driving perspective, and a Photo Mode. </p>



<p>Those who'd like to enhance the cinematic flair of their experience in Mafia: The Old Country can now activate Cinema Siciliano, which transforms the game's look into a black-and-white masterpiece inspired by vintage Italian films. Lastly, the Free Ride update also introduces new vehicles, guns, knives, outfits, and charms for players to acquire.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Mafia: The Old Country - Free Ride Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cHnpuVKyCAc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Mafia: The Old Country launched in early August to solid reviews from critics. <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/mafia-the-old-country-a-fine-sicilian-mafia-story/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">In my review</a>, I rated it 8 out of 10 and called it a fine Sicilian Mafia story:</p>



<p><em>Mafia: The Old Country aims squarely at being a narrative experience, and largely succeeds in that while also providing solid gameplay. It is a bit of a shame that we don't get to explore Sicily in this game, but if you're into Mafia narratives, this is among the best you can find in games, and the price isn't so high to boot.</em></p>



<p>Publisher 2K later boasted of <a href="https://wccftech.com/mafia-the-old-country-sold-over-800k-copies-in-first-week/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the game's sales</a>, revealing that it has been outperforming expectations. A couple of months ago, one of the main actresses from the game, Carina Conti, let slip that she heard the publisher <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-mafia-game-greenlit-mafia-the-old-country-actress/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">may have already greenlighted a new game</a>. This remains unconfirmed for the time being, but the parent company has hinted that the new approach of a shorter, more linear cinematic game has been successful, thus suggesting that developer Hangar 13 will continue down this path in the future. </p>



<p>Of course, we'll keep you updated should there be any new leaks or rumors of a sequel.</p>





			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/mafia-the-old-country-free-ride-update-adds-classic-difficulty-new-races/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>