<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 15:45:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RoboCop: Rogue City – Unfinished Business, Humanity, DREADZONE, And More Added To GeForce NOW]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/robocop-rogue-city-humanity-geforce-now/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/robocop-rogue-city-%E2%80%93-unfinished-business-humanity-dreadzone-and-more-added-to-geforce-now.1246239/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The latest batch of games being added to the GeForce NOW streaming service has been <a href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/geforce-now-thursday-robocop-rogue-city-unfinished-business/">announced</a>, with nine additions including both the base game and the brand-new DLC for RoboCop: Rogue City. </p>



<p>GeForce NOW users will also be able to check out the<a href="https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-patch-2-3-amd-fsr-4-frame-generation/"> latest update for Cyberpunk 2077</a> on the streaming service, which was officially pushed to all platforms today, and includes several key updates like support for AMD FSR 4. FSR 3.1 Frame Generation, new content, VRR support on consoles and more. </p>


<figure>
<div>

<figure>
<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>
</figure>
<div>
			    		
			    		
				    	<p><span>2 of 9</span>
			    	</p></div>
</div>
</figure>



<p>There's also a new update for Zenless Zone Zero that just went live, which players will also be able to check out on GeForce NOW. And out of the nine new game additions to GeForce NOW, four of them are brand new games that have all launched this week. </p>



<p>Here's the full list of new titles to check out on GeForce NOW as of today, July 17, 2025:</p>



<ul>
<li>Stronghold Crusader: Definitive Edition</li>



<li>The Drifter</li>



<li>He Is Coming</li>



<li>DREADZONE</li>



<li>RoboCop: Rogue City</li>



<li>RoboCop: Rogue City - Unfinished Business</li>



<li>Battle Brothers</li>



<li>BitCraft Online</li>



<li>Humanity</li>



<li>SteamWorld Dig</li>
</ul>



<p>Last week, GeForce NOW added the hit new co-op game <a href="https://wccftech.com/geforce-now-adds-hit-co-op-game-peak/">PEAK</a>, and prior to that, <a href="https://wccftech.com/system-shock-2-25th-anniversary-remaster-launches-onto-geforce-now-new-elder-scrolls-online-rewards-we-happy-few-and-more-added-to-gfn/">System Shock 2: 25th Anniversary Remaster</a> launched into the service.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/robocop-rogue-city-humanity-geforce-now/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Live Action TV Series Officially Greenlit By Netflix]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-live-action-tv-series-officially-greenlit-by-netflix/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-live-action-tv-series-officially-greenlit-by-netflix.1246236/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>An Assassin's Creed live-action TV series has been officially greenlit by Netflix, Ubisoft <a href="https://news.ubisoft.com/en-us/article/4tiTYS8oDJ3ygEoJHIyrdQ/netflix-greenlights-assassins-creed-liveaction-series">confirmed</a> today.</p>



<p>The show, which will follow characters across pivotal historical events as they get involved in the sceret war between two faction, one determined to shape humanity's future through control, the other fighting to preserve free will, essentially running with the same premise of the video game series focused on the long way between the Assassins and the Templars, is the first series to be developed under the agreement signed back in 2020 between Ubisoft and Netflix to produce content based on the popular series. Emmy nominees Roberto Patino (DMZ, Westworld, Sons of Anarchy) and David Wiener (Halo, Homecoming, The Killing) are set as creators, showrunners, and executive producers of the newly announced show.</p>



<p><em>"We've been fans of Assassin's Creed since its release in 2007. Every day we work on this show, we come away excited and humbled by the possibilities that Assassin's Creed opens to us,"</em> said David Wiener and Rober Patino in a statement. <em>"Beneath the scope, the spectacle, the parkour and the thrills is a baseline for the most essential kind of human story - about people searching for purpose, struggling with questions of identity and destiny and faith. It is about power and violence and sex and greed and vengeance. But more than anything, this is a show about the value of human connection, across cultures, across time. And it's about what we stand to lose as a species, when those connections break. We've got an amazing team behind us with the folks at Ubisoft and our champions at Netflix, and we're committed to creating something undeniable for fans all over the planet."</em></p>



<p>The latest entry in the Ubisoft series is Assassin's Creed Shadows. You can learn more about the solid open-world game set in Feudal Japan released earlier this year on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X and Xbox Series S by checking out my <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/assassins-creed-shadows-a-gorgeous-dive-into-feudal-chaos/">review.</a></p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-live-action-tv-series-officially-greenlit-by-netflix/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Is Reportedly Trying “Hail Mary” Tactics To Make Its Lawsuit Against Palworld Makers Stick]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-reportedly-doing-everything-to-make-lawsuit-against-palworld-stick/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-is-reportedly-trying-%E2%80%9Chail-mary%E2%80%9D-tactics-to-make-its-lawsuit-against-palworld-makers-stick.1246233/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>When Nintendo <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-is-officially-suing-pocketpair-creators-of-palworld/">confirmed it would be suing Pocketpair</a>, the studio behind last year's massive hit Palworld, many saw this as an inevitable outcome considering how litigious Nintendo is on a good day.</p>



<p>While the suit is still ongoing, and Pocketpair has already been forced to <a href="https://wccftech.com/palworld-developer-outlines-game-changes-caused-by-the-nintendo-lawsuit/">make changes to Palworld</a> based on the patents Nintendo is claiming Pocketpair is infringing on, a new report from <a href="https://gamesfray.com/nintendo-resorts-to-weird-patent-claims-as-its-litigation-against-palworld-maker-pocketpair-is-struggling/">Gamefrays</a> (spotted by <a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/gaming/nintendo-is-taking-desperate-measures-in-patent-infringement-case-against-palworld-and-its-looking-a-little-weird">Windows Central</a>) seems to show that Nintendo is doing everything and anything to make its suit against Pocketpair stick, even going so far as to change the patents it claims Pocketpair is infringing on, mid-suit. </p>



<p>Gamefrays does stipulate that changing a patent in the middle of an infringement suit isn't entirely unheard of, though it's usually done when the patent owner is concerned that its original patent will be found to have been invalid in the first place. It also doesn't necessarily mean that Nintendo is on the back foot or that it'll lose the case. Though, Gamefrays does point out that Nintendo's new language for the patent is awkward at best, which makes the change all the more weird.</p>



<p>Gamefrays calls out Nintendo's use of the phrases "<em>even when</em>" and "<em>even if</em>," neither of which is common when writing patents, nor are they clear to define in patent law. According to its report, Gamefrays calls the use of the word "<em>even</em>" and Nintendo's changes to the patents a "<em>Hail Mary</em>" move to try and secure a win for its suit in Japan. </p>



<p>Another unfortunate update on the lawsuit for Nintendo, is that it doesn't seem like it'll be able to bring a suit against Pocketpair in the US. The changes Pocketpair has already made, and the evidence Pocketpair is presenting around games with similar mechanics to Palworld that Nintendo has not gone after, all seem to be the immovable objects blocking Nintendo's path to suing Pocketpair in the US. Not that it won't keep trying, of course. </p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-reportedly-doing-everything-to-make-lawsuit-against-palworld-stick/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oblivion Remastered Developer Virtuos Confirms Mass Layoffs, Nearly 280 Staff Impacted Across Europe And Asia]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/oblivion-remastered-developer-virtuos-confirms-mass-layoffs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/oblivion-remastered-developer-virtuos-confirms-mass-layoffs-nearly-280-staff-impacted-across-europe-and-asia.1246158/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Virtuos, the co-development team that is working with Konami to deliver Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater, and the studio that just helped Bethesda develop The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered has <a href="https://www.virtuosgames.com/news/adapting-for-the-future-of-game-development/">confirmed</a> what was previously rumored, that the studio has suffered mass layoffs, with nearly 280 staff impacted, or 7% of the company.</p>



<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/oblivion-remastered-metal-gear-solid-delta-virtuos-mass-layoffs-rumor/">Yesterday</a>, French journalist Gauthier Andres was the first to report the layoffs, along with claims from sources they spoke to about internal troubles at Virtous. Today, Virtuos confirmed the cuts, which, according to Virtuos, are slightly under the 300 number that Andres first reported. Virtuos did not comment on any alleged internal issues, and in its statement claimed that its "<em>immediate focus is on managing this transition with care, transparency, and respect</em>."</p>



<p>"<em>Virtuos is evolving to meet the changing needs of our partners and the industry</em>," its statement began. "<em>As game development grows increasingly complex, we are realigning our global footprint and capabilities to strengthen our offering in high-value co-development, ranging from full game engineering to advanced art, including creative content production and live services</em>."</p>



<p>"<em>This evolution involves a rebalancing of roles across our studios and geographies. Approximately 7% of Virtuos' global workforce was affected, primarily in teams facing lower occupancy and slower demand due to structural shifts in the industry. This includes about 200 roles in Asia and 70 roles in Europe, including</em> <em>fewer than 10 in France, where the core team working on Oblivion Remastered is located</em>."</p>



<p>The statement goes on to explain why so many of the roles impacted are in its studios based in Asia, claiming the studio "<em>need[s] to better match the locations of our teams with those of our clients to support the increasingly iterative nature of creative co-development.</em>"</p>



<p>As far as the other projects Virtuos has on the go, the studio says it "<em>remains fully committed to all our partnerships, including ongoing work on announced titles such as Oblivion Remastered, Cyberpunk 2077, and Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</em>." </p>



<p> A key element of Andres' report from yesterday was how the studio's leadership is pushing to over-deliver in quality compared to the budget the studio is given. The Oblivion Remastered team was allegedly pushed to work harder despite Virtuos receiving no royalties on the game's sales, so that the studio could have Oblivion Remastered as a showpiece for the kind of work they are capable of.</p>



<p>That's the kind of strategy that can potentially lead to more contracts, but the only sure result a strategy like that can have is burning out the talent you're trying to show the studio has. </p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/oblivion-remastered-developer-virtuos-confirms-mass-layoffs/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>