<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 02:58:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Steam 2025 GOTY Award Goes to Hollow Knight: Silksong, Beating Clair Obscur: Expedition 33]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-steam-2025-goty-award-goes-to-hollow-knight-silksong-beating-clair-obscur-expedition-33/</link>
            <guid>1396564</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p><strong>Valve</strong> has just <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/steamawards/2025" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced</a> the winners of the <strong>2025 Steam Awards</strong>, and the biggest surprise is finding out that the <strong>Game of the Year</strong> prize went to <strong>Hollow Knight: Silksong</strong> instead of the massive favorite <strong>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</strong>. According to <a href="https://wccftech.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-has-third-most-goty-wins-in-single-year/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a report from earlier this week</a>, Sandfall Interactive's beloved turn-based JRPG has already <strong>dethroned Baldur's Gate III as the third game with the most GOTY awards</strong>, trailing only <strong>Elden Ring</strong> and <strong>The Last of Us Part II</strong>.</p>



<p>Even so, Steam users have chosen their preferred game released last year, and they have gone with <strong>Team Cherry</strong>'s long-awaited Metroidvania sequel. Valve does not disclose percentages or anything like that, so we'll never know the exact margins, but a win is a win. </p>



<p>Hollow Knight: Silksong also wins the '<strong>Best Game You Suck At</strong>' award, which is a category that includes the most challenging titles. The other finalists, for the record, were Path of Exile II, Elden Ring Nightreign, Marvel Rivals, and Where Winds Meet.</p>



<p>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 does still win a prize for the best soundtrack, though. The other winners are:</p>



<ul>
<li>The Midnight Walk - VR Game of the Year Award</li>



<li>Baldur's Gate III - Labor of Love Award (for a game supported well long past its launch date)</li>



<li>Hades II - Best Game on Steam Deck Award</li>



<li>Peak - Better With Friends Award</li>



<li>Silent Hill f - Outstanding Visual Style Award</li>



<li>ARC Raiders - Most Innovative Gameplay Award</li>



<li>Dispatch - Outstanding Story Rich Award</li>



<li>RV There Yet? - Sit Back and Relax Award </li>
</ul>



<p>In <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-games-of-2025-year-of-the-indie-ish/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our shortlist of the best ten games released in 2025</a>, I called it <strong>the year of the indie-ish</strong>, and that's very much shown in the 2025 Steam Awards. Which game did you vote for, anyway? Let us know in the comments section!</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/the-steam-2025-goty-award-goes-to-hollow-knight-silksong-beating-clair-obscur-expedition-33/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>