<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 16:50:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Painkiller Remake Officially Set for October 9 Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/painkiller-remake-officially-set-for-october-9-launch/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/painkiller-remake-officially-set-for-october-9-launch.1227072/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Saber Interactive and Anshar Studios have announced the release date for the <a href="https://wccftech.com/painkiller-returns-in-fall-2025-reimagined-with-co-op-support/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Painkiller remake.</a> This 'modern reimagining' of the classic 2004 first-person shooter game from People Can Fly will be available on October 9 for PC via Steam, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series S|X.</p>
<p>Pre-orders are open now on all storefronts. The Standard Edition of Painkiller can be purchased digitally for $39.99. It includes the “Iron Crusade” skin pack, which features skins for all four playable characters — Ink, Void, Sol, and Roch — as well as skins for six weapons: the Electrodriver, Stakegun, Shotgun, SMG, Hand Cannon, and Rocket Launcher. Pre-orders of the Standard Edition on consoles will come with the “Burnished Pride” retail-exclusive weapons pack, which includes additional gold skins for the aforementioned six weapons. The Deluxe Edition of Painkiller is priced at $49.99. It comes with the “Iron Crusade” pre-order bonus skin pack and three additional post-launch DLCs, each including six weapon skins and four character skins.</p>
<p><iframe title="Painkiller - Pre-order Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-a4ywaWme2M?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Just like in the original Painkiller, the player character is sentenced to Purgatory for crimes against Heaven. However, the Voice of the Creator gives them one last chance at redemption: blasting through hordes of demons in brutal, fast-paced combat using an array of infernal weapons. Players will fight their way through gruesome, gothic environments to stop Azazel, the fallen angel, from invading Earth, and earn salvation – either alone or with up to two other players in online co-op mode, which is a change from the original, a single player-only experience.</p>
<p>There will be lots of traversal options, such as jump, grappling hook, and dash, for players as they traverse the vast landscapes. They'll face grotesque terrors that range from hordes of demons to titanic terrors such as the monstrous offspring of Azazel, the Nephilim. Character progression sees tarot cards used to upgrade the player character's abilities. Each playable character has unique perks to boost energy, health, power, and damage.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/painkiller-remake-officially-set-for-october-9-launch/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Neverness to Everness Looks to Deliver the Anime GTA Fantasy You Never Knew You Wanted in New Footage]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/neverness-to-everness-anime-gta/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/neverness-to-everness-looks-to-deliver-the-anime-gta-fantasy-you-never-knew-you-wanted-in-new-footage.1226967/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Neverness to Everness, the open-world gacha RPG in development by Hotta Studio, looks to deliver the anime GTA fantasy that no one knew they wanted, judging from some recent footage.</p>
<p>The new footage was shared as part of a new Containment Test Preview livestream that provided a new look at some of the game's features and mechanics, such as the urban open-world, characters, traversal, and more. As if the urban setting wasn't enough to label the game as a sort of anime GTA, the developer shared during the livestream footage of one of the main playable characters stealing a car and becoming wanted by the police. While the disconnect between the character design and committing crimes is enormous, it's undeniable that there's something charming in seeing an anime GTA experience. Hopefully, the game will be as fun to play as it looks in this early footage.</p>
<p><iframe title="NTE Containment Test Preview Special Live Stream 📺" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rP3Qp7DbHMc?start=1431&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Neverness to Everness was <a href="https://wccftech.com/neverness-to-everness-is-a-new-gacha-open-world-rpg-from-tower-of-fantasy-devs-powered-by-ue5-with-nvidia-dlss-rtx/">announced</a> almost one year ago by Hotta Studio, a Perfect World subsidiary that released Tower of Fantasy, another gacha RPG, a couple of years back, which failed to make a significant splash in the genre dominated by HoYoverse's games like Genshin Impact. Powered by Unreal Engine 5, the game will feature cel-shaded graphics like most games featuring Japanese anime aesthetics and will support advanced PC features like NVIDIA DLSS and ray tracing. More information on the game and any upcoming playtests can be found on its <a href="https://nte.perfectworld.com/concept0718/en/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">official website.</a></p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/neverness-to-everness-anime-gta/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>