<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 11:58:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Appears to Be Preparing to Port More PlayStation Exclusives to Xbox and Nintendo Consoles]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/sony-appears-preparing-port-more-playstation-exclusives/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-appears-to-be-preparing-to-port-more-playstation-exclusives-to-xbox-and-nintendo-consoles.1254018/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>It's been a while since Sony decided to bring practically all of its PlayStation exclusive games to PC, albeit after some time. The 'multiplatform' strategy has done wonders for its bottom line, and Hiroki Totoki, now CEO of Sony Group Corporation, openly <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-wants-to-improve-operating-profit-with-a-more-aggressive-pc-first-party-games-release-plan/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">spoke</a> about aggressively pursuing that plan to improve the company's operating profit even further.</p>



<p>Going full-fledged multiplatform like Microsoft did for its Xbox division seemed practically taboo, though. Sure, there was the oddity of MLB The Show, which <a href="https://wccftech.com/mlb-the-show-21-xbox-game-pass-day-1/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">added an Xbox version starting in 2021</a>. However, that was more due to the license holder's will than Sony's. </p>



<p>More interesting was the recent decision to <a href="https://wccftech.com/helldivers-2-coming-to-xbox-summer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">launch Helldivers 2 on Xbox Series S and X</a> in exactly one month from today. Sure, it is a live service game and therefore inherently benefits from a larger player base, and it is particularly well-suited to Xbox, being a sci-fi shooter. </p>



<p>Might this be just the proverbial tip of the iceberg? A new job listing spotted online suggests that it could indeed be the case. Sony is <a href="https://job-boards.greenhouse.io/sonyinteractiveentertainmentglobal/jobs/5587289004" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">looking</a> for a Senior Director of Multiplatform &amp; Account Management who will '<em>play a critical leadership role in shaping and executing the global commercial strategy for PlayStation Studios software titles across all digital platforms beyond PlayStation hardware, including Steam, Epic Games Store, Xbox, Nintendo, and mobile. This role is accountable for optimizing title profitability, ensuring cross-functional alignment, and leading a high-performing team focused on multiplatform expansion, mid-range commercial planning, and platform partner management</em>.'</p>



<p>It might be that Sony is finally coming to Microsoft's same realization: with budgets ever on the rise and triple-A development taking longer and longer, arbitrarily cutting potential revenue sources just doesn't make as much sense as it has throughout the gaming industry's history.</p>



<p>I, for one, would very much welcome a fully multiplatform future. Ideally, Nintendo would join too at some point, although that might not be for a while - after all, they are known for doing their own thing.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/sony-appears-preparing-port-more-playstation-exclusives/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alien: Rogue Incursion – Part One: Evolved Edition Gameplay Revealed Ahead of September Release]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/alien-rogue-incursion-evolved-edition-gameplay-release-date-ps5-pc/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/alien-rogue-incursion-%E2%80%93-part-one-evolved-edition-gameplay-revealed-ahead-of-september-release.1253946/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><strong>Update 25/07/2025:</strong> A spokesperson for Survios has confirmed to Wccftech that those who already own Alien: Rogue Incursion - Part One as a VR game <strong>will have to buy the Evolved Edition separately</strong> if they want to play the new flat-screen version. </p>



<p>"<em>Currently those who own Alien: Rogue Incursion will have to repurchase the Evolved Edition</em>," we were told in an email. </p>



<p>It's possible, of course, that this changes from now to the September release date. But it's unfortunate to know that for now, players who have already paid for the game, who might've also wanted to try it out as a flat-screen title, can't do that without buying the whole game again. Hopefully, for those players, Survios changes its mind and makes it available as a free update for current owners. Or at least an upgrade path is introduced, with a reduced fee to get the new version as well.</p>



<p><strong>Original Story:</strong></p>



<p>Alien: Rogue Incursion - Part One first launched last year on PS5 and PC as a VR game for PS VR2 and PC VR before heading to Meta Quest 3 earlier this year. In <a href="https://wccftech.com/alien-rogue-incursion-part-one-evolved-edition-announced-no-vr-headset-needed/">May</a>, developer Survios announced that a new version of the game, which makes it playable as a flat-screen title called Alien: Rogue Incursion - Part One: Evolved Edition, and today, during San Diego Comic-Con, the studio revealed the first look at gameplay for the new version arriving on September 30, 2025.</p>



<p>The trailer shows a few quick shots of how the new version essentially boils down the VR shooter to a more run-of-the-mill horror shooter.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Alien: Rogue Incursion Evolved Edition | PS5 &amp; PC Gameplay Reveal" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LnfXZJdOkGk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Pre-orders are also live as of today, and if you don't already own the Evolved Edition, then you can grab it for $29.99 USD, with the digital deluxe edition for $39.99 USD. While we've asked Survios for clarification, it's not exactly clear if the Evolved Edition will be available to players who already own VR version of the game as a free update, or if this is an entirely new SKU and needs to be purchased separately.</p>



<p>So if you wanted to shoot Xenomorphs in a more classic shooter fashion without having to don a VR headset, then you might need to be ready to buy the game again. We'll update this story if Survios releases a clear statement on the matter.</p>



<p>And in the meantime, if you've already played the VR version, then you can rest easy knowing that Surivos is <a href="https://x.com/Survios/status/1931110743933645240">still working on Part Two</a>, though the studio has not given any indication as to when Part Two will arrive.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/alien-rogue-incursion-evolved-edition-gameplay-release-date-ps5-pc/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>