<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 21:33:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Layoffs Are Funding Increased Spending in AI Infrastructure]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/microsoft-layoffs-funding-increased-spending-ai-infrastructure/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-layoffs-are-funding-increased-spending-in-ai-infrastructure.1236462/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Microsoft has <a href="https://wccftech.com/microsoft-mass-gaming-layoffs-have-begun/">laid off</a> around 9K employees in the latest round of cuts, affecting 4% of the company's total workforce. <a href="https://www.seattletimes.com/business/microsoft/microsoft-to-lay-off-as-many-as-9000-employees-in-latest-round/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">According to The Seattle Times</a>, this is all part of the company's mandate to trim and make room for increased spending in AI infrastructure. </p>



<p>The report says it's not quite like one game developer from Halo Studios reckoned last week when they <a href="https://wccftech.com/microsoft-trying-replace-jobs-ai-agents/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a> Microsoft was doing its damnedest to replace personnel with AI agents. However, Microsoft is indeed cutting costs as much as possible to accommodate its planned expenditures of over $80 billion in this area, a $25 billion increase over the previous year. These investments are seen as more necessary than ever by Microsoft, with Open AI <a href="https://wccftech.com/sam-altman-says-gpt-5-coming-this-summer-as-openai-starts-eating-palantirs-lunch-and-grows-increasingly-territorial-with-microsoft/">showing its fangs lately in what has become a complicated partnership</a>.</p>



<p>However, the cuts are weighing heavily on the company's reputation in other areas, such as gaming. Microsoft spent dozens of billions on gaming acquisitions, such as Bethesda parent company ZeniMax Media and Activision Blizzard, to expand its Game Pass subscription service library. Still, the user base didn't grow nearly as much as hoped, and analysts are now <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-bet-wrong-horse-subscriptions-says-analyst/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">saying</a> that Xbox might have bet on the wrong horse, since subscriptions do not hold the same appeal for gamers as they do for music or TV/film fans.</p>



<p>Moreover, the industry's reaction to these latest layoffs was more scathing than ever before. Fourteen months after it <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-shuts-down-arkane-austin-tango-gameworks-and-a-couple-more-bethesda-softworks-studios/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">shut down Tango Gameworks</a>, which had released a successful and critically acclaimed game (Hi-Fi Rush), Microsoft <a href="https://wccftech.com/zenimax-online-new-mmorpg-canceled/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">cancelled</a> a promising online looter shooter from ZeniMax Online Studios, the makers of The Elder Scrolls Online, one of the gaming division's top performers. Former developers <a href="https://wccftech.com/canceled-zos-mmorpg-was-heading-in-a-great-direction-and-new-engine-had-found-its-footing-says-lead-graphics-programmer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">railed against </a>the decision, saying that the project was finally heading in a great direction, and there have been rumors that even Microsoft Gaming CEO Phil Spencer <a href="https://wccftech.com/spencer-reportedly-loved-playing-zenimax-onlines-new-game-in-march-only-to-cancel-it-in-july/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">had a blast while playing a vertical slice of Project Blackbird</a> earlier this year. </p>



<p>The only logical conclusion is that the executive did not wish to cancel the game himself, but may have received a mandate from above. Finishing Project Blackbird would have cost quite a bit, as it was just about to ramp up to production with an estimated late 2028 launch window, and Microsoft had other priorities - chiefly, bolstering its AI infrastructure. For gamers and developers alike, though, it's a shame.</p>





			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/microsoft-layoffs-funding-increased-spending-ai-infrastructure/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk: Edgerunners 2 Officially Confirmed]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-edgerunners-2-confirmed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cyberpunk-edgerunners-2-officially-confirmed.1236369/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>During the Anime Expo in Los Angeles, California, CD PROJEKT RED and studio TRIGGER <a href="https://x.com/edgerunners/status/1941255538047951061" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced</a> that Cyberpunk: Edgerunners 2 is officially in development. This is a major turnaround from the <a href="https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-edgerunners-isnt-getting-a-season-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">statement released in October 2022</a>. Edgerunners 2 will be a standalone anime series of 10 episodes set in the world of Cyberpunk 2077.</p>



<p>Hugo Award-winning writer Bartosz Sztybor, showrunner, story writer, and producer on Cyberpunk: Edgerunners 2, said in a statement:</p>



<p><em>David’s story might be over, but there’s plenty more to discover in Night City. And to again have the legendary animation studio TRIGGER along for the ride makes us at CD PROJEKT RED so excited to introduce a raw, real chronicle of redemption and revenge, something unlike what we’ve done before.</em></p>



<p>Sztybor will be joined by lead character designer Kanno Ichigo (Promare, Cyberpunk: Edgerunners) and Masahiko Otsuka (Gurren Lagann, Promare), who will be responsible for the screenplay adaptation. Cyberpunk: Edgerunners 2 will air on Netflix at an unspecified date.</p>



<p>As you might recall, Cyberpunk: Edgerunners launched in September 2022 to rave reviews. On Rotten Tomatoes, it enjoys an enviable 100% fresh rating. More importantly, it was the first real spark to <a href="https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-continues-its-edgerunners-fueled-comeback/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reignite interest</a> in CD PROJEKT RED's Cyberpunk 2077. The studio wisely timed Patch 1.6 to launch alongside the Netflix anime series, which added the Wardrobe feature, cross-progression between different platforms, three new side missions (Gigs), five new melee weapons, and six new firearms, in addition to some light Edgerunners-related content and tons of fixes. Cyberpunk 2077 player numbers spiked, and the sentiment around the game started turning around.</p>



<p>It is presently unclear whether CD PROJEKT RED will go to the trouble of making more Cyberpunk 2077 content to go with this series. It seems unlikely, though, as they are now deep into the <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-4-is-officially-in-full-scale-production-game-director-is-confident-in-a-remarkable-experience/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">production of The Witcher 4</a>.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-edgerunners-2-confirmed/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>