<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 15:20:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Todd Howard Initially Didn’t Want Troy Baker Playing Indiana Jones in The Great Circle]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/todd-howard-initially-didnt-want-troy-baker-playing-indiana-jones-in-the-great-circle/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/todd-howard-initially-didn%E2%80%99t-want-troy-baker-playing-indiana-jones-in-the-great-circle.1024227/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/todd-howard-initially-didnt-want-troy-baker-playing-indiana-jones-in-the-great-circle/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Troy Baker is one of the most prolific voice actors out there and has been in nearly everything you can think of. From voicing Joel in The Last of Us to Kanji Tatsumi in Persona 4, he has taken up a ton of roles. He's not only a voice actor in games, though, as he also appears in plenty of English dubs of anime, as well as other animated programs. When it came to choosing someone to play Indiana Jones in the upcoming Indiana Jones and the Great Circle, Todd Howard initially rejected the idea of Troy Baker being the one to do it.</p>
<p>Rolling Stone had the opportunity to have a discussion with both Howard and Baker before the launch of the Indy game on December 9. Here, they discussed how the game came to be and how Baker ended up getting involved. It was first announced that Troy Baker was going to be filling Harrison Ford's shoes in Indiana Jones and The Great Circle in January. Since then, we've slowly been learning more details about the game. "He really brings forward that charm and sense of humor in such a good way," said MachineGames Co-Founder and Game Director Jerk Gustaffson. As the person who got to <a href="https://wccftech.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-hands-on-preview-swinging-in-style/">preview the game</a>, it's safe to admit that Troy Baker did a great job of acting as Indiana Jones and managed to get his humor and wittiness down pat.</p>
<p>Todd Howard has long wanted to make an Indiana Jones game, but when he was searching for the person to fill the role, he found that Baker didn't give him the vibe he wanted. An article via <a href="https://ew.com/indiana-jones-troy-baker-the-great-circle-exclusive-8426963" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Entertainment Weekly</a> discusses the meeting between Baker and Howard.</p>
<p>"Upon being introduced for the first time through Zoom, Baker confirms Howard flat out told the actor to his face that he wasn't what they wanted." After the team at MachineGames and Howard had completed hundreds of interviews for the role, it was confirmed people chose Troy Baker every time. It's been confirmed that Troy Baker really went the extra mile to be able to fill the boots of Indiana Jones. He's a self-confessed fanatic, and trained with an authentic Indiana Jones-like whip with stunt actor Doc Duhame.</p>
<p>"I better know how to ride a motorcycle, ride a horse, crack a whip... Because if you don't believe me when I'm just standing there holding the whip, you're probably not going to believe it when you're actually the one cracking the whip," Baker said in <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming/indiana-jones-todd-howard-bethesda-troy-baker-1235146294/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an interview</a> with Rolling Stone.</p>
<p>If you're interested in the Indiana Jones game, make sure to keep an eye out for its release on December 9, 2024.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Red Dead Redemption PC Gets First Texture Mods]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/red-dead-redemption-pc-gets-first-texture-mods/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/red-dead-redemption-pc-gets-first-texture-mods.1024191/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/red-dead-redemption-pc-gets-first-texture-mods/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>It's been just two days since Rockstar Games finally <a href="https://wccftech.com/red-dead-redemption-pc-is-out-on-october-29-system-requirements-nvidia-dlss-frame-generation-confirmed/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">released</a> the official version of Red Dead Redemption PC, and modders haven't been idle. There are already plenty of useful mods, particularly for those keen to improve on the game's aged visuals.</p>
<p>Nexus Mods already hosts several texture mods for Red Dead Redemption PC. The most impressive of the current bunch might be '<a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/reddeadredemption/mods/52" target="_blank" rel="noopener">John Marston Reworked 4K Upscaled</a>', created by user modgamer767. This mod overhauls the protagonist's textures, bringing them to 4K resolution with the help of AI upscaling.</p>
<p>It's not just about character and environment textures - even particles need to be overhauled for such an old game. Luckily, a mod was <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/reddeadredemption/mods/28" target="_blank" rel="noopener">created</a> by Nexus Mods user FiK that improves at least some particles, such as smoke, sparks, and some environmental effects, thanks to 4K upscaling.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>Red Dead Redemption PC also includes the acclaimed expansion Undead Nightmare, so DerEhrwurden thought they'd <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/reddeadredemption/mods/83" target="_blank" rel="noopener">improve</a> some of those assets as well. For now, they have upscaled the undead animals from 1024x1024 to 2048x2048, but they plan to finish most of the Undead assets eventually. Last but not least, user Chainner has <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/reddeadredemption/mods/60" target="_blank" rel="noopener">performed</a> a 4X upscale of grass textures to improve their look.</p>
<p>This is merely the beginning of PC modding for Rockstar's masterpiece. For example, the maker of the comprehensive Reality Redemption Overhaul Project has already <a href="https://wccftech.com/stunning-red-dead-redemption-reality-redemption-visual-overhaul-mod-pc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">promised</a> to bring the mod to PC (it was previously available for Xbox 360 and Nintendo Switch) very soon.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, are you enjoying this version of the game? Let us know in the comments!</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age: The Veilguard Delivers Decent Image Quality And Good Performance on Consoles, Complete with Ray Tracing in Quality Mode]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/dragon-age-the-veilguard-decent-quality-performance-consoles/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-the-veilguard-delivers-decent-image-quality-and-good-performance-on-consoles-complete-with-ray-tracing-in-quality-mode.1024059/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/dragon-age-the-veilguard-decent-quality-performance-consoles/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Dragon Age: The Veilguard delivers decent image quality and great performance on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X, complete with ray tracing in Quality Mode.</p>
<p>In a new tech review posted a few hours ago, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@DigitalFoundry" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Digital Foundry</a> took a good look at the console versions of the latest entry in the series by BioWare, confirming details such as resolution, visual features, and more. On PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X, the game runs at 1080p resolution, upscaled to 4K using a custom version of AMD FSR 2.2 complete with some ray tracing features like ray-traced reflections and ambient occlusion in Quality Mode, and at 720p, upscaled to 1440p using dynamic resolution that can drop as low as 504p. Still, AMD FSR 2.2 seems to be doing a decent job, and image quality isn't massively impacted even with such low resolution, although it is definitely noticeable under scrutiny. Performance, at least, seems to be solid, consistently hitting the 60 FPS target.</p>
<p>Things don't fare as well on Xbox Series S. On the system, Dragon Age: The Veilguard runs at 648p in Quality Mode and 432p in Performance Mode, targeting 30 and 60 FPS, respectively. Despite some issues, such as a lack of motion blur in Quality Mode that prevents the 30 FPS gameplay from being smoother and lower image quality in Performance Mode, Digital Foundry found the experience serviceable on the system.</p>
<p><iframe title="Dragon Age: The Veilguard - PS5/Xbox Series X|S Tech Review - Impressive Visuals, Good Performance" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LZ6ePY7CapA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Dragon Age: The Veilguard launches today on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X, and Xbox Series S. You can learn more about the game in our <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/dragon-age-the-veilguard-biowares-back/">review.</a></p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>