<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:56:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kingmakers’ Early Access Release Has Been Delayed, No New Release Date In Sight]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/kingmakers-early-access-release-delayed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kingmakers%E2%80%99-early-access-release-has-been-delayed-no-new-release-date-in-sight.1317424/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Kingmakers, the third-person action time-travelling game that gives you a truck and an assault rifle against legions of medieval-era knights with nothing but swords and horses, was <a href="https://wccftech.com/kingmakers-the-medieval-based-third-person-action-game-that-pits-assault-rifles-against-swords-launches-in-early-access-this-october/">initially meant to release in early access on PC later this week,</a> on October 8, 2025. Now, that's no longer the case, and the game's release has been delayed with no new release date in sight.</p>



<p><a href="https://x.com/Kingmakers_Game/status/1974144040942625003">In a long statement posted to the X (formerly Twitter) account</a> for the game, developer Redemption Road Games confirmed it needs more time to polish the game, rather than "<em>cut any planned features, for the sake of getting it out the door</em> <em>earlier</em>." What will be coming soon, is a half-hour gameplay deep-dive digging into the gameplay, and updating players on what the team has been working on. </p>



<p>"<em>After much contemplation, we realize that the scheduled Kingmakers launch on October 8 will no longer be possible</em>," the studio confirmed at the top of its statement. "<em>We want to apologize to all the fans who are eagerly anticipating this game. We are sorry for letting you down</em>."</p>



<p>"<em>Why is Kingmakers being delayed? In short: it's an incredibly ambitious, uncompromising game, and we don't want to cut any planned features, for the sake of getting it out the door</em> <em>earlier.</em> <em>Our goal, from the start, has been to create something that's nothing like anything else on the market, in terms of gameplay, scale, scope, and interactivity</em>.</p>



<p><em>With Kingmakers, we set out to push the Unreal Engine 4 codebase to its absolute limits, while still providing true 60fps to midrange PCs, without the need for fake frames. We are an 80% engineering team, who got into this business to push technological barriers. We currently</em> <em>have tens of thousands of soldiers,</em> <em>each with AI and pathfinding that rivals what you'd expect from a AAA third-person shooter. When you walk away from a battle, it continues to play out. Nothing is faked. We have giant 6-story castles where every room can be entered and every wall, floor, and ceiling destroyed. When you build a Lumbermill, it's a real place that can be entered, or, in an enemy invasion, turned into a combat arena...</em></p>



<p><em>...We set out to do all of this, with full drop-in/drop-out 4 player multiplayer support, and we have. We just need a bit more time on content polish before we feel good about charging money for it</em>."</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Kingmakers is one of the few indie games that, when it first gets announced, <a href="https://x.com/Kingmakers_Game/status/1759943842466582568">has a viral moment and is suddenly in front of millions of eyes</a>. It has <a href="https://x.com/Kingmakers_Game/status/1868768562388910113">over a million wishlists on Steam</a> thanks to that first burst of virality, but hype fades as easily as it builds.</p>



<p>Whenever Kingmakers does release, we'll see if it is any deeper than the viral mix of driving a truck through hundreds of knights that can't do anything about it. Perhaps the coming gameplay deep-dive will begin to do away with those concerns, and of course, with it being an early access title, there will likely be plenty of time for it to develop and get better based on community feedback.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/kingmakers-early-access-release-delayed/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghost of Yōtei Has Strong Debut in the United Kingdom]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ghost-of-yotei-has-strong-debut-in-the-united-kingdom/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ghost-of-y%C5%8Dtei-has-strong-debut-in-the-united-kingdom.1317388/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The latest first-party PlayStation exclusive game, Ghost of Yōtei, is off to a strong start, at least in the United Kingdom. Former GI.biz editor-in-chief Chris Dring <a href="https://x.com/Chris_Dring/status/1974886331445903775?" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">shared on X</a> that Sucker Punch's latest game managed to reach number 1 in the weekly UK physical sales chart, beating EA Sports FC 26's second week on the market, a massive feat considering how popular the football game is in the country. Dring then clarified that there was a 40% drop compared to the predecessor, Ghost of Tsushima, but this should be put in perspective.</p>



<p>First of all, Ghost of Tsushima dropped in the middle of the COVID-19 pandemic, when practically everyone was stuck at home playing games. Moreover, it came at the very end of the PlayStation 4 lifecycle, only a few months ahead of the PS5 launch. This also means that Tsushima could count on a PS4 global install base about 20 million units larger than PS5's base now that Ghost of Yōtei has launched. Lastly, digital sales have slowly but surely gained ground on physical sales with every passing year, so we'll only know the full picture once digital sales data is also available.</p>



<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/ghost-of-yotei-exploring-the-price-of-vengeance-in-17th-century-ezo/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">As I explained in my review of the open world action/adventure game</a>, Ghost of Yōtei is a worthy sequel to Tsushima in practically everything that matters. Those who loved the studio's previous entry will no doubt enjoy the new title as well.</p>



<p>Sucker Punch Production hasn't shared any info about a potential DLC, although we only learned about Iki Island, the only Ghost of Tsushima DLC, much later than the base game's debut. We do, however, already know that the <a href="https://wccftech.com/ghost-of-yotei-legends-2026-release-gamescom-onl-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Legends co-op multiplayer mode will debut at some point in 2026</a>. The studio hasn't discussed the PC port yet, but it would make sense for Legends and the PC version to launch at the same time with cross-play enabled.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/ghost-of-yotei-has-strong-debut-in-the-united-kingdom/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy Tactics – The Ivalice Chronicles: The Seven Reaction Abilities You Must Learn]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/how-to/final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles-the-seven-reaction-abilities-you-must-learn/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-tactics-%E2%80%93-the-ivalice-chronicles-the-seven-reaction-abilities-you-must-learn.1317265/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles-classic-strategy-modern-upgrades/">Final Fantasy Tactics - The Ivalice Chronicles</a> offers ample character customization possibilities with one of the series' most versatile Job Systems to date. However, having this many abilities can feel overwhelming, especially with Reaction Abilities, whose efficacy can be challenging to evaluate just from their in-game descriptions. As these abilities are a central part of combat, often turning a losing fight into a decisive win, the right choice can completely change how a unit performs on the battlefield.</p>



<p><strong><em>NOTE: This guide is based on Enhanced mode’s Tactician difficulty, but it applies to other difficulty settings and Classic mode as well. All screenshots were captured from the 1.0 Steam version.</em></strong></p>



<div><h2>The Best Reaction Abilities in Final Fantasy Tactics - The Ivalice Chronicles</h2><ul><li><a href="#h-shirahadori" data-level="2">Shirahadori</a></li><li><a href="#h-auto-potion" data-level="2">Auto-Potion</a></li><li><a href="#h-critical-recover-hp" data-level="2">Critical: Recover HP</a></li><li><a href="#h-mana-shield" data-level="2">Mana Shield</a></li><li><a href="#h-vanish" data-level="2">Vanish</a></li><li><a href="#h-reflexes" data-level="2">Reflexes</a></li><li><a href="#h-first-strike" data-level="2">First Strike</a></li></ul></div>



<h2 id="h-shirahadori">Shirahadori</h2>



<figure><figcaption><em>Shirahadori is the best Reaction Ability in Final Fantasy Tactics - The Ivalice Chronicles</em></figcaption></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>Job: Samurai</strong></li>



<li><strong>JP: 700</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>Shirahadori is undoubtedly the best Reaction Ability in Final Fantasy Tactics - The Ivalice Chronicles for any unit with high Bravery. This ability turns the unit's Bravery stat into its parry rate for all physical attacks, both melee and ranged, meaning that a unit with 90+ Bravery will be able to parry the vast majority of physical attacks. While it doesn't provide any defense against magic or monster attacks, Shirahadori is so good that it makes it possible for a single unit to clear out an entire map without getting damaged once.</p>



<h2 id="h-auto-potion">Auto-Potion</h2>



<figure><figcaption><em>Auto-Potion is just as useful as Shirahadori, depending on the situation</em></figcaption></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>Job: Chemist</strong></li>



<li><strong>JP: 400</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>Auto-Potion is the ultimate restorative Reaction Ability in Final Fantasy Tactics - The Ivalice Chronicles, and the ability to learn for Ramza to win the <a href="https://wccftech.com/how-to/how-to-win-the-battle-at-riovanes-castle-keep-in-final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles-guide/">most challenging battle in the game</a>. This ability makes it so a unit automatically uses a Potion when receiving damage, prioritizing the weaker Potions in your possession. As such, you can get a guaranteed 150 HP healed per attack for a unit with high Bravery if you discard every Potion and Hi-Potion to use X-Potions exclusively, granting this unit unparalleled survivability against every attack that doesn't take them down.</p>



<h2 id="h-critical-recover-hp">Critical: Recover HP</h2>



<figure><figcaption><em>Critica: Recover HP is a solid Reaction Ability for tanks like the Samurai or the Knight</em></figcaption></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>Job: Monk</strong></li>



<li><strong>JP: 500 JP</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>Critical: Recover HP is not on the same level as Auto-Potion in terms of utility, but it's a pretty good ability to equip, especially for tanks with high HP like the Knight, Samurai, and Dragoon. When a unit is damaged and put in Critical condition, the ability will fully restore its HP. Unlike Auto-Potion, Critical: Recover HP has a higher degree of risk, as an attack could put the unit to low HP but not in Critical condition, so it's a little less reliable, but it's still overall very solid.</p>



<h2 id="h-mana-shield">Mana Shield</h2>



<figure><figcaption><em>Mana Shield requires some upkeep to be effective, but it's very good nonetheless</em></figcaption></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>Job: Time Mage</strong></li>



<li><strong>JP: 400 </strong></li>
</ul>



<p>Mana Shield is another solid Reaction Ability in Final Fantasy Tactics - The Ivalice Chronicles that can give a unit excellent survivability with the proper setup. With this ability equipped, received damage will be converted from HP to MP, which is great for any unit that doesn't use spells, essentially allowing them to survive mortal 1-hit KO attacks with no drawback. If you pair this ability with the Monk's Martial Arts skill Chakra, you can restore your MP to continue using this ability once the unit's MP has been depleted without having to rely on items.</p>



<h2 id="h-vanish">Vanish</h2>



<figure><figcaption><em>Vanish is a great Reaction Ability to take some risks against enemies using physical attacks</em></figcaption></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>Job: Ninja</strong></li>



<li><strong>JP: 1000</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>Vanish is a really good reaction ability that works best for units with excellent mobility to reduce the risks of rushing into enemy groups or for backline mages getting targeted by Archers. Upon receiving a physical attack, the unit will be granted Invisibility, making it impossible for them to be targeted by the enemy. Unfortunately, Invisibility will end as soon as the unit takes action, so Vanish isn't as versatile as some of the other best Reaction Abilities in the game.</p>



<h2 id="h-reflexes">Reflexes</h2>



<figure><figcaption><em>Reflexes can make some units almost untouchable</em></figcaption></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>Job: Ninja</strong></li>



<li><strong>JP: 400</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>Reflexes is a good Reaction Ability that works great for units with an innate high evasion rate or those equipping cloaks. Upon receiving an attack, the unit's evasion rates against physical and magical attacks are increased significantly, making it easier for them to evade attacks. Equip this ability to a Ninja wearing a cloak, and enemies will have a tough time hitting them, although there's still the small chance that attacks will land, so reliability isn't the best.</p>



<h2 id="h-first-strike">First Strike</h2>



<figure><figcaption><em>First Strike can be devastating with certain character builds.</em></figcaption></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>Job: Monk</strong></li>



<li><strong>JP: 1300</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>First Strike requires more effort to learn than the other Reaction Abilities above, but with the proper setup, it can be used offensively and defensively. This ability prevents human units within standard attack range from dealing damage by preemptively attacking them. While its usage is limited to standard physical attacks, if you equip a unit with both First Strike and the Dual Wield support ability from the Ninja, you can create a unit that can obliterate physical attackers before they even get the chance to attack.</p>



<p>With these Reaction Abilities, you should have no trouble dealing with every enemy that bars your way in Final Fantasy Tactics - The Ivalice Chronicles. Check out our other <a href="https://wccftech.com/tag/final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles-guides/">guides</a> if you need further help in the game. </p>





			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/how-to/final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles-the-seven-reaction-abilities-you-must-learn/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>