<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 14:18:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Halo Art Director Leaves Halo Studios After Working on the Series for 17 Years]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/halo-art-director-leaves-halo-studios-after-17-years-with-series-glenn-israel/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/halo-art-director-leaves-halo-studios-after-working-on-the-series-for-17-years.1321873/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Glenn Israel has worked on the Halo franchise for 17 years, joining Bungie back in 2008 when the studio was known for Halo, and stayed with the series by following it to 343 Industries (now Halo Studios) where he has been since. He is no longer working on the series that he spent nearly two decades with, however, as he announced with <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7379767940897959936/">a statement on his LinkedIn</a> that he has left Halo Studios, though the statement leaves plenty of questions as to the circumstances under which he is leaving.</p>



<p>"<em>As of today and after seventeen long years, I am officially no longer contributing to the Halo universe</em>," Israel wrote. "<em>There is little more I can say for the moment, though I intend to share this particular story in its entirety when it is absolutely safe to do so next year</em>. <em>In the meantime, I have a message for anyone and everyone who needs to hear it</em>."</p>



<p>"<em>I know that</em> <em>the state of our industry seems dire but never forget that you are free to choose. No illusion of security nor promise of wealth or fame or power is worth trading away your health, your dignity, your ethics or values - and no one can force you to. Stay strong, take evidence when necessary, and find where you belong. As always, I'll be here if you need to talk</em>."</p>



<p>As Israel mentions, he'll share more about the details of his departure at some point in 2026, but his statement also seems to suggest he's not leaving amicably.</p>



<p>It's no secret that 343 Industries/Halo Studios has had its struggles in the last few years, with <a href="https://wccftech.com/halo-joe-staten-joins-netflix-343-creative-director-frank-oconnor-leaves/">key members of the team leaving</a> before Israel, <a href="https://wccftech.com/former-halo-devs-blame-microsoft-343-industries/">layoffs and allegations towards parent company Microsoft for the studio's internal issues</a>, and fans turning on the studio for decisions <a href="https://wccftech.com/former-halo-devs-blame-microsoft-343-industries/">like leaving behind couch co-op on Halo Infinite</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/halo-the-master-chief-collection-microsotrancation-plans-abandoned/">almost including microtransactions in the Master Chief Collection</a>.</p>



<p>The future of the series has been unclear amidst all of this, particularly since Halo Infinite <a href="https://wccftech.com/halo-infinite-team-fell-short-on-post-launch-plan-retrenched-now-booty/">didn't exactly hit its mark at launch</a>. As far as what we know is next for the series, Halo Studios has committed to sharing more at the <a href="https://wccftech.com/halo-studios-whats-next-for-halo-halowc-2025/">Halo World Championships taking place later this month on October 24</a>, which could also be where <a href="https://wccftech.com/halo-combat-evolved-remake-development-virtuos/">a rumoured remake of Halo Combat Evolved is first revealed</a>.</p>



<p>Whenever Israel is able to share more about his departure, it'll be interesting to see what he touches on and how the changes to the studio and its struggles impacted his decision to leave Halo behind.</p>





			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/halo-art-director-leaves-halo-studios-after-17-years-with-series-glenn-israel/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Next Is Rumored to Target 2027 Launch; Partial Specs Leaked]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/xbox-next-2027-launch-rumor/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-next-is-rumored-to-target-2027-launch-partial-specs-leaked.1321738/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Xbox next-generation system is reportedly targeting a 2027 launch window, according to a new rumors circulating online.</p>



<p>The rumor originates from a new video shared by Moore's Law is Dead on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@MooresLawIsDead">YouTube</a>, whose track record regarding console rumors has been solid with <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-pro-45-faster-base-ps5/">on-point leaks for the PlayStation 5 Pro and the PlayStation Spectral Super Resolution upscaler</a>. According to the YouTuber, multiple unspecified sources have revealed that Microsoft is talking openly about the 2027 release window with partners behind the scenes, with reports having become even more frequent since earlier leaks of the APU..</p>



<h2 id="h-xbox-next-amd-magnus-apu-leaked-specifications">Xbox Next AMD Magnus APU Leaked Specifications</h2>



<p>Besides discussing the potential Xbox next-generation system release window, the new video by Moore's Law is Dead also discussed some of the specifications of the <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-6-codename-3nm-rdna-5-magnus-apu/">AMD Magnus APU</a> that will power the system, which you can find summarized below.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th colspan="2">Xbox Next (Magnus APU) Rumored Specs</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td colspan="2"><strong>APU ARCHITECTURE (Chiplet Design)</strong></td></tr><tr><td>Total Die Size</td><td>408 mm² (Full Size)</td></tr><tr><td>Chiplet 1 (SOC)</td><td>144 mm² (CPU Core, Video Out, AI Engine)<br>Node: TSMC N3P (Node confirmed in alleged external documentation).</td></tr><tr><td>Chiplet 2 (GPU)</td><td>264 mm² (Shared with desktop Radeon products)<br>Node: TSMC N3C or N3P (Unconfirmed).</td></tr><tr><td colspan="2"><strong>GPU</strong></td></tr><tr><td>Compute Units (CUs)</td><td>68 RDNA5 CUs (Disabled from up to 70 CUs)</td></tr><tr><td>Shader Engines</td><td>4 Shader Engines (3 standard engines + 1 lopsided shared engine with either 8 or 16 CUs). Each engine has 2 Shader Arrays.</td></tr><tr><td>L2 Cache</td><td>At least 24 MB L2 Cache (5x the Xbox Series X)<br>*Note: Speculative, based on desktop Radeon products.*</td></tr><tr><td colspan="2"><strong>CPU</strong></td></tr><tr><td>Core Architecture</td><td>Zen 6</td></tr><tr><td>Core Count</td><td>Up to 3 Zen 6 cores (Faster than the PS6 Orion cores) + 8 Zen 6c cores<br>Shared 12MB L3 cache<br>*Note: Final usable core count is unknown.*</td></tr><tr><td colspan="2"><strong>MEMORY AND POWER</strong></td></tr><tr><td>Memory Bus</td><td>192-bit Memory Bus</td></tr><tr><td>Total RAM</td><td>Up to 48 GB of GDDR7 (Possible configurations: 24 GB, 36 GB, or 48 GB)</td></tr><tr><td>TDP (Estimation)</td><td>250W to 350W (60-70% more than the PS6).<br>*Speculation: reportedly still aiming for a traditional console form factor.*</td></tr><tr><td colspan="2"><strong>NPU</strong></td></tr><tr><td>NPU Architecture</td><td>110 TOPS (at 6W) or 46 TOPS (at 1.2W)<br>*Note: Two power modes are likely for energy budgeting to meet Microsoft Copilot requirements.*</td></tr><tr><td>AI Performance (TOPS)</td><td>110 TOPS (at 6W) or 46 TOPS (at 1.2W)<br>*Note: Two power modes likely for energy budgeting to meet Microsoft Copilot requirements.*</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>Unlike for the PlayStation 6 Orion APU, Moore's Law is Dead doesn't know the final clock targets for the CPU and GPU of the Xbox next-generation system, so it's impossible to make a solid performance comparison between the two systems. </p>



<p>Even in the most extreme scenario of a 350W TDP, GPU clocking above 3GHz, and some CPU cores above 6GHz, the Xbox Next is expected to be no more than a third faster than the PlayStation 6. Considering Microsoft did lower the expected clock speeds of the Xbox Series X, the same could happen for the Xbox next-generation system, especially if the company is going for the expected power target of a console.</p>



<p>As such, on average, the Xbox next-generation system should be expected to offer the premium version of the performance the PlayStation 6 will offer, according to Moore's Law is Dead. If a game delivers 4K@120 FPS with ray tracing on the PS6, it will likely deliver 4K@144 FPS on the Xbox next-generation system. This is a small difference that will probably go unnoticed by anyone who isn't a PC-focused gamer playing on a high-refresh monitor looking for the very best.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="AMD Magnus APU Full Leak: RDNA 5, Zen 6, 110 TOPS NPU = XBOX Next-Gen Console!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X_pjrZQDerw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>As Moore's Law is Dead, the track record is not perfect, we have to take everything with a grain of salt until Microsoft announces the Xbox next generation system <a href="https://wccftech.com/amd-ceo-were-designing-a-full-roadmap-of-gaming-chips-for-xbox/">in much better detail than they have in the past</a>. <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-6-launching-2027-unless-unexpected-delays-happen-amd-leaker/">With both systems reportedly targeting a 2027 release window</a>, the next console generation is fast approaching.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/xbox-next-2027-launch-rumor/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>