<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 16:58:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oblivion Remastered and Metal Gear Solid Delta Developer Virtuos Suffering Mass Layoffs, 300 Developers To Lose Their Jobs – Rumor]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/oblivion-remastered-metal-gear-solid-delta-virtuos-mass-layoffs-rumor/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/oblivion-remastered-and-metal-gear-solid-delta-developer-virtuos-suffering-mass-layoffs-300-developers-to-lose-their-jobs-%E2%80%93-rumor.1245303/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>According to French journalist <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/gautoz.cool/post/3lu3ntewdrk2t">Gauthier Andres on Bluesky</a>, Virtuos, the studio players will recognize as the team working with Konami on <a href="https://wccftech.com/kojima-not-involved-metal-gear-solid-3-remake/">Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</a>, and also recently helped Bethesda release<a href="https://wccftech.com/review/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-back-in-cyrodiil-19-years-later/"> The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered</a>, is undergoing mass layoffs, with 300 developers set to lose their jobs. </p>



<p>In a multi-part thread, Andres claims that sources they have spoken to describe internal struggles within Virtuos, as the studio's leadership is seemingly losing the trust of its staff. They point to issues with the team being overworked on getting Oblivion Remastered to the finish line under Virtuos' making an effort of "<em>over-delivering on quality relative to the budget,</em>" seemingly as a way of making the studio stand out in an already crowded industry of support and co-development teams. </p>



<p>Tensions between staff and leaders were compounded by the fact that, per Andres' claims, Virtuos isn't enjoying any royalty payments off the success of Oblivion Remastered, which has risen to be one of the <a href="https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-nightreign-was-one-of-may-2025s-top-5-games-by-revenue-according-to-newzoo-while-oblivion-remastered-remains-firm-in-the-top-20-for-revenue-and-mau/">best-selling games of 2025 so far.</a> </p>







<p>Leadership allegedly announced a freeze on raises and a reduction in bonuses this past February, which certainly didn't help the situation, and now, with these layoffs, according to Andres, developers at Virtuos Lyon have gone on strike to protest the cuts, and the impact they'd have to the company's productivity and operating capacity. And, to make matters worse for developer morale, Virtuos leaders have also allegedly begun pushing generative AI tools on employees, who are now allegedly mandated to attend basic training sessions on using AI tools. </p>



<p>According to Andres, 200 of the 300 proposed cuts are happening to a team based in China, while the remaining 100 cuts are impacting developers at its France and US-based studios. Virtuos has yet to make an official statement acknowledging the layoffs at the time of this writing. We'll update this story as more official details are revealed.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/oblivion-remastered-metal-gear-solid-delta-virtuos-mass-layoffs-rumor/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2077 Patch 2.3 Launches on July 17, Introducing New Content, AMD FSR 4, FSR 3.1 Frame Generation, XeSS 2.0 With Frame Generation on PC, VRR ]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-patch-2-3-amd-fsr-4-frame-generation/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cyberpunk-2077-patch-2-3-launches-on-july-17-introducing-new-content-amd-fsr-4-fsr-3-1-frame-generation-xess-2-0-with-frame-generation-on-pc-vrr.1245234/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The next Cyberpunk 2077 patch will launch tomorrow and will introduce plenty of new features to the game on PC and consoles.</p>



<p><span>As confirmed during a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aFLKoZaHak8" target="_blank">livestream</a>&nbsp;today, the 2.3 patch, which launches tomorrow, July 17, focuses on vehicles and customization, introducing three new cars and one new bike, which will be fully customizable alongside new quests that must be completed to unlock them.</span> In addition, the patch will also introduce the AutoDrive feature, which allows users to drive their cars hands-free to a destination set with a marker and enjoy Night City like never before, also thanks to the new cinematic camera. The Delamain Taxi service can also be hired for AutoDrive, providing players with more options to enjoy the stunning urban landscape of the game.</p>



<p>The new Cyberpunk 2077 2.3 patch will also introduce expanded photo mode options, quality of life improvements, and enhanced HDR settings on all formats. Additionally, the patch will also introduce on PC AMD FSR 3, AMD FSR 3.1 Frame Generation, Intel XeSS 2.0 with XeSS Frame Generation, and Intel HDR 10 - Gaming support, which will be properly enabled with new drivers from AMD and Intel, providing users with more options to tweak the experience and enjoy it at its best. The console versions of the game are also getting VRR support with the new patch.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="REDstreams — Update 2.3 Overview" width="500" height="375" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aFLKoZaHak8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Cyberpunk 2077 is now available on PC, PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Xbox Series X, Xbox Series S, Xbox One and Nintendo Switch 2. Tomorrow's launch of the 2.3 patch coincides with the game's release on <a href="https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-ultimate-edition-no-ray-tracing-enabled-by-default-m3-max-for-60fps/">Mac</a>.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-patch-2-3-amd-fsr-4-frame-generation/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Surgent Studio’s Dead Take Launches This Month, As Matt Mercer, Laura Bailey, Sam Lake, And More Join The Cast]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/surgent-studios-dead-take-release-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/surgent-studio%E2%80%99s-dead-take-launches-this-month-as-matt-mercer-laura-bailey-sam-lake-and-more-join-the-cast.1245231/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>When Tales of Kenzera: ZAU developer, Surgent Studios, announced its new game, <a href="https://wccftech.com/tales-of-kenzera-developer-announces-new-horror-game-dead-take-coming-to-pc-in-2025/">Dead Tak</a>e, would feature Ben Starr and Neil Newbon in the cast, that alone was a sign that the game would feature some excellent performances. </p>



<p>Now, along with announcing the game's release date, Surgent Studios has announced that it was able to gather one of the strongest casts in video games for Dead Take, as it will also feature Matt Mercer, Jane Perry, Laura Bailey, Sam Lake, Alanah Pearce, CDawgVA, and Travis Willingham, when it launches at the end of the month on <strong>July 31, 2025.</strong></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="DEAD TAKE | FULL CAST REVEALED | OFFICIAL TRAILER" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aXhJB9ICvfc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>"<em>Dead Take is about actors. So We needed actors who've lived it,"</em> said Surgent Studios founder and creative director on Dead Take, Abubakar Salim, in a press release. "<em>It's a game about the high ambition and the rot underneath it. The lies we tell ourselves to get in the spotlight, and the monsters we become to stay there. Everyone in this cast has felt that pressure. This was a chance to bleed it out</em>."</p>



<p>The new horror game puts players in the shoes of Chase Lowry, an actor played by Neil Newbon who is looking for his friend, Vinny Monroe, played by Ben Starr. Monroe has gone missing at a Hollywood party, and as Lowry searches for Monroe, the night dives deeper into a terrifying mystery. It'll be intriguing to see what Dead Take has in store for players when it arrives in a little more than two weeks time, at the time of this writing.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/surgent-studios-dead-take-release-date/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HBO Says Neil Druckmann Has Provided “A Good Blueprint” For The Last Of Us Show, Not Concerned With His Departure Amid 16 Emmy Nominations]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/hbo-not-concerned-neil-druckmann-departure-the-last-of-us-show-16-emmy/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hbo-says-neil-druckmann-has-provided-%E2%80%9Ca-good-blueprint%E2%80%9D-for-the-last-of-us-show-not-concerned-with-his-departure-amid-16-emmy-nominations.1245120/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>At the beginning of the month, Naughty Dog and Neil Druckmann <a href="https://wccftech.com/neil-druckmann-hbo-the-last-of-us-naughty-dog/">announced</a> that Druckmann would be stepping away from his role with HBO's The Last of Us, to put his full efforts back to his day job, being the studio head of Naughty Dog and working on their next project, Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet.</p>



<p>In an interview with <a href="https://variety.com/2025/tv/news/hbo-casey-bloys-the-penguin-season-2-the-last-of-us-future-1236461127/">Variety</a>, HBO chairman and chief executive officer Casey Bloys spoke about what Druckmann's departure means for the show from their perspective, and for Bloys, Druckmann leaving the show doesn't seem to be a huge concern. </p>



<p><em>"Obviously it was great to have Neil involved in the beginning</em>," Bloys began. "<em>The whole reason that I wanted to do 'Last of Us' is after 'Chernobyl,' I said to Craig [Mazin], 'What do you want to do next?' And 'Last of Us' was what he wanted to do. That's what was most important to me, Craig's creative excitement about the show. It was fantastic to have Neil involved. A lot of people don't realize that Neil has a full time job creating video games and running Naughty Dog. It's a really big job that he's got. So I understand why he needs to focus on that. But I believe he's given us a good blueprint with the show. And obviously Craig is a pro, so I think we'll be in excellent shape. I'm not worried at all.</em>"</p>



<p>Bloys continued to say that season 3 of the show is slated to arrive in 2027, and whether there will be a fourth season is up to showrunner Craig Mazin. "<em>I'm following Craig's lead on that</em>," Bloys said.</p>



<p>Druckmann's departure might be cause for concern for some viewers, but it's not surprising that Bloys isn't outwardly concerned, especially since the show was just<a href="https://www.televisionacademy.com/files/assets/Downloads/77thnominations-list-v1.pdf"> nominated for 16 Emmy Awards</a>, bringing the series total up to 40 nominations between two seasons.</p>



<p>Bella Ramsey and Pedro Pascal both picked up Emmy nominations for lead actress and actor in a drama series, respectively. Kaitlyn Dever also picked up a nomination for outstanding guest actress in a drama series, while the overall show was nominated for outstanding drama.  Other notable nominations among the 16 include nominations for prosthetics and makeup, special effects, and Catherine O'Hara also getting a nomination for her guest role in the show. </p>



<p>Any major production is a team effort, and while Druckmann's involvement was clearly an important part of the show's first two seasons, it's not like it earned 40 Emmy nominations based on Druckmann's efforts alone. There's a whole team of people who are making this show, and it'll be interesting to see how Mazin continues the story, without Druckmann leaning over his shoulder and weighing in on the details as much as he might've been for the first two seasons.</p>



<p>And players can rejoice over the fact that, hopefully, Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet will arrive on time in its current release window slated for 2026.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/hbo-not-concerned-neil-druckmann-departure-the-last-of-us-show-16-emmy/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>