<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 14:20:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lossless Scaling Adaptive Frame Generation Delivers Consistently Smooth Output With Low Base Framerates Even on a Mid-Range Ryzen 5 3600, RTX 4060 Sys]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/lossless-scaling-adaptive-frame-generation-delivers-consistently-smooth-output-mid-range/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lossless-scaling-adaptive-frame-generation-delivers-consistently-smooth-output-with-low-base-framerates-even-on-a-mid-range-ryzen-5-3600-rtx-4060-sys.1133328/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/lossless-scaling-adaptive-frame-generation-delivers-consistently-smooth-output-mid-range/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Lossless Scaling's new <a href="https://wccftech.com/adaptive-frame-generation-is-lossless-scalings-latest-feature/">adaptive frame generation</a> is a great proof of concept that can deliver consistently smooth output with low base framerates even on mid-range system configurations.</p>
<p>During the latest episode of their weekly podcast, the tech experts at <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@DigitalFoundry" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Digital Foundry</a> took a quick look at the new feature introduced to the upscaler earlier this month, highlighting how, even on a mid-range system powered by a Ryzen 5 3600 CPU and an RTX 4060 GPU, the feature is capable of delivering consistently smooth 120 FPS output with low base framerates, high settings and even ray tracing at 1440p resolution in Control, and at native 4K resolution in Starfield. While the experience is far from perfect due to visual artifacts and the massive latency caused by the low base framerates, which is only partially alleviated by tech like NVIDIA Reflex, the new Lossless Scaling feature is an amazing proof of concept, also considering how it does not rely on any specific hardware technology.</p>
<p><iframe title="Lossless Scaling Dynamic Frame-Gen To Screen Refresh Rate: Impressive!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KfDjUUnN6OI?start=2&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Everything that Lossless Scaling offers is great for games that do not support upscalers from major vendors, but DLSS, FSR, and Intel XeSS will continue to be the better options for games with official support. AMD's upscaler, in particular, has made some impressive steps forward with its <a href="https://wccftech.com/amd-fsr-4-better-fsr3-dlss-cnn/">latest version</a>, delivering an image quality that is on par with the previous version of DLSS, which still retains the crown of the best upscaler currently available thanks to the introduction of the superior Transformer model which can deliver <a href="https://wccftech.com/nvidia-dlss-4-super-resolution-performance-better-dlss-3-8-quality/">impressive image quality with lower input resolution</a> than the previous CNN model.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Control 2 Has Entered Full Production, Remedy Entertainment Confirms]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/control-2-full-production-remedy/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/control-2-has-entered-full-production-remedy-entertainment-confirms.1133304/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/control-2-full-production-remedy/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Control 2 has entered full production and is now Remedy's third game in full production, the company confirmed in a new update shared today.</p>
<p>In Remedy's <a href="https://investors.remedygames.com/app/uploads/2025/03/remedy-annual-report-2024.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">annual report</a>, the Finnish company confirmed that the full-blown sequel to the action-adventure game released back in 2020 is now in full production, besides<a href="https://wccftech.com/fbc-firebreak-multiplayer-game-set-in-the-control-world-revealed-with-new-trailer/"> FBC: Firebreak</a>, the co-op game set in the Control universe previously known as Project Condor, and the Max Payne 1&amp;2 remake, which entered full production <a href="https://wccftech.com/max-payne-1-and-2-remake-full-production/">last August</a>. Besides confirming the change of development state for the game, the new update doesn't provide any new information on the game, which will be powered by the studio's proprietary Northlight engine and will push the boundaries of action and storytelling, which Remedy has been successfully doing for years.</p>
<p>In proper Remedy fashion, Control 2 was teased in the Alan Wake 2 - The Lake House DLC expansion released last year. While it does a great job offering more of what the base offers, the expansion is a must-play only for die-hard fans of the base game and the Remedy Connected Universe, as I highlighted in my <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/alan-wake-2-the-lake-house-whos-the-real-monster/">review.</a></p>
<p><em>With its great atmosphere and tight story pacing, Alan Wake 2: The Lake House retains the same elements that made the base game so engaging. The lack of significant new mechanics and its very short length, however, make it a worthwhile purchase only for the most die-hard fans of Alan Wake 2 and the Remedy Connected Universe.</em></p>
<p>Control 2 is now in development for PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X and Xbox Series S.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Half-Life 2 RTX Demo Announced for March 18 as RTX Remix Is Officially Released with DLSS 4 Multi Frame Generation]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/half-life-2-rtx-demo-announced-for-march-18-as-rtx-remix-is-officially-released-with-dlss-4-multi-frame-generation/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/half-life-2-rtx-demo-announced-for-march-18-as-rtx-remix-is-officially-released-with-dlss-4-multi-frame-generation.1133235/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/half-life-2-rtx-demo-announced-for-march-18-as-rtx-remix-is-officially-released-with-dlss-4-multi-frame-generation/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>As part of its GDC 2025 news, NVIDIA announced that a free Half-Life 2 RTX demo will be released on March 18. Fans will have the opportunity to sample around two hours of gameplay of the work that Orbifold Studios has already completed, checking out the full ray traced graphics, remade assets, particles, and animations in the Ravenholm and Nova Prospekt levels.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, today marks the official release of the RTX Remix remastering suite, a little over a year after its <a href="https://wccftech.com/nvidia-rtx-remix-open-beta-qa-with-nyle-usmani-past-present-and-future-of-the-generalized-modding-platform/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Open Beta debut</a>. NVIDIA has introduced features like DLSS 4 Multi Frame Generation, RTX Neural Radiance Cache, RTX Skin, and RTX Volumetrics, all of which are, of course, included in the Half-Life 2 RTX demo. NVIDIA boasts frame rate improvements of 2.4x compared to the RTX Remix Open Beta, which only supported DLSS 3.5 Frame Generation, in Portal RTX, mainly thanks to DLSS 4 Multi Frame Generation and RTX Radiance Cache, although the runtime was also optimized and texture streaming improved.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/RTX-Remix-DLSS-4-Multi-Frame-Generation-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>

<p>NVIDIA also offered a look at how RTX Skin and RTX Volumetrics improve the Half-Life 2 RTX demo.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Half-Life-2-RTX-Demo-RTX-Skin-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>


<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Half-Life-2-RTX-Demo-RTX-Volumetrics-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>

<p>With a new Character Replacement feature, RTX Remix users will find it easier to remaster the original assets of old PC games. After working on the remaster in the Blender software, they'll be able to remap the skeleton in RTX Remix to get a properly remastered asset that works correctly.</p>
<p>NVIDIA said there are 150 compatible games (including <a href="https://wccftech.com/left-4-dead-2-path-tracing-rtx-5080-obliterates-performance/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Left 4 Dead 2</a> and the <a href="https://www.moddb.com/mods/painkiller-rtx-remix" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Painkiller Remixed mod</a>), not to mention 350 mod projects being actively worked on by a community of over 30K modders. PBRFusion 3 is also now available to easily remaster materials for Physically Based Rendering (PBR). This new version introduces the following features:</p>
<ul>
<li>Custom fine-tuned model for better upscaling of lower resolution textures</li>
<li>Custom fine-tuned depth model</li>
<li>Higher quality Normal Maps</li>
<li>Seamless Maps</li>
</ul>
<p>It generates normal maps, height maps, and roughness maps. You can find a guide <a href="https://huggingface.co/NightRaven109/PBRFusion" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>.</p>
<p>As a side note, NVIDIA <a href="https://wccftech.com/nvidia-dlss-4-now-in-over-100-games-more-titles-coming-soon-neural-shading-support-directx-next-month/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> that there are now over 100 games and apps with support for DLSS 4 Multi Frame Generation. They also confirmed the following titles will support the technology:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/lost-soul-aside-launches-on-may-30th-on-pc-and-playstation-5-new-trailer-released/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lost Soul Aside</a></li>
<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/mecha-break-open-beta-mashmak-pc-hands-on-preview-extracted-core/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mecha BREAK</a></li>
<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/phantom-blade-zero-gamescom-hands-on-preview-brutally-engaging/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Phantom Blade Zero</a></li>
<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/stellar-blade-pc-june/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Stellar Blade</a></li>
<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/tides-of-annihilation-qa-2026-tentative-launch-30-hours-light-rpg-elements-exclusive-screens/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tides of Annihilation</a></li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2827230/Wild_Assault/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Wild Assault</a></li>
</ul>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NVIDIA Announces RTX Neural Shading Support Going Live in April’s DirectX Agility Preview]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nvidia-announces-rtx-neural-shading-support-going-live-in-aprils-directx12-preview/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nvidia-announces-rtx-neural-shading-support-going-live-in-april%E2%80%99s-directx-agility-preview.1133232/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nvidia-announces-rtx-neural-shading-support-going-live-in-aprils-directx12-preview/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>NVIDIA has kicked off the official GDC 2025 news rounds with a bang, revealing that official RTX Neural Shading support will go live next month thanks to an updated DirectX Agility SDK Preview released by Microsoft. While the RTX Kit <a href="https://wccftech.com/nvidia-rtx-kit-with-neural-shaders-is-out-now-mega-geometry-and-neural-texture-compression-demos-available/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">has been available</a> via GitHub since last month, the DirectX support will accelerate RTX Neural Shading with GeForce GPUs Tensor Cores.</p>
<p>John Spitzer, NVIDIA VP of Developer Technology, said in a statement:</p>
<p><em>Neural rendering is the future of graphics and we are happy to partner with Microsoft to bring AI to programmable shaders in DirectX. All game developers can use Tensor Cores built into GeForce RTX GPUs to deliver next-gen realism and performance to Windows gaming.</em></p>
<p>Shawn Hargreaves, Direct3D Dev Manager at Microsoft, added:</p>
<p><em>Microsoft is adding Cooperative Vectors support to DirectX and HLSL, starting with a preview this April. This will advance the future of graphics programming by enabling neural rendering across the gaming industry. Unlocking Tensor Cores on NVIDIA RTX will allow developers to fully leverage RTX Neural Shading for richer, more immersive experiences on Windows.</em></p>
<p>For now, three main uses of RTX Neural Shading have been detailed:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/nvidia-neural-compression-technique-unlocks-16x-texture-detail/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RTX Neural Texture Compression</a> can create neural representations of thousands of textures in less than a minute, saving up to 7x VRAM/RAM compared to regular compression techniques.</li>
<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/neural-radiance-cache-technique-aims-to-make-path-tracing-faster-on-nvidia-gpus-thanks-to-tensor-cores-and-ai/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RTX Neural Radiance Cache</a> can infer theoretically infinite multi-bounce indirect lighting starting from just one or two bounces, optimizing visuals and performance.</li>
<li>RTX Neural Materials compresses complex shader code typically reserved for offline materials composed of multiple layers, such as porcelain and silk. It provides material processing that is up to 5x faster.</li>
</ul>
<p>Needless to say, this is just a preview. It will be a while before it's officially released, and then we'll have to wait for game developers to actually implement the features. However, owners of the GeForce RTX 50 Series GPUs are future-proof in this regard since the <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/geforce-rtx-5090-founders-edition-gamers-pricey-dream/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">new graphics cards</a> already support RTX Neural Shading.</p>
<p><iframe title="Zorah | Neural Rendering, Powered by GeForce RTX 50 Series and AI" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZtTtUyqGs-o?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>In other GDC 2025 news, NVIDIA demonstrated an updated version of the Zorah demo first showcased at CES. A sample will be available next week with the following features: RTX Mega Geometry, RTX Hair, ReSTIR Path Tracing, and ReSTIR Direct Illumination.</p>
<p>Additionally, the NVIDIA RTX Unreal Engine 5 branch on GitHub was just updated with support for the RTX Mega Geometry and RTX Hair technologies. The former <a href="https://wccftech.com/alan-wake-2-rtx-mega-geometry-performance-vram-improvements/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">debuted</a> in the most recent Alan Wake 2 patch, while the latter will do so in Indiana Jones and the Great Circle <a href="https://wccftech.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-to-get-dlss-4-multi-frame-generation-and-rtx-hair-with-february-update/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">through an update</a>.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/NVIDIA-ACE-inZOI-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>

<p>NVIDIA also confirmed that its <a href="https://wccftech.com/nvidia-ace-to-power-dynamic-ai-characters-companions-and-bosses-in-pubg-naraka-bladepoint-inzoi-and-mir5/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ACE AI technology</a> will debut when inZOI (whose system requirements have just been <a href="https://wccftech.com/inzoi-will-require-a-rather-powerful-pc-ryzen-7-9800x3d-recommended-for-high-preset/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">revealed</a>) launches in early access on March 28, offering an on-device language model exclusively available on GeForce RTX GPUs. NVIDIA ACE will also be integrated later this month in NARAKA BLADEPOINT: MOBILE PC VERSION, where the AI will be a helpful game companion. The same will be added to Black Vultures: Prey of Greed, an upcoming MMOFPS by Korean developer WEMADE, previously codenamed <a href="https://www.kedglobal.com/korean-games/newsView/ked202305080012" target="_blank" rel="noopener">This Means War</a>.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Netflix Games GenAI Vice President Mike Verdu Has Left The Company]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/netflix-games-genai-vice-president-mike-verdu-has-left-the-company/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/netflix-games-genai-vice-president-mike-verdu-has-left-the-company.1133193/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/netflix-games-genai-vice-president-mike-verdu-has-left-the-company/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Big changes are underway at Netflix, as the executive who led the streaming giant's foray into gaming has been confirmed to have left the company less than six months after assuming a new role.</p>
<p>As confirmed to <a href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/netflix-mike-verdu-exit-gdc" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GameFile</a>, Mike Verdu, former Vice President of Netflix's GenAI, has left the company for undisclosed reasons. GameFile asked the executive for comment but did not return the request.</p>
<p>Mike Verdu joined Netflix back in 2021 to help the company launch its gaming division, whose reins he left to former EA and Ubisoft executive Alain Tascan last July, then assuming the role of<a href="https://wccftech.com/netflix-investing-in-generative-ai-for-games-after-closing-studios/"> vice president of GenAI</a>, the company's division focused on generative AI. This transition was reportedly planned, although the quick exit from the company as a whole only five months after assuming a new role suggests that other issues may have been ongoing behind the scenes.</p>
<p>Considering how generative AI is becoming more and more prominent, it is unlikely Netflix's plans for GenAI are going to change with Mike Verdu leaving the company. The former vice president highlighted, last year, how he was focused on "<em>a creator-first vision for AI, one that puts creative talent at the center, with AI being a catalyst and an accelerant."</em> This is a vision that is shared among big publishers such as Microsoft, who recently revealed its <a href="https://wccftech.com/xboxs-muse-ai-model-is-a-one-of-a-kind-model-that-can-generate-gameplay/">Muse AI model</a> that is capable of generating gameplay, but it remains to be seen how much they will stick to the idea of generative AI empowering developers, and not use it to take their jobs away.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>