<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 15:00:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Red Dead Redemption Voice Actors Seem To Be Teasing A Red Dead-Related Announcement Coming This Week]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/red-dead-redemption-voice-actors-teasing-red-dead-announcement-coming-this-week/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/red-dead-redemption-voice-actors-seem-to-be-teasing-a-red-dead-related-announcement-coming-this-week.1220568/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/red-dead-redemption-voice-actors-teasing-red-dead-announcement-coming-this-week/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Rob Wiethoff, the actor who plays John Marston in Red Dead Redemption and Red Dead Redemption 2, teased in a <a href="https://x.com/Okami13_/status/1934015849603453002">live stream this past Saturday</a> while playing Red Dead Redemption, that there's 'something' coming this week related to the Red Dead series, likely closer to Friday, that he is incredibly excited to share and discuss with players, once the news is made public.</p>
<p>"<em>I've got such exciting news. I can't share it with you right now, and it's absolutely killing</em> <em>me</em>," he began. "<em>By the end of this week, hopefully sooner. Not this week, I guess. Probably, not as soon as tomorrow, but definitely before Friday. Oh my goodness, the news that I have to share - and I won't be the only one sharing it. I cannot wait for you to know what's going on. And that's all I can say.</em>"</p>
<p>What made it seem like a direct reference to Red Dead and a Red Dead-related announcement coming is that he ended his vague and excited statement by saying "<em>I'm so excited, but I truly cannot think of anything else, especially playing this game, I can't think of anything else.</em>"</p>
<p>Adding to Wiethoff's vague statements after the live stream was Roger Clark, the actor who plays Arthur Morgan in Red Dead Redemption 2. When asked if he knew what Wiethoff was talking about on X, <a href="https://x.com/rclark98/status/1934308877446660381">he replied with a simple "<em>Yes,</em>"</a> and a gif of a grinning dog, smiling like they have a secret no one else knows.</p>
<p>Then, Noshir Dalal, the voice actor for Charles in Red Dead Redemption 2, <a href="https://x.com/NoshirDalal/status/1934390960332378568">replied to Clark's tweet with his own vague tease,</a> adding even more weight to the pile.</p>
<p>It's possible that all three actors are hinting that we'll finally get the reveal of the long-awaited current-gen update for Red Dead Redemption 2, a game that originally launched on PS4 and Xbox One, and is still without a native PS5 and Xbox Series X/S version. Red Dead Redemption 2 looks great on PC, <a href="https://wccftech.com/red-dead-redemption-2-mod-enhanced-ambient-occlusion-trailer-quality/">even better with certain mods,</a> but console players are still left playing the last-gen version. A PS5 and Series X/S version would be a huge announcement for fans of the series.</p>
<p>And now that the <a href="https://wccftech.com/red-dead-redemption-pc-better-lighting-shadows-comparison/">first Red Dead game has a remastered</a> and graphically upgraded version, it's high time the sequel gets its due.</p>
<p>It could also be that Rockstar is about to add another game to the Nintendo Switch 2 lineup, with a Switch 2 version of RDR2 coming. It could also be that the game is coming to Switch 2, and it's getting a native PS5 and Xbox Series X/S version with graphical upgrades.</p>
<p>Or it's none of them, and instead we're getting some sort of Red Dead adaptation or just something else entirely. Who knows at this point, but you have to imagine that Wiethoff and company wouldn't get players riled up if there wasn't something big behind it. Just weeks ago, we saw voice actors from the original <a href="https://wccftech.com/a-third-persona-4-voice-actor-has-confirmed-they-wont-be-returning-for-the-persona-4-remake/">Persona 4 cast make subtle hints</a> in the lead-up to <a href="https://wccftech.com/persona-4-revival-announced-for-pc-and-consoles-with-new-trailer/">Persona 4 Revival's</a> reveal. Hopefully, these teases are leading towards a similar level of announcement.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FBC: Firebreak Game Ready Driver Out Now; DLSS 4 Boosts Performance by 9.3X on Average]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/fbc-firebreak-game-ready-driver-out-now-dlss-4-boosts-performance-by-9-3x-on-average/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fbc-firebreak-game-ready-driver-out-now-dlss-4-boosts-performance-by-9-3x-on-average.1220460/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/fbc-firebreak-game-ready-driver-out-now-dlss-4-boosts-performance-by-9-3x-on-average/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, Remedy Entertainment has released FBC: Firebreak, its first cooperative multiplayer game set in the so-called Remedy Connected Universe. You can read our review-in-progress <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/fbc-firebreak-review-in-progress-dont-forget-to-shower/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>.</p>
<p>NVIDIA has just released a new GeForce Game Ready driver (version 576.80) that delivers day-one optimizations for the game. The driver also fixes several bugs in many games, as noted in the <a href="https://us.download.nvidia.com/Windows/576.80/576.80-win11-win10-release-notes.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">official changelog</a>:</p>
<ul>
<li>Dune: Awakening: stability issues</li>
<li>EA Sports FC 25: stability issues</li>
<li>Dragon's Dogma 2: displays shadow flicker</li>
<li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33: stability issues</li>
<li>Enshrouded: crashes after launching game</li>
<li>Monster Hunter World: stability issues when playing in DX12 mode</li>
<li>Gray Zone Warfare: stability issues</li>
<li>Marvel Rivals: stability issues</li>
<li>Ghost of Tsushima Director's Cut: Flickering/corruption around light sources</li>
<li>GTA V Enhanced: stability issues</li>
<li>Honor of Kings: World: stability issues</li>
<li>Forza Horizon 5: stability issues</li>
<li>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle: Image corruption</li>
</ul>
<p>FBC: Firebreak, like Control and Alan Wake 2 before it, supports the full extent of the NVIDIA RTX suite. It integrates DLSS 4, including DLSS Super Resolution, DLSS Frame Generation, DLSS Multi Frame Generation, and DLSS Ray Reconstruction to enhance ray tracing fidelity and frame rates. Additionally, all GeForce RTX gamers benefit from the NVIDIA RTX Mega Geometry (a feature that <a href="https://wccftech.com/alan-wake-2-rtx-mega-geometry-performance-vram-improvements/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">debuted</a> in Remedy's Alan Wake 2, which also runs on the Northlight engine) when ray tracing is enabled, reducing CPU and GPU Bounding Volume Hierarchies build and update times and reducing VRAM consumption.</p>
<p><iframe title="FBC: Firebreak | 4K RTX On Gameplay - Full Ray Tracing &amp; DLSS 4!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nV2pLZxBWNk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>According to NVIDIA, FBC: Firebreak runs 9.3x faster on average when DLSS 4 with Multi Frame Generation, DLSS Super Resolution, and DLSS Ray Reconstruction at 4K max settings on GeForce RTX 50 Series desktop graphics cards. Gamers equipped with the latest series of GeForce GPUs can play FBC: Firebreak with path tracing enabled at almost 200 frames per second on the GeForce RTX 5070 Ti, at nearly 250 frames per second on the GeForce RTX 5080, and at 362 frames per second on the GeForce RTX 5090.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>Another NVIDIA-partnered game, id Software's DOOM: The Dark Ages, will receive its highly anticipated path tracing update tomorrow. On top of all the aforementioned DLSS features, the game also introduces NVIDIA's Spatial Hash Radiance Cache (SHaRC) technology, which enables the efficient computation of path-traced light; moreover, Shader Execution Reordering technology further enhances the performance of GeForce RTX GPUs. NVIDIA reports that DLSS 4 accelerates performance at 4K by an average of 6.8x on GeForce RTX 5090 and GeForce RTX 5080 cards. The flagship GPU averages 234 frames per second, while the RTX 5080 registers around 167 frames per second.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>In other NVIDIA DLSS updates, the vehicle combat racing game Warhammer 40,000: Speed Freeks recently exited Steam Early Access with support for DLSS Super Resolution. Later this week, Sloclap will launch the 5v5 multiplayer arcade football game REMATCH with integration for NVIDIA DLSS 4 Super Resolution, Frame Generation, and Multi Frame Generation.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>