<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 17:06:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASCAR 25 Developer iRacing Studios to Create New IndyCar Racing Game Series with Debut Game Due Out in 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/iracing-studios-indycar-racing-game-series-2026/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nascar-25-developer-iracing-studios-to-create-new-indycar-racing-game-series-with-debut-game-due-out-in-2026.1280928/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>iRacing Studios, the developer behind the first major NASCAR game since 2021, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3873970/NASCAR_25/">NASCAR 25</a>, which is due out in October, will produce and develop a series on IndyCar racing games for PC and consoles, with the first of this new series coming to PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X/S sometime in 2026.</p>



<p>The news was announced with a press release on iRacing Studios' <a href="https://www.iracing.com/iracing-studios-to-produce-standalone-indycar-video-game-in-2026/">official website</a>, as iRacing.com Motorsport Simulations and IndyCar have signed "<em>a long-term licensing agreement for iRacing Studios to produce standalone INDYCAR titles for console and PC.</em>"</p>



<p>We don't yet have an official title for this new series, but its significance for racing fans cannot be overstated, as it's the first major IndyCar racing game "<em>in more than two decades</em>," according to iRacing and INDYCAR.</p>



<p>"<em>INDYCAR fans have long been clamoring for a standalone title for consoles, and we're excited to give them what they're looking for in 2026,</em>" said iRacing.com Motorsport Simulations president, Tony Gardner. "<em>iRacing Studios' standalone INDYCAR title will offer all the excitement of the NTT INDYCAR SERIES and an immersive experience that fans of all ages can enjoy. We are already very excited about how the game is coming together."</em></p>



<p>IndyCar president J. Douglas Boles added, "<em>The most competitive and challenging racing on the planet deserves a dedicated and widely available gaming experience. iRacing Studios is the ideal partner for us, trusted and known to our core fans and ready to share our sport with a wider and highly engaged audience.</em>"</p>



<p>According to the press release, this new game will include licensed vehicles and drivers from the NTT INDYCAR SERIES and INDY NXT, featuring online multiplayer, a career mode for players to progress through, and will be made on iRacing Studios' proprietary Orontes game engine.</p>



<p>"<em>Our company has grown significantly in recent years with the addition of new development teams and studios,</em>" Gardner continued. "<em>Our INDYCAR title will benefit from this growth as it will be the sole focus of one of these teams. However, the game will also incorporate elements like car and track assets, technology and driving characteristics from other iRacing Studios products</em>."</p>



<p>iRacing has always been more simulation than arcade focused, so it's not exactly trying to take away players from games like Forza Horizon, but it'll be interesting to see how this new IndyCar game fares when it arrives, and how its coming NASCAR 25 game does in October. It definitely feels like there's more of an interest in the overall sport of racing with major films recently released on the subject, even if they're not IndyCar or NASCAR-focused. We'll see what October 2025, and then 2026, has in store for racing fans.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/iracing-studios-indycar-racing-game-series-2026/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Dino Crisis Trademark Has Been Filed In Brazil, Suggesting Series’ Revival May Be in the Cards]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/new-dino-crisis-trademark-revival/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-dino-crisis-trademark-has-been-filed-in-brazil-suggesting-series%E2%80%99-revival-may-be-in-the-cards.1280817/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Dino Crisis series could be among the next classic CAPCOM series to be revived, judging from some recent findings.</p>



<p>As reported by <a href="https://residentevil.com.br/lab/registros-de-resident-evil-requiem-e-dino-crisis-no-inpi-brasil/">Brazilian publication REVIL</a>, a new Dino Crisis trademark has been recently registered with the National Institute of Industrial Property. The July 3 filing is separate from the 1999 filing for the original and has been submitted around the time the Resident Evil Requiem registration has, suggesting that this new filing isn't meant for the updated PC versions of the first entries in the series released earlier this year, but for something different altogether. Interestingly enough, the trademark's class is the same as that used for the Resident Evil Requiem trademark, entertainment and video games class, so there's definitely the chance something related to the series is in the works, possibly a new entry in the series, a remake or even a remaster in the vein of the <a href="https://wccftech.com/onimusha-2-samurais-destiny-hands-on-preview-aging-like-fine-wine/">Onimusha 2: Samurai's Destiny remaster.</a></p>



<p>The new Dino Crisis series registration with the National Institute of Industrial Property in Brazil isn't the only recent indication that the long-dormant series may be close to a return to the spotlight, following other series' revivals like <a href="https://wccftech.com/onimusha-way-of-the-sword-announced-for-pc-and-consoles-with-a-2026-release-date/">Onimusha</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/okami-2-re-engine/">Okami</a>. <a href="https://wccftech.com/dino-crisis-has-been-trademarked-in-japan-by-capcom-reigniting-hopes-for-a-comeback/">Back in March</a>, CAPCOM trademarked Dino Crisis again in Japan, which is usually done in Japan not just to protect rights to a property, but also when there's an intention to use the IP again. As CAPCOM did something similar with Onimusha, it looks increasingly likely that the series will be making some sort of comeback in the future.</p>



<p>As already mentioned, Dino Crisis made a small return <a href="https://wccftech.com/dino-crisis-1-and-2-pc-enhancements/">earlier this year</a> with the GOG release of the first two entries in the series. Both games have been updated with new features, such as improved DirectX game renderer, new rendering options including V-Sync control, gamma correction, integer scaling, anti-aliasing and more, increased rendering resolution to 4K and color depth to 32-bit, improved geometry calculation, smoother animation, video and music playback, cloud saves support, and much more</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/new-dino-crisis-trademark-revival/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>