<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 03:27:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deep Rock Galactic: Survivor Releases Out Of Early Access In September]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/deep-rock-galactic-survivor-releases-out-of-early-access-in-september/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/deep-rock-galactic-survivor-releases-out-of-early-access-in-september.1161249/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/deep-rock-galactic-survivor-releases-out-of-early-access-in-september/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Developed by Funday Games and published by Ghost Ship Games, Deep Rock Galactic: Survivor is the rougelike auto-shooter spin-off of first-person co-op mining shooter <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/deep-rock-galactic-a-dwarf-is-always-a-dwarf-even-in-space/">Deep Rock Galactic</a>. The top-down adventure launched in early access on Steam in February 2024, and Ghost Ship Games announced today it'll launch out of early access later this year.</p>
<p>Announced during the Triple-I Initiative Showcase, Deep Rock Galactic: Survivor will hit its 1.0 launch on <strong>September 17, 2025.&nbsp;</strong>It'll be available on PC through Steam at launch, though hopefully, once it hits 1.0, we'll hear something about when it'll be moving to consoles.</p>
<p>Over 1 million players have already dived into Deep Rock Galactic: Survivor since its release a little more than a year ago, and in that time, Funday Games has released multiple new biomes and characters for players to try out, with more sure to come when its 1.0 release arrives.</p>
<p>Unlike Deep Rock Galactic, which has a co-op focus, Survivor is a single-player game that challenges players to take down waves of hordes of aliens. At the same time, you search for anything and everything shiny and valuable.</p>
<p>Funday Games promises that the 1.0 update will be "<em>the biggest update we've ever made</em>," though the exact details of the update remain unclear. Fans are hoping that it will include the anticipated endless mode, which was previously delayed from the last content update for Survivor, as Funday Games opted to focus on getting Deep Rock Galactic: Survivor ready for its September 1.0 release instead.</p>
<p><iframe title="Deep Rock Galactic: Survivor - 1.0 Release Date Trailer | The Triple-i Initiative" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Fxv51gpDO3g?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The trailer for its release date does show players, though, that a new mechanic, 'Gear,' will be added with 1.0. Unfortunately, we don't have any concrete answers to how players get it, what functions gear has, or any other questions players have about it. Funday is holding off on those details until the game's release is closer.</p>
<p>Deep Rock Galactic: Survivor's release date wasn't the only news from Ghost Ship Games during the Triple-I Initiative Showcase, as we also got word that a closed alpha test for <a href="https://wccftech.com/deep-rock-galactic-rogue-core-is-a-roguelite-spin-off-of-the-popular-co-op-game/">Deep Rock Galactic: Rogue Core</a> will be taking place soon, ahead of the game's early access launch. You can sign up for a chance to participate in that playtest on Rogue Core's <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2605790/Deep_Rock_Galactic_Rogue_Core/">Steam page</a>.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>