<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 18:31:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Developers of The God Slayer ‘Do Not Want to Use AI Too Much’]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-god-slayer-developers-do-not-want-to-use-ai-too-much/</link>
            <guid>1374523</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/the-god-slayer-is-an-open-world-steampunk-action-rpg-from-the-makers-of-my-time-series/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The God Slayer</a> is the next big project in development at Chinese developer Pathea Games, known for My Time at Portia, My Time at Sandrock, and the upcoming third installment in that series, My Time at Evershine. </p>



<p>With The God Slayer, the studio is challenging itself with a more mature open world steampunk action RPG, not to mention switching engines from Unity to Epic's Unreal Engine 5. I recently <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-god-slayer-qa-from-our-point-of-view-weve-always-been-making-open-world-rpgs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">interviewed</a> Zifei Wu, founder and creative director at Pathea Games, to learn more about the game. During that conversation, I also inquired about the studio's stance on using generative AI tools during game development. You can find his answer below.</p>



<p><em>I think the only AI we use is when we're iterating. Like, for example, we say okay, we want this character to be a female salesperson, and then we'll try to use AI to go online to search for different models and stuff like that, and then after that, we just do it ourselves. I think overall, our developers don't want to use AI too much. First of all, you don't see a lot of Asian steampunk examples out there, so the examples that AI gives us are weird if I can put it that way. So, a lot of the stuff we actually have to think about ourselves and start from scratch. Overall, that's helped us keep the world setting as well as the characters of The God Slayer grounded. So I think, as far as like for us, I think we're not using too much AI. It's at least for now, the correct way to go.</em></p>



<p>The usage of generative AI tools is currently one of the most controversial topics within most industries, and that certainly includes the gaming industry. We recently reported that Masahiro Sakurai, the creator of Super Smash Bros., <a href="https://wccftech.com/super-smash-bros-creator-development-ai/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">believes</a> that generative AI could make large-scale development more manageable. Hideo Kojima, the creator of the Metal Gear and Death Stranding franchises, <a href="https://wccftech.com/hideo-kojima-sees-creating-together-with-ai-way-stay-one-step-ahead/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">aims</a> to utilize the technology to automate basic tasks, allowing him to focus on the creative aspects of game development.</p>



<p>In an interview with Wccftech, Richard Pillosu, co-founder of Spanish indie developer Epictellers Entertainment, <a href="https://wccftech.com/theres-no-point-using-ai-for-any-creative-endeavor-says-game-developer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">shared</a> a similar, albeit more unequivocal, opinion, stating that there is no point in using AI in any creative endeavour. In another Wccftech exclusive, Dean Hall, known for DayZ and ICARUS, <a href="https://wccftech.com/dayz-creator-says-ai-fears-remind-him-people-worrying-about-google-wikipedia-ai-is-here/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a> that AI is here and what really matters is how to deal with its impact. Lastly, Take-Two CEO Strauss Zelnick <a href="https://wccftech.com/take-two-ceo-says-game-characters-should-be-ai-trained-human-scripts-more-natural-conversations/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">noted</a> that game characters could feel more realistic if AI-trained on scripts created by humans.</p>



<p>The God Slayer will be released for PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series S|X, and potentially for next-gen platforms if available at the game's launch.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/the-god-slayer-developers-do-not-want-to-use-ai-too-much/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>