<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:46:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2077 Celebrates 5th Anniversary with Heavy Discount, New Trading Card Game and More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-celebrates-5th-anniversary-heavy-dsicount-new-trading-card-game/</link>
            <guid>1378369</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>It's been exactly five years since CD Projekt RED released Cyberpunk 2077. Today, the Polish studio is celebrating the fifth anniversary of its most recent game with a series of initiatives, including a special trailer looking back on the emotional story experienced by the protagonist, V, and the players while in the City of Legends.</p>



<p>It's been a whirlwind for sure, both in and out of the game. Riding on the hype guaranteed by the success of The Witcher III: Wild Hunt, Cyberpunk 2077 <a href="https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-is-the-biggest-digital-launch-ever-refunds-didnt-substantially-affect-aggregate-sales-says-superdata/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">had the biggest digital game launch of all time</a> based on revenue and units (10.2 million units sold), but the game's bugs and performance issues on previous generation consoles (PlayStation 4 and Xbox One) heavily damaged its reputation, especially when Sony <a href="https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-delisted-from-playstation-store/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">decided to remove the game from the PlayStation Store</a>, a nearly unprecedented move for such a highi-profile game, until the developer fixed the problems.</p>



<p>CD Projekt RED worked very hard to achieve this, eventually delivering a more refined and expanded experience through various updates (particularly with version 2.0) and the <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/cyberpunk-2077-phantom-liberty-shiny-firmware-update/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">excellent Phantom Liberty expansion</a>. Fans recognized the improvement, and now Cyberpunk 2077 is once again appreciated. Over the past five years, it has sold <a href="https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-eclipses-35-million-copies-sold-cyberpunk-2077-sequel-scales-up/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">more than 35 million units</a>, and more will be sold this Holiday season thanks to the heavy discounts (up to 65% off) available now across multiple storefronts. The game also has a sequel <a href="https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-sequel-might-include-multiplayer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">currently in development</a>.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Cyberpunk 2077 5th Anniversary Trailer — City of Legends" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fHrEootHhlc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Meanwhile, Cyberpunk 2077 fans can look forward to the newly announced Cyberpunk Trading Card Game, announced in partnership with WeirdCo. As with most TCGs, a crowdfunding campaign will debut on Kickstarter next year. The Cyberpunk TCG will let players assemble the ultimate edgerunner crew comprising characters from across the franchise, pitting them against opponents in a battle to become Night City legends. Featuring custom artwork, Cyberpunk TCG is designed for trading card players, avid collectors and Cyberpunk franchise fans alike.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Cyberpunk Trading Card Game | Hype Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ChsJ7XMrz14?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Several new partnerships and products were also announced as part of the fifth anniversary celebrations, offering players more ways to engage with the world of Cyberpunk 2077. The Cyberpunk 2077 5th Anniversary Collector’s Set is available to pre-order and gives players the chance to get their hands on secret Arasaka tech. Presented in a steel case, it includes a light-up replica of the Relic biochip from the game, a USB thumb drive containing the game's soundtrack, three holographic tarot cards, and two pins. The Collector's Set is available with or without Cyberpunk 2077 Ultimate Edition via the CD PROJEKT RED Gear Store.</p>



<p>In partnership with Corsair, an Arasaka Edition <a href="https://fave.co/48HjOR1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">keyboard</a>, <a href="https://fave.co/4a9YYw6" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">mouse</a>, and <a href="https://fave.co/44gYErQ" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">mousepad</a> have also been made available for pre-order, bringing a touch of the megacorp lifestyle to players' setups.</p>



<p>Brand-new Displates featuring custom artwork inspired by movie posters have also been unveiled, turning iconic Cyberpunk 2077 characters such as Jackie Welles, Panam Palmer, and Adam Smasher into would-be stars. Collectors can <a href="https://fave.co/3MrwfsY" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">purchase</a> these Displates today.</p>



<p>CD PROJEKT RED has teamed up with Viture to create the limited-edition Cyberpunk 2077 Luma Cyber XR Glasses. These high-tech glasses are now available for purchase <a href="https://www.viture.com/product/viture-x-cyberpunk-2077-luma-cyber-xr-glasses?color=Jet+Black&amp;size=Regular+%28IPD+58-70mm%29" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">at the Viture store</a> for $549. Lastly, Madrinas has a new Cyberpunk 2077 collection, featuring an anniversary cold brew and shaker set, <a href="https://madrinas.com/products/cyberpunk-2077-anniversary-bundle" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">available for pre-order at $32.99</a>.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-celebrates-5th-anniversary-heavy-dsicount-new-trading-card-game/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Losing Hope For a Half-Life 3 Announcement? Get a Glimpse of the Future of the Series in New Half-Life 2 RTX Remix Comparison]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/losing-hope-for-a-half-life-3-announcement-get-a-glimpse-of-the-future-of-the-series-in-new-half-life-2-rtx-remix-comparison/</link>
            <guid>1378237</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Half-Life 3 is a game that no fan of the series thought would ever see the light of day. Although the game hasn't been revealed yet, there have been <a href="https://wccftech.com/half-life-3-playtested-summer-reveal/"><strong>numerous indications over the past few months that Valve may be working on a new entry in the series</strong></a>. However, if the wait for an announcement is becoming unbearable, you can get a glimpse of the potential future of the series in a new look at the impressive <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-half-life-2-rtx-demo-is-an-excellent-showcase-of-rtx-remixs-possibilities/"><strong>Half-Life 2 RTX Remix mod</strong></a>.</p>



<p>A new look at one of the most impressive modding projects, powered by NVIDIA's modding tool, was provided a few days ago by a new comparison video from <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://www.youtube.com/@MxBenchmarkPC"><strong data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)">MxBench</strong><strong>m</strong><strong data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)">arkPC</strong></a>. The video compares the vanilla release with the latest version of the project, which incorporates significant improvements over its initial launch.</p>



<p>Although the performance hit on an RTX 5080 GPU is considerable, the new PBR assets, GPU and CPU performance improvements, lighting enhancements, improved volumetric fog and water, and the new tonemapper which prevents image from being too bright make this mod worth a try for fans of the series who want to experience the game like never before.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Half-Life 2 Path Tracing with RTX Remix After Months of Updates - Graphics/Performance Comparison" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rkWv-usrOcA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>As mentioned above, Half-Life 3 is no longer a fever dream of fans of the series, but a concrete possibility. Although the <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed"><a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://wccftech.com/half-life-3-hopes-reignited-insiders-suggest-its-announcement-is-still-coming/">rumored 2025 announcement</a></strong> of the <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><a data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" href="https://wccftech.com/half-life-3-hlx-optimization/">project known as HLX</a></strong> may not materialize, <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/half-life-3-hlx-end-of-development/">Valve is undoubtedly actively working on it</a></strong>, adding new features to the Source 2 engine over the past few months that will likely be incorporated into the game. Some of these will reportedly make <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed"><a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://wccftech.com/half-life-3-is-reportedly-getting-announced-soon-but-how-will-it-play/">Half-Life 3 a very immersive experience</a></strong> that should make the wait since the launch of Half-Life:Alyx well worth it.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/losing-hope-for-a-half-life-3-announcement-get-a-glimpse-of-the-future-of-the-series-in-new-half-life-2-rtx-remix-comparison/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>