<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 10:18:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hollow Knight: Silksong Already Passed 5 Million Players, and Its Audience Largely Overlaps with Soulslike Fans]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/hollow-knight-silksong-5-million-audience-overlaps-soulslike/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hollow-knight-silksong-already-passed-5-million-players-and-its-audience-largely-overlaps-with-soulslike-fans.1292241/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>There's little doubt that Hollow Knight: Silksong is another smashing success for indie developer Team Cherry. Following the award-winning release of Hollow Knight in 2017, the Australian team immediately set to work on the sequel, which, however, was delayed several times, worrying fans in the process.</p>



<p>Now that it's out on PC and consoles, though, Hollow Knight: Silksong has already garnered widespread acclaim and broken records. We <a href="https://wccftech.com/hollow-knight-silksong-breaks-players-peak-gets-luma-hdr-mod/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reported</a> a few days ago that it had surpassed 562K concurrent players on Steam, and that was just one platform. </p>



<p>Today, Rhys Elliott from Alinea Analytics has <a href="https://alineaanalytics.substack.com/p/silksong-passed-5m-players-in-three?" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">shared</a> more in-depth data about the game's popularity. According to Alinea, the game has already passed five million players across all platforms in three days, including over a million just on console Game Pass. Most of those players came from Steam, though, where over three million players purchased the game, generating around $50 million in revenue.</p>



<p>That is perhaps not unexpected, given that Hollow Knight: Silksong had been included in the Steam wishlists of 5.2 million users, more than any game scheduled to launch this year. Alinea Analytics data reveals that the US, China, Russia, Japan, and Brazil were the top countries on Steam, while the PlayStation audience is different: 30% from North America, 14% from Western Europe, and 14% from Eastern Asia.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>The genuine surprise came from the fact that the game's audience apparently overlaps with Soulslike fans, as shown in the infographics above. Despite the different genre, they clearly enjoy the game's tight, challenging gameplay.</p>



<p>2025 was another strong year so far for indie games, but Hollow Knight: Silksong outsold them all by a considerable margin. Alinea Analytics reports that, after three days, these were the four best-selling games on Steam:</p>



<ul>
<li>R.E.P.O. - 253K units</li>



<li>PEAK - 332K units</li>



<li>Schedule - 858K units</li>



<li>Hollow Knight: Silksong - 3 million units</li>
</ul>



<p>Having said that, Silksong came with a lot of hype, whereas the others only became popular over time after their respective releases. As such, a more appropriate comparison will have to wait.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/hollow-knight-silksong-5-million-audience-overlaps-soulslike/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy VII Rebirth Rumored to Launch in 2026 for Xbox Series and Nintendo Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-rumored-launch-2026-xbox-series-nintendo-switch-2/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-rumored-to-launch-in-2026-for-xbox-series-and-nintendo-switch-2.1292205/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1n9qetv/comment/ncoma6b/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">According to insider NatetheHate</a>, Square Enix is preparing to launch Final Fantasy VII Rebirth on Xbox Series S|X and Nintendo Switch 2 consoles sometime in 2026.</p>



<p>The rumor admittedly doesn't come as a huge surprise. The Japanese publisher has long since turned a new leaf from its PlayStation exclusivity days, <a href="https://wccftech.com/square-enix-unveils-new-business-plan-with-aggressive-multiplatform-strategy-and-quality-over-quantity-focus/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">vowing to bring more of its games to other consoles</a> as well. Moreover, the first game in the remake trilogy, Final Fantasy VII Remake, is officially heading to both platforms at some point in this Winter season.</p>



<p>It only stands to reason that the second entry, Final Fantasy VII Rebirth, would soon follow. After all, Final Fantasy VII Rebirth already made it to PC earlier this year, and its debut on the platform <a href="https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-is-january-2025s-third-best-selling-game-in-the-us-thanks-to-its-pc-release/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">helped the game reach third place in January's Circana best-selling games chart for the United States</a>.</p>



<p>Rebirth also received even higher acclaim from the press and fans alike than its predecessor. On Wccftech, the game <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">got a rare perfect score</a> from reviewer Kai Tatsumoto:</p>



<p><em>If there’s one word to describe Final Fantasy VII Rebirth, it would be ambitious. Tetsuya Nomura, Kazushige Nojima, and the rest of Creative Business Unit I at Square-Enix have turned what is merely the remainder of Final Fantasy VII’s Disc One upon leaving Midgar into a 100-hour-long epic. Moments of distracted exploration throughout the massive wide-open environments are often bookended with more linear story segments that balance comedy and somber moments. Players will feel more intimately engrossed with the story of those chosen by the planet and routinely have their fond memories of playing the original tickled with delight. Final Fantasy VII Rebirth is an absolute must-play for fans of the series.</em></p>



<p>Meanwhile, Square Enix is of course also working on the third and final chapter of the Final Fantasy VII remake trilogy. In fact, franchise director Tetsuya Nomura <a href="https://wccftech.com/kingdom-hearts-4-final-fantasy-vii-remake-part-3-tetsuya-nomura/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">assured fans</a> just a few days ago that the development is 'on schedule'. We could be looking at a 2028 release window, if the four-year gap between Remake and Rebirth is anything to go by, but it's too early to be any more accurate.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-rumored-launch-2026-xbox-series-nintendo-switch-2/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Wars Outlaws to Get Nintendo Switch 2 Demo Later This Year]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/star-wars-outlaws-nintendo-switch-2-demo-this-year/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/star-wars-outlaws-to-get-nintendo-switch-2-demo-later-this-year.1292199/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Star Wars Outlaws, Ubisoft Massive's open galaxy action/adventure game, launched a year ago to mildly positive reviews from critics. However, the game <a href="https://wccftech.com/star-wars-outlaws-has-only-sold-1-million-copies-since-launch-learning-curve-assassins-creed-shadows/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sold a lot less than Ubisoft had hoped for</a>, making it a key factor in the publisher's subsequent decision to delay Assassin's Creed Shadows from its original November 2024 release window to March 20, 2025, in a bid to avoid the same fate.</p>



<p>Over time, Massive improved various aspects of the game (such as the <a href="https://wccftech.com/star-wars-outlaws-will-be-patched-to-improve-those-annoying-insta-fail-stealth-missions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">annoying stealth missions that instantly failed upon being spotted</a>) and released the two promised story DLCs, A Pirate's Fortune and Wild Card. The game never really bounced back in popularity, though, and Ubisoft CEO Yves Guillemot eventually <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-ceo-blames-star-wars-outlaws-failure-on-the-ip-says-no-game-can-be-supported-forever/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">commented</a> that the state of the Star Wars IP played its part in the mixed reception from players.</p>



<p>Star Wars Outlaws has now just launched on the Nintendo Switch 2, however. On this platform, it has a chance of making a better impression from the get-go since it includes all the free updates and DLCs released up to this point. Moreover, despite worries that the technically advanced game powered by the Snowdrop engine would struggle on the hybrid handheld console, it turns out that Massive <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-star-wars-outlaws-well-docked/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">did a great job at porting the game</a> despite the technical limitations. Now, Ubisoft has <a href="https://www.ubisoft.com/en-us/game/star-wars/outlaws/news-updates/1kKhQ1Heps7YmSJdFiV87L/switch-2-release-faq" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">confirmed</a> that you can expect a free demo to go live soon, in case you want to get a taste of Kay Vess and Nix before purchasing.</p>



<p>If you've enjoyed the game and are hoping this release could spearhead a sequel, though, that ship might have already sailed. According to a recent rumor from Tom Henderson, Ubisoft has already <a href="https://wccftech.com/star-wars-outlaws-sequel-recently-canceled-rumor-ubisoft/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">canceled a Star Wars Outlaws sequel</a> that was still in its early development stages and had not entered full production yet. </p>



<p>It's too bad, as this was one of the few Star Wars games not at all centered on Force users. Star Wars 1313 and Project Ragtag were other two such projects, of course, and we all know that both got canceled before ever making it to the market. The only remaining hope is Amy Hennig's untitled Star Wars game, which was announced in April 2022. She is also currently working on Marvel 1943: Rise of Hydra, which is now <a href="https://wccftech.com/amy-hennig-and-skydance-games-marvel-1943-rise-of-hydra-delayed-into-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">set to launch next year</a>. Chances are we won't learn any more about the Star Wars project until the Marvel one is released.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/star-wars-outlaws-nintendo-switch-2-demo-this-year/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel’s Wolverine Is Looking Fantastic According to Playtesters, Says Insider]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/marvels-wolverine-looking-fantastic-according-playtesters/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel%E2%80%99s-wolverine-is-looking-fantastic-according-to-playtesters-says-insider.1292193/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Last week, a rumor from Insider Gaming <a href="https://wccftech.com/state-of-play-insomniac-worlverine-playstation-rumor/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">suggested</a> that Insomniac Games and Sony could finally be readying a gameplay reveal for Marvel's Wolverine during another State of Play presentation slated for later this month.</p>



<p>The game was <a href="https://wccftech.com/insomniacs-wolverine-announced-for-playstation-5/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced</a> during a PlayStation Showcase in September 2021. However, in late 2023, Insomniac Games <a href="https://wccftech.com/insomniac-games-hacked-by-a-ransomware-attack-data-surrounding-marvels-wolverine-surfaces-online/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">suffered a major hack</a> of its staff's personal data and the studio's upcoming projects, chiefly the Wolverine game. This inevitably led to a delay - the game was previously <a href="https://wccftech.com/marvels-wolverine-hard-r-not-fully-open-world-2024-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">rumored</a> to be targeting a 2024 or 2025 release window, which clearly did not pan out as originally intended.</p>



<p>The good news for fans of Marvel's Wolverine is that not only is the unveiling close, but according to the same source, Tom Henderson, playtesters have been very impressed with the game. The insider even hinted that the reveal might come with a release date, though that sounds more like a personal hope than hard knowledge. Here's the quote from the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ebz9vqIyNhc&amp;t=2284s" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">latest Insider Gaming podcast</a>:</p>



<p><em>I heard that there was going to be or there is going to be a State of Play towards the end of the month, and then, separately, from a person who I've known for years and has given me the most reliable information you can get, he then said that the Wolverine trailer is done. You put two and two together, it suggests that Marvel's Wolverine trailer is done because it's going to be at the State of Play in September. It might not be. And if it isn't, then possibly The Game Awards. We all know that Geoff Keighley likes his big reveals. Or who knows, maybe there's another event.<br></em><br><em>So, it is done. It obviously was delayed to quite a big extent. From what I've managed to hear, from people working on the project, obviously, the ransomware attack and all the game leaking is one thing, but then the emotional strain that it places on people when you have all of your information leaked, like your address, social security numbers, and all that kind of stuff, is massive. So that obviously delayed the game as well. But from a few playtesters I've been speaking to, they think the game looks fantastic. So that's good news, and fingers crossed we get to see a release date in a couple of weeks' time. </em></p>



<p>We don't really know anything concrete in terms of game features about Marvel's Wolverine. What we do know is that the original Creative Director and Game Director for the project, Brian Horton and Cameron Christian (who had previously worked on 2020's <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/marvels-spider-man-miles-morales-ps5-champion-of-the-people/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Marvel's Spider-Man: Miles Morales</a>), were replaced last year by Marcus Smith and Mike Daly, who worked on 2021's <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/ratchet-clank-rift-apart-purpose-ps5/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ratchet and Clank: Rift Apart</a>.</p>



<p>Additionally, it has been previously hinted by Marvel's Spider-Man and Spider-Man 2 Creative Director Bryan Intihar that there might be a crossover with Wolverine at some point. If we had to guess, though, that could be happening later down the line, and the Friendly Neighborhood superhero probably would only appear as a cameo in Marvel's Wolverine.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/marvels-wolverine-looking-fantastic-according-playtesters/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>