<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 05:23:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2077 Won’t Be Getting a PS5 Pro Patch Anytime Soon]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-wont-be-getting-a-ps5-pro-patch-anytime-soon/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cyberpunk-2077-won%E2%80%99t-be-getting-a-ps5-pro-patch-anytime-soon.1041171/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-wont-be-getting-a-ps5-pro-patch-anytime-soon/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>In a short and sweet post on X by CD Projekt Red on the official Cyberpunk 2077 X account, they confirmed that there are no plans for a PS5 Pro patch. For many, this comes as a huge disappointment, especially since the game has come such a long way from how it was when it was first released. When Cyberpunk 2077 was first released, the game was incredibly buggy and wasn't performing the way many had expected from CD Projekt Red. After all, this is a company that made award-winning games like The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt. However, since that time, the game has improved significantly, with a smoother performance, stunning graphics, and a great story for many to get lost in.</p>
<p>With the release of the PS5 Pro, many huge titles on PlayStation have been confirmed to be getting a PS5 Pro patch, which will enhance the game to work with the new hardware within the PS5 Pro to provide frame rate boosts and better-looking graphics. To celebrate the PS5 Pro, Sony has proudly announced that there are at least 40 or 50 games that will get the PS5 Pro patch on launch. However, there has been <a href="https://wccftech.com/ps5-pro-has-double-the-amount-of-enhanced-games-than-ps4-pro-at-launch/">an updated list</a> since then that confirms over 80 games will be getting the PS5 Pro patch when the console launches or when the game is set to release.</p>
<p>CD Projekt Red confirmed that there will be no PS5 patch anytime soon after a user named <a href="https://x.com/CyberpunkGame/status/1859151714747552122" target="_blank" rel="noopener">NextGenNero reached out on X</a> to ask whether it will be getting one. They stated, "We currently have no plans for the PS5 Pro patch," which led to a lot of fans of the game being disappointed by the news.</p>
<p>While Cyberpunk 2077 has no plans for getting a PS5 Pro patch, games such as Silent Hill 2, Star Wars Jedi: Survivor, and Alan Wake 2 have been confirmed to get patches to supposedly enhance the game on the new expensive version of the PlayStation 5. However, these games, in particular, have had mixed results, as confirmed by tests by Digital Foundry. That being said, they have tested some other top games on the PS5 Pro and given the new patches a whirl, and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2024-ps5-pro-hands-on-preview-is-it-worth-it" target="_blank" rel="noopener">some games have performed as expected</a>, providing improved frame rates and better graphics.</p>
<p>Whether CD Projekt Red is just waiting it out and plans to do a PS5 Pro patch once audiences have had a chance to experiment with games that are enhanced for the Pro, or they just don't plan to do a patch at all remains to be seen.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>