<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 15:29:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 Might Launch on March 28, Says Italian Website]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-might-launch-on-march-28-says-italian-website/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-might-launch-on-march-28-says-italian-website.1070757/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-might-launch-on-march-28-says-italian-website/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Countless Nintendo Switch 2 rumors have circulated over the past couple of years, but none had nailed down the new console's launch date yet. A few hours ago, the Italian website UAGNA <a href="https://www.uagna.it/videogiochi/esclusiva-ecco-la-data-di-uscita-di-nintendo-switch-2-200465" target="_blank" rel="noopener">shared</a> the rumor that Nintendo Switch 2 accessories (first-party as well as third-party ones) will launch on the market on March 28. As such, they believe this to be the release date for the console, too.</p>
<p>To begin with, we must take this with a big grain of salt. That said, it's not completely out of the realm of possibility. In fact, last month, another rumor <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-march-2025-release/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">pointed</a> to a January reveal and a subsequent late March debut for the console. Just a few days ago, we learned that the date for the announcement could be January 8, 2025.</p>
<p>It would be an accelerated timetable compared to the predecessor. The Switch <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/nintendo-switch-review-gen-hat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">launched</a> on March 3, 2017, but it was first showcased by Nintendo on October 20, 2016. The console was then briefly demonstrated in December at Jimmy Fallon's show, while a proper press event, including the final release date, took place in January. If these rumors are true, Nintendo might be compressing everything into the January unveiling.</p>
<p>The console's specifications have long been shared by leaks and are unlikely to have changed since. Nintendo has once again partnered with NVIDIA, <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-pro-successor-rumored-nvidia-tegra239-soc-confirmed-to-be-real-to-feature-8-core-cpu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">choosing their Tegra 239 SoC</a>, which is a customized version of the Orin SoC originally announced in 2018. It will be powered by an eight-core CPU with 12x ARM Cortex-A78AE cores and a GPU based on the Ampere architecture featuring 2048 CUDA Cores. Support for NVIDIA DLSS Super Resolution and Ray Reconstruction is believed to be included.</p>
<p>However, it seems that the Nintendo Switch 2 will only <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-dock-4k-30-fps-only/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">output at 4K resolution and 30 frames per second</a> when docked. If confirmed, this would undoubtedly be disappointing for a new console that debuts in 2025—rival consoles from Sony and Microsoft have supported not only 60 frames per second but now even up to 120 frames per second for years.</p>
<p>So far, analysts are bullish on the new hardware's sales prospects, believing that the new platform <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-sell-17-million-units/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">could sell 80 million units by 2028</a>. Of course, a lot will depend on the games. The long-awaited Metroid Prime 4 could be a cross-platform launch like The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild for the Switch, but the new hardware (despite the <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-officially-confirmed-to-be-backward-compatible/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">confirmed backward compatibility</a>) will need some brand new titles to really gain traction.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wccftech’s Best DLC/Expansion of 2024 – Give Us More!]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-dlc-expansion-of-2024-give-us-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wccftech%E2%80%99s-best-dlc-expansion-of-2024-%E2%80%93-give-us-more.1070559/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-dlc-expansion-of-2024-give-us-more/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>This year, many awesome games were released, and some fantastic DLCs and expansions for games for titles that debuted in previous years were also launched. Some of them were completely unexpected, while others had people waiting eagerly for the DLC to unlock on their device so that they could get stuck in. Here is Wccftech's best DLC/expansion of 2024.</p>
<p><em>Previously on Wccftech's Best Games of 2024: <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-shooter-games-of-2024-fun-blasts-for-everyone/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Shooters</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-roleplaying-games-of-2024-a-year-for-the-history-books/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RPGs</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-indie-games-of-2024-full-house/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Indies</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-fighting-games-of-2024-the-return-of-the-strongest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fighting</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-horror-games-of-2024-a-bloody-massacre/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Horror</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-action-games-of-2024-no-enemy-left-standing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Action</a></em></p>

<figure></figure>

<h2>Alan Wake 2: Night Springs (8.5/10)</h2>
<p>Alan Wake 2 has received two DLCs, both of which were released this year. Night Springs came out stronger than The Lake House. Both were phenomenal and the perfect addition to the Remedy universe. In typical Alan Wake fashion, the story was wild and unpredictable but a ton of fun to dive into.</p>
<p>Admittedly, it is starkly different from the game it's attached to. It doesn't have much to do with the main characters of Alan Wake 2 and instead takes you on three individual characters' journeys, including Control protagonist Jesse Faden. Below is an excerpt from the review written by Francesco De Meo.</p>
<p><em>While the gameplay is pretty much in line with the North Star episode, this episode is considerably better than the other two and the one that feels the closest to the base experience. It is possibly even more daring than the base game in terms of visual presentation, masterfully blending together some very different styles, something that alone makes it worth the price of admission.</em></p>

<figure></figure>

<h2>Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree (<a href="https://wccftech.com/review/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-worthy-of-the-greater-wills-blessing/">10/10</a>)</h2>
<p>Starting off strong, Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree is an absolutely fantastic expansion to Elden Ring and has so much content that it's basically the same value as a whole game for half the price. This was eagerly awaited by many and was even given a perfect score by Francesco De Meo:</p>
<p><em>Shadow of the Erdtree's open-world design stands out as a testament to how the Elden Ring experience still surpasses anything else on the market. As such, I believe a perfect score is justified, even with the evident lack of significant innovation and some technical hiccups.</em></p>
<p>It introduced some great bosses and more lore for the Elden Ring universe. Players got to face off against some of the hardest bosses the Elden Ring universe has seen, with new ways to level up and gain strength to carry them through the DLC. FromSoftware can do no wrong, or so it seems anyway.</p>

<figure></figure>

<h2>Final Fantasy XIV: Dawntrail</h2>
<p>This year also saw the release of a new expansion for one of the most loved MMORPGs on the market right now. Dawntrail is the latest DLC for Final Fantasy XIV, a DLC that is brilliant in its own right but doesn't quite stand up to the excellence of Shadowbringers or Endwalker, for example. However, the game hasn't really ever experienced a terrible expansion, and all have elements that are enjoyable in their own way.</p>
<p>The same goes for Dawntrail, which introduced new Jobs (playable classes) for players to pick up, too. Players now have the option to play as a <a href="https://wccftech.com/how-to/how-to-unlock-viper-in-ffxiv-dawntrail/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Viper</a> or a <a href="https://wccftech.com/how-to/how-to-unlock-pictomancer-in-ffxiv-dawntrail/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pictomancer</a>, which are two incredibly fun classes to get into.</p>

<figure></figure>

<h2>Dredge: The Iron Rig</h2>
<p>Dredge is a fantastic game that blends the "cozy game" genre with a hint of horror. The game takes you on a solo fishing adventure, where everything is not quite as it seems. Soon, you're fishing up <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2561450/DREDGE__The_Iron_Rig/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lovecraftian horrors</a> from the ocean and making a quick buck by selling them to a vendor who doesn't seem all too surprised.</p>
<p>This year saw the release of The Iron Rig, the second official expansion for the game. It adds another couple of hours to the game and allows you to build the newest destination, with 50 new fish to catch and more achievements to get. Compared to the base game, this expansion is more focused on the fishing element, which is perfect for those who enjoy that element of the game.</p>

<figure></figure>

<h2>World of Warcraft: The War Within (<a href="https://wccftech.com/review/world-of-warcraft-the-war-within-better-than-ever/">9.5/10</a>)</h2>
<p>World of Warcraft is a game that often gets a lot of hate, as they have released some expansions that haven't done the game justice and led to the game nearly dying (thank you, Shadowlands.) However, The War Within is an expansion done right, introducing a fun new villain from the Void. The new zones are gorgeous (albeit a bit laggy in Dornogal), with a lot of fun side quests, dailies and a great campaign that is still being added to.</p>
<p>When it comes to expansions being accessible, The War Within is up there as one of the best. The focus is no longer strictly on those who want to do Mythic+ dungeons and Mythic Raiding, and there's a shift of focus over to those who enjoy questing and doing single-player content or multiplayer content with minimal consequences. Here's my summary from the review:</p>
<p><em>Overall, World of Warcraft: The War Within has been a delight to experience, from fun and rewarding mount grinds to surprisingly adorable pets (looking at you, Oop'lajax), as well as some genuinely heartbreaking quests that you get to experience in the main story campaign.</em></p>
<h2>Community Poll</h2>
<p>What was your favorite DLC or expansion of 2024? Vote in the poll below!</p>
<div id="democracy-1379" data-opts="{&quot;ajax_url&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/wccftech.com\/wp-admin\/admin-ajax.php&quot;,&quot;pid&quot;:1379,&quot;max_answs&quot;:0,&quot;answs_max_height&quot;:&quot;500&quot;,&quot;anim_speed&quot;:&quot;400&quot;,&quot;line_anim_speed&quot;:1500}"><p><strong>Best DLC/Expansion of 2024</strong></p></div>
<h2>Honorable Mentions</h2>
<p>Here are some other expansions and DLC that came out this year that deserve a mention, just in case the others in this list didn't do it for you.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/alan-wake-2-the-lake-house-whos-the-real-monster/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Alan Wake 2: The Lake House</a></li>
<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/diablo-iv-vessel-of-hatred-systems-galore/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Diablo IV: Vessel of Hatred</a></li>
<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/destiny-2-the-final-shape-gets-launch-trailer-ahead-of-next-weeks-debut/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Destiny 2: The Final Shape</a></li>
<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-xvi-the-rising-tide-dlc-release-date/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Final Fantasy XVI: The Rising Tide</a></li>
<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/dead-island-2-sola-a-festival-to-undie-for/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dead Island 2: SoLa</a></li>
</ul>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>