<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 13:42:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Techland Wants to Switch to a 3-4 Year Cycle Starting with Dying Light: The Beast]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/techland-wants-to-switch-to-a-3-4-year-cycle-starting-with-dying-light-the-beast/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/techland-wants-to-switch-to-a-3-4-year-cycle-starting-with-dying-light-the-beast.1221777/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/techland-wants-to-switch-to-a-3-4-year-cycle-starting-with-dying-light-the-beast/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>At Summer Game Fest 2025, Wccftech's Kai Tatsumoto met with Techland Dying Light Franchise Director Tymon Smektala to discuss the Polish studio's upcoming game, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3008130/Dying_Light_The_Beast/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dying Light: The Beast</a>.</p>
<p>Ahead of the full interview's publication, here's an interesting tidbit: Smektala not only defends the decision to make Dying Light: The Beast a standalone game (it started as a DLC for Dying Light 2: Stay Human) but also reveals that Techland wishes to release games more often, shortening their average development cycles.</p>
<p><em>I understand why some players might think, 'oh, it started as a small thing and now they charge full price, they just want to sell it as the next game.' But it actually is, it is the return of Kyle Crane. The campaign is comparable to the previous games, and I think it really is the best Dying Light game we have ever made.&nbsp; One day, we realized we had a new game on our hands.</em></p>
<p><em>That realization is also something that we would like to assume moving forward as a developer. Because both Dying Light 1 and 2 took seven years to make. We think that with a slightly different approach, with a bigger focus, we can release games more often. We are probably looking at a three or four year cycle, and I think that Dying Light: The Beast is the first step in that direction.</em></p>
<p>Indeed, when you consider that Dying Light 2: Stay Human <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/dying-light-2-stay-human-apocalypse-divided/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">launched</a> in February 2022 and Dying Light: The Beast is <a href="https://wccftech.com/dying-light-the-beast-launches-on-august-22/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">set to launch</a> in late August 2025, there's just about three and a half years between the two releases. More importantly, this strategy stands out in stark opposition to regular triple-A development, which is continuously getting longer. Nowadays, the average triple-A game requires five or more years to be properly finished, assuming things don't go very wrong somewhere in the process.</p>
<p>It is undoubtedly a bold strategy from Techland, though we'll have to play Dying Light: The Beast first before assessing if it can be successfully pulled off. Stay tuned for our full interview with Tymon Smektala, which is going up shortly.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[$1.4 Million Worth Of Nintendo Switch 2 Consoles Were Stolen On Their Way To GameStop]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/1-4-million-worth-of-nintendo-switch-2-consoles-were-stolen-on-their-way-to-gamestop/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/1-4-million-worth-of-nintendo-switch-2-consoles-were-stolen-on-their-way-to-gamestop.1221774/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/1-4-million-worth-of-nintendo-switch-2-consoles-were-stolen-on-their-way-to-gamestop/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A truck transporting <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/nintendo-switch-2-console/">Nintendo Switch 2</a> consoles from Nintendo's headquarters in Washington to a GameStop in Texas was robbed before the consoles could complete their journey. The perpetrator(s) stole 2,810 consoles, approximately $1.4 million worth of Switch 2 devices.</p>
<p>The theft was reported while the truck was stopped in Bennett, Colorado, where, according to a local report from <a href="https://www.denver7.com/news/crime/colorado-authorities-investigate-theft-of-nearly-3k-nintendo-switch-2-consoles-from-semi-truck">ABC Denver 7</a>, the driver noticed the semi-truck had been broken into during a pre-drive inspection.</p>
<p>It's currently unknown when the theft happened on the journey from Washington. The semi-truck had been sitting at a truck stop in Bennett called Love's Truck Stop when the driver spotted the theft. The driver also claimed not to know what was in the semi, only that it was games or toys.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>The investigation into the theft is still ongoing, but for now, somewhere in the US, there are nearly 3,000 Switch 2 consoles floating around that, unless they're found, Nintendo won't be adding to their total units sold numbers. Anyone who may have tips about the theft is encouraged to call 720-874-8477.</p>
<p>In just the first four days after launch, the <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-debuts-with-3-5-million-units-sold-in-4-days/">Nintendo Switch 2 sold 3.5 million units</a> globally, with <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-set-another-record-by-selling-1-1-million-units-in-its-launch-week-in-the-us/">1.1 million units</a> being sold in the United States alone in the console's first week on the market. The console is flying off the shelves, <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-nintendo-switch-2-is-selling-twice-as-fast-as-the-og-switch/">selling twice as fast as the original Switch at launch</a>, and in this case, flying out the back of a truck. Even without the nearly 3,000 consoles stolen, the Switch 2 is expected to <a href="https://wccftech.com/switch-2-2025-sales-forecast-bumped-from-15-to-16-million-units-by-dfc-intelligence/">sell upwards of 16 million units in 2025</a>.</p>
<p>It's unfortunate for those in Texas who were looking to grab a Switch 2 that they'll have to wait a little longer for a new batch of consoles to arrive, as long as that next batch isn't robbed as well.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 Makes Widespread Use of NVIDIA DLSS, But May Be Difficult To Spot Due to Differences With Image Characteristics on PC]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-widespread-nvidia-dlss/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-makes-widespread-use-of-nvidia-dlss-but-may-be-difficult-to-spot-due-to-differences-with-image-characteristics-on-pc.1221666/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-widespread-nvidia-dlss/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Although pre-release footage suggested the contrary, the Nintendo Switch 2 makes widespread use of NVIDIA DLSS, but it may be difficult to notice if the upscaler is being used due to differences in image characteristics compared to PC.</p>
<p>Replying to a supporter's question during this week's episode of their podcast, the tech experts at Digital Foundry highlighted how the new Nintendo consoles makes widespread use of the NVIDIA upscaler, saying that it was difficult to say if this was indeed the case before launch due to the image characteristics of Switch 2 DLSS being different from those seen on PC. Based on certain visual elements, however, it is now possible to say if a game is using NVIDIA DLSS on the system, such as the disocclusion and aliased edges patterns seen in the Pokémon Scarlet and Violet update.</p>
<p>Looking further into the matter, the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@DigitalFoundry" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Digital Foundry</a> tech experts also highlighted how there's a good chance that NVIDIA DLSS on Nintendo Switch 2 comes with different modes, like on PC. The most common version seems to be a lightweight version that can easily upscale the resolution to 1080p in handheld mode and to 1440p or 4K in docked mode, but that doesn't do a great job of reconstructing the image in motion. The most glaring example is in Fast Fusion, where NVIDIA DLSS is used to upscale to 4K resolution in docked mode. Image quality is fine in still shots, but in motion, things are much different. Hogwarts Legacy seems to use this lightweight version of DLSS as well, only that the much slower pace of the game, and the higher base resolution deliver much better results, although different from what the upscaler delivers on PC. Besides this lightweight version, however, there seems to be at least another version of NVIDIA DLSS available to developers, as the implementation seen in Cyberpunk 2077 seems to be closer to the PC version, rather than the one seen in the other launch titles.</p>
<p><iframe title="DF Direct Weekly #218: MindsEye Launch Disaster, Next-Gen PS Handheld Specs, Switch 2 Sells 3.5m!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tWlnVVbtNwc?start=4663&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Besides supporting NVIDIA DLSS to deliver better image quality and performance upscaling from lower resolutions, the Nintendo Switch 2 offers plenty of unexpected benefits via its backward compatibility feature. Although updated games take better advantage of the increased system specs over the original system, several unpatched games can<a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-backward-compatibility-better-original-system/"> brute-force better performance in several different titles.</a></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>