<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 14:52:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oblivion Remastered Developer Virtuos Confirms Mass Layoffs, Nearly 280 Staff Impacted Across Europe And Asia]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/oblivion-remastered-developer-virtuos-confirms-mass-layoffs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/oblivion-remastered-developer-virtuos-confirms-mass-layoffs-nearly-280-staff-impacted-across-europe-and-asia.1246158/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Virtuos, the co-development team that is working with Konami to deliver Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater, and the studio that just helped Bethesda develop The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered has <a href="https://www.virtuosgames.com/news/adapting-for-the-future-of-game-development/">confirmed</a> what was previously rumored, that the studio has suffered mass layoffs, with nearly 280 staff impacted, or 7% of the company.</p>



<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/oblivion-remastered-metal-gear-solid-delta-virtuos-mass-layoffs-rumor/">Yesterday</a>, French journalist Gauthier Andres was the first to report the layoffs, along with claims from sources they spoke to about internal troubles at Virtous. Today, Virtuos confirmed the cuts, which, according to Virtuos, are slightly under the 300 number that Andres first reported. Virtuos did not comment on any alleged internal issues, and in its statement claimed that its "<em>immediate focus is on managing this transition with care, transparency, and respect</em>."</p>



<p>"<em>Virtuos is evolving to meet the changing needs of our partners and the industry</em>," its statement began. "<em>As game development grows increasingly complex, we are realigning our global footprint and capabilities to strengthen our offering in high-value co-development, ranging from full game engineering to advanced art, including creative content production and live services</em>."</p>



<p>"<em>This evolution involves a rebalancing of roles across our studios and geographies. Approximately 7% of Virtuos' global workforce was affected, primarily in teams facing lower occupancy and slower demand due to structural shifts in the industry. This includes about 200 roles in Asia and 70 roles in Europe, including</em> <em>fewer than 10 in France, where the core team working on Oblivion Remastered is located</em>."</p>



<p>The statement goes on to explain why so many of the roles impacted are in its studios based in Asia, claiming the studio "<em>need[s] to better match the locations of our teams with those of our clients to support the increasingly iterative nature of creative co-development.</em>"</p>



<p>As far as the other projects Virtuos has on the go, the studio says it "<em>remains fully committed to all our partnerships, including ongoing work on announced titles such as Oblivion Remastered, Cyberpunk 2077, and Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</em>." </p>



<p> A key element of Andres' report from yesterday was how the studio's leadership is pushing to over-deliver in quality compared to the budget the studio is given. The Oblivion Remastered team was allegedly pushed to work harder despite Virtuos receiving no royalties on the game's sales, so that the studio could have Oblivion Remastered as a showpiece for the kind of work they are capable of.</p>



<p>That's the kind of strategy that can potentially lead to more contracts, but the only sure result a strategy like that can have is burning out the talent you're trying to show the studio has. </p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/oblivion-remastered-developer-virtuos-confirms-mass-layoffs/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dune: Awakening And Rematch Mark Strong Launches As Both Enter June 2025’s Top 10 Games By Revenue Per Global Firm Newzoo]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/dune-awakening-rematch-newzoo-june-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dune-awakening-and-rematch-mark-strong-launches-as-both-enter-june-2025%E2%80%99s-top-10-games-by-revenue-per-global-firm-newzoo.1246095/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Global data firm <a href="https://newzoo.com/">Newzoo</a> has released its latest report on the top 10 games for June 2025 by both monthly active users (MAU) and revenue. In its report for <a href="https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-nightreign-was-one-of-may-2025s-top-5-games-by-revenue-according-to-newzoo-while-oblivion-remastered-remains-firm-in-the-top-20-for-revenue-and-mau/">May 2025</a>, Elden Ring Nightreign was the top story, but this time around, it's Dune all June, as <a href="https://wccftech.com/dune-awakening-patch-notes-deep-desert-changes/">Dune: Awakening</a> breaks into the top-5 games by revenue, and Sloclap's arcade football game <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/rematch-review-an-excellent-football-game-thats-been-tackled-at-the-knees/">Rematch</a> is able to eek into the top-10.</p>



<p>Nightreign hasn't entirely fallen off the map, to be fair, it's just a few places behind where it sat in May, as Dune: Awakening took Nightreign's place as the number five game in the list of top 10 games by revenue. Rematch, for its part, made it to number nine, while everything else in the top 10 rankings mostly stayed the same, save for Valorant jumping up six places to make it into the top 10 at number seven.</p>



<p>Zooming out a bit more into the top-20, other notable entries are Toby Fox's Deltarune, which snuck in at number 20, and the highly anticipated release of <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-review-in-progress-one-more-for-the-road/">Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</a>, which arrived at the tail-end of June and made it into the top-20 games by revenue in 15th place. </p>



<p>Dead By Daylight was another notable entry in the top-20 games by revenue, in part because it was one of the few games to hold a top-20 spot in both revenue and MAUs for June 2025. It jumped 17 places from May to make it into the top-20 games by revenue for June, and 13 places to do the same in MAUs, both driven by a new collaboration with Five Nights at Freddy's.</p>



<p>The MAU list for June 2025 was less malleable than the revenue list, as very little changed regarding the top 10. <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/elden-ring-nightreign-conquering-the-night/">Elden Ring Nightreign</a>, Rematch, and Splitgate 2 were the only games not in the top-20 for MAUs in May 2025 that were able to jump into the top-20 for June.</p>



<p>Here's Newzoo's full report and overview for June 2025 for the top games on PC and consoles: </p>



<h2 id="h-engagement-highlights">Engagement Highlights</h2>



<ul>
<li><em><strong>Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six Siege X</strong>&nbsp;(#7, +3) ushered in a new chapter with the launch of Siege X. The update introduced a fresh game mode, revamped maps and movement mechanics, and compelling incentives for returning players, introducing rewards based on years of service.</em>&nbsp;&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li><em><strong>NBA 2K25</strong>&nbsp;(#9, +2) rolled out Season 8, coinciding with a major cross-platform sale that boosted player engagement.&nbsp;&nbsp;</em></li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li><em><strong>Star Wars Battlefront II (2017)&nbsp;</strong>(#12, +3) continues to benefit from a community-driven resurgence that began in May. EA capitalized on this momentum by offering steep discounts during the Steam Summer Sale, resulting in a 27% month-over-month increase in monthly active users across all platforms.&nbsp;</em>&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li><em><strong>ELDEN RING NIGHTREIGN&nbsp;</strong>(#13, +20) launched May 29. Thus, the July steep increase in engagement is in line with expectations. Ongoing updates and bug fixes have steadily improved its reception, with Steam reviews climbing to 82% lifetime and 87% recent.</em>&nbsp;&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li><em><strong>Dead by Daylight&nbsp;</strong>(#15, +13) saw its highest engagement in over four years following the release of its Five Nights at Freddy’s crossover DLC on June 17</em>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li><em><strong>REMATCH (2025)&nbsp;</strong>(#16, +45) officially launched on June 19, nearly doubling its engagement compared to the final May playtest - marking a strong debut.</em>&nbsp;&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li><em><strong>Splitgate 2&nbsp;</strong>(#17, +43) officially launched on June 7, introducing the Battle Royale mode for the first time - an addition not available during earlier play tests.</em></li>
</ul>



<figure><figcaption>Image credits: Newzoo</figcaption></figure>



<h2 id="h-revenue-movers-and-breakthroughs">Revenue Movers and Breakthroughs</h2>



<ul>
<li><em><strong>Dune: Awakening</strong>&nbsp;(#5, new) launched on June 10 and attracted 1.3 million players within its first 20 days, underscoring the enduring appeal and strength of the Dune IP.&nbsp;&nbsp;</em></li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li><em><strong>Valorant&nbsp;</strong>(#7, +6) celebrated its fifth anniversary on June 2 with a major update that introduced a new season and new map. The game also saw a significant engagement boost, fueled by a major international tournament&nbsp;&nbsp;</em></li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li><em><strong>REMATCH (2025)</strong>&nbsp;(#9, new) broke into the top 10 highest-grossing games of June following its release. The surge in players on its paid ($29.99) release compared to its free play tests highlights both the game’s quality and the demand for fresh, competitive experiences.</em>&nbsp;&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li><em><strong>League of Legends&nbsp;</strong>(#12, +7) honored Jian "Uzi" Zihao as the second inductee into its Hall of Legends. Commemorative cosmetics celebrating the player were released as part of the tribute.&nbsp;</em>&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li><em><strong>Death Stranding 2: On The Beach&nbsp;</strong>(#15, new) debuted on June 26 as a PlayStation exclusive, selling over 400,000 copies in just the final five days of the month.&nbsp;&nbsp;</em></li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li><em><strong>Dead by Daylight</strong>&nbsp;(#16, +17) partnered with Five Nights at Freddy’s for its latest DLC, released on June 17. This collaboration drove the game’s highest monthly revenue since Newzoo began tracking in April 2020.&nbsp;&nbsp;</em></li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li><em><strong>DELTARUNE&nbsp;</strong>(#20, new) the latest release from the creators of UNDERTALE, launched on June 4 and has already drawn in over one million players, building on the success of its predecessor.&nbsp;</em></li>
</ul>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/dune-awakening-rematch-newzoo-june-2025/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>