<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:56:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wccftech’s Most Anticipated Adventure Games of 2025 – Journeys of All Kinds]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-adventure-games-of-2025-journeys-of-all-kinds/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wccftech%E2%80%99s-most-anticipated-adventure-games-of-2025-%E2%80%93-journeys-of-all-kinds.1094316/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-adventure-games-of-2025-journeys-of-all-kinds/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Last year, fans of adventure games <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-adventure-games-of-2024-all-kinds-of-journeys/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">were treated to a great release schedule</a>. Can 2025 match or even surpass it? Possibly, thanks to several experienced studios like Don't Nod and Hazelight, which have proved to be masters of the genre time and again. We still don't have a release date for The Wolf Among Us 2; Telltale <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-wolf-among-us-2-isnt-canceled-confirms-telltale-games/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">confirmed</a> a few months ago that the long-anticipated sequel isn't canceled, but it doesn't sound like it's coming in 2025. Thankfully, in the meantime, there'll be plenty of fun to be had between triple-A and independent productions.</p>
<p><em>Previously on Wccftech's Most Anticipated Games of 2025: <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-fighting-games-of-2025-off-year/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fighting</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-action-games-of-2025-excellence-ahead/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Action</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-indie-games-of-2025-retro-and-vibrancy/">Indie</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-roleplaying-games-of-2025-heroes-and-monsters/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RPG</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-horror-games-of-2025-new-scares-inbound/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Horror</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-sports-and-racing-games-of-2025-in-the-fast-lane/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sports and Racing</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-strategy-and-simulation-games-of-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Strategy and Simulation</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-shooter-games-of-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Shooter</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-multiplayer-games-of-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Multiplayer</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-dlc-of-2025-give-us-more/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DLC/Expansion</a></em></p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Lost-Records-Bloom-Rage.jpg"></a></figure>

<h2>Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage (February 18, April 15)</h2>
<p>The creators of Life is Strange return with a sort of spiritual successor titled <a href="https://wccftech.com/lost-records-bloom-rage-interview-discussing-the-setting-inspirations-multiple-timelines/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage</a>. The story will be split into two episodes, scheduled to be released around two months apart.</p>
<p>Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage is set in the fictional town of Velvet Cove, Michigan, and features four former friends (Nora, Autumn, Kat, and Swann) who are reunited after 27 years. As Swann, players will actually navigate two different timelines: the Summer of 1995, when their friendship blossomed, and 2022, when the group gets together again despite having sworn not to speak again after they had buried a secret together. Don't Nod promises players will be able to shape both timelines somehow, while dialogue will feel more realistic thanks to the ability to ignore or interrupt what the others have just said. Given the studio's pedigree in the adventure games genre, this is likely one of the most widely anticipated titles.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/SplitFiction_KeyArt_RGB_1920x1080.jpg"></a></figure>

<h2>Split Fiction (March 6)</h2>
<p>After the enormous success of 2021's <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/it-takes-two-love-multi-genre/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">It Takes Two</a>, which won many awards and sold over 20 million copies, Josef Fares and his Hazelight Studio are about to try again with <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-split-fiction-trailer-showcases-co-op-gameplay-and-side-stories/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Split Fiction</a>. Once more, this adventure game has been designed specifically to be played in split-screen cooperative multiplayer, so you'll need a friend to experience it.</p>
<p>This time around, the main characters are Mio and Zoe, two writers who work on sci-fi and fantasy, respectively. The beginning of the narrative sees them being trapped in their own stories after being hooked up to a machine designed to steal their creative ideas. They don't really feel much for one another at first, but they must work together if they are to escape this prison, mastering a variety of skills and overcoming various challenges as they jump between the sci-fi and fantasy worlds they had envisioned in their works.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/southofmidnight-1-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>

<h2>South of Midnight (April 8, PC and Xbox Series S|X)</h2>
<p>The first project developed by Compulsion Games since they were acquired by Microsoft is undoubtedly an action/adventure game with a fair amount of action and puzzles. However, the developers have stressed that the story, rather than the gameplay, is the main focus of <a href="https://wccftech.com/south-of-midnight-is-out-on-april-8/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">South of Midnight</a>. In a fantasy world inspired by Deep Southern Gothic tales, protagonist Hazel suddenly becomes a Weaver, a magic user who repairs broken spirits and bonds.</p>
<p>The stop-motion-inspired visuals are certainly catchy, but Hazel's journey—both across the land and within herself—should take center stage when the game launches in early April.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Karma-The-Dark-World-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>

<h2>KARMA: The Dark World (TBA)</h2>
<p>Shanghai-based developer Pollard Studio managed to stand out among the sea of upcoming new game releases with its debut project, <a href="https://wccftech.com/first-in-a-trilogy-of-trailers-released-for-karma-the-dark-world-paying-homage-to-david-lynch/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">KARMA: The Dark World</a>. The developers described it as a first-person cinematic psychological thriller set in a dystopian 1984 East Germany.</p>
<p>In this alternate timeline, the Leviathan Corporation rules society with an iron fist, controlling its citizens through mass surveillance, strict social class rules, mind-altering drugs, and the promise that the gates to utopia will open for those who obey. As Daniel McGovern, a Roam Agent for Leviathan's Thought Bureau, players will get to use advanced tech to enter the minds of the accused, investigate crime scenes, interview suspects, and report their findings to Leviathan.</p>
<p>Through a combination of investigative tools and interviews, players will solve puzzles and uncover the truth of a dark tale of love, loss, and deception where nothing is what it seems, and every twist and turn brings a new twist to unravel.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/9e3bdf401739725548c412cae9dd92b91b33f553b9f1d050-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<h2>Spirit of the North 2 (TBA)</h2>
<p>The cute fox from 2020's Spirit of the North returns in the sequel to this peculiar adventure game franchise. In Spirit of the North 2, players will be transported to an ancient world in ruins. As a lonely fox, with the help of a wise raven companion, they must find the lost legendary guardians and free them from the grasp of a dark shaman called Grimnir.</p>
<p>These corrupted guardians will have to be defeated and subsequently cleansed in puzzle-based encounters. Developer Infuse Studio also promised a large and ancient open world to explore, filled with history to discover, not to mention challenges to overcome and secrets to unlock.</p>
<h2>Community Poll</h2>
<p>What's your most anticipated among our adventure games list?</p>
<div id="democracy-1401" data-opts="{&quot;ajax_url&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/wccftech.com\/wp-admin\/admin-ajax.php&quot;,&quot;pid&quot;:1401,&quot;max_answs&quot;:0,&quot;answs_max_height&quot;:&quot;500&quot;,&quot;anim_speed&quot;:&quot;400&quot;,&quot;line_anim_speed&quot;:1500}"><p><strong>Most Anticipated Adventure Game of 2025</strong></p></div>
<h2>Honorable Mentions</h2>
<p>Here's five more adventure games slated for 2025 that you should track as they get closer to the respective launch dates.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1299460/Wanderstop/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Wanderstop</a></li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1166940/Dead_Static_Drive/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dead Static Drive</a></li>
<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/forever-skies-co-op-launch-available-today-huge-overhaul-added-in-new-update/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Forever Skies</a></li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2582320/Mixtape/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mixtape</a></li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2806640/The_Talos_Principle_Reawakened/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Talos Principle: Reawakened</a></li>
</ul>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wccftech’s Most Anticipated DLC of 2025 – Give us More!]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-dlc-of-2025-give-us-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wccftech%E2%80%99s-most-anticipated-dlc-of-2025-%E2%80%93-give-us-more.1094157/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-dlc-of-2025-give-us-more/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>2025 is going to be a jam-packed year for new games being released, but who could forget about the many DLCs and expansions that are confirmed to be happening this year? Admittedly, some have yet to be detailed or even announced, but the ones that have been are bound to keep you watching the calendar for their release date. Without further ado, here is Wccftech's most anticipated DLC of 2025.</p>
<p><em>Previously on Wccftech's Most Anticipated Games of 2025: <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-fighting-games-of-2025-off-year/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fighting</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-action-games-of-2025-excellence-ahead/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Action</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-indie-games-of-2025-retro-and-vibrancy/">Indie</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-roleplaying-games-of-2025-heroes-and-monsters/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RPG</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-horror-games-of-2025-new-scares-inbound/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Horror</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-sports-and-racing-games-of-2025-in-the-fast-lane/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sports and Racing</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-strategy-and-simulation-games-of-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Strategy and Simulation</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-shooter-games-of-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Shooter</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-multiplayer-games-of-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Multiplayer</a></em></p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Atomic-Heart-DLC-3-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<h2>Atomic Heart: Enchantment Under the Sea (January 28)</h2>
<p>This expansion actually launches today on PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Xbox Series X|S, Xbox One, and PC. Following its <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/atomic-heart-soviet-bioshock/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">February 2023 launch</a>, Atomic Heart has already received two DLCs, both of which have been welcomed with mixed feelings across the board. However, the third time's the charm, right? In this DLC, you will return to Facility 3826 as Major P-3, with Twin at your side as you go diving into the depths and explore uncharted watery depths to try and save humanity.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/age-of-empires-4HD-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<h2>Age of Empires 4 Untitled DLC (TBA)</h2>
<p>The name of the upcoming DLC hasn't been revealed yet, but World's Edge has confirmed that there will be a new DLC coming at some point in 2025 for Age of Empires 4. So far, the game has received a lot of seasonal content, but it has also received a mixture of <a href="https://wccftech.com/age-of-empires-iv-anniversary-season-3-upate-ottomans-malians/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">free</a> and paid DLC. These DLCs have added the Ottomans and Malians to the game, as well as a paid DLC called The Sultans Ascend, which added other civilizations to the game. Hopefully, the DLC is what the fans have been hoping for.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Indiana-Jones-Giants-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>

<h2>Indiana Jones and The Great Circle - The Order of Giants (TBA)</h2>
<p>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle was <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-indiana-at-his-finest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">one of the best games released in 2024</a>. Needless to say, we're eager to get our hands on its announced story-driven DLC, The Order of Giants, which is included with the purchase of the Premium Edition. As implied by the title, this expansion should shine further light on the secretive organization that the main game reveals to be actually named Nephilim Order. There's little doubt that Indiana will once again face many shenanigans in this new adventure, though we don't know who else might appear in it - could we see other familiar faces from the movies? Only time will tell.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/Lies-of-P-header.jpg"></a></figure>

<h2>Lies of P Untitled DLC (TBA)</h2>
<p>Unfortunately, this is another DLC that doesn't have a <a href="https://wccftech.com/lies-of-p-dlc-to-launch-in-q1-2025-neowiz-now-working-on-a-sci-fi-survival-horror-game/">confirmed release date yet</a>. However, we do know that it is slated for release this year, possibly in the first quarter, while Neowiz is also working on a sequel to Lies of P that is coming in the future. It's uncertain as to what this DLC will be about, but it's perfect for those who enjoyed Lies of P or are wanting more of the soulslike experience.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/rain-world-the-watcher-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>

<h2>Rain World: The Watcher (March 28)</h2>
<p>Rain World has already received a fair bit of new content over the years since its release in 2017, with Downpour being the first major DLC that the game received back in 2023. Luckily, for those who are a fan of the slugcats, Rain World will be getting its second paid DLC, named The Watcher, released on March 28, 2025. While January has been going on for what feels like ten years, it will soon be over, meaning March will be even closer than before.</p>
<h2>Community Poll</h2>
<p>What DLC are you most excited about this year? Vote in the poll below!</p>
<div id="democracy-1400" data-opts="{&quot;ajax_url&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/wccftech.com\/wp-admin\/admin-ajax.php&quot;,&quot;pid&quot;:1400,&quot;max_answs&quot;:0,&quot;answs_max_height&quot;:&quot;500&quot;,&quot;anim_speed&quot;:&quot;400&quot;,&quot;line_anim_speed&quot;:1500}"><p><strong>Most Anticipated DLC of 2025</strong></p></div>
<h2>Honorable Mentions</h2>
<p>There will be plenty of other expansions released this year for a myriad of games, and these deserve an honorable mention.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.ea.com/games/the-sims/the-sims-4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Sims 4 expansions</a></li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1868140/DAVE_THE_DIVER/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dave the Diver: In the Jungle</a></li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1229240/Chained_Echoes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Chained Echoes: Ashes of Elrant</a></li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1244090/Sea_of_Stars/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sea of Stars</a></li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/219990/Grim_Dawn/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Grim Dawn: Fangs of Asterkarn</a></li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1771300/Kingdom_Come_Deliverance_II/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kingdom Come Deliverance 2 expansions</a></li>
</ul>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>