<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 14:44:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GeForce NOW Prepares 5th Anniversary with Avowed, KCD2, Civilization VII and More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/geforce-now-prepares-5th-anniversary-with-avowed-kcd2-civilization-vii-and-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/geforce-now-prepares-5th-anniversary-with-avowed-kcd2-civilization-vii-and-more.1095858/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/geforce-now-prepares-5th-anniversary-with-avowed-kcd2-civilization-vii-and-more/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>With the 5th anniversary of GeForce NOW coming up very soon, NVIDIA promised to add a triple-A game each week in February, including big titles like Warhorse's Kingdom Come: Deliverance II, Obsidian's Avowed, and Firaxis' Civilization VII, among others. Here's the full list of GeForce NOW additions planned for February 2025:</p>
<p>● <a href="https://wccftech.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-ii-gets-2025-post-launch-roadmap/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kingdom Come Deliverance II</a> (New release on Steam, Feb. 4)<br>
● Ambulance Life: A Paramedic Simulator (New Release on Steam, Feb. 6)<br>
● SWORN (New release on Steam, Feb. 6)<br>
● <a href="https://wccftech.com/sid-meiers-civilization-vii-system-requirements-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sid Meier’s Civilization VII</a> (New release on Steam and Epic Games Store, Feb. 11)<br>
● <a href="https://wccftech.com/ex-blizzard-vets-announce-legacy-steel-and-sorcery-early-access-date/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Legacy: Steel &amp; Sorcery</a> (New release on Steam, Feb. 12)<br>
● Tomb Raider IV-VI Remastered (New release on Steam, Feb. 14)<br>
● <a href="https://wccftech.com/avowed-hands-on-preview-eora-from-a-whole-new-perspective/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Avowed</a> (New release on Steam, Battle.net and Xbox, available on PC Game Pass, Feb. 18)<br>
● <a href="https://wccftech.com/lost-records-bloom-rage-interview-discussing-the-setting-inspirations-multiple-timelines/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage</a> (New release on Steam, Feb. 18)<br>
● Abiotic Factor (Steam)<br>
● Alan Wake (Xbox, available on the Microsoft Store)<br>
● Ashes of the Singularity: Escalation (Xbox, available on the Microsoft Store)<br>
● The Dark Crystal: Age of Resistance Tactics (Xbox, available on the Microsoft Store)<br>
● HUMANITY (Steam)<br>
● Murky Divers (Steam)<br>
● Somerville (Xbox, available on the Microsoft Store)<br>
● Songs of Silence (Steam)<br>
● UNDER NIGHT IN-BIRTH II Sys:Celes (Steam)</p>
<p>This week, GeForce NOW users can expect to find the following additions to the cloud gaming platform:</p>
<ul>
<li>Space Engineers 2 (New release on&nbsp;Steam, Jan. 27)<u></u><u></u></li>
<li><u></u><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/eternal-strands-the-world-is-your-playground/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Eternal Strands</a> (New release on&nbsp;Steam, Jan. 28)<u></u><u></u></li>
<li><u></u>Orcs Must Die! Deathtrap (New release on&nbsp;Steam, Jan. 28)<u></u><u></u></li>
<li><u></u><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/sniper-elite-resistance-sniping-never-changes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sniper Elite: Resistance</a> (New release on&nbsp;Steam&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.xbox.com/games/store/sniper-elite-resistance/9MXRG5GCRPXZ?utm_source=nvidia&amp;utm_campaign=geforce_now" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.xbox.com/games/store/sniper-elite-resistance/9MXRG5GCRPXZ?utm_source%3Dnvidia%26utm_campaign%3Dgeforce_now&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1738309450653000&amp;usg=AOvVaw3pDCIt56BysuOkj0QOE5yZ">Xbox</a>, available on PC Game Pass, Jan. 30)<u></u><u></u></li>
<li><u></u>Heart of the Machine (New release on&nbsp;Steam, Jan. 31)<u></u><u></u></li>
<li><u></u>Citizen Sleeper 2: Starward Vector (New release on&nbsp;Steam, Jan. 31)<u></u><u></u></li>
<li><u></u><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/dead-island-2-cool-zombie-slaying-and-little-else/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dead Island 2</a> (Xbox, available on PC Game Pass)<u></u><u></u></li>
<li><u></u><a href="https://wccftech.com/pax-dei-early-access-qa-mainframe-talks-improvements-from-the-wilderness-alpha-monetization-and-much-more/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pax Dei</a> (Steam)<u></u><u></u></li>
<li><u></u>Sifu (Steam)</li>
</ul>
<p>There's also a bunch of new games that were added to GeForce NOW throughout January despite not originally being planned:</p>
<p>● Road 96 (New release on Xbox, available on PC Game Pass, Jan. 7)<br>
● <a href="https://wccftech.com/aloft-by-astrolabe-interactive-scheduled-to-launch-into-early-access-on-january-15th/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Aloft</a> (New release on Steam, Jan. 15)<br>
● <a href="https://wccftech.com/assetto-corsa-evo-to-get-open-world-map-in-summer-2025-early-access-begins-january-16/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Assetto Corsa EVO</a> (New release on Steam, Jan. 16)<br>
● Among Us (Xbox, available on PC Game Pass)<br>
● Amnesia: Collection (Xbox, available on the Microsoft Store)<br>
● DREDGE (Epic Games Store)<br>
● Generation Zero (Xbox, available on PC Game Pass)<br>
● HOT WHEELS UNLEASHED 2 - Turbocharged (Xbox, available on PC Game Pass)<br>
● Kingdom Come: Deliverance (Xbox, available on the Microsoft Store)<br>
● Lawn Mowing Simulator (Xbox, available on the Microsoft Store)<br>
● <a href="https://wccftech.com/marvel-rivals-and-path-of-exile-2-staying-on-top-in-revenue-says-newzoo-report/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Marvel Rivals</a> (Steam)<br>
● Sins of a Solar Empire: Rebellion (Xbox, available on the Microsoft Store)<br>
● <a href="https://wccftech.com/smite-2-gets-open-beta-launch-adding-three-new-modes-five-new-gods/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SMITE 2</a> (Steam)<br>
● STORY OF SEASONS: Friends of Mineral Town (Xbox, available on the Microsoft Store)<br>
● Townscaper (Xbox, available on the Microsoft Store)</p>
<p>As a reminder, NVIDIA is taking the payment processing for GeForce NOW billing internally. While this transition takes place (for the next five weeks, in their estimation), <a href="https://wccftech.com/geforce-now-is-free-for-a-while-if-youre-an-existing-paid-user-as-nvidia-takes-over-payment-processing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">existing paid users won't be billed again</a>, which means they can effectively play for free.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GeForce RTX 5090 Founder’s Edition Review – Gamer’s Pricey Dream]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/review/geforce-rtx-5090-founders-edition-gamers-pricey-dream/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/geforce-rtx-5090-founder%E2%80%99s-edition-review-%E2%80%93-gamer%E2%80%99s-pricey-dream.1095756/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/review/geforce-rtx-5090-founders-edition-gamers-pricey-dream/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			<div><header>Product Info</header><div><div>
						<h5>NVIDIA GeForce RTX 5090 Founder's Edition</h5><p><span>January 30, 2025</span>
					</p></div><div>
							<h5>Type</h5><p><span>Desktop Graphics Card</span>
						</p></div></div></div>			
			<p>In just a few hours, NVIDIA will officially launch its next flagship graphics card, the GeForce RTX 5090 Founder's Edition. There might well be shortages or price hikes, but that's another matter entirely. Hardcore PC gamers have been waiting for more than usual (the GeForce RTX 4090 launched in October 2022) to get a new GPU, and they're eager for it despite the high price (the graphics card's official MSRP is $1,999), as shown by the queues that have already started forming outside some stores. Should you be paying that much, though, even if you can afford it? In this article, I'll tackle that question after testing the graphics card strictly from a gamer's point of view.</p>
<p>First of all, some pictures of the hardware component and the package it came in. The GeForce RTX 5090's design is certainly very sleek, and I appreciate that it takes up two slots rather than three.</p>
<figure>
<div>

<div>
		
		
		<p><span>2 of 9</span>
	</p></div></div>
</figure>


<p>If you're a regular Wccftech reader, you're probably well-informed on all the specs and features of the GeForce RTX 5090 through <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/msi-geforce-rtx-5090-suprim-soc-32-gb-gpu-review-enter-the-realm-of-ai-charged-gaming/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">our hardware coverage</a>. Still, a quick recap is in order. This is a monster GPU with 21760 CUDA Cores, 32 GB GDDR7 VRAM, 512-bit memory interface, 3352 AI TOPS for Tensor Cores operations, and 318 TFLOPS for Ray Tracing operations. With all that, it's no wonder it requires 1000W of system power, drawing up to 575W for itself.</p>
<p>On the productivity side, the RTX 50 Series includes hardware support for encoding and decoding the 4:2:2 pro-grade color format, as well as 9th Gen NVENC video encoders and a 6th Gen NVIDIA decoder. NVIDIA also added support for the latest DisplayPort 2.1b UHBR20 specification, which can go up to 8K@165Hz with Display Stream Compression (DSC).</p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>GPU Engine Specs</strong></td>
<td>NVIDIA CUDA Cores</td>
<td>21760</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Shader Cores</td>
<td>Blackwell</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Tensor Cores (AI)</td>
<td>5th Generation<br>
3352 AI TOPS</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Ray Tracing Cores</td>
<td>4th Generation<br>
318 TFLOPS</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Boost Clock (GHz)</td>
<td>2.41</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Base Clock (GHz)</td>
<td>2.01</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Memory Specs</strong></td>
<td>Standard Memory Config</td>
<td>32 GB GDDR7</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Memory Interface Width</td>
<td>512-bit</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Technology Support</strong></td>
<td>NVIDIA Architecture</td>
<td>Blackwell</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Ray Tracing</td>
<td>Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>NVIDIA DLSS</td>
<td>DLSS 4<br>
Super Resolution<br>
DLAA<br>
Ray Reconstruction<br>
Frame Generation<br>
Multi Frame Generation</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>NVIDIA Reflex</td>
<td>Reflex 2<br>
Low Latency Mode<br>
Frame Warp (Coming Soon)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>NVIDIA Broadcast</td>
<td>Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>PCI Express Gen 5</td>
<td>Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Resizable BAR</td>
<td>Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>NVIDIA App</td>
<td>Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>NVIDIA Ansel</td>
<td>Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>NVIDIA FreeStyle</td>
<td>Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>NVIDIA ShadowPlay</td>
<td>Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>NVIDIA Highlights</td>
<td>Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>NVIDIA G-SYNC</td>
<td>Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Game Ready Drivers</td>
<td>Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>NVIDIA Studio Drivers</td>
<td>Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>NVIDIA Omniverse</td>
<td>Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>RTX Remix</td>
<td>Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Microsoft DirectX 12 Ultimate</td>
<td>Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>NVIDIA GPU Boost</td>
<td>Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>NVIDIA NVLink (SLI-Ready)</td>
<td>No</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Vulkan 1.4, OpenGL 4.6</td>
<td>Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>NVIDIA Encoder (NVENC)</td>
<td>3x Ninth Generation</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>NVIDIA Decoder (NVDEC)</td>
<td>2x Sixth Generation</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>AV1 Encode</td>
<td>Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>AV1 Decode</td>
<td>Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>CUDA Capability</td>
<td>12.8</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>VR Ready</td>
<td>Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Display Support</strong></td>
<td>Maximum Digital Resolution</td>
<td>4K at 480Hz or 8K at 165Hz with DSC</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Standard Display Connectors</td>
<td>3x DisplayPort, 1x HDMI</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Multi Monitor</td>
<td>up to 4</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>HDCP</td>
<td>2.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Card Dimensions</strong></td>
<td>Length</td>
<td>304 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Width</td>
<td>137 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Slot</td>
<td>2-Slot</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>SFF-Ready Enthusiast GeForce Card</td>
<td>Founders Edition - Yes<br>
Varies by manufacturer</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Thermal and Power Specs</strong></td>
<td>Maximum GPU Temperature (in C)</td>
<td>90</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Total Graphics Power (W)</td>
<td>575</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Required System Power (W)&nbsp;<sup>(5)</sup></td>
<td>1000</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Supplementary Power Connectors</td>
<td>4x PCIe 8-pin cables (adapter in the box) OR<br>
1x 600 W PCIe Gen 5 cable</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>The GPU is the pinnacle of the brand-new Blackwell architecture, which NVIDIA says is optimized for neural rendering. Doubling down on AI, NVIDIA has created the so-called RTX Neural Shaders (part of the larger <a href="https://wccftech.com/nvidia-rtx-kit-shows-how-neural-rendering-will-power-the-next-visual-leap-in-gaming/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RTX Kit suite</a>), small neural networks that can be embedded into programmable shaders. An RTX Neural Shaders SDK lets developers train their game data and shader code on an RTX AI PC and accelerate their neural representations and model weights at run-time with NVIDIA Tensor Cores.</p>
<p>So far, NVIDIA has identified three key applications: RTX Neural Texture Compression, RTX Neural Materials, and RTX Neural Radiance Cache. However, all those will require support from the graphics APIs; Microsoft has already <a href="https://wccftech.com/microsoft-directx-neural-rendering-ai-focused-graphics-nvidia-rtx-50-tensor-core-gpus/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> that the Cooperative Vectors are coming soon to DirectX 12. The Khronos Group will undoubtedly come up with a similar solution for Vulkan. Afterward, though, it will be up to game developers to implement these features in their games. Long story short, it might be a while before we see RTX Neural Shaders applied to actual games, making it automatically not a focus of the GeForce RTX 5090 launch reviews.</p>
<p>The same goes for NVIDIA Reflex 2; the new Frame Warp technology promises to cut down PC latency by up to 75% (the original Reflex reduced latency by up to 50%), which sounds great, especially for Multi Frame Generation since it slightly increases latency. But Reflex 2 isn't available yet - and it won't be exclusive to RTX 50 graphics cards anyway.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/21-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>

<p>What is necessarily at the front and center of every conversation surrounding the new RTX 50 GPUs is, of course, NVIDIA DLSS 4. Now, there's two parts to that: on one hand, NVIDIA has released a new, more advanced upscaling model based on vision transformer technology. So far, DLSS has been based on traditional CNN (convolutional neural network) models. According to NVIDIA, though, these models simply aren't smart enough to make the best choices, which sometimes translates into visual artifacts or ghosting. The new DLSS 4 transformer models are trained on twice the amount of parameters and, according to NVIDIA, already provide better results than CNN models, not to mention they can be further improved over the coming years, whereas CNNs have pretty much reached their maximum capabilities.</p>
<p>The new Ray Reconstruction model already improves image quality, while the Super Resolution model is being released as a beta.</p>
<figure>
<div>

<div>
		
		
		<p><span>2 of 9</span>
	</p></div></div>
</figure>


<p>The new models are available to every GeForce RTX user. Similarly, the new Frame Generation model<span>, which&nbsp;<a href="https://wccftech.com/nvidia-dlss-boss-doesnt-rule-out-possible-frame-generation-support-for-rtx-30-series/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">replaces the hardware Optical Flow accelerator</a> with a faster and more efficient AI-based model,</span>&nbsp;is available on both RTX 40 and 50 GPUs.</p>
<p>What's exclusive to Blackwell architecture graphic cards like the GeForce RTX 5090 is DLSS Multi Frame Generation. According to NVIDIA, there's a number of hardware advancements making generating multiple frames possible. The main one is the 5th Gen Tensor Cores, which reportedly offer up to 2.5X more AI processing performance. Moreover, the new graphics cards have been enhanced with hardware Flip Metering capabilities for optimal frame pacing. Previously, Frame Generation relied on traditional CPU-based pacing, which can introduce variability that affects smoothness. With the arrival of DLSS 4, NVIDIA has updated Frame Generation and Multi Frame Generation to use Flip Metering instead of CPU-based pacing, allowing the display engine for 40 and 50 Series GPUs to precisely control display timing.</p>
<p>With DLSS Multi Frame Generation, NVIDIA is promising absolutely massive performance gains of up to 8x in the heaviest games, like Alan Wake 2, Black Myth: Wukong, and Cyberpunk 2077.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/nvidia-dlss-4-multi-frame-generation-up-to-8x-faster-performance-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>However, those best-case scenario frame rate uplifts are measured with the DLSS Performance Mode; in this review, I've instead put the GeForce RTX 5090 through the grinder when using the highest quality DLSS setting available in any game, DLAA or, if that's not an option, Quality Mode.&nbsp; In all cases, I've enabled the maximum in-game settings without resorting to out-of-game tweaks or mods. 4K resolution has been selected in all instances.</p>
<p>The testing rig is:</p>
<ul>
<li>AMD Ryzen 7 9800X3D</li>
<li>MSI MAG B650 TOMAHAWK WIFI</li>
<li>32GB DDR5 6000 MHz</li>
<li>2TB NVMe SSD Western Digital Black SN850X</li>
</ul>
<p>Before starting, it's worth clarifying that all testing was conducted with the latest (not public yet) version of NVIDIA's FrameView software. There's a very good reason for that, as it is presently the only benchmarking software that accurately reports the MsBetweenDisplayChange metrics. With the aforementioned new Flip Metering, NVIDIA says that MsBetweenDisplayChange, rather than MsBetweenPresents, is the best metric to represent what the user actually sees. That's because it is reported near the end of the render pipeline after flip metering has occurred, whereas the measurement of MsBetweenPresents takes place earlier when flip metering hasn't yet paced the frames.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/86-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>

<p>As advised by NVIDIA, I exported FrameView data to be visualized with <a href="https://www.gpureport.cz/windows/FLAT/flat.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FLAT</a> (Frame Latency Analytics Tool), which was then used to create the frame time pie charts.</p>

	<div><div>
			<h2>Contents</h2>
			<!-- <span class="toctogglespan">
				<label class="toctogglelabel" for="toctogglecheckbox">Hide</label>
			</span> -->
		</div><nav><ul><li>1. <span>Intro</span></li><li>2. <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/geforce-rtx-5090-founders-edition-gamers-pricey-dream/2/">GeForce RTX 5090 Founder's Edition - DLSS 4 Multi Frame Generation Testing</a></li><li>3. <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/geforce-rtx-5090-founders-edition-gamers-pricey-dream/3/">GeForce RTX 5090 Founder's Edition - Regular Testing</a></li><li>4. <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/geforce-rtx-5090-founders-edition-gamers-pricey-dream/4/">GeForce RTX 5090 Founder's Edition - 3DMark Testing and Closing Thoughts</a></li></ul></nav></div><!-- .mpp-post-navigation -->
				

						
			
						<section>
				<p>With the release of the GeForce RTX 5090 Founder's Edition, NVIDIA has once again proved why it's the leader in the desktop GPU segment. The new graphics card features potentially groundbreaking new future-facing technologies like RTX Neural Shaders, but even in the here and now, it delivers extremely high performance even when testing the most taxing PC games with the maximum settings. DLSS 4 Multi Frame Generation is another great advancement that is sure to keep the upscaler well ahead of the increasing competition, though perhaps the most impactful improvement is the hardware flip metering that greatly improves frame pacing and, therefore, smoothness. 

Once again, the only real downside is the pricing, which has received a sizable bump over the Ada generation, when the RTX 4090 cost $1,599. If money is no object, though, this is the GPU to get to realize all your 4K@200+Hz path traced gamer's dreams.</p>
				<div>
												<ul>
							<h6>Pros</h6>
							<li>The GeForce RTX 5090 delivers excellent performance in all tested PC games, even without DLSS 4 Multi Frame Generation
</li><li>The hardware Flip Metering is a game-changer for how much it improves smoothness
</li><li>The RTX Neural Shaders ensure the graphics card will remain relevant for years to come</li>						</ul>
																		<ul>
							<h6>Cons</h6>
							<li>The pricing is unfortunately quite a bit higher than last generation</li>						</ul>
										</div>
				<a rel="sponsored nofollow noskim" href="">Buy for  from Amazon</a>
				<span>The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may
					earn from qualifying purchases.</span>
			</section>
			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grand Theft Auto VI and Grand Theft Auto Online Could Be Sold Separately; Rockstar Is Targeting Solid 30 FPS on Consoles, According to Former Animator]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-online-sold-separately-30-fps-target/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grand-theft-auto-vi-and-grand-theft-auto-online-could-be-sold-separately-rockstar-is-targeting-solid-30-fps-on-consoles-according-to-former-animator.1095735/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-online-sold-separately-30-fps-target/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Grand Theft Auto VI and Grand Theft Auto Online will be sold separately at launch, with a potential upgrade for the full game available for those who only purchase the online component of the next entry in the Rockstar series, according to rumors circulating online.</p>
<p>On the <a href="https://gtaforums.com/topic/1000113-gta-vi-speculation-discussion-part-%E2%88%9E-the-leonida-drought/page/73/#findComment-1072491760" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GTA Forums</a>, known Rockstar leaker Tez2 said that the release of the sixth main entry in the series will coincide with the first time the full package and the online component will be sold separately at launch. According to the leaker, Rockstar Games will have to factor the price of the online component into the total cost of the game, but could benefit from pricing the online standalone lower to provide access to players who cannot afford the full price, who could, eventually, upgrade to the full game including the main story campaign. At the same time, if the online component is priced low, it could help Rockstar Games keep the price of the full experience low, which is something many in the industry wouldn't want to see, as there are expectations that a potential $80 price tag for Grand Theft Auto VI could <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-6-growth-engine-pricing/">normalize video game pricing</a>, which hasn't increased much in the past few years despite rising costs.</p>
<p>The rumors of Grand Theft Auto Online possibly being sold separately from the full Grand Theft Auto VI package isn't the only news related to the highly-anticipated game that's come in the past few hours.&nbsp;<span>As reported by&nbsp;<a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/grand-theft-auto/gta-6-will-run-at-30fps-on-console-former-gta-5-and-red-dead-redemption-2-animator-expects-and-your-best-shot-at-60fps-may-be-hoping-for-pc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GamesRadar</a>, former Rockstar Games animator, Mike York commented on what console players should expect in terms of performance, saying that the developer is likely going to go for a steady 30 FPS, optimizing the game as much as possible to make sure it will never dip below the target.</span> On PlayStation 5 Pro, using the PlayStation Spectral Super Resolution upscaler, the game could hit 60 FPS, according to the former Rockstar developer, but 60 FPS shouldn't be expected on base hardware at launch. From their experience, the former animator is sure Rockstar is going to squeeze as much performance from consoles as possible to make the game run at 30 FPS, and then later optimize for 60 FPS, as the higher framerate is not as important as making the game amazing at 30.</p>
<p>Grand Theft Auto VI launches on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S later this year. A precise release date has yet to be confirmed.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>