<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 10:17:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[“We Nicked It From The Office”: Fable Lead Confirms In-Game Mockumentary Style]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/fable-lead-confirms-mockumentary-style-is-in-the-game/</link>
            <guid>1414003</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>There's no doubt that most of the curiosity surrounding the <strong>Xbox Developer Direct 2026</strong> was directed at <strong>Fable</strong>. Sure, <strong>Forza Horizon 6</strong> is massively anticipated on the heels of the excellent previous game, but it's mostly a known quantity. Fable, on the other hand, has been missing for over fifteen years, and it's now being rebooted by a new developer, <strong>Playground Games</strong>. </p>



<p>The presentation <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/fable-launches-autumn-2026-amazingly-faithful/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">was very promising</a></strong>. As I noted in my article, it appears that the developers have successfully retained most of the spirit and gameplay features that made the original trilogy unique. However, there's still a lot we have to discover about the game. A fresh interview with Game Director <strong>Ralph Fulton</strong>, <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2026/01/22/fable-interview-overview-details-developer-direct-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">published on the Xbox Wire blog</a>, helps with that. In the interview, Fulton mentions that Fable will feature a 'sensational cast of characters', although it's too early to unveil who will be playing them, except for <strong>Richard Ayoade</strong>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/fable-first-gameplay-xbox-games-showcase-richard-ayoade/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">who was revealed nearly three years ago as Dave</a>. </p>



<p>Then, Fulton went through the studio's inspirations to get that British humour right. <strong>Ricky Gervais's The Office</strong> was apparently the main inspiration, but not only for the tone: the show's trademark <strong>mockumentary style</strong> wasn't just reserved for the trailers; it will actually be found in the game.</p>



<p><em>We were inspired by the incredibly rich variety of British comedies that have been around over the last 20 years like ‘Peep Show,’ ‘The IT Crowd’ and so many others. We started with ‘The Office’, which again started out as quintessentially British, but also travels really, really well. Not just that IP, but a lot of the techniques and the devices that it’s popularized, you know. It’s that really grounded, awkward style of humour which really appeals to us. And the actors who have been in a lot of these shows – and indeed some of whom are in our game – they’re known all over the world.</em></p>



<p><em>The other cool thing about The Office is something we’ve kind of nicked. You’ve maybe seen in our trailers that we have a sort of mockumentary interview style. I think a lot of people assume we just did that for those trailers, but it’s actually a device we use throughout the game. I’ve never seen it in games before, but it allows you a way to really neatly tell a joke or drop a little bit of character detail in a way that would feel really clunky in a dialogue, but suddenly feels entirely natural when you do it to ‘camera’.</em></p>



<p>To be honest, I'm not too thrilled about this. While the mockumentary style made perfect sense for The Office, I'm not sure it will work just as well in a game like Fable. Sure, the British humour was always part of the series, but that and the mockumentary style are quite two different things. <strong>I'm not sure delivering lines to 'camera' makes sense when you're supposed to be feeling immersed in the fantasy world of Albion</strong>.</p>



<p>That said, as I wrote earlier, <strong>everything else about Playground's game looks spot on</strong>, so perhaps this will only be a minor annoyance - and perhaps it might even be fun from time to time. It won't be too long until we find out: now we know that Fable will be released in Autumn for PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series S and X. If I were Microsoft and Playground, though, <strong>I'd make sure to release well before Grand Theft Auto VI</strong>, which is currently set for November 19, 2026.</p>



<p>As a side note, the game <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftech-awards-25-winners-clair-obscur-gta-6/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">just won Wccftech's most anticipated roleplaying game of 2026 category award</a></strong> from both staff and community.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/fable-lead-confirms-mockumentary-style-is-in-the-game/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nioh 3 Unveils New Footage in Fresh Gameplay Showcase]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nioh-3-unveils-new-footage-fresh-gameplay-showcase/</link>
            <guid>1413994</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>This morning, <strong>Koei Tecmo</strong> unveiled new <strong>Nioh 3</strong> footage in a 17.5-minute gameplay showcase. As you know if you've read <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/roundup/nioh-3-everything-we-know-about-team-ninjas-supernatural-action-rpg/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our roundup article on the game</a></strong>, Nioh 3 actually takes place across multiple time periods, including the early <strong>Edo</strong> period, the <strong>Sengoku</strong> period, the <strong>Heian</strong> period, and the <strong>Bakumatsu</strong> period. </p>



<p>Today's gameplay showcase begins in the second one, also known as the <strong>Warring States</strong> period. In the game's version of the era, the <strong>Yōkai</strong> (demons) freely roam the land, and a horrifying realm known as the <strong>Crucible</strong> has manifested. The player explores a large, open field while seeking a way to the Crucible. </p>



<p>The protagonist, the historical figure <strong>Tokugawa Takechiyo </strong>(Iemitsu), <strong>can switch between the classic samurai style and the new ninja style at any time during combat</strong>. Switching is particularly useful whenever there's a need to adapt to certain enemies and situations, or simply to shift to the player's preferred play style.</p>



<p>Samurai mode lets Tokugawa confront enemies head-on, utilizing martial arts and deflecting attacks while switching between stances to unleash a variety of strikes. On the other hand, Ninja style aims to outmaneuver enemies with <strong>Ninjutsu</strong>, evading with mid-air and behind-the-back attacks.</p>



<div><p><strong>Not everyone or everything is hostile in Nioh 3, though</strong>. The developers from Team Ninja highlighted that Tokugawa will encounter friendly characters and even friendly Yōkai on his journey. Interacting with them may bring useful rewards.</p><p>Ultimately, Tokugawa's journey heads to the aforementioned Crucible, a treacherous area ruled by dangerous, hostile Yōkai. <strong>Players should expect even more challenging fights in this area</strong>. According to the developers, those who summoned the Crucible are heroes who have lost their way, succumbing to their own ambitions and misguided causes.</p></div>



<p>The gameplay video then switches to the Heian period, where the land is entirely frozen. Here, as in the other time periods, the protagonist must cleanse the Crucible to restore the land, purging it of Yōkai corruption.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="【2/6発売】『仁王３』ゲームプレイ紹介映像" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Hf5iPTgQKKE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Nioh 3 <strong>is set to launch on February 6, 2026</strong> for PC and PlayStation 5. Eager fans can jump in early to sample the free demo, <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/nioh-3-new-demo-ps5-pc-january-29-2026-carries-full-game-crossplay-missing/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">which will be released on January 29</a></strong>. Its save data also carries over to the full game, so in essence it's a bit like having early access to the initial portion.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/nioh-3-unveils-new-footage-fresh-gameplay-showcase/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>