<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 18:25:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NVIDIA DLSS 4 Ultra Quality Mode Offers Better Performance Than DLAA With Negligible Image Quality Impact, New Comparison Video Highlights]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nvidia-dlss-4-ultra-quality-mode-better-perfromance-image-quality-dlaa/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nvidia-dlss-4-ultra-quality-mode-offers-better-performance-than-dlaa-with-negligible-image-quality-impact-new-comparison-video-highlights.1194237/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nvidia-dlss-4-ultra-quality-mode-better-perfromance-image-quality-dlaa/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>NVIDIA DLSS 4 set in the Ultra Quality mode via the NVIDIA App can deliver better performance than DLAA with a negligible impact on image quality, as highlighted by a new comparison video.</p>
<p>The comparison video shared today by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@MxBenchmarkPC">MxBenchmarkPC</a> puts The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered, Cyberpunk 2077, The Witcher 3, STALKER 2 and Kingdom Come Deliverance 2 running at 1440p resolution with NVIDIA DLSS 4 in DLAA, Ultra Quality Mode, and Quality Mode side by side, highlighting how Ultra Quality Mode, which can be used in any supported game by using the DLSS Override - Super Resolution option and setting it to 77% input resolution, delivers better performance than DLAA with a negligible impact on image quality that is definitely hard to notice in motion in all the game featured in the comparison. The fact that Ultra Quality mode seems to work so well makes it baffling that it isn't an official option available in games.</p>
<p><iframe title="DLSS 4 Ultra Quality Mode vs DLAA - Same Image Quality as DLAA but More FPS? | RTX 5080" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UY67EY50nGw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>After its launch earlier this year, NVIDIA DLSS 4 has been implemented in over 125 games and apps, and the list is expanding every week with new games. <a href="https://wccftech.com/nvidia-dlss-4-multi-frame-generation-and-other-rtx-updates-shown-off-for-upcoming-and-existing-pc-games/">In the coming weeks</a>, F1 25, Dune: Awakening, MindsEye, and FBC: Firebreak will launch with NVIDIA DLSS 4 support, followed by the Soulslike Wuchang: Fallen Feathers, which launches on July 24th.</p>
<p>The release of NVIDIA DLSS 4 coincided with the launch of Multi Frame Generation, which is exclusive to the RTX 50 series cards, and the new AI Transformer Model, which delivers better image quality than the previous CNN model in the same modes. More information on the latest iteration of the upscaler can be found on its <a href="https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/geforce/technologies/dlss/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">official website.</a></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Stellar Blade Sequel Is Coming, Shift Up Confirms]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/a-stellar-blade-sequel-is-coming-shift-up-confirms/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-stellar-blade-sequel-is-coming-shift-up-confirms.1194234/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/a-stellar-blade-sequel-is-coming-shift-up-confirms/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/stellar-blade-review-nearly-automatic-angel/">Stellar Blade</a> is getting a sequel, developer Shift Up has confirmed. In the company's latest<a href="https://shiftup.co.kr/eng/ir/irdata.php?ptype=view&amp;idx=254&amp;page=1&amp;code=irdata_eng"> investor relations presentation</a>, a chart showing how the studio plans to grow going forward confirms plans for a Stellar Blade sequel, seemingly set to release sometime before 2027.</p>
<p>The chart also confirms plans for Shift Up's next game, an action RPG currently codenamed Project Witches, and plans for Stellar Blade's "platform expansion," which, if Xbox owners want to keep pie-in-the-sky hopes, could mean an Xbox version. But it is likely just referring to the PC version that is due next month.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>No Xbox version aside, a sequel is exciting news for fans of the 2024 action hit, especially if the studio is able to complete the game and release it sometime before 2027. Though that release window should be taken with a grain of salt for now, seeing as how there's always the chance for things to change or slow down development, no matter the studio or the project.</p>
<p>After being one of the most popular games in 2024, Stellar Blade will continue to be a part of the conversation with its PC launch this coming June 11, 2025. Though not for entirely positive reasons, unfortunately, as its release is currently marred by the fact that it is <a href="https://wccftech.com/stellar-blade-doesnt-require-a-psn-account-to-play-on-pc-but-its-still-blocked-in-130-countries-on-steam/">not available to purchase on Steam in 130 countries</a>, despite not having any PlayStation Network sign-in requirements.</p>
<p>Shift Up has released a statement saying <a href="https://wccftech.com/stellar-blade-dev-is-working-with-sony-to-resolve-pc-region-locking-claims-denuvo-doesnt-impact-frame-rates/">it is working to fix the issue as soon as possible</a>, though it's unclear if the problem will be resolved by launch.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>