<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 17:41:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South of Midnight – Where To Find All Notes – Chapter 8]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/how-to/south-of-midnight-where-to-find-all-notes-chapter-8/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/south-of-midnight-%E2%80%93-where-to-find-all-notes-%E2%80%93-chapter-8.1169538/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/how-to/south-of-midnight-where-to-find-all-notes-chapter-8/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The first thing you notice about Compulsion Games' latest title, <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/south-of-midnight-boring-combat-drags-down-a-beautiful-and-emotional-story/">South of Midnight</a>, might be its striking visuals, but its strongest aspect is its excellent storytelling.</p>
<p>That includes the writing and performances in the cutscenes and the notes you can discover that add more context to the story. That's why, beyond just doing it for the achievement, it is worth your time to try and find all of the 103 notes there are to find across the 14 chapters of South of Midnight's story.</p>
<p>This guide will show you where to find the 4 notes hiding in Chapter 8.</p>
<h2>South of Midnight - Where To Find All Notes - Chapter 8</h2>
<p>After having to look out for 15 notes in Chapter 7, you'll be happy to know that Chapter 8 is a much easier time with only 4 notes to find.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p><strong>Their Eyes Were Watching -&nbsp;</strong>You'll be able to find this note right at the beginning of the level, immediately after using a wind tunnel for the first time. When you land, it'll be waiting on a tree stump to your right.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p><strong>Delta-346-Weird Happenings -</strong> After using a wind tunnel for the second time in the level, head left when you land to find a Floof knot and this note lying on the ground.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p><strong>Delta-346- Red Yarn</strong> - After finding the previous note, you'll have to clear some branches away to wall-run over a gap. When you reach the other side, on the right side of the path, you'll find some sunflowers with a tree stump next to them, where you'll find this note waiting for you.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p><strong>Delta 346 - Search Called Off</strong> - You'll find this note just after the first combat encounter of the level. Use the grapple hook to cross the gap after completing the encounter, and before heading into the cave blocked by wood and red yarn, this note will be on the ground on the right side of the path.</p>
<p>And that's where to find all the notes in South of Midnight's Chapter 8. If you've followed along with the rest of these guides, you'll have found 57 notes by now. Only 46 more to find.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remake Will Be Officially Showcased Tomorrow, Bethesda Announces]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remake-will-be-officially-showcased-tomorrow-bethesda-announces/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remake-will-be-officially-showcased-tomorrow-bethesda-announces.1169460/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remake-will-be-officially-showcased-tomorrow-bethesda-announces/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Finally, after weeks of <a href="https://wccftech.com/oblivion-remake-april-release/">leaks</a> and even official <a href="https://wccftech.com/oblivion-remake-shadowdrop/">screenshots appearing online</a>, Bethesda has not only officially acknowledged The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remake but also announced that we'll get a full reveal and showcase of the game tomorrow, <strong>April 22, 2025</strong>, at <strong>8 am PT / 11 am ET / 4 pm BT.<br>
</strong></p>
<p>A short <a href="https://x.com/bethesda/status/1914341006188712023">post</a> from the studio's official X account tells us when we'll learn more about the long-awaited remake and where to check it out, with the 'where' being either the Bethesda <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/Ed_E2crglcw">YouTube</a> or <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/bethesda">Twitch</a> channels.</p>
<p>The title of the video on Bethesda's YouTube channel says "<em>All will be revealed...,</em>" hopefully implying that we'll not only learn about what has gone into the remake, the new features available, and the release date.</p>
<p><iframe title="All will be revealed...." width="500" height="375" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ed_E2crglcw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The release date could very well be tomorrow, shortly after the reveal. Rumors about the Elder Scrolls IV Oblivion Remake already had their sights set on today, or at least <a href="https://wccftech.com/oblivion-remake-could-be-mere-days-from-launch-according-to-leaker/">sometime</a> in the back half of April, for the game's release.</p>
<p>In hindsight, we know that those rumors claiming an April 21 release had their wires crossed with today's announcement that the reveal would be tomorrow. But now we can expect to play Oblivion on at least Xbox consoles and PCs before the week is out. It's still up in the air whether it'll be available on PS5 right away or if Xbox players will enjoy a short period of exclusivity for the remake before it comes to PS5.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>