<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 14:30:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oblivion Remastered Unofficial Patch Packs Massive Number of Fixes and Improvements]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/oblivion-remastered-patch-fixes/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/oblivion-remastered-unofficial-patch-packs-massive-number-of-fixes-and-improvements.1179507/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/oblivion-remastered-patch-fixes/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A new The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered unofficial patch is now available for download, addressing a huge number of bugs.</p>
<p>The patch, which can be downloaded from <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/oblivionremastered/mods/477" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nexus Mods</a> and requires game version 0.411.140.0, addresses a massive number of issues, including script, quest, NPC, object, item, dialogue bugs, and more. The main goal of the unofficial patch is to eventually fix every bug in Oblivion Remastered that won't be fixed by the developers within the capabilities of the Creation Kit and other community-developed tools. The complete changelog for the latest version of the unofficial patch can be found <a href="https://www.afkmods.com/Unofficial%20Oblivion%20Remastered%20Patch%20Version%20History.html">here.</a></p>
<p>As the game still uses the original's Gamebryo engine, The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered features the usual selection of bugs and issues that have become tradition for Bethesda games. Even with these bugs and performance issues on PC, the remaster of the fourth entry in the beloved series is a more than worthy purchase for any role-playing game fan, as I highlighted in my <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-back-in-cyrodiil-19-years-later/">review</a>.</p>
<p><em>Enhancing the original where it mattered most while preserving what made it truly unique, The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered stands as the definitive way to experience Bethesda’s classic. Although the shift in atmosphere and noticeable performance issues will put some players off, as will the dated gameplay, the game couldn't have debuted on current gaming platforms in a better way.</em></p>
<p>The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered is now available on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X and Xbox Series S.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grand Theft Auto VI Launches On May 26 2026, Rockstar Games Confirms]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-launches-may-26/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grand-theft-auto-vi-launches-on-may-26-2026-rockstar-games-confirms.1179504/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-launches-may-26/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-another-trailer/">Grand Theft Auto VI</a> has been delayed from its Fall 2025 release window, and will now launch next year on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S.</p>
<p>Today, Rockstar Games confirmed on <a href="https://x.com/RockstarGames/status/1918265468076605706?t=Px5bjAPYlpMHJab6nnPEdQ&amp;s=19" target="_blank" rel="noopener">X</a> the highly anticipated new entry in the series will not launch this year as expected, and will now release on May 26, 2026 worldwide on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X and Xbox Series S. While apologizing to fans for launching the game later than expected, the developer highlighted how their goal has always been to try and exceed their exceptions and with Grand Theft Auto VI, they want to do no different. As such, extra development time is required to reach the quality that players expect and deserve. More information on the game will be shared soon, so hopefully another look at the game won't take too long.</p>
<p>While it is disappointing to learn that Grand Theft Auto VI will not be released later this year on consoles, it is most definitely not that surprising. Considering their long history of delays, it would have been more surprising for Rockstar Games not to delay what is going to be, regardless, the biggest entertainment launch of all time to date, according to <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-is-expected-to-be-the-biggest-entertainment-launch-of-all-time-but-a-performance-below-expectations-could-impact-the-entire-industry/">analysts</a>.</p>
<p>Grand Theft Auto VI launches on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X, and Xbox Series S on May 26, 2026. We will update you as soon as Rockstar Games shares more information, so stay tuned for all the latest news.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>