<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 14:49:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Virtua Fighter Project Pre-Development Video Shows Impressive Visuals and Animations]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/new-virtua-fighter-project-pre-development-video-shows-impressive-visuals-and-animations/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-virtua-fighter-project-pre-development-video-shows-impressive-visuals-and-animations.1075890/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/new-virtua-fighter-project-pre-development-video-shows-impressive-visuals-and-animations/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A pre-development video for the new Virtua Fighter project in the works by Ryu Ga Gotoku Studio was shared during CES 2025, providing a quick look at the sort of visuals the game should be expected to push.</p>
<p>The video, which was shown during <a href="https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/events/ces/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">NVIDIA's CES 2025 keynote</a>, is essentially a proof-of-concept video showcasing two versions of the series' protagonist, Akira, duking it out in a highly detailed town environment with an Asian flair. Still, it is undeniable that the direction the celebrated fighting game series by SEGA is taking is looking quite promising in the visuals and animation department.</p>
<p><iframe title="“New VIRTUA FIGHTER Project” pre-development concept video" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GtLRfES1YQU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The new Virtua Fighter project was announced <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-virtua-fighter-project-century-announced-by-like-a-dragon-series-developer-ryu-ga-gotoku-studio/">last month</a> during The Game Awards show, along with another project called Project Century, which looks more in line with the Like a Dragon series. Sadly, very little is currently known about these projects, and it may be a while before we hear more about them, considering they both lack official names.</p>
<p>Despite the new Virtua Fighter project likely being far from release, fans of the series still have something to look forward to. Later this month, <a href="https://wccftech.com/sega-brings-virtua-fighter-5-r-e-v-o-to-steam-this-winter/">Virtua Fighter 5 R.E.V.O</a> is launching on PC, taking the gameplay of the fifth entry in the series, which is also available on PlayStation 5 as Ultimate Showdown, and bringing it to new heights with rollback netcode support, 4K visuals and additional content.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>