<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 10:46:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Octopath Traveler 0: Essential Beginner’s Tips –  Best Starter Jobs, and Early Game Strategies]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/how-to/octopath-traveler-0-essential-beginners-tips-best-starter-jobs-and-early-game-strategies/</link>
            <guid>1372495</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Welcome to Orsterra! <em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Octopath Traveler 0</em> can be overwhelming at first with its new Town-Building mechanics, 8-person parties, and custom protagonist. This guide will help you with the best advice to enjoy the first few hours of the adventure and get started on this epic journey.</p>



<p>For a complete list of all our guides, be sure to check out our <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://wccftech.com/how-to/octopath-traveler-0-all-guides-walkthroughs-and-beginner-tips-hub/"><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">Octopath Traveler 0 Complete Guides and Walkthrough Hub</strong>.</a></p>



<div><h2>Table of contents</h2><ul><li><a href="#h-pick-warrior-as-your-first-job" data-level="2">Pick Warrior as Your First Job</a></li><li><a href="#h-pick-scholar-as-your-second-job" data-level="2">Pick Scholar as Your Second Job</a></li><li><a href="#h-always-check-the-quests-menu" data-level="2">Always Check the Quests Menu</a></li><li><a href="#h-always-use-path-actions-whenever-possible" data-level="2">Always use Path Actions Whenever Possible</a></li><li><a href="#h-be-efficient-in-battle-to-get-amazing-rewards" data-level="2">Be Efficient in Battle To Get Amazing Rewards</a></li><li><a href="#h-don-t-sleep-on-food" data-level="2">Don't Sleep on Food</a></li></ul></div>



<h2 id="h-pick-warrior-as-your-first-job">Pick Warrior as Your First Job</h2>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Octopath-Traveler-0-Warrior.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>The Warrior Job is the best early-game choice for beginners</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>While each Job has its own uses, the Warrior stands out as the best starting Job, especially if Octopath Traveler 0 is your first entry in the series. Besides offering solid power and defense and a great selection of offense-oriented skills, the Warrior can wield Swords and Spears, two weapon options that won't be available for your party for some time due to the characters that can be recruited in the first few hours of the adventure.</p>



<p>Additionally, many of the enemies you will encounter in the first chapters of the Master of Power, Master of Wealth and Master of Fame quests are weak against Swords, so having a Warrior capable of taking advantage of this weakness will prove to be invaluable as you get acquainted with the game's mechanics.</p>



<h2 id="h-pick-scholar-as-your-second-job">Pick Scholar as Your Second Job</h2>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Octopath-Traveler-0-Scholar.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>The Scholar works great as a secondary Job for your protagonist in the early game</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Compared to the Warrior, the Scholar Job is not a great starter Job, but it's a great secondary Job. While the Boost system cannot be used to increase the number of times an elemental spell can hit enemies, these properties are just as important to Break enemies.</p>



<p>As Octopath Traveler 0 allows you to switch the main character's Jobs right from the main menu (Skills - Protagonist's Job ), you can easily adapt to the enemies you are facing in a specific area by switching between Warrior and Scholar as required, letting the other starting characters cover the other weapon-based weaknesses and the Ice and Dark elements the Scholar cannot hit.</p>



<p>Unlocking a second Job is also very easy. All you need to do is learn three skills with the Job you have unlocked last. So, to have the Scholar as your second job, all you have to do is learn three skills for the Warrior for a total of 430 JP (30 JP for the first skill, 100 for the second, 300 for the third), regardless of which skill is unlocked.</p>



<p>As a side bonus, the Scholar's first Support Skill, Study Foe, also reveals one undiscovered weakness for any enemy at the start of battle, making this Job a great one to run with certain party configurations.</p>







<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Octopath-Traveler-0-Quests-Menu-1.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>The Quests menu comes with some really useful features</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>The Quests section in the main menu is really useful for a couple of reasons. Its primary purpose is to list all of the available quests, but it has some additional functions that make it even more useful.</p>



<ul>
<li>By pressing the Cross (PlayStation), A (Xbox) / B (Nintendo Switch) button while a quest is highlighted, you can not only track any quest but also fast travel to its location, cutting down the time needed to start it.</li>



<li>Besides listing all the known available quests, the Quests menu also lists available quests that you haven't discovered yet. Its icon also indicates if it is a regular side quest or a Traveler focused quest that will allow you to recruit a new party member.</li>
</ul>



<p>For these reasons, always check the Quests menu whenever you have completed a main story quest. This allows you to engage with side content and help you achieve completion quickly.</p>



<h2 id="h-always-use-path-actions-whenever-possible">Always use Path Actions Whenever Possible</h2>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Octopath-Traveler-0-Path-Actions-1.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Path Actions should be used every time you reach a new town</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Path Actions return in Octopath Traveler 0, and they are more useful than ever before. By pressing the Square (PlayStation)/X (Xbox)/Y (Nintendo Switch) button near any applicable NPC, it is possible to Inquire to learn more about them, Entice them to purchase or obtain items after a fight, Hire them as Combat Helpers or Invite them to live in Wishvale. </p>



<p>As these NPCs sometimes offer some rather useful items such as Masteries that can be used to equip skills to characters and powerful gear, you will want to use Path Action interactions on every possible character. Depending on your current level of Power, Wealth and Fame, your interactions may fail and may force you to restore your reputation at a nearby Tavern, but if you handle this properly and don't attempt interactions that have a high failure chance, you can take great advantage of these mechanics at all times during the adventure</p>



<h2 id="h-be-efficient-in-battle-to-get-amazing-rewards">Be Efficient in Battle To Get Amazing Rewards</h2>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Octopath-Traveler-0-Battle-Rewards.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Performing well in battle is rewarded with some great bonuses</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Octopath Traveler 0 rewards your combat performance by providing EXP, JP and Leaf (money) bonuses depending on how well you do.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><td><strong>Condition</strong></td><td><strong>Reward</strong></td></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><strong>Overkill/Break</strong></td><td>EXP Bonus</td></tr><tr><td><strong>1-Turn Kill</strong></td><td>JP Bonus</td></tr><tr><td><strong>No Damage Win</strong></td><td>Leaf Bonus</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>As such, you should always look into completing battles after breaking enemies in a single turn. This is difficult to achieve against elite enemies and bosses, but if you do so every random encounter against mobs, the rewards will pile up, make your characters stronger, and allow you to engage more with the game's Job and Mastery systems.</p>



<h2 id="h-don-t-sleep-on-food">Don't Sleep on Food </h2>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Octopath-Traveler-0-Food.jpg"></a><figcaption><em data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-processed">Food can be way more useful than regula</em><em>r</em><em data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-processed"> items</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Although items are as important as ever to restore HP and SP and heal status ailments quickly, you really shouldn't discount how important Food is. These items, which can be cooked from the Tavern in Wishvale, provide a variety of bonuses for a set number of turns, ranging from stat increases to automatic HP and SP restoration. As the selection of available Food increases as you play the game, make sure to check out at the Tavern what can be cooked to gain a sound advantage against all sorts of enemies.</p>



<p>Want to know how all of these mechanics come together in the game? Check out our <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/octopath-traveler-0-review-in-progress-a-masterclass-in-villany/"><strong>Octopath Traveler 0 review.</strong></a></p>



<blockquote>
<p><strong><em>NOTE: Tips based on 30 hours of playtime in the Steam 1.0 version. Screenshots captured from the same version</em></strong></p>
</blockquote>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/how-to/octopath-traveler-0-essential-beginners-tips-best-starter-jobs-and-early-game-strategies/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Octopath Traveler 0: Complete Guides and Walkthrough Hub]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/how-to/octopath-traveler-0-all-guides-walkthroughs-and-beginner-tips-hub/</link>
            <guid>1372492</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Octopath Traveler 0 is the third main entry in the series that launched the popular HD-2D visual style, combining high-quality sprites with 3D environments. However, the game based on the mobile game Champions of the Continent is more than a great-looking game, as its web of interconnected mechanics, in conjunction with its great story, makes for a very engaging experience.</p>



<div><h2>Table of contents</h2><ul><li><a href="#h-gameplay-overview" data-level="2">Gameplay Overview</a></li><li><a href="#h-getting-started" data-level="2">Getting Started</a></li><li><a href="#h-character-creation" data-level="2">Character Creation</a></li><li><a href="#h-job-and-mastery-system" data-level="2">Job and Mastery System</a></li><li><a href="#h-combat-system" data-level="2">Combat System</a></li><li><a href="#h-playable-characters-travelers" data-level="2">Playable Characters (Travelers)</a></li><li><a href="#h-town-building" data-level="2">Town-Building</a></li><li><a href="#h-story-progression" data-level="2">Story Progression</a></li><li><a href="#h-review" data-level="2">Review</a></li></ul></div>



<h2 id="h-gameplay-overview">Gameplay Overview</h2>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Octopath-Traveler-0-field.jpg"></a><figcaption><em data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-processed">Octopath Traveler</em><em> </em><em data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-processed">0 twists the series' formula in some interesting ways </em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Octopath Traveler 0 is a traditional Japanese role-playing game where the player takes control of a custom character embarking in a journey all over Orsterra (the world of the original Octopath Traveler) to defeat three powerful villains - The Master of Power Tytos, The Master of Wealth Herminia and The Master of Fame Auguste - and save the world.</p>



<p>Compounding the game's traditional traversal mechanics is a turn-based combat system that pits up to eight party members against all sorts of enemies. Breaking the enemy using attacks with specific properties and boosting the efficacy of regular attacks and skills are the core mechanics upon which combat is based.</p>



<p>Octopath Traveler 0 also introduces town-building mechanics that let players influence the restoration of Wishvale, and unlock important upgrades via new facilities, including a monster arena.</p>



<h2 id="h-getting-started">Getting Started</h2>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Octopath-Traveler-0-Path-Actions.jpg"></a><figcaption><em data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)">Coming to grips with all of the game's</em><em> </em><em data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)">mechanics can be challenging</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>With so many interconnected mechanics, starting the game can be daunting for both newcomers and those who haven't played any of the previous games in a while.</p>



<p><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed"><a data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" href="https://wccftech.com/how-to/auto-draft/">These Octopath Traveler </a></strong><strong><a data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" href="https://wccftech.com/how-to/auto-draft/">0</a></strong><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed"><a data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" href="https://wccftech.com/how-to/auto-draft/"> beginner's tips</a></strong> will help you navigate the early game challenges and make the experience more enjoyable right from the beginning.</p>



<h2 id="h-character-creation">Character Creation</h2>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Octopath-Traveler-0-Character-Creation.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Octopath Traveler 0 lets you create and customize your protagonist</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Octopath Traveler 0 is the first entry in the series to feature a single main character as opposed to the eight characters of past games. This character can be fully customized at the beginning of the game.</p>



<p>During character creation, you can determine the character's appearance, Learned Skill, Favorite Dish, and three belongings. </p>



<blockquote>
<p><em><strong>A comprehensive Character Creation guide will go live soon.</strong></em></p>
</blockquote>



<h2 id="h-job-and-mastery-system">Job and Mastery System</h2>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Octopath-Traveler-0-Jobs.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>The Job System returns, but with some twists</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>The Octopath series' signature Job System returns in Octopath Traveler 0, but with some twists. Only the main character can switch between the usual eight jobs - <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">Warrior, Merchant, Thief, Apothecary, Hunter, Cleric, Scholar, Dancer.</strong></p>



<p>Every other character, or traveler, comes with a set Job that cannot be changed. However, the Mastery system allows you to equip a set number of Action and Passive skills for superior customization.</p>



<blockquote>
<p><em><strong>A deep dive into the Octopath Traveler 0 Job and Mastery system will go live soon.</strong></em></p>
</blockquote>



<h2 id="h-combat-system">Combat System</h2>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Octopath-Traveler-0-combat.jpg"></a><figcaption><em data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)">Combat is even more fun with 8 party members</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Octopath Traveler 0 employs a classic turn-based combat system where the player and the enemy take turns to attack, use skills and items, cast spells, or defend. Besides featuring the Break and Boost mechanics of the previous two games, the new entry in the series expands the combat party to eight total members, opening up a lot of interesting options.</p>



<blockquote>
<p><em><strong>A deep dive into the Octopath Traveler 0 combat mechanics and new 8-members party will go live soon.</strong></em></p>
</blockquote>



<h2 id="h-playable-characters-travelers">Playable Characters (Travelers)</h2>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Octopath-Traveler-0-Phenn.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Over 30 characters will join you in your quest in Octopath Traveler 0</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Octopath Traveler 0 features over 30 characters, or travelers, each one coming with a set Job, which is a unique variation of one of the eight Jobs the protagonist can use. Many of these travelers are entirely optional, requiring you to complete dedicated quests to recruit.</p>



<blockquote>
<p><strong><em>A complete list of Octopath Traveler 0 characters and details on how to recruit them will go live soon.</em></strong></p>
</blockquote>



<h2 id="h-town-building">Town-Building</h2>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Octopath-Traveler-0-Town-Building.jpg"></a><figcaption><em data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-processed">The game'</em><em>s</em><em data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-processed"> town-building mechanics that are tightly integrated in the experience</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Octopath Traveler 0 is the first entry in the series to feature town-building mechanics that allow you to have an actual hand in the restoration of Wishvale and the management of its residents. You will unlock more facilities and customization options over the course of the game to make the village truly your own while enjoying some great benefits.</p>



<blockquote>
<p><em><strong>An in-depth look at the Octopath Traveler 0 town-building mechanics will go live soon.</strong></em></p>
</blockquote>



<h2 id="h-story-progression">Story Progression</h2>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Octopath-Traveler-0-Story.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Octopath Traveler 0 features multiple main quests to complete focused on the restoration of Wishvale and the game's main villains</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Featuring a single protagonist as opposed to the usual eight, Octopath Traveler 0 does away with the eight individual storylines to offer a more focused experience. Following the prologue, you will be able to take on the Master of Power, Master of Wealth, and Master of Fame quests as well as the Rekindling the Flame quest focused on the restoration of Wishvale.</p>



<p>After completing the Master of quests, you will be able to begin the Finale arc, which brings the story to its conclusion.</p>



<h2 id="h-review">Review</h2>



<p>While mildly complex, all of these mechanics come together really well in the game. You can learn more about this by checking out our <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/octopath-traveler-0-review-in-progress-a-masterclass-in-villany/"><strong>Octopath Traveler 0 review.</strong></a></p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/how-to/octopath-traveler-0-all-guides-walkthroughs-and-beginner-tips-hub/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>