<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 15:08:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Donkey Kong Country Returns HD Trailer Showcases Fun Features]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/new-donkey-kong-country-returns-hd-trailer-showcases-fun-features/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-donkey-kong-country-returns-hd-trailer-showcases-fun-features.1057803/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/new-donkey-kong-country-returns-hd-trailer-showcases-fun-features/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A new Donkey Kong Country Returns HD trailer has been released by <a href="https://wccftech.com/xenoblade-chronicles-series-developer-monolith-soft-is-now-fully-owned-by-nintendo/">Nintendo</a>, and it showcases some of the content that players can expect from this nostalgic journey. This game was originally released on both the Nintendo Wii and the Nintendo 3DS, with the 3DS having extra levels. In this new visually-enhanced version of the game, those levels will be included, and as a result, there are 80 levels across nine different worlds for players to explore. For those interested in getting this game, it will be available on Nintendo Switch on January 16, 2025. For a glimpse into what's to come, make sure to check out the trailer below.</p>
<p><iframe title="A barrelful of details on Donkey Kong Country Returns HD! (Nintendo Switch)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/skNFOPOiyYw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>This game has lots of fun details for those who are completionists, as there are secrets and collectibles to gather, as well as a Time Attack medal, which will require the player to be quick on their feet, especially when it comes to facing off against the boss battles at the end of each world.</p>
<p>Much like many other Donkey Kong games, players will also be able to play this game in local co-ops, allowing you to play with a friend or family member, where your teammate can play as Diddy Kong and give you a helping hand.&nbsp; By having Diddy Kong help you out, you will be able to utilize his jet pack, which can be used for some of the more challenging jumps in the game, as well as to fight off enemies using his peanut popgun.</p>
<p>When the game was first released for the Nintendo Wii, it was proven to be quite challenging. In this remastered version of Donkey Kong Country Returns HD, you will have the option to choose between Classic Mode, which is the difficulty it was at originally, or playing using Modern Mode if you need a bit of a helping hand and want an easier experience.</p>
<p>Of course, it's completely up to you whether you play this game solo or with a friend, and you are still able to succeed just using Donkey Kong's Ground Pound and Barrel Roll.</p>
<p>For those interested, you<a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/donkey-kong-country-returns-hd-switch/?srsltid=AfmBOooFtowm_VZ2XeH0f79at3njXQb3iRlhA9zoLIZEmBbGY991JSvm" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> can currently pre-order the game</a> now for a price of $59.99, with the game set to release on January 16, 2025.</p>

			
			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The PlayStation 5 Is More Than Capable of Emulating PlayStation 3 Games, New Test Confirms]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-capable-emulating-playstation-3/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-playstation-5-is-more-than-capable-of-emulating-playstation-3-games-new-test-confirms.1057737/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-capable-emulating-playstation-3/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The base PlayStation 5 is more than capable of emulating PlayStation 3 games at a hardware level, a new test confirms.</p>
<p>A new video shared by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@LowestLogan" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lowest Logan</a> on YouTube showcases a test conducted using an AMD BC-250, a mining card that features the PlayStation 5 silicon, most likely created by repurposing chips that did not meet the full specifications required by the console, complete with 16 GB of GDDR6 RAM. The card, however, has some limitations over the actual PS5 hardware, as two CPU cores have been disabled, and only 24 compute units are available over the total number of 32 units.</p>
<p>To get the AMD BC-250 to run games like the PlayStation 5 hardware it is based on, Lowest Logan had to overcome plenty of challenges, as both Windows and Linux distros did not run properly. After some experimenting, however, the YouTuber managed to get everything up and running and has tested some PlayStation 3 games via the excellent RPCS3 emulator, proving the claims that PS3 emulation is too computationally heavy for the PS5 are false. Both Gran Turismo 5 Prologue and Little Big Planet ran well at both native and higher resolution, keeping steady framerates even with some of the hardware limitations over the actual PS5, including memory limitations, as the GPU driver only saw a single memory clock state for the GPU, 450 Mhz, which put it on the same level of an RX 480 GPU, a much weaker card than the RX 6700 GPU the PS5 GPU is close to. So, even with a lot of performance left on the table, the current generation console is more than capable of running PlayStation 3 games.</p>
<p><iframe title="I Ran PS3 Games on PS5 Silicon to Prove Sony Wrong" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_zbw_A9dIWM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>As of now, select PlayStation 3 games are available on PlayStation 5, but only via game streaming, and a<span>&nbsp;P<a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/ps-plus/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">layStation Plus Premium</a> subscription is required to access these titles</span>. More information on this subscription tier can be found <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/ps-plus/">here</a>.</p>

			
			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xenoblade Chronicles Series Developer Monolith Soft Is Now Fully Owned by Nintendo]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/xenoblade-chronicles-series-developer-monolith-soft-is-now-fully-owned-by-nintendo/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xenoblade-chronicles-series-developer-monolith-soft-is-now-fully-owned-by-nintendo.1057728/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/xenoblade-chronicles-series-developer-monolith-soft-is-now-fully-owned-by-nintendo/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Xenoblade Chronicles series developer Monolith Soft is now fully owned by Nintendo, as the Japanese company has reportedly purchased the remaining shares of the company it did not previously own.\</p>
<p>As reported by <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/nintendo-now-owns-100-of-monolith-soft/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Automaton</a>, the development studio's <a href="https://www.monolithsoft.co.jp/company/#overview">official website</a> confirmed that now Nintendo is the only owner. The studio, which was founded in 1999 by Xenogears' creator Tetsuya Takahashi after he left SquareSoft, started a prolific partnership with Nintendo with the release of Xenoblade Chronicles on the original Wii, which led to Nintendo eventually purchasing 80% of Monolith shares from Namco in 2007, which were further increased to 96% in 2011. The remaining 4% shares were owned by founders Hirohide Sugiura, Tetsuya Takahashi, and Yasuyuki Honne.</p>
<p>Given that Nintendo already owned the Xenoblade Chronicles developer, today's news shouldn't really impact the developer in any major capacity. Besides working on their franchise, Monolith Soft also supported the development of other Nintendo games, such as The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild and Tears of the Kingdom, so the studio has been an integral part of the development process for many first-party Nintendo titles for some time.</p>
<p>Monolith Soft's next game will be&nbsp;<a href="https://wccftech.com/xenoblade-chronicles-x-definitive-edition-comparison/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Xenoblade Chronicles X: Definitive Edition</a>, a new version of the open-world role-playing game originally released on Wii U in 2015. Launching on March 20th, 2025, the new version of the game will come with updated visuals as well as an alternate version of the post-credit scene featuring a mysterious hooded figure, which could finally tie the game with the rest of the series.</p>

			
			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
	</div>

		
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Executive Says Exclusivity Will Be Considered on a Case-by-Case Basis]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/xbox-executive-says-exclusivity-will-be-considered-on-a-case-by-case-basis/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-executive-says-exclusivity-will-be-considered-on-a-case-by-case-basis.1057695/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/xbox-executive-says-exclusivity-will-be-considered-on-a-case-by-case-basis/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Microsoft's Xbox finally has a Game of the Year contender in a popular category such as action/adventure (or, as I called it <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-indiana-at-his-finest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in my review</a>, adventure/action) with Indiana Jones and the Great Circle. It's a bit ironic that it launched a couple of weeks too late to be considered for The Game Awards show that goes live tomorrow.</p>
<p>Regardless of that, Microsoft and all parties involved (Bethesda, MachineGames, LucasFilm) are very happy about the great reception of the game. Speaking to Variety after the reviews hit, Xbox president of game content and studios Matt Booty also discussed the exclusivity topic, suggesting that it will be evaluated on a case-by-case basis.</p>
<p><em>We are very much making the exclusivity and windowing decisions on a game by game basis, and each of our studios is in a little bit of a different position. There’s also the production timeline on a game, so the decision on spacing comes there first. We want to make sure there’s a great experience for our Xbox players, and then the gap between when it becomes available on PlayStation is as much a production decision as it is anything else. This is a game that was in production before we acquired Bethesda, even.</em></p>
<p>This sounded like a partial backtrack compared to Microsoft Gaming CEO Phil Spencer's <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-handheld-red-line-porting-games/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">latest statement</a> that there were no 'red lines' when it came to Xbox exclusives being ported to other consoles.</p>
<p>With Indiana Jones and the Great Circle, the situation was a bit more complex. As mentioned by Booty, the game started development ahead of Microsoft's acquisition of Bethesda parent company ZeniMax. As such, it was originally<a href="https://wccftech.com/bethesdas-indiana-jones-game-exclusive/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> not planned</a> to be an Xbox exclusive. That changed later as Microsoft <a href="https://wccftech.com/indiana-jones-game-will-be-pc-xbox-exclusive-and-day-1-on-gp/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">decided</a> to launch the game only on Xbox and PC to boost its Game Pass subscription service. To do so, they had to <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-exclusivity-indiana-jones-made-sense/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">amend the contract</a> with Lucasfilm (and Disney).</p>
<p>However, Microsoft's stance on exclusivity toward rival consoles has changed drastically in the last few months, beginning with the <a href="https://wccftech.com/starfield-indiana-jones-not-going-multiplatform-4-older-xbox-titles-will/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ports of Sea of Thieves, Hi-Fi Rush, Pentiment, and Grounded</a>. Consequently, Indiana Jones and the Great Circle got a simultaneous <a href="https://wccftech.com/find/?q=indiana+jones+timed" target="_blank" rel="noopener">release date announcement</a> for PC and Xbox and a release window for PlayStation 5, leaving some Xbox fans a bit baffled.</p>
<p>Following Spencer's statement, it seemed like there were no barriers anymore, but Booty's words leave some room for Microsoft to potentially keep some exclusives close to its chest. The general trend is clearly to maximize revenue by releasing games on as many platforms as possible, though.</p>
<p>Their next big console exclusive is Obsidian's <a href="https://wccftech.com/avowed-hands-on-preview-eora-from-a-whole-new-perspective/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Avowed</a>, due to launch on February 18 for PC and Xbox Series S|X.</p>

			
			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
	</div>

		
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>