<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 17:09:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Epic Announces New PvE Mode LEGO Fortnite Expeditions Launching Tomorrow]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/epic-announces-new-pve-mode-lego-fortnite-expeditions-launching-tomorrow/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/epic-announces-new-pve-mode-lego-fortnite-expeditions-launching-tomorrow.1220886/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/epic-announces-new-pve-mode-lego-fortnite-expeditions-launching-tomorrow/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/epic-games-sues-fortnite-cheat-maker/">Epic</a> has officially <a href="https://www.fortnite.com/news/squad-up-and-save-the-day-in-lego-fortnite-expeditions">announced</a> LEGO Fortnite Expeditions, a new PvE mode that is launching tomorrow, on&nbsp;<strong>June 18, 2025</strong>.</p>
<p>Expeditions is a mission-based mode where you jump into various missions with three other players as a four-player co-op mode all with the aim of taking down a mysteriously masked villain, Mask Maker Daigo, who will destroy the world if you and your friends don't put a stop to his antics first.</p>
<p>You'll head out on these missions from your home base, the Supernova Academy, where you and the newly introduced heroes you'll play as, Shadow Caller, The Hunter, and Rift Ripper, are all training to become the next class of world-saving superheroes.</p>
<p>Epic also unveiled a gameplay trailer showing off each of the three hero classes in action, with Rift Ripper being extremely mobile and capable of reaching high areas with their Rift Jump and a Rift Dodge that works like a short-distance teleport.</p>
<p>Shadow Caller is very mobile in a different way, as they're able to hover above the ground while using magical projectiles to dispatch enemies. While The Hunter is a fast-moving ranged-focused class with a Bull's-eye Blade that can multiply the damage you do and make your attacks more accurate in battle.</p>
<p><iframe title="LEGO Fortnite Expeditions - Super Gameplay Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hMOPVQSHIic?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Beyond the core powers each class has, you'll also be able to increase your damage output with what Epic is calling the 'Tools in the Toolbox,' which gives you the choice between Dual Daggers, a War Hammer, or Plasma Pistols, to add an extra punch to combat.</p>
<p>LEGO Fortnite Expeditions will be available tomorrow and will be found in Discover in LEGO Fortnite, or it can be accessed from Odyssey and Brick Life using the Battle Bus Station.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Overwatch 2 Outlines Season 17, Due to Begin on June 24]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/overwatch-2-outlines-season-17-due-to-begin-on-june-24/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/overwatch-2-outlines-season-17-due-to-begin-on-june-24.1220817/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/overwatch-2-outlines-season-17-due-to-begin-on-june-24/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Blizzard has announced that Season 17 is set to begin next Tuesday in Overwatch 2. The developers also shared what players can expect to find in the upcoming season of the free-to-play team-based hero shooter game.</p>
<p>The team previously <a href="https://wccftech.com/overwatch-2-team-says-stadium-mode-is-very-popular-outlines-future-roadmap/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> that Stadium continues to be very popular among Overwatch 2 players, so it is no surprise that much of this season is dedicated to the mode. Three heroes (Zenyatta, Sigma, and Junkrat) will be available in Stadium, and two new maps are being added: Esperança and Samoa. Moreover, thanks to expanded build tools and the debut of Stadium Forge, match strategy will run deeper. Stadium Forge is a create/save/share system that will allow players to test and refine team compositions. It will even include early and late game example loadouts for every hero.</p>
<p>Season 17 will also see the first-ever Stadium rank reset, giving everyone a fresh start to prove their skill. Drives will reward consistent performance, Custom Games will let users create their own rules, and fresh All-Star rewards will incentivize players to partake in the mode.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>At long last, map voting is being added to Overwatch 2 in Quick Play and Competitive. After the role queue locks, players will see three randomized map options to choose from. Every vote adds a 1-in-10 chance to that map's odds, and the winner is selected using a roulette-style roll. Team chat, battle tags, and individual votes are hidden to minimize pressure. Leaver penalties kick in as soon as voting begins, by the way.</p>
<p><iframe title="Season 17: Powered Up! Official Trailer | Overwatch 2" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7p5K_d1qgfQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Blizzard is also introducing three new maps. In Core mode, Aatlis is a vibrant new Flashpoint map showcasing the beauty and culture of Morocco. With lush gardens and luxury resort spaces, this map is built for tighter fights, cleaner rotations, and fast-paced momentum. As mentioned before, in Stadium mode, the streets of Esperança return in a round-based format with new elevation layers, allowing teams to switch tactics between rounds. It's kind of a Push map designed specifically for Stadium's unique format. Finally, the volcanic control point from Samoa joins the Stadium pool, bringing lava and loadouts together. Expect open arenas, intense vertical action, and ample space for high-mobility competitions.</p>
<p>Blizzard is launching two Mythics on day one for the first time in Overwatch 2. These are D.Va's Mythic Horang Hero Skin and Reaper's Mythic Steel Death Weapon Skin, both of which evolve through four tiers.</p>
<p>In about a month, the game will get a limited-time 6v6 mode called Hacks &amp; Hijinks in which match modifiers change every round. Players might float in low gravity, chase down health packs that charge your Ultimate, or react to brand-new mechanics that shake things up. Hacks &amp; Hijinx is only going to be available on Control maps between July 15 and 28.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>