<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 17:44:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Troy Baker To Return in Naughty Dog’s New Untitled Game, Neil Druckmann At Helm]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/troy-baker-to-return-in-naughty-dogs-new-untitled-game-neil-druckmann-at-helm/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/troy-baker-to-return-in-naughty-dog%E2%80%99s-new-untitled-game-neil-druckmann-at-helm.1044822/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/troy-baker-to-return-in-naughty-dogs-new-untitled-game-neil-druckmann-at-helm/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Troy Baker is a staple voice actor in the gaming sphere, and it's no surprise that he'll be making a return to Naughty Dog's new untitled game. For this title, Neil Druckmann will be at the helm, the mind behind The Last of Us and Uncharted. At the moment, there is no real information about the project, but <a href="https://www.gq-magazine.co.uk/article/troy-baker-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-interview" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GQ has confirmed</a> that Troy Baker has signed on to appear in the title in some capacity. It's not stated whether he'll be playing a big or small role, but it's positive that his voice will be recognized by many who dig into the upcoming project.</p>
<p>Naughty Dog has had a little bit of a difficult time, as they decided to cancel The Last of Us Online in December last year. This was an attempt to create a live service version of the beloved franchise, especially after the first season of the TV show did so well. The Last of Us did have multiplayer game modes before, where you could face off against other factions in combat. While they were trying to make The Last of Us Online, they said that they had to pull it as the studio would have had to funnel all of its resources into post-launch content for many years to come. By doing this, it would have heavily impacted any single-player games that they would be producing.</p>
<p>When The Last of Us Online was shut down, Naughty Dog confirmed that there was an ambitious single-player game in the works, but there have been no details released about the game since that announcement.</p>
<p>While there are minimal details about the upcoming Naughty Dog project, Druckmann has stated that he wants to breakaway from being known as the studio behind The Last of Us, and wants recognition for other projects. "I promise you, we will not be The Last of Us Studio forever," said Druckmann in an <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/naughty-dog-will-not-be-the-last-of-us-studio-forever-as-it-works-on-multiple-single-player-projects-neil-druckmann-says" target="_blank" rel="noopener">interview with IGN</a> in June.</p>
<p>Whether we will see any details emerge about this project in the near future remains to be seen. However, you'll be able to spot Troy Baker on the screen again soon as he is set to play Indiana Jones in MachineGames' Indiana Jones and the Great Circle. If you want to read our thoughts on that upcoming title, you can read <a href="https://wccftech.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-hands-on-preview-swinging-in-style/">the preview I did here</a>.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hitman Has Cut Ties With Conor McGregor After Court Ruling]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/hitman-cut-ties-with-conor-mcgregor-after-court-ruling/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hitman-has-cut-ties-with-conor-mcgregor-after-court-ruling.1044669/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/hitman-cut-ties-with-conor-mcgregor-after-court-ruling/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Hitman developer IO Interactive has made the decision to cut ties with the MMA fighter Conor McGregor after last week's Irish High <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/nov/22/mma-fighter-conor-mcgregor-assaulted-woman-at-dublin-hotel-jury-finds">Court ruling</a> where he was found to be guilty of assaulting and raping a woman in December 2018. The decision to cut ties comes shortly after a collaboration between IO Interactive and McGregor was confirmed, where he would be a character in the Hitman series called <a href="https://wccftech.com/hitman-world-of-assassination-featuring-conor-mcgregor-attracts-large-player-base/">The Disruptor</a>. His voice and likeness were used for the character, where he was featured as one of the game's Elusive Targets. There was a mission available, as well as a DLC pack that would provide permanent access to an arcade contract featuring The Disruptor and new cosmetics. However, since the ruling, IO Interactive has made the decision to cut all ties and will be removing all content featuring McGregor from the game.</p>
<p><a href="https://x.com/Hitman/status/1861049881160273921" target="_blank" rel="noopener">This statement</a> was made via social media this afternoon, where IO posted their announcement on X. The statement goes on to say: "In light of the recent court ruling regarding Conor McGregor, IO Interactive has made the decision to cease its collaboration with the athlete, effective immediately. e take this matter very seriously and cannot ignore its implications. Consequently, we will begin removing all content featuring Mr. McGregor from our storefronts starting today."</p>
<p>The Disruptor most recently returned to the Hitman game earlier this month as a limited-time mission that players would be able to participate in, with the mission set to be playable until 8 December. However, all of this will now be removed from the game. For those who own The Disruptor DLC, it hasn't been stated what will happen to the content since it's already been purchased. However, in cases like these, where content is removed regardless of circumstance, those who already own it tend to be able to continue to access it.</p>
<p>With the Irish Jury deciding what they did, McGregor was ordered to pay at least 248k Euro in damages. Despite this, he's also said that he plans to appeal the verdict. As there's no date as to when this will happen, it's hard to say what IO Interactive would be able to do about the situation should McGregor be successful in his appeal of last week's court ruling. For now though, people will no longer be able to purchase any content relating to the athlete for the unforeseeable.</p>


				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy VII Rebirth Director Thinks Xbox Is a Great Hardware Platform, Wants to Bring the Remake Trilogy to as Many Players as Possible]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-director-xbox-great-platform/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-director-thinks-xbox-is-a-great-hardware-platform-wants-to-bring-the-remake-trilogy-to-as-many-players-as-possible.1044666/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-director-xbox-great-platform/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Final Fantasy VII Rebirth, like its predecessor, hasn't been released on Xbox consoles so far, but it definitely sounds like the door is still open to seeing the Remake trilogy on Microsoft consoles in the future.</p>
<p>Speaking with <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/final-fantasy/final-fantasy-7-rebirths-director-is-an-xbox-fan-and-with-square-enix-testing-the-multiplatform-waters-he-says-he-wants-to-being-the-jrpg-to-as-many-players-out-there-as-possible/">GamesRadar+</a> shortly before taking the stage at this year's Golden Joystick Awards, game director Naoki Hamaguchi commented on the trilogy as a whole, saying that while nothing could be announced at the time, he certainly wants to bring the Final Fantasy VII remake series to as many players as possible. As such, they want to "create that situation, that environment, where more players can play the games in the future, and we want to look in that direction."</p>
<p>Square Enix changing its stance on platform exclusivity, which already produced some results with the release of select titles that missed Xbox consoles at launch, isn't an isolated happening but an industry-wide change, according to the Final Fantasy VII Rebirth director. With so many platforms available, it is no longer possible to release a game on a single platform and get most of the players wanting to play such a game on that single platform. Giving his personal opinion on the matter, Hamaguchi-san, owning an Xbox console, praised it as a great hardware platform, so it definitely sounds like there wouldn't be any resistance on his part to get the game out on Microsoft's consoles.</p>
<p>Despite having only released Final Fantasy VII Rebirth <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth/">earlier this year,</a> Naoki Hamaguchi and his team are already hard at work on the third and final part of the remake trilogy.<a href="https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-vii-remake-part-3-story-completed/"> The story and concept for the game are already completed</a>, so hopefully, it won't take much to see the first glimpse of the conclusion of Cloud's story.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>