<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 18:25:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nioh 3 Could Launch on Xbox Series S/X as Early as in August]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nioh-3-could-launch-xbox-as-early-as-in-august/</link>
            <guid>1423099</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>As we mentioned <a href="https://wccftech.com/roundup/nioh-3-everything-we-know-about-team-ninjas-supernatural-action-rpg/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in our <strong>Nioh 3</strong> info roundup article</a>, this third entry in <strong>Koei Tecmo</strong> and <strong>Team Ninja</strong>'s fantasy action RPG series is the first one not published by Sony and, as such, releases day and date on PC alongside PlayStation 5.</p>



<p>What we did not know exactly were <strong>the terms of a console-specific timed exclusivity</strong>. The lack of any mention of an Xbox Series S|X version was a dead giveaway that it would not be available at launch, and indeed, Sony <strong>was still likely to have secured some sort of temporal exclusivity</strong>. Now, more information on this matter has been shared at the very end of the official Nioh 3 PS5 Features trailer: the game cannot be released on other consoles <strong>for at least six months after the official launch date of February 6, 2026</strong>.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Nioh 3 - Features Trailer | PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bL_umw0ScIA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>This means that technically, <strong>Koei Tecmo could make the Xbox Series S and X versions available as early as August</strong>. Of course, it most likely won't be the case, but this suggests Xbox users won't have to wait too long to step into the role of <strong>Tokugawa Takechiyo</strong> as he fights off his brother and a horde of yokai demons to secure his ascension to Shogun. It's even theoretically possible that the <strong>Nintendo Switch 2</strong> could run the game, at least based on the official PC system requirements. Whether that means the developers and publisher actually port the game to Nintendo's latest hybrid console remains to be seen.</p>



<p>As a reminder, <strong>you can already step into the fray of Nioh 3</strong> <a href="https://wccftech.com/nioh-3-new-demo-ps5-pc-january-29-2026-carries-full-game-crossplay-missing/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">thanks to the free demo that was released on both PC and PlayStation 5 a few days ago</a>. The save created while playing this demo can be carried over to the full game, so you won't be starting from scratch when it becomes available in a few days.</p>



<p>Stay tuned for our review.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/nioh-3-could-launch-xbox-as-early-as-in-august/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[“Evil Has Always Had a Name”: Capcom’s New Short Film Sets the Mood for Resident Evil Requiem]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/evil-has-always-had-a-name-capcoms-new-short-film-sets-the-mood-for-resident-evil-requiem/</link>
            <guid>1423045</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>It's officially February, which means that we're finally within the release month for <strong>Resident Evil Requiem</strong>. The new mainline entry in the long-running horror franchise looks like it could be one of the series' best, if it's able to strike the right balance between <a href="https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-requiem-gameplay-resident-evil-showcase-capcom/">its <strong>RE2</strong> and <strong>RE7</strong>-inspired sections featuring <strong>Grace Ashcroft</strong> and its <strong>RE4</strong>-inspired sections</a> with the iconic <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/leon-hot-uncle-resident-evil-requiem-capcom-female-staff/">Leon Kennedy</a></strong>.</p>



<p>Resident Evil Requiem will be arriving on PC, PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and Nintendo Switch 2 on <strong>February 27, 2026,</strong> and ahead of that release date, developer <strong>Capcom</strong> has shared a new short film to get players in the mood for the new entry, and to further play on one of the new features the game will include, namely the fact that <a href="https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-requiem-zombies-more-unpredictable-than-ever/"><strong>zombies will retain</strong> some of their human memories and actions.</a></p>



<p>The three-and-a-half-minute short film titled "<em>Evil Has Always Had a Name</em>" stars Longlegs actor <strong>Maika Monroe</strong>, and as one viewer put it, it is "<em>better than most RE movies</em>." The film follows a mother and daughter living in Raccoon City ahead of the outbreak that RE2 centers on. It ends with a heartbreaking shot of the mother, now a zombie, visiting her daughter's grave with a photo of them in her hands.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Resident Evil Requiem - Evil Has Always Had A Name | Short Film" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/M6gXJoN8RNk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>She's shot by an unidentified patrol group clearing out zombies in the area, but it's clear that her visit is meant to emulate what we've already seen in trailers for Requiem, with zombies repeatedly carrying out actions they did in their human lives.</p>



<p>It's an emotional short that really sets the mood and tone for Resident Evil Requiem, and serves as a tragic reminder that when you're facing off against zombies in Requiem as either Grace or Leon, they were all people once, with their own lives, families, and loved ones.  If the storytelling in the game is able to carry the same emotional weight this short film does, then we're in for an incredible horror experience when Requiem arrives on February 27.</p>



<p>Even before its official release, Requiem is setting up Capcom for a strong year. After <a href="https://wccftech.com/this-is-pretty-damning-lapsed-players-may-not-be-coming-back-to-monster-hunter-wilds-after-all-as-monster-hunter-rise-continues-to-outsell-the-game/">a strong third-quarter financial report for the company (save for the sales of <strong>Monster Hunter Wilds</strong> compared to its predecessor)</a>, the <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/capcom-shares-soar-great-sales-forecast-resident-evil-requiem/">company's shares rose by 10%,</a></strong> with strong forecasting thanks to Resident Evil Requiem's imminent arrival, followed by <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/monster-hunter-stories-3-twisted-reflection-release-date-march-2026-nintendo-switch-2/">Monster Hunter Stories 3: Twisted Reflection</a></strong> coming up in March 2026.</p>



<p>When we <a href="https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-requiem-gamescom-hands-on-preview-turn-on-the-lights/">got the chance to check out Requiem during Gamescom 2025</a>, Wccftech's Francecsco De Meo noted that the demo he played "<em>did an excellent job showcasing its survival horror mechanics and how technological advancements will enhance a fairly classic experience</em>." Requiem also made the list for <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-horror-games-of-2026-a-new-era-of-dread/">Wccftech's Most Anticipated Horror Games in 2026</a></strong> and our <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-games-of-2026-the-return-of-aaa/">Most Anticipated Games of 2026</a></strong> overall.</p>



<p>For all of our Resident Evil Requiem coverage, <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/roundup/resident-evil-requiem-everything-we-know-about-the-new-game-in-capcoms-beloved-horror-franchise/">check out our hub page here for all the news, guides, interviews, and our coming review of the game</a></strong>. </p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/evil-has-always-had-a-name-capcoms-new-short-film-sets-the-mood-for-resident-evil-requiem/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>