<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 09:47:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Quest I & II HD-2D Remake Is Out on October 30, Switch 2 Version Added]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/dragon-quest-i-ii-hd-2d-remake-is-out-on-october-30-switch-2-version-added/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-quest-i-ii-hd-2d-remake-is-out-on-october-30-switch-2-version-added.1199247/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/dragon-quest-i-ii-hd-2d-remake-is-out-on-october-30-switch-2-version-added/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>On Dragon Quest Day, Square Enix has <a href="https://x.com/DragonQuest/status/1927258985721184644" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> the release date of the highly anticipated Dragon Quest I &amp; II HD-2D Remake. The remake combo will debut on October 30 for all main platforms: PC (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2893570/DRAGON_QUEST_I__II_HD2D_Remake/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/dragon-quest-i-ii-hd-2d-remake/9MT8RHZXFP5M/0017" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Microsoft Store</a>), PlayStation 5, Xbox Series S|X, Nintendo Switch, and Nintendo Switch 2. It will be priced at $59.99.</p>
<p>All digital pre-orders will receive the following bonus items:</p>
<p>• One pair of elevating shoes<br>
• Three seeds of strength<br>
• Three seeds of defence<br>
• Three seeds of agility<br>
• Three seeds of life<br>
• Three seeds of magic</p>
<p>Players with existing save data for <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</a> are entitled to the following bonus in-game items in the Dragon Quest I &amp; II HD-2D Remake:</p>
<p>• Dragon Quest I: One dog suit<br>
• Dragon Quest II: One cat suit</p>
<p>These bonus in-game items can be acquired by:<br>
• Dragon Quest I: Opening the chest inside the inn in Tantegel.<br>
• Dragon Quest II: Opening the chest inside the inn in Midenhall.</p>
<p>Your save data for Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake must be tied to the same account that you play Dragon Quest I &amp; II HD-2D Remake with for you to claim these rewards. Moreover, you are still eligible for these rewards if you start playing Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake after you have begun playing Dragon Quest I &amp; II HD-2D Remake.</p>
<p><iframe title="DRAGON QUEST&nbsp;I&nbsp;&amp;&nbsp;II HD-2D&nbsp;Remake  | Teaser&nbsp;Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CDtWQZNL5MA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake was a massive success for Square Enix, earning the praise of fans and critics alike. <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">In Wccftech's review</a>, the game was rated 8.6 out of 10 by Kai Tatsumoto:</p>
<p><em>Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake has been given a complete graphical overhaul, instead giving the iconic RPG a makeover in the same vein as Square-Enix’s Octopath Traveler and other similar titles. The entire world is brightly colored and blooming with light. Even if you’re intimately familiar with every step retracing Ortega’s journey, the complete reimagining of the adventure makes this feel like a brand new adventure rather than just another release of Seeds of Salvation. All I can say now is that I can’t wait to go through the other Remakes next year.</em></p>


			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DAVY x JONES Is an Intriguing FPS from the Makers of BLACKTAIL]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/davy-x-jones-is-an-intriguing-fps-from-the-makers-of-blacktail/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/davy-x-jones-is-an-intriguing-fps-from-the-makers-of-blacktail.1199232/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/davy-x-jones-is-an-intriguing-fps-from-the-makers-of-blacktail/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Polish developer PARASIGHT, maker of <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/blacktail-intriguing-slavic-witchcraft/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BLACKTAIL</a>, has announced a new and intriguing first-person shooter game titled DAVY x JONES.</p>
<p>As you might easily guess from the title, the protagonist is the infamous pirate of legend. In this game, though, he's been betrayed, robbed, and even beheaded. But that's not the end for him, who falls into The Locker, a surreal pirate hell, and allies with his own skull - a guide and a source of endless jokes - to get revenge on the one who wronged him, none other than Blackbeard.</p>
<p>Bartosz Kaproń, CEO and Creative Director of PARASIGHT, said in a statement:</p>
<p><em>We're beyond excited to finally unleash DAVY x JONES upon the world. At PARASIGHT, we believe great stories should hit as hard as the action—and in DAVY x JONES, they literally do. We split our protagonist in two—his skull and his body—and threw them into the pirate underworld to fight their way back to legend. It’s our wildest journey yet, packed with surreal adventure, larger-than-life characters, and just enough surprise to keep things fun. If you've ever dreamed of swashbuckling through the afterlife with your own severed head cracking wise beside you—this is your game.</em></p>
<p><iframe title="Davy x Jones: Official Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QFXyTRgrRi0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The Locker is split into nine islands drifting across an endless sea of clouds. In these unique environments, players will face twisted fiends, cursed souls, and legendary behemoths like the Kraken — guardians of the underworld’s darkest secrets.</p>
<p>However, another behemoth, the whale-ship hybrid Abby, befriends the protagonist and becomes his mobile base. Players can even recruit legendary officers to crew her and unleash her cannons in combat. Fights will mix swordfighting, gun action, and a grappling hook to get close.</p>
<p>Moreover, enemy drops provide an element of risk versus reward. Each defeated enemy drops Underworld Essence, and when Essences converge, they merge into a treasure chest containing powerful loot. However, each chest also unleashes an unpredictable fiend, so it's up to the player to decide whether to take that risk.</p>
<p>There's no release window yet, but DAVY x JONES will be launched for PC (there's already a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2611170/DAVY_x_JONES/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam page)</a> and consoles.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nacon Is Once Again Publishing WRC Games, New WRC Series In Development]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nacon-is-once-again-publishing-wrc-games-new-wrc-series-in-development/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nacon-is-once-again-publishing-wrc-games-new-wrc-series-in-development.1199013/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nacon-is-once-again-publishing-wrc-games-new-wrc-series-in-development/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The FIA World Rally Championship has <a href="https://www.wrc.com/en/news/nacon-confirmed-as-wrc-games-publisher-from-2027-">announced</a> that Nacon will once again be in charge of publishing WRC video games with the official FIA World Rally Championship license after it had previously gone to Codemasters and EA. <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/codemasters-wrc-license">Codemasters purchased</a> the licensing rights to make its own series of WRC games in 2020, which began with <a href="https://wccftech.com/ea-sports-wrc-roadmap-officially-revealed/">EA Sports WRC 2023</a>, launched on November 3, 2023.</p>
<p>After <a href="https://wccftech.com/codemasters-ceo-ea-is-like-our-cinderella-shoe-a-perfect-fit-they-listen-but-dont-force-us/">EA acquired Codemasters</a>, EA was supposed to have the rights to make WRC games from 2023 to 2027, but for whatever reason, either EA or the WRC decided to end the partnership after just one game. Prior to Codemasters' purchasing the WRC licensing rights, Nacon had published the previous seven WRC games, all of which were developed by French developer Kylotonn, which Nacon acquired in 2018.</p>
<p>Last month, <a href="https://wccftech.com/codemasters-shows-off-f1-25-gameplay-confirms-wrc-games-are-on-pause/">Codemasters confirmed</a> it would be "<em>pausing development plans on future rally titles.</em>" With today's announcement that the WRC license is back in Nacon's hands, we know why.</p>
<p>"<em>We are thrilled to renew our collaboration with WRC Promoter,</em>" Nacon chief executive officer Alain Falc said in a <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/05/26/3088220/0/en/PRESS-RELEASE-NACON-ANNOUNCES-AGREEMENT-WITH-WRC-PROMOTER-FOR-THE-PUBLISHING-OF-THE-OFFICIAL-GAMES-OF-THE-FIA-WORLD-RALLY-CHAMPIONSHIP-FROM-2027-TO-2032.html">press release</a>.</p>
<p>"<em>This iconic license provides an exceptional playground to build a highly refined driving experience that lives up to the expectations of rally fans. Between 2015 and 2023, we had the opportunity to work closely with the championship's official teams and many drivers, allowing us to gain solid and unique expertise in translating rallying into a video game experience. This new venture marks a major milestone: a fully reimagined project driven by a passionate and specialized team, with a clear ambition to elevate rally games to new heights</em>."</p>
<p>The new deal between the FIA World Rally Championship and Nacon gives Nacon the rights to make WRC games for the 2027 to 2032 seasons, which means that Nacon will likely take the next two years to develop the new WRC series announced with this news. According to the press release, this new series is "<em>aiming to deliver an immersive experience that faithfully reflects the reality of the championship and meets the expectations of both rally enthusiasts and new players</em>."</p>
<p>"<em>After a comprehensive evaluation, we are delighted to have reached an agreement with Nacon</em>," said FIA World Rally Championship chief marketing officer Arne Dirks. "<em>Their vision for the franchise stands out, and their expertise in delivering great rally games is unquestioned. We look forward to breaking new ground together in this collaboration, to truly turn the WRC games into epic adventures and offer gaming experiences beyond rally as we know it today</em>."</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DOOM The Dark Ages VR Mod Released by Luke Ross]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/doom-the-dark-ages-vr-mod-released-by-luke-ross/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/doom-the-dark-ages-vr-mod-released-by-luke-ross.1198974/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/doom-the-dark-ages-vr-mod-released-by-luke-ross/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Virtual reality modder Luke Ross has <a href="https://www.patreon.com/posts/were-eternally-129851027?utm_medium=clipboard_copy&amp;utm_source=copyLink&amp;utm_campaign=postshare_fan&amp;utm_content=web_share" target="_blank" rel="noopener">released</a> a new R.E.A.L. VR mod to bring DOOM The Dark Ages to VR devices. To have access to it, you'll need an active subscription to his Patreon at the VR Friend tier, which costs $10 monthly. Of course, this would also provide you with access to all of Luke Ross's prior VR mods, such as <a href="https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-vr-mod-coming-thanks-to-modder-luke-ross/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Elden Ring</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/marvels-spider-man-vr-mod-by-luke-ross-is-now-available-to-patreon-subscribers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Marvel's Spider-Man</a>, Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora, Indiana Jones and the Great Circle, Dark Souls, Death Stranding, and more. The modder had previously released VR ports of Take-Two's Mafia: Definitive Edition, Grand Theft Auto V, and Red Dead Redemption 2, but a DMCA takedown notice from the publisher <a href="https://wccftech.com/vr-modder-luke-ross-gets-dmca-notice-for-his-rdr2-gta-and-mafia-vr-mods/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">forced him to take those down</a>, to the great disappointment of the VR community.</p>
<p>As usual with his mods, VR gaming YouTuber Bearded Banjo was able to check out the new DOOM The Dark Ages Mod beforehand and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0AaIs90I3gY" target="_blank" rel="noopener">published an enthusiastic video report of himself playing</a>. Bearded Banjo described the experience as 'fast, frantic, and sometimes overwhelming'. The mod supports head tracking and head-based aiming, but motion controls are unavailable, so you'll have to stick with using the gamepad. Banjo said the gameplay was captured on a PC equipped with an NVIDIA GeForce RTX 4090 while using a Quest 3 connected via wired link.</p>
<p>The experience was smooth overall, even though he couldn't get NVIDIA DLSS Super Resolution to work with the mod for the time being. This could be fixed in a future update by Luke Ross. As a side note, the VR modder <a href="https://www.patreon.com/posts/score-one-for-129841705" target="_blank" rel="noopener">posted</a> the results of his experiments with <a href="https://wccftech.com/heres-how-you-can-run-amd-fsr-4-on-basically-any-title/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Optiscaler</a>, which is a great boost to those wishing to play his VR mods on an AMD GPU:</p>
<p><em>Thanks to that mod, in almost every game that supports DLSS upscaling, you can substitute AMD's FSR implementation and have it run effortlessly on AMD hardware. But from the game's point of view, the video buffers will still be produced in DLSS format, and that means that my R.E.A.L. VR mod can intercept them and fix the disocclusions by translating the calls to work in stereoscopic mode, thus getting rid of the shimmering around nearby objects and NPCs.</em></p>
<p>You can read our DOOM The Dark Ages review (non-VR) <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/doom-the-dark-ages-review/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>. The game has <a href="https://wccftech.com/doom-the-dark-ages-reaches-3-million-players-7x-faster-than-eternal/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reached</a> the 3 million player milestone much faster than DOOM Eternal. However, the jury is still out on whether it was financially more successful, as most of those are likely to have played the game on Game Pass. According to Ampere Analysis estimates, over two million players <a href="https://wccftech.com/more-than-2m-doom-the-dark-ages-launch-players-were-on-xbox-only-500k-playing-on-ps5/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">checked out the game on Xbox</a> while player numbers on PC and PlayStation 5 were around half a million, definitely lower than anticipated, at least on the PC platform.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Shadows Update 1.0.5 Unlocks Pre-Order Bonus Quest For All Players, Includes Dead By Daylight Collaboration And More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-shadows-update-1-0-5-unlocks-pre-order-bonus-quest-for-all-players-includes-dead-by-daylight-collaboration-and-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-shadows-update-1-0-5-unlocks-pre-order-bonus-quest-for-all-players-includes-dead-by-daylight-collaboration-and-more.1198959/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-shadows-update-1-0-5-unlocks-pre-order-bonus-quest-for-all-players-includes-dead-by-daylight-collaboration-and-more/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Ubisoft Quebec has published the <a href="https://www.ubisoft.com/en-us/game/assassins-creed/news/3hJ2jNQEK4AXQGMg79pm2h">patch notes</a> for Assassin's Creed Shadows' next title update, 1.0.5, which will be available on PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC tomorrow, Tuesday, May 27, 2025.</p>
<p>The update makes the 'Thrown to the Dogs' quest, which was previously only available for players who pre-ordered Shadows, available to all players. It also includes a collaboration event between Assassin's Creed Shadows and <a href="https://wccftech.com/dead-by-daylight-2v8-game-mode-and-cross-progression-date-reveal/">Dead by Daylight</a>, with an entirely new Dead by Daylight-inspired quest.</p>
<p>Ubisoft teases the premise of the quest in the patch notes, but doesn't get into specific details. "<em>As villagers begin to disappear, Naoe becomes suspicious of the strange presence attacking the local people of Harima</em>," the patch notes read. "<em>To succeed, you will need to master unique mechanics in order to confront a formidable otherworldly threat...</em>"</p>
<p>There's also a much smaller collaboration with <a href="https://wccftech.com/balatro-gets-four-new-cosmetic-collaborations-in-new-update/">Balatro</a>, which doesn't add a Balatro-themed quest but a new trinket for Naoe and an amulet for Yasuke that are both inspired by Balatro.</p>
<p>Ubisoft also made two key improvements to the game's parkour system. Now, when you're climbing up or down a building, so long as the directional inputs don't change, you will continue to sprint without having to re-engage sprinting. Also, Naoe and Yasuke can now vertically jump up to grab "<em>any ledge, awnings or overhangs within reach, reducing the need to rely on vertical wall runs</em>."</p>
<p>There are also a number of features that have been added to the game's Photo Mode, like being able to alter the time of day for a photo or save custom filters. And, as with any major patch, there's also a slew of bug fixes across multiple aspects of the game.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony’s Days Of Play Sale Will Reportedly Kick Off This Week, Includes PS5 And PS5 Pro Discounts, Console Bundles, And More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/sonys-days-of-play-sale-will-reportedly-kick-off-this-week-includes-ps5-and-ps5-pro-discounts-console-bundles-and-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony%E2%80%99s-days-of-play-sale-will-reportedly-kick-off-this-week-includes-ps5-and-ps5-pro-discounts-console-bundles-and-more.1198911/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/sonys-days-of-play-sale-will-reportedly-kick-off-this-week-includes-ps5-and-ps5-pro-discounts-console-bundles-and-more/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><strong>Update 26/05/2025:</strong> Shortly after Dealabs reported the European sale prices for PlayStation hardware like the PS5 Pro and PS VR2 for the Days of Play sale, Insider-Gaming reported the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-playstation-days-of-play-2025-discounts-united-states/">US</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-days-of-play-2025-discounts-uk/">UK</a> prices for the consoles.</p>
<p>According to Insider-Gaming, in the US, the PS5 Pro will be $50 off from its regular price, so it'll go from $699.99 to&nbsp;<strong>$649.99</strong> for the Days of Play sale. The PS VR2 is also getting a $50 price cut in the US for the sale, on both the standard version of the headset and the bundle version that comes with Horizon Call of the Mountain. Both will be&nbsp;<strong>$349.99</strong> during the sale.</p>
<p>In the UK, the PS5 Pro is being cut by&nbsp;<strong>£45</strong>, and will go from its regular £699.99 price to&nbsp;<strong>£654.99.&nbsp;</strong>The base PS5 console, both the standard edition with a disc drive and the digital edition without a disc drive, are getting a&nbsp;<strong>£90</strong> price cut.</p>
<p>So the standard PS5 will go from £479.99 to&nbsp;<strong>£389.99</strong>, and the digital edition PS5 will go from £429.99 to&nbsp;<strong>£339.99.&nbsp;</strong>The PS VR2 is also getting the same&nbsp;<strong>£45</strong> price cut as the PS5 Pro, bringing it from £399.99 to&nbsp;<strong>£354.99</strong> for the standard edition of the headset and the previously mentioned Horizon Call of the Mountain bundle.</p>
<p><strong>Original Story:</strong></p>
<p>According to a report from <a href="https://www.dealabs.com/magazine/days-of-play-2025-voici-un-apercu-sur-les-dates-et-promotions-du-prochain-evenement-playstation-60170">Billbil-kun at Dealabs</a>, Sony is due to launch its Days of Play sale this coming Wednesday, May 28, 2025, which will include the first discount for the PS5 Pro, discounts for base PS5 consoles, bundles that package Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 with a PS5, and more.</p>
<p>Regarding Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 console bundles, <a href="https://wccftech.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-ps5-bundles-are-reportedly-coming-soon/">Billbil-kun reported earlier this month</a> that those bundles would be on their way, and this latest report adds that they'll be revealed <a href="https://www.dealabs.com/magazine/voici-la-date-de-sortie-des-packs-ps5-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-60177">alongside</a> the rest of the Days of Play sales this week.</p>
<p>If the price of the PS5 Pro has kept you from buying it, then this sale might not exactly change your mind. According to Dealabs, the price of the PS5 Pro is only being slashed by <strong>€50</strong>, while the base PS5 is getting a <strong>€100</strong> price cut for both the standard edition of the console that comes with a disc drive and the digital edition that doesn't come with a drive.</p>
<p>PlayStation VR2 is also getting a small price cut, and just like the PS5 Pro, PlayStation is only taking €50 off the price of its current-generation VR headset.</p>
<p>Here are all the hardware discounts that will be part of the Days of Play sale, per Billbil-kun and Dealabs:</p>
<ul>
<li>PS5 Standard Edition (with disc drive): <strong>€449.99&nbsp;</strong>instead of €549.99</li>
<li>PS5 Digital Edition (without disc drive):&nbsp;<strong>€399.99&nbsp;</strong>instead of €499.99</li>
<li>PS5 Pro:&nbsp;<strong>€749.99</strong> instead of €799.99</li>
<li>PS VR2:&nbsp;<strong>€399.99</strong> instead of €449.99</li>
</ul>
<p>Also, players looking to grab extra controllers will be able to do so as a "<em>selection</em>" of DualSense controllers will be on sale for&nbsp;<strong>€54.99</strong>.</p>
<p>Beyond the hardware sales, the Days of Play sale usually includes a litany of software sales, both for PS5 games and Sony's PlayStation Plus subscription service. There's no exact word on what those will look like at the time of writing, but we'll know soon enough, as Dealabs claims the sale will be fully revealed tomorrow, Tuesday, May 27, 2025.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Half-Life 3 Will Be The Last Entry in the Series – Rumor]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/half-life-3-last-entry-series/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/half-life-3-will-be-the-last-entry-in-the-series-%E2%80%93-rumor.1198875/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/half-life-3-last-entry-series/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The yet-to-be-announced Half-Life 3 could finally bring the series' story to a conclusion, which wouldn't be a bad thing, everything considered.</p>
<p>As reported by <a href="https://comicbook.com/gaming/news/half-life-3-rumor-last-game-trilogy-valve/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ComicBook</a>, the third main entry in the series will also be the final one, according to <a href="https://www.patreon.com/posts/half-life-129859708?utm_medium=clipboard_copy&amp;utm_source=copyLink&amp;utm_campaign=postshare_fan&amp;utm_content=web_share" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DanielRPK</a>, as Valve wants to leave the series behind. Given the conclusion of the second entry in the series and the decades it will eventually take its successor to release, this is definitely not a bad thing.</p>
<p>While DanielRPK's track record is not spotless regarding video game leaks, there's a good chance that what they have revealed about Half-Life 3 is true, considering what other known Valve leakers have said in the past few weeks. Just a few days ago, GabeFollower revealed that the game's story hook may not be <a href="https://wccftech.com/half-life-3-main-story-hook/">widely appreciated</a>, and the series ending right after being properly brought back would definitely be something that fans would not enjoy, although, as already mentioned, getting an ending, no matter how controversial, would undoubtedly be better than having the series end with the cliffhanger seen in Half-Life 2: Episode Two.</p>
<p>Though Half-Life 3 has yet to be officially announced, the day the highly anticipated game will be revealed may not be too far off. According to rumors, the game is being widely playtested right now for a possible Summer reveal and Winter release, and is fully playable from beginning to end.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>