<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 19:30:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Embark Studios Brings the Cold Snap Back to ARC Raiders and Launches a PvE-Focused Event Tomorrow]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/arc-raiders-cold-snap-shared-watch-pve-event-embark-studios/</link>
            <guid>1430359</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Last week, <strong>Embark Studios</strong> announced <a href="https://wccftech.com/arc-raiders-players-can-prepare-for-the-second-expedition-with-a-new-catch-up-mechanic-and-lowered-stash-value-requirements/">a few changes coming to Expeditions</a> in <strong>ARC Raiders</strong> to help players be better prepared to send off their Raiders into the unknown. Now, as we near the end of the first Expedition, the team has confirmed the next event that'll start tomorrow and bring players to the end of the month.</p>



<p>Firstly, Embark is bringing back the <strong>Cold Snap</strong> map condition as part of the regular rotation of map conditions players can experience starting tomorrow, <strong>February 10, 2026</strong>. It was a fun map condition for the winter season, and added an interesting layer of survival gameplay to your runs Topside, because you had to make sure you didn't get caught out in the cold for too long. It's good to see it make a return, and hopefully, Embark makes a habit of keeping beloved map conditions around, even if they're introduced as part of a seasonal event. </p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Clear skies and sunny temperatures are predicted for Topside this weekend, but don't pack your winter gear away yet folks; the weather towers are predicting sporadic snowfall in the foreseeable future!<br>The Cold Snap returns to our regular rotation of conditions from February 10… <a href="https://t.co/J4OACyBc9y">pic.twitter.com/J4OACyBc9y</a></p>— ARC Raiders (@ARCRaidersGame) <a href="https://twitter.com/ARCRaidersGame/status/2020180761849331776?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 7, 2026</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>Second, and perhaps most exciting for ARC Raiders players cut from a certain cloth, is that the studio will kick off a new, <strong>PvE-focused</strong> event called <strong>Shared Watch</strong> tomorrow, February 10, that'll run until <strong>February 24, 2026.</strong></p>



<p>More information about the event is set to arrive in tomorrow's patch notes, but the basics of it are that players will progress through the event's rewards by earning <strong>Merits</strong>, which will unlock items, Raider tokens, and a new baseball-themed <strong>Slugger</strong> cosmetic set.</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>You watch my back, I'll watch yours - that’s how Speranza keeps ticking 🫶<br>Join your fellow Raiders in celebrating the Shared Watch; team up with strangers, turn your barrels on the machines, and earn rewards in the process.</p><p>The Shared Watch Event begins tomorrow! <a href="https://t.co/ssYtkLxZ4r">pic.twitter.com/ssYtkLxZ4r</a></p></div>— ARC Raiders (@ARCRaidersGame) <a href="https://twitter.com/ARCRaidersGame/status/2020905547927552273?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 9, 2026</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>ARC Raiders might technically be a PvPvE game, but depending on who you ask, some players would describe it as an entirely PvE game. Scores of players within the community are seemingly uninterested in participating in the PvP components and would rather work together with their fellow Raiders to take down ARCs and gather loot.</p>



<p>It's unclear if this event will include a PvE-only mode, but it's definitely PvE-focused, as it encourages players to work together to take down ARCs, which is one of the best thrills that ARC Raiders offers outside of the tension of safely extracting to Speranza by the skin of your teeth.</p>



<p>For more on ARC Raiders, <a href="https://wccftech.com/how-to/arc-raiders-complete-guides-and-walkthrough-hub/">check out our complete walkthrough and guides hub</a> for help on your own raiding journey. For all of our coverage of the hottest new extraction shooter on the market, <a href="https://wccftech.com/roundup/arc-raiders-everything-we-know-about-the-latest-hot-extraction-shooter/">check out our dedicated hub with news, guides, interviews, and review coverage</a> of ARC Raiders.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/arc-raiders-cold-snap-shared-watch-pve-event-embark-studios/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EXODUS’ Side Content Will Always Feel Tied to the Companions and the Game’s Themes, Promises Ex BioWare Writer]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/exodus-side-content-tied-to-companions-and-game/</link>
            <guid>1430299</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Now that <a href="https://wccftech.com/exodus-mass-effect-like-action-adventure-rpg-gets-new-trailer-early-2027-launch-window/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">we're roughly one year away from the planned launch of <strong>EXODUS</strong></a>, the Mass Effect-inspired sci-fi action RPG in development at <strong>Archetype Entertainment</strong>, the developers are starting to share more about the game. <span><a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/rpg/more-than-mass-effects-spiritual-successor-exodus-wants-to-pull-decades-of-player-choice-into-a-single-story-and-the-devs-think-theyve-cracked-it/" target="_blank">Speaking with Gamesradar</a>, Narrative Director Drew Karpyshyn (who wrote the first three Mass Effect games while at BioWare) stressed that side content in EXODUS will always feel tied to the companions and the game's overarching themes, rather than being tacked on as in some roleplaying games.</span></p>



<p><em>We don't want things to feel tacked-on. We definitely don't want you to feel like you're doing it because you're obligated, or you just need the experience points. We want side quests to be something you would do even if you weren't getting a reward. You're going to get rewards of course, but we want you to feel like 'this is something I'm interested in, this is something I want to explore'. Side content should always feel "tied to the themes of our game, tied to the companions you have, tied into the interesting aspects of our game that maybe don't get explored as much on the critical path.</em></p>



<p>In the Gamesradar interview, Karpyshyn also noted that EXODUS <strong>focuses on only a small portion of the overall lore</strong> the team has had to build for the science fiction franchise (which already has a published book, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Exodus-Archimedes-Peter-F-Hamilton-ebook/dp/B0CSYWZNRS?ref_=nav_ya_signin" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Archimedes Engine</a>, an upcoming book, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0FTTDG2CC?ref_=dbs_m_mng_rwt_calw_tkin_1&amp;storeType=ebooks" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Helium Sea</a>, and a Traveler's Handbook tabletop RPG).</p>



<p><em>You take a couple of core themes that you want to explore, and then you have to gauge reaction of the rest of the team and people as they experience the IP. We can't add everything into one game. The game would be thousands of hours, which sounds great in theory, but isn't realistic.</em></p>



<p>This bodes well for potential future installments, although Archetype Entertainment will have to ensure the first entry lands well before Wizards of the Coast provides the green light to make new titles. </p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/exodus-side-content-tied-to-companions-and-game/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nexon’s StarCraft Game Might Not be an RTS, But The Rumoured Upcoming StarCraft Shooter]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nexon-starcraft-shooter-blizzard-entertainment/</link>
            <guid>1430296</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			<div data-nosnippet="">
		
		<ul>
			<li>0-20%: Unlikely - Lacks credible sources</li>
			<li>21-40%: Questionable - Some concerns remain</li>
			<li>41-60%: Plausible - Reasonable evidence</li>
			<li>61-80%: Probable - Strong evidence</li>
			<li>81-100%: Highly Likely - Multiple reliable sources</li>
		</ul>
	</div>


			
			
			
			<p>Last month, <strong>Blizzard Entertainment</strong> announced that it would <a href="https://wccftech.com/blizzard-announces-showcases-for-world-of-warcraft-diablo-hearthstone-and-overwatch-all-within-the-next-two-weeks/">host four showcase events for its biggest ongoing franchises</a>, to update players on what's next for each series. We've already seen the showcases for <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/world-of-warcraft-midnight-roadmap-housing-blizzcon-2026/">World of Warcraft</a></strong> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/were-dropping-the-2-overwatch-2-is-now-just-called-overwatch-moving-forward/"><strong>Overwatch</strong>,</a> with today's <strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kohfwPjrSkg">Hearthstone</a></strong> presentation coming next, followed by a <strong>Diablo</strong> showcase later this week. But you might have noticed that one major franchise is missing from that list: <strong>StarCraft</strong>.</p>



<p>In fairness, it's not surprising that StarCraft was left out of getting a showcase to start the year, only because it's been years since we've seen a new entry in the StarCraft series. When we heard that <a href="https://wccftech.com/nexon-not-blizzard-will-reportedly-be-making-the-next-starcraft-game/"><strong>Nexon</strong> would be taking charge of making the next game in the series in April 2025</a>, the direction in which Nexon would take the franchise was unclear, with the assumption being that the studio would be making another <strong>real-time strategy (RTS) </strong>game. Not just because StarCraft has traditionally been an RTS series, but also because of how popular the genre is in Nexon's home base of Korea.</p>



<p>Then, last month, a report from Windows Central pointed to a <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/third-person-starcraft-shooter-will-reportedly-be-unveiled-at-blizzcon-2026/">StarCraft-based third-person shooter</a></strong> as the headlining title at <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/blizzcon-2026-tickets-on-sale-in-two-days-pricing-events-confirmed/">BlizzCon 2026</a></strong>, though there was no suggestion of who is behind it aside from the presumption that it would be Blizzard.</p>



<p>Now, however, a new report from <a href="https://m.dnews.co.kr/m_home/view.jsp?idxno=202601301526154230994">The Korea Economic Daily</a> (<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1r0592a/new_details_from_nexons_starcraft_game/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=mweb3x&amp;utm_name=mweb3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">spotted on Reddit</a>) seems to point to Nexon's upcoming StarCraft project, and the rumoured third-person shooter being one in the same. The project is reportedly being made within Nexon's "<em>shooter headquarters</em>," implying that it won't be an RTS title.</p>



<p>It's worth taking all of this with a grain of salt, especially considering the fact that we have no confirmation from Blizzard that a StarCraft game is on its way. What we do have is a tease from Blizzard about this year's BlizzCon being <a href="https://wccftech.com/world-of-warcraft-midnight-roadmap-housing-blizzcon-2026/">"<em>one for the ages</em>,"</a> the aforementioned Windows Central report, and a <a href="https://wccftech.com/blizzard-allegedly-incubating-a-starcraft-shooter/">2024 report from Jason Schreier that Blizzard is also working on a StarCraft shooter</a>.</p>



<p>If the previous report about Blizzard incubating its own StarCraft shooter is correct, and it's being made alongside the shooter that Nexon is said to be working on, then the next two games in the StarCraft universe could both be shooters, with the next RTS entry in the series still in limbo.</p>



<p>Hopefully, BlizzCon 2026 will have all the answers if we don't hear from Blizzard sooner. The convention is set to take place on <strong>September 12-13, 2026,</strong> so StarCraft fans might still have a few more months of waiting to see what's next for the franchise. </p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/nexon-starcraft-shooter-blizzard-entertainment/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>