<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 19:18:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Get Resident Evil Requiem for Free with a 12-Month GeForce NOW Ultimate Subscription]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/get-resident-evil-requiem-free-12-month-geforce-now-ultimate/</link>
            <guid>1447384</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/how-to/resident-evil-requiem-pc-performance-analysis-tuning-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Don't have the PC</a> to play <strong>CAPCOM</strong>'s new <strong>Resident Evil Requiem</strong> game, but you'd really love to experience it anyway? If you have a solid Internet connection (and live in a supported region of the world), <strong>NVIDIA</strong> can give you the chance through its <strong>GeForce NOW</strong> cloud platform, and they're also bundling the game with new 12-month Ultimate memberships. For the record, a year-long GeForce NOW Ultimate subscription sets you back <strong>$199.99</strong>, but the game itself is <strong>$70</strong>, which you'd be saving if you were planning on buying it anyway.</p>



<p>With GeForce NOW Ultimate, you'd have access to <strong>nearly all of the game's features available to GeForce RTX 50 Series GPU owners</strong>: NVIDIA DLSS 4 with Multi Frame Generation, Ray Reconstruction, and path tracing. The only thing not supported right now on the cloud is the new <strong>DLSS 4.5 second-generation transformer model</strong>, which debuted on local GPUs earlier this year.</p>



<p>Here's the full list of features that the GFN Ultimate membership offers over the Free and Performance tiers:</p>



<ul>
<li>8-hour gaming sessions</li>



<li>Up to 5K resolution</li>



<li>Up to 240 FPS (360 FPS on RTX 5080 servers)</li>



<li>First priority access to the queue</li>



<li>16 vCPU cores 56 GB DRAM</li>



<li>Surround 7.1 audio</li>



<li>DLSS Frame Generation</li>



<li>NVIDIA Reflex</li>



<li>Cloud G-Sync</li>



<li>GeForce RTX 5080-class performance </li>



<li>DLSS Frame Generation (Multi-Frame Generation on RTX 5080 servers)</li>
</ul>



<p>Here's a tease <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/resident-evil-requiem-encyclopedia-evil/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">from our Resident Evil Requiem review</a>, penned by Nathan Birch:</p>



<p><em>Resident Evil Requiem is the Every-Evil, as Capcom has taken all the things they've done with the franchise over the past decade or so and stitched them together into a towering monster of a survival horror game. Parts of this game are the best, scariest, and most intense this series has ever been, other parts are merely alright, but no part of the game is bad and it's all very distinctly Resident Evil. While it won't be everyone's new favorite, Resident Evil Requiem should hit enough right notes for most fans.</em></p>



<p>Besides CAPCOM's latest entry in the renowned survival horror series, <strong>here's the full list of new GeForce NOW games joining the library this week</strong>:</p>



<ul>
<li>TCG Card Shop Simulator (New release on Xbox, available on Game Pass Feb. 24)</li>



<li>Blizzard Arcade Collection (New release on Ubisoft Connect, Feb. 25)</li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/diablo-ii-resurrected-review/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Diablo II: Resurrected</a> (New release on Ubisoft Connect, Feb 25)</li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/spellcasters-chronicles-interview-game-director-quantic-dream/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Spellcasters Chronicles</a> (New release on Steam, Feb. 26, GeForce RTX 5080-ready)</li>



<li>Anno: Mutationem (Xbox, available on Game Pass)</li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/roundup/arc-raiders-everything-we-know-about-the-latest-hot-extraction-shooter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Arc Raiders</a> (Xbox, available on the Microsoft Store, GeForce RTX 5080-ready)</li>



<li>DEVOUR (Steam)</li>



<li>Galactic Civilizations 3 (Xbox, available on the Microsoft Store)</li>



<li>MotoGP22 (Xbox, available on the Microsoft Store)</li>



<li>Torque Drift 2 (Steam)</li>
</ul>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/get-resident-evil-requiem-free-12-month-geforce-now-ultimate/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>