<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:34:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Best Boon To Complete Runs Successfully in Hades II – Best Boon Guide]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/how-to/the-best-boon-to-complete-runs-successfully-in-hades-ii-best-boon-guide/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-best-boon-to-complete-runs-successfully-in-hades-ii-%E2%80%93-best-boon-guide.1358188/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Hades II presents a tougher challenge than its predecessor. With an increased focus on ranged combat and high enemy density, surviving the trek to Tartarus and the summit requires more than just high damage; it demands superior survivability.</p>



<p>While many players focus on maximizing DPS, one specific Boon is often overlooked, yet provides immense utility for nearly every single build: <strong>Aphrodite's Glamour Gain.</strong></p>



<blockquote>
<p><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed"><em data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)">NOTE: Guide based on the experience accumulated in 67 runs spread over 45 hours in the 1.0 Steam release. Screenshots captured from the Post-Launch Patch 1 version.</em></strong></p>
</blockquote>



<div><h2>Table of contents</h2><ul><li><a href="#h-glamour-gain-is-the-best-defensive-boon-in-hades-ii" data-level="2">Glamour Gain is the Best Defensive Boon in Hades II</a><ul><li><a href="#h-comparison-with-other-weak-inducing-boons" data-level="3">Comparison With Other Weak-inducing Boons</a></li></ul></li><li><a href="#h-maxing-out-glamour-gain-s-potential" data-level="2">Maxing Out Glamour Gain’s Potential</a></li><li><a href="#h-how-to-get-glamour-gain-as-often-as-possible" data-level="2">How to Get Glamour Gain As Often As Possible</a></li><li><a href="#h-glamour-gain-best-weapon-synergies" data-level="2">Glamour Gain Best Weapon Synergies</a></li><li><a href="#h-how-effective-glamour-gain-really-is" data-level="2">How Effective Glamour Gain Really Is?</a></li></ul></div>



<h2 id="h-glamour-gain-is-the-best-defensive-boon-in-hades-ii">Glamour Gain is the Best Defensive Boon in Hades II</h2>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/20251109193532_1-scaled.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Don't sleep on Aphrodite's Glamour Gain Boon</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Aphrodite's <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Glamour Gain</strong> is arguably the most valuable defensive tool in Melinoë's arsenal, hands-down. It's often overlooked by players obsessed with big numbers, but its core utility - superior, passive survivability - is critical for clearing the more challenging later regions.</p>



<p>The reasons for its power are simple:</p>



<ol>
<li><strong data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-processed">Passive Weak Curse Inflictio</strong><strong>n</strong><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-processed">:</strong> Glamour Gain automatically inflicts the <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Weak</strong> curse on nearby enemies. You don't need to attack, Dash, or Cast; merely being near a foe triggers the effect.</li>



<li><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">Damage Reduction:</strong> The Weak curse causes afflicted enemies to deal <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">at least 30% less damage</strong>, and this stacks with other damage-reducing effects (like the <strong data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)">Strength Arcana, which also increases your attack power at the cost of Death Defianc</strong><strong>e</strong>).</li>



<li><strong>Magic Restoration:</strong> It gradually restores your <strong>Magic</strong> (starting at 6 points per second) while near enemies, giving you passive regeneration to fuel your Casts and Omega attacks.</li>
</ol>



<p>In Hades II, Melinoë is frequently swarmed by multiple enemies from all sides, especially in difficult areas like Tartarus and Mount Olympus. Since more than one enemy will be near you almost constantly, the effects of Glamour Gain ensure that nearly every hit you take is <strong>reduced considerably.</strong></p>



<h3 id="h-comparison-with-other-weak-inducing-boons">Comparison With Other Weak-inducing Boons</h3>



<p>Other Aphrodite Boons can inflict Weak (<strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">Rapture Ring</strong> with Casts or <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Passion Rush</strong> with Rushing), but they require active input. <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Glamour Gain</strong> provides its life-saving utility automatically and consistently within Melinoë's effective fighting range, making it far more reliable and ultimately more useful.</p>



<h2 id="h-maxing-out-glamour-gain-s-potential">Maxing Out Glamour Gain’s Potential</h2>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/20251110005409_1-scaled.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>The Broken Resolve Boon makes Glamour Gain even more useful</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Once you secure Glamour Gain, try to get these two essential Aphrodite Boons to maximize its effectiveness. With these additions, you not only reduce incoming damage but also significantly boost your damage against Weak-inflicted foes:</p>



<ol>
<li><strong>Sweet Surrender:</strong> Weak-afflicted enemies take <strong>+10% more damage</strong> (minimum, scales with rarity). This turns your defensive boon into a potent offensive multiplier.</li>



<li><strong>Broken Resolve:</strong> Weak effects are <strong>more potent</strong>, increasing the base damage reduction beyond 30%. This is pure survivability insurance.</li>
</ol>



<h2 id="h-how-to-get-glamour-gain-as-often-as-possible">How to Get Glamour Gain As Often As Possible</h2>



<figure><figcaption><em>Equipping the Beautiful Mirror Keepsake increases your chances of obtaining the Glamour Gain Boon during Nights</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Due to roguelike mechanics of Hades II, there is no guaranteed way to be offered Glamour Gain on every run, but you can use the Keepsake system to dramatically increase your chances:</p>



<ol>
<li><strong>Unlock the Keepsake:</strong> Obtain the <strong>Beautiful Mirror</strong> Keepsake from Aphrodite by giving her Ambrosia to increase Melinoë's affinity with the Goddess.</li>



<li><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">Equip Strategically:</strong> While equipping the keepsake at the start of a run guarantees an Aphrodite Boon, I found in my own 67 runs that equipping the Beautiful Mirror for the <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">second region</strong> in both the Underworld and Surface paths yields the best chance of Glamour Gain being offered.</li>
</ol>



<blockquote>
<p><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed"><em data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)">If Glamour Gain is not among the choices offered, make sure to save the Boon Rarification chance granted by the Beautiful Mirror </em></strong><strong><em>K</em></strong><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed"><em data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)">eepsake until it does show up. Maximizing this Boon's rarity early is highly valuable.</em></strong></p>
</blockquote>



<h2 id="h-glamour-gain-best-weapon-synergies">Glamour Gain Best Weapon Synergies</h2>



<figure><figcaption><em>Every weapon in Hades II benefits in some capacity from the effects of Glamour Gain</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Glamour Gain synergizes really well with every weapon in Hades II, as the passive <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">Weak</strong> <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">Curse application</strong> and <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Magic regeneration</strong> are great to have regarldess of the weapon's capabilities.</p>



<ul>
<li>The <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">Sister Blades,</strong> <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Moonstone Axe, </strong>and <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">The Black Coat</strong> benefit the most due to he short range of their Attacks. Glamour Gain massively offsets this shortcoming, turning both weapons into really solid choices, especially if you have means to restore HP consistently</li>
</ul>







<ul>
<li><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">The Witch's Staff</strong> and <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Umbral Flames</strong> have slightly better Attack range than the tree weapons above, but they still benefit from Glamour Gain a lot thanks to the constant Magic regeneration, which helps both weapons dish out the best damage they can.</li>
</ul>







<ul>
<li>The <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">Argent Skull</strong> also benefits a lot from Glamour Gain, no matter the playstyle. Whether you launch your skulls into the enemy or charge into them using the Special, the damage reduction of Weak afflicted enemies considerably reduces the risk associated with this weapon.</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-how-effective-glamour-gain-really-is">How Effective Glamour Gain Really Is?</h2>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/20251118013225_1-scaled.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>All of these successful Nights were completed with the help of the Glamour Gain Boon</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Although powerful damage Boons are vital, the consistent safety provided by Glamour Gain enables aggressive play and reduces the need for expensive healing or unnecessary deaths. Focusing on this Boon first allowed my success rate to skyrocket, making many of the enemy encounters way more manageable</p>



<blockquote>
<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Don't Sleep on Aphrodite's Glamour Gain in Hades II" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WY2Pwb0qJr8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p><em data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(232, 230, 227, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(232, 230, 227, 0.2)">This run through Olympus and The Summit isn't my best, but Glamour Gain made it so that I could still defeat Typhon and win the night, despite getting close to defeat a few times.</em></p>
</blockquote>



<p>With Glamour Gain providing a reliable safety net, you can start focusing on how to maximize your damage with other Boons. In case you are still struggling to find a weapon suited to your playstyle, you can learn more about them in our <a href="https://wccftech.com/how-to/hades-2-weapons-tier-list-guide/">Hades II Weapons Tier List.</a></p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/how-to/the-best-boon-to-complete-runs-successfully-in-hades-ii-best-boon-guide/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Mount and Blade II: Bannerlord – War Sails Trailer Shows Off the Kinds of Intense Naval Battles Arriving Next Week]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/new-mount-and-blade-ii-bannerlord-war-sails-gameplay-trailer/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-mount-and-blade-ii-bannerlord-%E2%80%93-war-sails-trailer-shows-off-the-kinds-of-intense-naval-battles-arriving-next-week.1358137/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Mount and Blade II: Bannerlord developer TaleWorlds Entertainment is set to release the biggest expansion yet for its strategy action game. War Sails, which adds naval combat to the ever-expanding war sandbox within Mount and Blade II: Bannerlord. The new expansion <a href="https://wccftech.com/war-sails-naval-expansion-mount-blade-ii-bannerlord-out-november-26/">will launch a week from the time of this writing, on November 26, 2025</a>, and ahead of that launch, TaleWorlds Entertainment has debuted a new gameplay trailer showing off the kinds of intense naval battles players will take part in.</p>



<p>The new eight-and-a-half-minute gameplay showcase shows a battle between the latest faction entering the game, the Nords, and the Khuzaits in a nighttime river battle.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Mount &amp; Blade II: Bannerlord – War Sails | Khuzaits vs Nords Naval Battle Showcase" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/74HAcUOg4R4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>The battle is an impressive display of what's to come for Mount and Blade II fans, with a whole new combat element arriving in the game for the first time. When War Sails arrives next week, it'll be available on all platforms simultaneously and can be purchased for $24.99.</p>



<p>For players not purchasing the expansion, there will be a free update going live that same day, adding a slew of updates and fixes to the game for all players, including overhauled mission atmospheres, overhauled spear bracing, improvements to melee, ranged, and cavalry combat, expanded modding capabilities, and more.</p>



<p>If you are purchasing the expansion, then you'll be able to build your naval fleet with 20 unique ships, including 15 warships, four trading ships and one civilian fishing vessel across an expanded Calradia. All of the ships are modelled after historic examples of medieval ships, and players will be able to undertake a naval campaign as part of the new expansion, where you'll be battling the elements as much as you are battling enemy fleets.</p>



<p>Mount and Blade II: Bannerlord is already a cinematic action strategy experience with its epic ground battles, so this step into naval warfare is the next natural evolution of its sandbox gameplay. We'll see how it lands with players when War Sails arrives next week.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/new-mount-and-blade-ii-bannerlord-war-sails-gameplay-trailer/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Take-Two CEO Says Game Characters Should Be Able to Be AI-Trained on Human-Made Scripts to Have More Natural Conversations]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/take-two-ceo-says-game-characters-should-be-ai-trained-human-scripts-more-natural-conversations/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/take-two-ceo-says-game-characters-should-be-able-to-be-ai-trained-on-human-made-scripts-to-have-more-natural-conversations.1358080/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>In a recent appearance <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/video/2025/11/17/gaming-is-americas-pastime-and-the-entertainment-business-of-the-future-says-take-two-ceo-zelnick.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">on CNBC's morning business news program Squawk Box</a>, Take-Two CEO Strauss Zelnick said that in the future, game characters will likely be AI-trained on human-made scripts to have more natural conversations with players, instead of being limited to the scripted interactions that the developers had foreseen when they envisioned the game. </p>



<p><em>Historically, we had to script every single action that a character engaged in, and because it is interactive, think about how much scripting that is. Now, we're always going to need great writers, and we always will have plenty of scripting, but characters should be able to be trained on that very scripting that has been created by great writers and then interact in a way that feels more natural. I do see that happening.</em></p>



<p>Could that be one of the major new features that Rockstar Games has prepared for Grand Theft Auto VI, now officially one year away from its launch (provided there are no further delays)? Just two days ago, a new rumor <a href="https://wccftech.com/gta-6-is-likely-to-be-unmatched-for-almost-two-decades/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">surfaced</a> about the game featuring extremely ambitious features that may remain unmatched for 'decades'.</p>



<p>Regardless of whether a similar feature makes it in GTA VI or not, the technology is absolutely here now. <a href="https://wccftech.com/nvidia-ace-to-power-dynamic-ai-characters-companions-and-bosses-in-pubg-naraka-bladepoint-inzoi-and-mir5/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">NVIDIA ACE</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/inworld-and-nvidia-demonstrate-on-device-ai-character-behavior/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Inworld AI</a> already offer something like that, where game characters can respond to natural conversations depending on what they should be aware of. </p>



<p>Zelnick's comment, however, comes at a time when there's a lot of tension on the usage of AI in the industry. Black Ops 7 was <a href="https://wccftech.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-out-now-immediately-called-out-for-ai-slop/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">criticized for its 'AI slop' assets</a>, while ARC Raiders <a href="https://wccftech.com/amidst-arc-raiders-success-embarks-use-of-gen-ai-voices-bubbles-over-even-epics-ceo-joins-the-fray/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">came under fire for using generative AI to voice NPCs</a>. On that subject, the developers behind the highly successful episodic adventure game Dispatch <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/dispatch-is-on-course-to-beat-its-three-year-sales-target-in-three-months-heres-how" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">told GamesIndustry</a>:</p>



<p><em>You're not going to be surprised because it's built on something you've heard before if you go the AI route. So, yeah, honestly, AI feels like a production solution, not a creative one. Maybe it's a creative one if you aren't creative.</em></p>



<p>Of course, when discussing AI, there's much more beyond just empowering game characters or voicing them. As part of his reply on CNBC, Take-Two CEO Strauss Zelnick also highlighted that the company is using the technology to create 'efficiencies', which, however, won't reduce the headcount but will instead let them focus on creative tasks.</p>



<p><em>Table stakes are creating more efficiency in development and marketing, and every enterprise is trying to do that. We're trying to do that and we're seeing some good early results in creating efficiencies. By the way, efficiencies is not code for reducing employment, it's code for taking away mundane tasks so people can focus on more interesting, creative tasks. </em></p>



<p>That is, after all, the sentiment behind many other AI statements we covered recently, from <a href="https://wccftech.com/hideo-kojima-sees-creating-together-with-ai-way-stay-one-step-ahead/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hideo Kojima</a> to <a href="https://wccftech.com/theres-no-point-using-ai-for-any-creative-endeavor-says-game-developer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ricard Pillosu</a>. Perhaps, though, it was Dean Hall who, <a href="https://wccftech.com/dayz-creator-says-ai-fears-remind-him-people-worrying-about-google-wikipedia-ai-is-here/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">speaking to Wccftech</a>, really got to the heart of the issue:</p>



<p><em>I think that regardless of what we do, AI is here. So really, then, it's about a matter of how do we deal with what the impact of that is.</em></p>





			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/take-two-ceo-says-game-characters-should-be-ai-trained-human-scripts-more-natural-conversations/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>