<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 19:37:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Disneyland Game Rush Brings The Disney Parks To Fortnite For A Limited Time Starting Tomorrow]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/disneyland-game-rush-brings-disney-parks-to-fortnite-starting-tomorrow/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/disneyland-game-rush-brings-the-disney-parks-to-fortnite-for-a-limited-time-starting-tomorrow.1344817/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Starting tomorrow, Fortnite players will be able to jump into a new creative island made by Epic Games called Disneyland Game Rush. It's a limited-time creative island that includes seven mini games, each inspired by different famous Disneyland and Disney World attractions and rides as part of the 70th anniversary of Disneyland.</p>



<p>It's not the massive persistent universe that Fortnite and Disney <a href="https://wccftech.com/disney-invests-1-5-billion-in-epic-to-create-a-persistent-universe-in-fortnite-based-on-its-franchises/">have been planning and working on for more than a year now</a>, but it's perhaps a small glimpse as to what that might look like, and from a technical standpoint, a big step forward towards creating the look of the Disney theme parks within Fortnite.</p>



<p>The seven mini-games include games based on newer attractions, like the Guardians of the Galaxy - Mission: Sneak Out! game, based on the Guardians of the Galaxy - Mission: Breakout ride, has you sneaking around and completing the mission without being caught. A Star Wars: Stormtrooper Showdown mini-game has you putting down as many Stormtroopers as possible.</p>



<p>However, for the big Disney parks fans, the more meaningful mini-games are likely the ones based on Disney parks classics, like the Space Mountain: Rocket Race mini-game, the Metterhorn: Slip-and-Climb mini-game, and the Haunted Mansion: Scavenger Haunt mini-game.</p>



<p>A report from<a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fortnites-disneyland-game-rush-is-an-incredibly-authentic-first-step-into-fortnite-for-disney-parks?utm_source=threads,twitter"> IGN includes some screenshots</a> of the game modes and what players can expect when they jump into the island once it is available to the public tomorrow, November 6, 2025.</p>


<figure>
<div>

<figure>
<figure><figcaption><em>Fortnite Disneyland Game Rush. Image credit: Disney, via IGN</em></figcaption></figure>



<figure><figcaption><em>Fortnite Disneyland Game Rush. Image credit: Disney, via IGN</em></figcaption></figure>



<figure><figcaption><em>Fortnite Disneyland Game Rush. Image credit: Disney, via IGN</em></figcaption></figure>



<figure><figcaption><em>Fortnite Disneyland Game Rush. Image credit: Disney, via IGN</em></figcaption></figure>



<figure><figcaption><em>Fortnite Disneyland Game Rush. Image credit: Disney, via IGN</em></figcaption></figure>



<figure><figcaption><em>Fortnite Disneyland Game Rush. Image credit: Disney, via IGN</em></figcaption></figure>



<figure><figcaption><em>Fortnite Disneyland Game Rush. Image credit: Disney, via IGN</em></figcaption></figure>



<figure><figcaption><em>Fortnite Disneyland Game Rush. Image credit: Disney, via IGN</em></figcaption></figure>
</figure>
<div>
				    		
				    		
					    	<p><span>2 of 9</span>
				    	</p></div>
</div>
</figure>



<p>When the island is publicly available tomorrow, you can find it by searching for it with this code: 4617-4819-8826.</p>





			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/disneyland-game-rush-brings-disney-parks-to-fortnite-starting-tomorrow/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur’s Gate 3 Path to Menzoberranzan Mod to Get First Playable Alpha By June 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/baldurs-gate-3-path-to-menzoberranzan-mod-alpha-by-june-2026/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldur%E2%80%99s-gate-3-path-to-menzoberranzan-mod-to-get-first-playable-alpha-by-june-2026.1344751/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>While the <a href="https://wccftech.com/baldurs-gate-3-update-7-is-out-next-week-adding-mods-and-new-cinematics/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Baldur's Gate 3 modding scene</a> might not be quite as thriving as that of a Bethesda game like Skyrim, there are still a couple of major projects to follow, such as the Path to Menzoberranzan mod. Modder Lotrich, <a href="https://www.patreon.com/PathToMenzoberranzan" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">with the help of over 1,300 Patreon supporters</a>, has established a team of more than 130 contributors.</p>



<p>According to a project update shared this week on the Path to Menzoberranzan Discord channel, the team operates under a centralized structure. There is a group of project directors for each branch of development, and each project director is assisted by leads (coordinators) and seniors, who help oversee project contributors across different departments.</p>



<p>While the full release of the Baldur's Gate 3 mod is still years away, the first playable Alpha is estimated to be available in the first half of 2026. The team said it will include the game's prologue, which should be similar in scope to the Nautiloid of BG3. Over time, more updates will be released to introduce new locations and advance the narrative. The extent of these updates will depend on feedback and the feasibility of implementation. Path to Menzoberranzan reportedly features many interconnected storylines, and the creators want users to experience a satisfying portion of the story with each new update.</p>



<p>As Forgotten Realms experts will have already surmised from the title, the mod adds an entirely new standalone adventure focused on the bright mercantile city of Athkatla and the dark and perilous nature of the Underdark, all the way to the legendary capital of the Drow.</p>



<p>Throughout the story, which spans three acts like Baldur's Gate 3, players will revisit areas from Baldur's Gate 2: Shadows of Amn while also exploring entirely new lands. The campaign is set to feature a new protagonist with a new personal quest and up to 8 brand-new companions, each with their own personal agendas and some of whom will be romanceable.</p>



<p>In Act I, players will visit Athkatla, shop at iconic places like the Adventurer Mart, and explore the long-abandoned dungeon once occupied by the malicious mage Jon Irenicus. In Act II, the player will begin their journey to the titular location, Menzoberranzan, and Act III will feature the drow city itself.</p>



<p>The Path to Menzoberranzan modding team also promised the following features:</p>



<ul>
<li>Fully voiced companions and world NPCs—no AI-generated voiceovers;</li>



<li>Custom concept art and 3D assets as needed;</li>



<li>Handcrafted visual style for Menzoberranzan, built from scratch;</li>



<li>Multiple side quests on top of the main overarching story;</li>



<li>New items, outfits, NPC models;</li>



<li>Original musical theme.</li>
</ul>



<p>Another large-scale Baldur's Gate 3 mod<span>, '<a href="https://wccftech.com/baldurs-gate-3-custom-campaign-the-grand-theater-sell-your-lute-to-the-devil-gets-first-playable-version/" target="_blank">The Grand Theater - Sell your Lute to the Devil</a>', is currently 25% complete,</span> according to its creators. If you're instead looking for a mod that lets you play against your friends, <a href="https://wccftech.com/baldurs-gate-3-mod-versus-mode-closest-thing-game-master-mode/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the Versus mode</a> is the one to get.</p>





			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/baldurs-gate-3-path-to-menzoberranzan-mod-alpha-by-june-2026/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>