<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:53:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield Studios and EA Tease that Naval Warfare is On the Horizon for Battlefield 6]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/battlefield-studios-ea-tease-naval-warfare-on-the-horizon-battlefield-6/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-studios-and-ea-tease-that-naval-warfare-is-on-the-horizon-for-battlefield-6.1318558/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>At the time of this writing, Battlefield 6 is days away from launching on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X/S worldwide. The <a href="https://x.com/Battlefield/status/1974127507260510622">global launch times are up</a>, and the <a href="https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-reportedly-has-1-7-million-pre-orders-predicted-to-sell-5-million-first-week/">estimated 1.7 million players bought in for October 10</a> will be boots on the ground by the end of the week. So naturally, it's time for Battlefield Studios and EA to talk about what's next for Battlefield 6 on October 11, and every day after that.</p>



<p>In the latest <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/battlefield/battlefield-6/news/community-update-play-your-way">Community Update blog post on the Battlefield website</a>, Battlefield Studios laid out a few data points regarding what it has noticed over the course of its Battlefield Labs testing, followed by updates and changes players who participated in that testing and in the Beta this summer will notice when the game launches this coming Friday.</p>



<p>Towards the end of the post, in the section titled, "<em>On the Horizon</em>," the Battlefield Studios team writes, "<em>There is much more to look forward to beyond our Seasons as our team continues reviewing Battlefield Labs data, player feedback, and ideating on completely new ideas for the future, starting with an exciting new Battlefield take on Battle Royale.</em>"</p>



<p>"<em>Separately, requests for naval warfare have not gone unnoticed, nor have the calls for a certain fan-favourite little helicopter, platoons, and more</em>.<em> We appreciate all of your suggestions, and want you to know we're listening.</em>"</p>



<p>The <a href="https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-season-1-starts-october-28-roadmap-unveiled/">recently revealed Season 1 roadmap </a>doesn't include the introduction of naval warfare, nor does it include the return of Little Bird, the helicopter that is most likely referenced by the phrase "<em>little helicopter</em>." But that doesn't mean those inclusions won't be ready for Season 2, or Season 3, and so on. At least Battlefield Studios has made the point that it is part of the conversation for Battlefield 6's future.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/battlefield-studios-ea-tease-naval-warfare-on-the-horizon-battlefield-6/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>