<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 14:15:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NVIDIA DLSS 4 Multi Frame Generation Is Available in Project Motor Racing and Prologue: Go Wayback!]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nvidia-dlss-4-multi-frame-generation-in-project-motor-racing-prologue-go-wayback/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nvidia-dlss-4-multi-frame-generation-is-available-in-project-motor-racing-and-prologue-go-wayback.1364056/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>The latest PC games to support NVIDIA DLSS 4 Multi Frame Generation are Prologue: Go Wayback!, which launched last Thursday <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2943740/Prologue_Go_Wayback/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">on Steam Early Access</a>, and Project Motor Racing, due to launch <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/299970/Project_Motor_Racing/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">on Steam</a> today.</p>



<p>The former is a single-player, open world, emergent, survival roguelike game created by PUBG creator Brendan Greene and his team at PLAYERUNKNOWN Productions. In Prologue: Go Wayback!, players can traverse a new wilderness space of around 64 square kilometers that is generated every time they play. They can chart a path across rugged terrain, overcome the elements and write their own exploration story as they attempt to reach the distant Weather Tower. The game has a year of content updates already planned, after which it will launch its 1.0 version. Players with a GeForce RTX 50 Series GPU can activate DLSS 4 Multi Frame Generation to get the highest possible frame rates. GeForce RTX 40 Series users can boost their FPS with DLSS Frame Generation, and all other users can enhance performance with DLSS Super Resolution, which leverages NVIDIA's latest transformer AI model. </p>



<p>Prologue: Go Wayback! is the second of a series of game projects planned by PLAYERUNKNOWN Productions, the ultimate goal being Artemis, a massive multiplayer sandbox game that is still many years out. You can read our exclusive interview with Brendan Greene <a href="https://wccftech.com/playerunknown-qa-fortnite-and-others-just-look-like-ip-bubbles-to-me-the-metaverse-has-to-be-different/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>.</p>



<p>As for <a href="https://wccftech.com/project-motor-racing-arrives-this-november-with-full-modding-support-on-day-one-new-trailer-showcases-career-mode/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Project Motor Racing</a>, it's the new racing simulation game developed by Straight4 Studios and published by GIANTS Software. The game offers racing fans 28 tracks spanning multiple eras and over 70 faithfully replicated cars across 13 racing classes. Project Motor Racing includes a single-player career mode, a multiplayer mode where you can compete against others and navigate races packed with four classes, all of which are attempting to win their respective categories simultaneously. GeForce RTX 50 Series players can use DLSS 4 with Multi Frame Generation to get maximum performance. GeForce RTX 40 Series players can increase their frame rates with DLSS Frame Generation, while all other users can activate DLSS Super Resolution to enhance image quality using NVIDIA's most recent transformer AI model.</p>



<p>Earlier this month, the city builder game Whiskerwood <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2489330/Whiskerwood/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">was launched on Steam Early Access</a> by Minakata Dynamics and Hooded Horse. Its twist is that you do not manage humans, but mice who toil under cat overlords. A free demo is available, and both the demo and the full game support NVIDIA DLSS Super Resolution and DLAA.</p>



<p>Lastly, NVIDIA reminded its users that the highly anticipated action/adventure game Tides of Annihilation, which <a href="https://wccftech.com/tides-of-annihilation-stunning-boss-fight-gameplay-showing-off-mirror-realm/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">was showcased once again last week</a> during the Xbox Partner Preview event, will support NVIDIA DLSS 4 Multi Frame Generation on day one.</p>



<p>As a side note, NVIDIA users can claim a free Battlefield 6 Marksman SVK-8.6 DMR weapon skin from the NVIDIA app with GeForce Rewards by following these simple instructions: load the NVIDIA app, click “Redeem” on the left nav, and follow the steps to get the skin while supplies last.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/nvidia-dlss-4-multi-frame-generation-in-project-motor-racing-prologue-go-wayback/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>