<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 23:18:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rainbow Six Siege X Is Out Now, Brings Free Access to the Game]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/rainbow-six-siege-x-is-out-now-brings-free-access-to-the-game/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rainbow-six-siege-x-is-out-now-brings-free-access-to-the-game.1214952/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/rainbow-six-siege-x-is-out-now-brings-free-access-to-the-game/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Ubisoft has announced that <a href="https://wccftech.com/rainbow-6-siege-x-launches-in-june-bringing-the-biggest-evolution-in-the-games-history/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rainbow Six Siege X</a> is now available on all platforms (PC, PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Xbox One, Xbox Series S|X, and Amazon Luna). The sizable update improves graphics and adds new content, but also brings free access to the game, allowing newcomers to join with a selection of operators and play Unranked, Quick Match, and Dual Front modes without paying. Certain features like Ranked playlists, Siege Cup, additional operators, and cosmetics require payment to unlock.</p>
<p>Two of the available options are the Elite Edition, which grants access to all game modes, including Ranked playlists and Siege Cup, and 16 additional operators for $19.99, and the Ultimate Edition, which also unlocks all game modes, the Ranked playlists and the Siege Cup, but adds immediate access to 52 Operators and the Disruptor Pack for a price of $39.99.</p>
<p><iframe title="Rainbow Six Siege X: Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BI9fgQY0d5I?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>In Rainbow Six Siege X, players will experience the brand-new permanent 6v6 mode, Dual Front. For the first time, Dual Front mixes Attackers and Defenders to seize enemy sectors while defending their own. During matches, players can respawn, change their selected operator, and complete time-limited Neutral Sector assignments. Siege X also introduces significant upgrades and overhauls to the graphics, gameplay, and audio.</p>
<p>At launch, five modernized 5v5 maps received upgrades to lighting, shadows, and resolution: Clubhouse, Chalet, Border, Bank, and Kafe. Three new 5v5 maps will be modernized each season thereafter.</p>
<p>The gameplay of Rainbow Six Siege X is deeper thanks to new destructible items, including gas pipes, metal detectors, and fire extinguishers. Players can interact with these items strategically to outplay their opponents. Rappel navigation and momentum movement have also been improved, providing more fluid controls. Players can now sprint horizontally along walls on rappel and maneuver around building corners.</p>
<p>The audio propagation and reverberation have been overhauled, making the game sound more realistic than before. This enables players to gather critical intelligence through audio cues, allowing them to pinpoint the location and type of rooms where enemy players are on the map. Lastly, Ubisoft Montréal has added a new onboarding experience that will help new players build their skills and confidence.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hangar 13 Says Mafia: The Old Country Will Be “The Best Looking Mafia Game” Thanks To Unreal Engine 5]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/hangar-13-says-mafia-the-old-country-will-be-the-best-looking-mafia-game-thanks-to-unreal-engine-5/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hangar-13-says-mafia-the-old-country-will-be-%E2%80%9Cthe-best-looking-mafia-game%E2%80%9D-thanks-to-unreal-engine-5.1214895/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/hangar-13-says-mafia-the-old-country-will-be-the-best-looking-mafia-game-thanks-to-unreal-engine-5/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/mafia-the-old-country-launches-on-august-8th-for-only-50-new-gameplay-trailer-released/">Mafia: The Old Country</a> is due to arrive on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X/S on August 8, 2025, and in the lead up to its launch, developer Hangar 13 is doing everything it can to showcase how improved this prequel entry to the series is since we last checked in with the Mafia franchise.</p>
<p>The latest of those efforts is a new <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gwkvXUiG8do">developer diary video</a>, "<em>Art Meets Technology,</em>" which digs into how much better looking Mafia: The Old Country is compared to the rest of the series thanks to the new technologies available in Unreal Engine 5.</p>
<p>"<em>It allows us to tell that story in a way that we just wouldn't be able to, with other technologies,</em>" said art director Steve Noake. He continued, "<em>F</em><em>rom Metahuman, to Nanite, to Lumen. These are all different technologies which we are pushing to the max, to be honest. It's allowing us to grasp the intricacies of a performance, it's allowing us to automate some parts of the process, to be able to get to a point where we can really start to put our human thumbprints on some of these assets.</em>"</p>
<p><iframe title="Breaking Omertà: &quot;Art Meets Technology&quot; | Mafia: The Old Country" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gwkvXUiG8do?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Lead character artist Ivan Rylka added that there's a "<em>notable improvement</em>" in what's possible with Unreal Engine 5 versus what Hangar 13 was capable of doing prior to UE5, and confidently claimed "<em>I have no hesitation that this will be the best looking Mafia game in the franchise.</em>"</p>
<p>It's clear that Hangar 13 is putting in every effort to make Mafia: The Old Country look and feel as good as possible. It'll be interesting to see if it's more than just looks by the time it arrives this coming August.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>