<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 18:51:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xenomorph, A Spiritual Successor To Alien vs Predator On The Atari Jaguar Is In Development From Athena Worlds]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/xenomorph-a-spiritual-successor-to-alien-vs-predator-on-the-atari-jaguar-is-in-development-from-athena-worlds/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xenomorph-a-spiritual-successor-to-alien-vs-predator-on-the-atari-jaguar-is-in-development-from-athena-worlds.1171683/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/xenomorph-a-spiritual-successor-to-alien-vs-predator-on-the-atari-jaguar-is-in-development-from-athena-worlds/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>UK-based studio Athena Worlds has announced that it is working on a new stealth survival game called Xenomorph, a spiritual successor to the beloved Alien vs. Predator game launched for the Atari Jaguar in 1994.</p>
<p>We know little about the game so far, except that it is happening after Jane Whittaker, the former co-programmer on the Atari AvP game in 1994, announced the project on <a href="https://x.com/WhittakerGames/status/1914981311263002968">his personal X account</a>.</p>
<p>"<em><span>You have been asking me for a personal sequel to our</span> Atari AvP for 30 years...</em>" Whittaker wrote. "<em>Funding, team in place. Production underway!</em>" Whittaker also included a key art image for the game, showcasing the classic shot of a Xenomorph with both its mouths wide open, ready to strike.</p>
<p>Whittaker is also the chief executive officer of Athena Worlds and commented on what this project means to him in a <a href="https://www.techpowerup.com/335859/athena-worlds-announces-xenomorph-a-spiritual-sequel-to-alien-vs-predator">press release</a>, saying, "<em>It is a very personal journey for me</em><em>. So many people still talk about our work on AvP to this day, with a massive following. I have been asked for over 30 years to create my next survival and stealth strategy game. I am beyond thrilled to say that thanks to generous support, my day has come.</em>"</p>
<p>The game is in development for PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X/S consoles, though this announcement just states that the project is in the works. There's no news about when we might see it come to light.</p>
<p>Whittaker also confirmed that <span>Mike Meaden</span> will be the project's creative lead, and Blaire Wathen will lead character design.</p>
<p>Regarding the game's setting, the press release includes a short snippet of the world players will be stepping into. It reads, "<em>After crash landing on planet XL-243, you quickly find you are not alone and the battle for survival begins</em><em>.</em>"</p>
<p>The release also confirms that Xenomorph is "<em>aimed at being a landmark open world game of exploration, survival, high stakes tension and combat</em>."</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bethesda Provided Game Codes For The Oblivion Remaster To The Entire Skyblivion Team]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/bethesda-provided-game-codes-for-the-oblivion-remaster-to-the-entire-skyblivion-team/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bethesda-provided-game-codes-for-the-oblivion-remaster-to-the-entire-skyblivion-team.1171635/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/bethesda-provided-game-codes-for-the-oblivion-remaster-to-the-entire-skyblivion-team/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>We all knew that an official remaster for <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-looks-gorgeous-and-its-out-now/">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion</a> was coming from Bethesda and Virtuos. There were <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remake-will-be-officially-showcased-tomorrow-bethesda-announces/">more than enough leaks</a> to let us know ahead of time. But we also knew for a long time that a group of modders were already working on their own remake/remaster of Oblivion in Skyrim, called <a href="https://wccftech.com/skyblivion-lead-comments-on-nearly-official-oblivion-remaster/">Skyblivion</a>.</p>
<p>Bethesda has always supported modding groups like the Skyblivion team, mainly by not getting in their way and trying to halt the work the modders are doing with a cease and desist order. With the launch of the Oblivion Remaster, Bethesda went a bit further in their support, the Skyblivion team confirmed.</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://x.com/TESRSkyblivion/status/1914751791381495955">post on X</a>, the Skyblivion team thanked Bethesda for sending each member of the modding team a game code for the Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remaster.</p>
<p>"<em>Huge thanks to our friends at Bethesda Studios for their continued support of Skyblivion!</em>" the post read. "<em>As massive fans, we're beyond grateful for the generous gift of Oblivion Remastered game keys for our entire modding team! This means so much to us. Thank you for everything, Bethesda</em><em>.</em>"</p>
<p>Skyblivion is a total conversion mod that turns the Special Edition release of The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim into Oblivion. It's been in development for <a href="http://wccftech.com/skyrim-special-edition-oblivion-remaster-mod-skyblivion-gets-new-teaser-trailer/">years</a>, and nearly a decade later, the Skyblivion team is nearing the finish line, with a launch planned for <a href="https://wccftech.com/skyblivion-team-confirms-2025-launch-window-though-dlcs-will-come-later/">sometime in 2025</a>.</p>
<p>Wccftech has <a href="https://wccftech.com/skyblivion-lead-comments-on-nearly-official-oblivion-remaster/">followed</a> its development for practically the whole of that time, so we're just as excited for its release as we are of the fact that Bethesda and Virtuos have made their own remaster of Oblivion.</p>
<p>Both versions will also have big key differences, like the fact that Skyblivion will include more gameplay changes and cut content instead of just being the original Oblivion with a fresh coat of Unreal Engine 5 paint. There's room enough for both Skyblivion and the Oblivion Remaster. In the end, it's the fans who are winning.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>