<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 11:26:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Persona 4 Remake To Be Revealed During This Year’s Xbox Games Showcase – Rumor]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/persona-4-remake-revealed-xbox/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/persona-4-remake-to-be-revealed-during-this-year%E2%80%99s-xbox-games-showcase-%E2%80%93-rumor.1209114/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/persona-4-remake-revealed-xbox/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The rumored <a href="https://wccftech.com/persona-4-remake-persona-2-remaster-development/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Persona 4 Remake</a> is going to be revealed during this year's Xbox Games Showcase in two days, according to rumors circulating online.</p>
<p>As reported by <a href="https://mp1st.com/news/persona-4-remake-xbox-games-showcase" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MP1st</a>, a source familiar with the situation confirmed to the outlet that the remake of the fourth entry in the series by ATLUS will be revealed on June 8th during the annual Xbox Games Showcase. The source confirmed the game is coming to PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X|S, but couldn't confirm a Nintendo Switch 2 version, so there's the chance the game will launch later on Nintendo's new system. No other details have been confirmed, so it remains to be seen if the Persona 4 Remake will feature improvements in line with those seen in<a href="https://wccftech.com/review/persona-3-reload-review/"> Persona 3 Reload</a>, and if it will be based on the original, or the Golden enhanced version.</p>
<p>What we know almost for sure about the remake is that none of the original voice cast will be returning. In the past few weeks, <a href="https://wccftech.com/persona-4-remake-seemingly-confirmed-by-spider-man/">Yuri Lowenthal</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/persona-4-remake-wont-see-the-return-of-another-beloved-voice-actress/">Erin Fitzgerald</a>, and <a href="https://wccftech.com/a-third-persona-4-voice-actor-has-confirmed-they-wont-be-returning-for-the-persona-4-remake/">Amanda Winn Lee</a>, who voiced Yosuke, Chie, and Yukiko, won't return in the remake. Having contributed so much to the characters they played, it is disappointing not to see them return, but at the same time, it's not exactly surprising they won't, considering Persona 3 Reload features a brand new voice cast.</p>
<p>The Persona 4 Remake has yet to be officially announced. We will cover this Sunday's Xbox Games Showcase as it happens, so stay tuned for the official announcement.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ARK Gets PS5 Pro Patch with PSSR Support, UE5.5 Upgrade, and 10-Year Anniversary]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ark-gets-ps5-pro-patch-with-pssr-support-ue5-5-upgrade-and-10-year-anniversary/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ark-gets-ps5-pro-patch-with-pssr-support-ue5-5-upgrade-and-10-year-anniversary.1209111/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/ark-gets-ps5-pro-patch-with-pssr-support-ue5-5-upgrade-and-10-year-anniversary/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Studio Wildcard is celebrating the 10-year anniversary since the early access launch of ARK: Survival Evolved in its Unreal Engine 5 remaster, ARK: Survival Ascended, which was <a href="https://wccftech.com/ark-survival-ascended-first-ue5-gameplay-cross-platform-modding/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">released</a> nearly two years ago.</p>
<p>During this event, Survivors can collect cake slices for buffs, discover a flashy set of Party Dinos, and grab new cosmetics like the Birthday Suit and Party Hat skins. There's even a DJ Party emote, a Rave Dance, and a Club ARK tropical Island makeover. The 10-year anniversary celebration is already live on official servers until Tuesday, June 17. Owners of unofficial ARK servers can enable it by adding "-ActiveEvent=Birthday" to their command line. The developers also introduced a drop-down option to enable Active Events in Host/Single-Player mode under Game Rules &gt; Rules.</p>
<p>There's a lot more in store for fans than just the event, though. A free update has been released, updating the game from Unreal Engine 5.2 to Unreal Engine 5.5. According to Studio Wildcard, players can expect a noticeable performance boost, not to mention improved visual rendering, quicker loading times, and a lower install size thanks to optional downloads for the expansion DLCs. Additionally, PlayStation 5 Pro owners can look forward to improved long-range shadow and support for the PlayStation Spectral Super Resolution (PSSR) upscale, which delivers up to 30% higher frame rates.</p>
<p><iframe title="ASA Unreal 5.5 Upgrade, Anniversary Event, Astraeos Update" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/l3Ta689CCoQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>There's also new content available for owners of the Astraeos DLC. The Lemnokis update adds another vast island created by the renowned ARK modder Nekatus. This sprawling new island features diverse biomes, hidden caves, and towering redwoods. Its ancient ruins and colossal statues hint at lost civilizations. However, the lush expansion isn't just for sightseeing, as players can also take on the game's first-ever duo minibosses: Kalydonios and Erymanthian. These two massive boars fight with fire and poison. From deep-sea resource zones and the mysterious Maelstrom far offshore to a glacier cave tucked beneath the redwoods, Lemnokis is loaded with far-flung new adventures and prime build spots, not to mention the return of the fan-favourite snow owls.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Myth Wukong Xbox Launch Scheduled for Exactly One Year After PC/PS5]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/black-myth-wukong-xbox-launch-scheduled-for-exactly-one-year-after-pc-ps5/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-myth-wukong-xbox-launch-scheduled-for-exactly-one-year-after-pc-ps5.1209036/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/black-myth-wukong-xbox-launch-scheduled-for-exactly-one-year-after-pc-ps5/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, Chinese developer GameScience announced the Xbox release date of its highly acclaimed action RPG Black Myth Wukong. The game will debut on Xbox Series S and X consoles on August 20, 2025, exactly one year after the launch on PC and PlayStation 5.</p>
<p>The issue of the <a href="https://wccftech.com/black-myth-wukong-delays-xbox-series-sx-version-opens-pre-orders-on-pc-ps5-shares-pc-requirements/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">delay</a> was long disputed among the fanbase and even between GameScience and Microsoft itself. The developer of Black Myth Wukong openly <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-series-s-low-ram-black-myth-wukong/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> that the low amount of RAM available on the Xbox Series S was causing optimization headaches that had to be resolved before the launch. Microsoft, on the other hand, <a href="https://wccftech.com/black-myth-wukong-delay-has-nothing-to-do-with-xbox-limitations-says-microsoft/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">commented</a> that the Xbox console was not the issue.</p>
<p>It's hard to know where the truth lies in this case, but it is quite peculiar that everything has been worked out to coincide with the one-year anniversary of the same. It's definitely possible that there was a silent timed exclusivity deal with Sony. After all, a PlayStation executive <a href="https://sonyinteractive.com/en/news/blog/leadership-spotlight-a-conversation-with-phil-rosenberg/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">confirmed</a> in an interview that the Content Ventures team supported games like Genshin Impact, Stellar Blade, and Black Myth Wukong, and the two other games did launch on PlayStation first.</p>
<p>Anyway, pre-orders for the Xbox version will open on June 18. On the same day, GameScience has also planned to kick off the first discount campaign, which will reduce the price by 20%. Thankfully, the same will apply to Xbox pre-orders from June 18 to July 11.</p>
<p>Black Myth Wukong was a smashing success for GameScience, <a href="https://wccftech.com/black-myth-wukong-sold-18-million-copies-expansion/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">selling over 18 million units</a> in just the first two weeks. More importantly for Xbox gamers, it's a damn good game well worth playing if you're into its genre, as explained thoroughly in <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/black-myth-wukong-a-compelling-journey-into-chinese-tradition/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Wccftech's review</a> penned by Francesco De Meo:</p>
<p><em>Black Myth: Wukong couldn't have been a better debut for Game Science. Although their action role-playing game may not be innovative, it's got great production values, it's fun to play, it's engaging, and it's beautiful to look at. Some minor issues, such as a challenge level that could be too low for some and an experience that gets a little stale over time, hold back the game a bit, but in all honesty, I wouldn't be surprised to see more than a few players name Black Myth: Wukong their Game of the Year.</em></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>