<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 12:30:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grand Theft Auto VI May Remain the Most Expensive Entry, as Future Titles Could Be Cheaper to Develop Thanks to AI]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-most-expensive-gta-7-ai/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grand-theft-auto-vi-may-remain-the-most-expensive-entry-as-future-titles-could-be-cheaper-to-develop-thanks-to-ai.1235922/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Grand Theft Auto VI will likely remain the most expensive entry in the series even after its sequel is released, as a former Rockstar Games employee expects the development of the seventh entry to be cheaper.</p>



<p>Speaking on the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@KIWITALKZ">KIWI TALKS</a> show, former Rockstar Games Technical Lead Obbe Vermeij, who worked on many iconic entries in the series like Vice City and San Andreas, discussed the future of the franchise past the sixth entry in the series launching next year, saying that there's likely not going to be a more expensive entry in the series than Grand Theft Auto VI because a lot of the development work is going to be taken over by AI, such as the work for maps and cutscenes. As such, no longer needing manual labor for these tasks, it is expected that Grand Theft Auto 7 will be cheaper to make than its predecessor, painting once again a grim picture for anyone working in the gaming industry. It will take a while, however, to see if Vermeij's prediction will be true, as we are unlikely to see Grand Theft Auto 7 for a very long time.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="#191 - Obbe Vermeij Interview On The GTA Trilogy, GTA VI, Rockstar And His Indie Game Plentiful....." width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AYcdZTGvIBs?start=1323&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Talking about Grand Theft Auto 7 definitely seems a bit premature, considering Grand Theft Auto VI still has to come out. The highly anticipated new entry in the series was supposed to launch before the end of the year, but back in May, Rockstar Games confirmed the game would need more time and will launch in <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-launches-may-26/">May 2026</a>. Despite the delay, the excitement surrounding the game continues to be high, and some of its features promise to change not only open-world games but also entertainment as a whole, such as the rumored option for <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-may-allow-music-artists-to-upload-their-music-directly-in-the-game/">artists to upload their music directly into the game.</a></p>



<p>Grand Theft Auto VI launches on May 26, 2026 on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X and Xbox Series S.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-most-expensive-gta-7-ai/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Forza Motorsport Dev Turn 10 Has Been Turned Into a Forza Horizon Support Studio – Rumor]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/forza-motorsport-dev-turn-10-support-forza-horizon/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/forza-motorsport-dev-turn-10-has-been-turned-into-a-forza-horizon-support-studio-%E2%80%93-rumor.1235919/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Forza Motorsport series developer Turn 10 has become a Forza Horizon support studio, according to rumors circulating online.</p>



<p>As spotted on the <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/former-turn-10-studios-employee-claims-that-forza-motorsport-has-been-shuttered-and-the-studio-will-be-supporting-horizon.1235709/">ResetERA forums</a>, former Turn 10 employee Fred Russel revealed on <a href="https://www.facebook.com/AlfaMale164S">Facebook</a> that the studio has shuttered the Forza Motorsport space and is now <a href="https://i.gyazo.com/0883ecbe1a63f7f109aa85ebde368458.png">a support studio for the Forza Horizon series</a> developed by Playground Games. As <a href="https://wccftech.com/forza-motorsport-developer-turn-10-hit-hard-layoffs/">over 70 employees were laid off this week</a>, this was somewhat expected.</p>



<p>Forza Motorsport developer Turn 10 is only one of the studios that has been impacted by the recent wave of layoffs. The Initiative, the studio put together to work on a new entry in the Perfect Dark series, was <a href="https://wccftech.com/perfect-dark-cancelled-the-initiative-shut-down-microsoft-layoffs/">shut down</a>, and the project was cancelled. Rare's<a href="https://wccftech.com/rare-everwild-cancelled-microsoft-gaming-layoffs/"> Everwild</a> was similarly cancelled, as was a new MMORPG by ZeniMax Online, which was <a href="https://wccftech.com/spencer-reportedly-loved-playing-zenimax-onlines-new-game-in-march-only-to-cancel-it-in-july/">reportedly loved by Phil Spencer back in March</a>, but apparently being widely appreciated by the head of Xbox is not enough to avoid cancellation. Other projects developed by other partners were also cancelled, including <a href="https://wccftech.com/doom-creators-romero-games-next-unannounced-project-has-been-cancelled/">an unannounced FPS</a> that was in the works by Romero Games, the studio founded by the co-creator of the DOOM series, John Romero.</p>



<p>It's a massive shame that the Forza Motorsport series seems to be done for the time being, as the latest entry in the franchise was a return to form, according to Chris. You can learn more about it in his <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/forza-motorsport-review/">review.</a></p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/forza-motorsport-dev-turn-10-support-forza-horizon/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation 5 Pro Can’t Run the Same AMD FSR 4 Mode as RDNA 4 GPUs; Released Games May Need an Update to Use the Upscaler]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-pro-can-t-run-amd-fsr-4-ai-model/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-5-pro-can%E2%80%99t-run-the-same-amd-fsr-4-mode-as-rdna-4-gpus-released-games-may-need-an-update-to-use-the-upscaler.1235868/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>AMD FSR 4 running on PlayStation 5 Pro promises to be more interesting than anticipated, judging from what a well-known insider revealed recently.</p>



<p>Speaking on the NeoGAF forums, known AMD insider KeplerL2 commented on the recent announcement that the next version of the AMD upscaler is coming to PlayStation 5 Pro next year, saying that the system cannot run the model that is being used by the upscaler to run on RDNA4 GPUs. Sony and AMD started working on the mid-generation refresh before AMD decided to move FSR to an ML model, and when the company made the switch, the PlayStation 5 Pro design was done with no FP8 support. As such, it will be very interesting to see how running the <a href="https://wccftech.com/amd-fsr4-ps5-pro-2026-rdna5/">full-fat version of the upscale</a>r on the system will be achieved.</p>



<p>Those expecting to see games that support the AI-powered PSSR on PlayStation 5 Pro to automatically support AMD FSR 4 without developer intervention, however, may be disappointed. As far as KeplerL2 <a href="https://www.neogaf.com/threads/ps5-pro-is-getting-a-big-upgrade-in-2026-%E2%80%94-i-asked-mark-cerny-what%E2%80%99s-coming-and-why-amd%E2%80%99s-future-pc-gpus-feel-more-playstation-than-ever.1685909/post-270585067">knows</a>, the current version of the PlayStation Spectral Super Resolution upscaler doesn't allow system-level DLL swaps, so there's a very likely chance that developers will have to update already released games if they want to take advantage of AMD FSR 4 once it becomes available for the system in 2026.</p>



<p>Besides offering the aforementioned AI-powered PlayStation Spectral Super Resolution upscaler, whose implementation has been hit and miss, depending on the game, the PlayStation 5 Pro offers other improvements that make it the system of choice to enjoy PS5 games at their very best. You can learn more about the system by checking out Kai's <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/playstation-5-pro-hardware-the-next-gen-graphics-upgrade/">review.</a></p>





			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-pro-can-t-run-amd-fsr-4-ai-model/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Once Human 2.0 Is Out Now; Console Ports and PvP Spin-Off Are Inbound]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/once-human-2-0-is-out-now-console-ports-and-pvp-spin-off-are-inbound/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/once-human-2-0-is-out-now-console-ports-and-pvp-spin-off-are-inbound.1235814/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>NetEase Games made a lot of significant <a href="https://wccftech.com/once-human-exceeds-230000-peak-players-since-release-devs-tease-major-update/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Once Human</a> announcements during yesterday's Global Annual Showcase. Annual version 2.0 is now available and every player can claim 11 Lightforge Ingots for free by participating in the new events and completing tasks. Players can earn additional rewards through in-game activities, such as playing the Dreamland Wonder mini-games, rescuing the giant Chefosaurus Rex, and checking in daily.</p>



<p>The developers also launched a new PvE scenario called Endless Dream. It's a Nightmare-themed world filled with bizarre, psychedelic elements, such as CRT TVs and abandoned amusement parks. This haunted, odd world is filled with secrets waiting to be uncovered.</p>



<p>The entire world map is available from the start in Endless Dream. This strange world is a shattered reflection of the subconscious, divided into Dream Zones and Nightmare Areas. To survive, players must face supernatural environmental hazards and be wary of the new Confusion mechanic.</p>



<p>Those who wish to purify the Dream Zones must contend with their guardians: Light Dreamers, Deep Dreamers, and the most lethal of all, Eternal Dreamers. These new Deviants include Agony, a humanoid/transformer hybrid that emits electricity; Misery, a statue with flowers growing within its body that attacks by detonating itself; and Naivety, an adorable teddy bear with a haunted TV in its belly.</p>



<p>Once Human players have the power to shape the land in the Endless Dream. They can freely build offensive and defensive structures without territorial restrictions. Exploring the world and conquering its nightmares unlocks additional traits and influences the outcome through a real-time, five-stage dynamic progression based on how efficiently players purge the nightmares. This results in one of multiple endings.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Once Human | PvE Scenario Endless Dream Live Now!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SAzi7orRJEk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>NetEase also provided updates on console ports and a spin-off. When it comes to consoles, Once Human is set to launch in 2026 on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series S|X, with the ports nearing completion.</p>



<p>As for the PvP spin-off, Once Human: RaidZone is set to launch on July 30 and it's all about combat. Players start with nothing and must gather weapons and building materials from the land. Forming alliances with other players is necessary, but only temporary. You must pick your allies carefully and be ready to turn on them when needed.</p>



<p>The entire RaidZone map is unrestricted, and players can strike each other's bases at any time. The Deviation Powers from the base game have also been reworked for the PvP experience, so players can unleash the might of Deviations on their foes.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/once-human-2-0-is-out-now-console-ports-and-pvp-spin-off-are-inbound/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Some Switch 2 Units Are Overheating, According to Reports]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/some-switch-2-units-are-overheating/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/some-switch-2-units-are-overheating-according-to-reports.1235811/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>According to several <a href="https://nintendosoup.com/japanese-users-complain-about-overheating-nintendo-switch-2-consoles-and-noisy-fans/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reports</a>, most of which are coming from Japan, some Nintendo Switch 2 units may be overheating. At least, that's what users are assuming when they see sudden freezes and crashes while the console's fans run at max speed in the vain attempt to cool down the hardware.</p>



<p>This happens with all kinds of Nintendo Switch 2 games, from the most taxing ones like CD Projekt RED's Cyberpunk 2077 to way less complex titles like Rune Factory: Guardians of Azuma.</p>



<p>A few reports came in from Western gamers, too. Reddit user NitroWalrus732 <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Switch/comments/1l4918o/switch_2_overheating/?utm_source=embedv2&amp;utm_medium=post_embed&amp;utm_content=post_body&amp;embed_host_url=https://www.tomshardware.com/video-games/handheld-gaming/nintendo-switch-2-units-allegedly-overheating-users-report-issues-while-playing-cyberpunk-2077-and-less-power-hungry-games" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">wrote</a>:</p>



<p><em>I've had my Switch 2 display a message saying that the system was overheating and entering sleep mode twice now, both times while playing Tears of the Kingdom Switch 2 Edition docked. I was also running at 2k resolution which probably wasn't helping but this is still worrying. Anybody else experienced this? Wondering if I could have a faulty system or maybe TotK is just that intensive.</em></p>



<p>If you're experiencing similar issues, there's not much that you can do except clean the air vents and turn off the console for a while to let it cool down. If the issues persist, you should send it to Nintendo for repair.</p>



<p>Regardless of such problems, the Nintendo Switch 2 continues to sell extremely well. According to the <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-likely-sold-more-than-5-million-units-in-june/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">latest estimates</a>, the hybrid handheld/home console may have surpassed 5 million units sold in June, although these are not official figures. Nintendo's own fiscal year forecast of 15 million units should be easily beaten by March 2026.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/some-switch-2-units-are-overheating/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>