<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - wccftech_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/wccftech_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for wccftech_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 13:17:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oblivion Remastered Unofficial Patch Packs Massive Number of Fixes and Improvements]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/oblivion-remastered-patch-fixes/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/oblivion-remastered-unofficial-patch-packs-massive-number-of-fixes-and-improvements.1179507/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/oblivion-remastered-patch-fixes/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A new The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered unofficial patch is now available for download, addressing a huge number of bugs.</p>
<p>The patch, which can be downloaded from <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/oblivionremastered/mods/477" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nexus Mods</a> and requires game version 0.411.140.0, addresses a massive number of issues, including script, quest, NPC, object, item, dialogue bugs, and more. The main goal of the unofficial patch is to eventually fix every bug in Oblivion Remastered that won't be fixed by the developers within the capabilities of the Creation Kit and other community-developed tools. The complete changelog for the latest version of the unofficial patch can be found <a href="https://www.afkmods.com/Unofficial%20Oblivion%20Remastered%20Patch%20Version%20History.html">here.</a></p>
<p>As the game still uses the original's Gamebryo engine, The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered features the usual selection of bugs and issues that have become tradition for Bethesda games. Even with these bugs and performance issues on PC, the remaster of the fourth entry in the beloved series is a more than worthy purchase for any role-playing game fan, as I highlighted in my <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-back-in-cyrodiil-19-years-later/">review</a>.</p>
<p><em>Enhancing the original where it mattered most while preserving what made it truly unique, The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered stands as the definitive way to experience Bethesda’s classic. Although the shift in atmosphere and noticeable performance issues will put some players off, as will the dated gameplay, the game couldn't have debuted on current gaming platforms in a better way.</em></p>
<p>The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered is now available on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X and Xbox Series S.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grand Theft Auto VI Launches On May 26 2026, Rockstar Games Confirms]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-launches-may-26/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grand-theft-auto-vi-launches-on-may-26-2026-rockstar-games-confirms.1179504/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-launches-may-26/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-another-trailer/">Grand Theft Auto VI</a> has been delayed from its Fall 2025 release window, and will now launch next year on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S.</p>
<p>Today, Rockstar Games confirmed on <a href="https://x.com/RockstarGames/status/1918265468076605706?t=Px5bjAPYlpMHJab6nnPEdQ&amp;s=19" target="_blank" rel="noopener">X</a> the highly anticipated new entry in the series will not launch this year as expected, and will now release on May 26, 2026 worldwide on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X and Xbox Series S. While apologizing to fans for launching the game later than expected, the developer highlighted how their goal has always been to try and exceed their exceptions and with Grand Theft Auto VI, they want to do no different. As such, extra development time is required to reach the quality that players expect and deserve. More information on the game will be shared soon, so hopefully another look at the game won't take too long.</p>
<p>While it is disappointing to learn that Grand Theft Auto VI will not be released later this year on consoles, it is most definitely not that surprising. Considering their long history of delays, it would have been more surprising for Rockstar Games not to delay what is going to be, regardless, the biggest entertainment launch of all time to date, according to <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-is-expected-to-be-the-biggest-entertainment-launch-of-all-time-but-a-performance-below-expectations-could-impact-the-entire-industry/">analysts</a>.</p>
<p>Grand Theft Auto VI launches on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X, and Xbox Series S on May 26, 2026. We will update you as soon as Rockstar Games shares more information, so stay tuned for all the latest news.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blades of Fire Free Copies to Be Given Away at London Comic-Con – If You’re Celebrating Your Steel Wedding]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/blades-of-fire-free-copies-to-be-given-away-at-london-comic-con-if-youre-celebrating-your-steel-wedding/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/blades-of-fire-free-copies-to-be-given-away-at-london-comic-con-%E2%80%93-if-you%E2%80%99re-celebrating-your-steel-wedding.1179417/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/blades-of-fire-free-copies-to-be-given-away-at-london-comic-con-if-youre-celebrating-your-steel-wedding/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, Blades of Fire publisher 505 Games announced a rather unusual offer. They'll be giving away free digital copies of the game (presumably handing out redeemable codes) at London Comic-Con in three weeks, on Friday, May 23. There's a pretty big caveat, though: you have to be celebrating your Steel Wedding (11-year) anniversary on May 22. That means you only get a free copy if you were married on May 22, 2014, and can bring a wedding certificate (or copy/photo) attesting to this.</p>
<p>The seemingly arbitrary date is obviously a reference to <a href="https://wccftech.com/blades-of-fire-is-a-new-action-adventure-from-mercurysteam-out-on-may-22/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the game's launch date</a>, set for May 22, 2025 on PC (only <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/blades-of-fire-f8178f" target="_blank" rel="noopener">on the Epic Games Store</a>, at least for now), PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series S|X. The game will be priced at $59.99, although there's a 10% pre-order discount available now on PC and Xbox. PlayStation users can also get the same discount, but only if they have an active PlayStation Plus subscription. As a side note, if you want to play on PC but don't have a good enough hardware (the system requirements <a href="https://wccftech.com/blades-of-fire-detailed-requirements-upscaled-4k/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">are fairly demanding</a>), the game will be playable via cloud <a href="https://wccftech.com/geforce-now-to-get-doom-the-dark-ages-blades-of-fire-and-more-in-may/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">through NVIDIA GeForce NOW</a>.</p>
<p>Blades of Fire had a relatively short marketing period, having been revealed only in late February. However, MercurySteam has shared many details on the action/adventure game since. The title is set in a fantasy world where the evil queen Nerea has magically turned everyone's steel into stone, making it impossible to challenge her rule. However, protagonist Aran de Lira receives a unique hammer that isn't affected by the curse and sets out on a journey to take her down.</p>
<p>Forging weapons is, therefore, <a href="https://wccftech.com/blades-of-fire-will-focus-strictly-on-weapons-and-your-skills-instead-of-magic-and-rpg-stats/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a big part of the game</a>. Not only are there seven weapon families and 30 Forge Scrolls, but even the choice of materials will greatly influence the crafted weapon, leading to many different combinations. It will be up to the player to choose the right tool for the job, too, as weapons can have wildly different efficiencies depending on the enemy's armor. With over 50 enemy types, players will have to keep track of each one's strengths and weaknesses. The combat system also lets players attack specific body parts.</p>
<p>MercurySteam also <a href="https://wccftech.com/blades-of-fire-is-a-narrative-driven-game-where-you-decide-how-much-you-want-to-know/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> that Blades of Fire is narrative-driven. At the same time, players will decide how much they want to know about the story. One way to do that is by engaging in dialogue with Aran's companion, the young scholar Adso de Zelk, who is something of a human encyclopedia.</p>
<p>After <a href="https://wccftech.com/blades-of-fire-gdc-2025-hands-on-preview-a-pleasant-surprise/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">going hands-on with the game at GDC 2025</a>, Kai Tatsumoto was quite interested in the final game:</p>
<p><em>MercurySteam’s strange AA blacksmithing adventure wasn’t on my radar before going to GDC after missing the initial preview event, but after going hands-on for an hour or so, I was pleasantly surprised with their latest unique IP. It’s just unique enough with the strong emphasis on forging and reforging that gives this action adventure a hook that I haven’t seen done before to this extent. The actual story itself could be a standard fantasy slop, and I’d still be on board for crafting a massive warhammer and just playing out my barbarian fantasies.</em></p>
<p>By the way, a new Blades of Fire trailer will go live later today during Future Game Show's Gamescom LATAM edition. We'll update this story once it is available.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>